<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Journal of Portfolio Management5</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>An alternative future: Part II - An exploration of the role of hedge funds.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asness, C.
An argument can be made that hedge funds, particularly a combination of traditional index funds and hedge funds, represent the future of investment management-but we are not there yet, for a variety of reasons. Some dark sides of hedge fund investing stand in the way. Hedge fund fees remain a contentious issue. Fees must become more rational in terms of paying for alpha versus hedge fund beta versus traditional beta. Other evolutionary changes must occur to make hedge funds more user-friendly, particularly for institutional investors.</description><author>Asness, C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The losers in the game of meeting expectatilons</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comovement as an investment tool - Potentially useful.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornell, B.
A new tool for discovering mispriced securities is based on an analysis of comovement in asset prices. Recent research demonstrates that comovement can be due to both the trading patterns of noise traders and underlying economic fundamentals. As comovement can be measured much more accurately than expected returns, it can be used to identify securities for which the influence of noise traders is high and thus the securities most likely subject to mispricing. Analysis of comovement is a screening device that can provide important information about potential mispricing.</description><author>Cornell, B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The changing mosaic of investment patterns - A new picture of allocation decisions.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leibowitz, M. L.; Hammond, P. B.
The stock market bubble of the late 1990s and its aftermath suggest that volatile short-term trends and our wider range of asset classes may require as a response a more fluid strategy than the standard stable policy asset allocation model. Three basic questions are: What do the recently available data on institutional and individual investor asset allocation indicate about how different types of investors respond to equity market movements? How should we understand these different behaviors? And what are the implications for equity markets? An integrated rebalancing model based on these findings offers a framework for development of more proactive allocation strategies.</description><author>Leibowitz, M. L.; Hammond, P. B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The beta-Plus measure in asset allocation - Natural segmentation into stock-like and diversifier components.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leibowitz, M. L.
The explicit covariance matrix employed in the standard asset allocation process can also be used to develop an analytic beta measure of the portfolio's exposure to the equity market. While these allocation-level beta measures are typically not an element in the routine performance reports of U. S. pension and endowment funds, they would be an informative addition. There are powerful arguments for routine incorporation of beta measures in asset allocation studies as a separate component of risk specification.</description><author>Leibowitz, M. L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>S&amp;P 500 indexers, tracking error, and liquidity - A complex answer to profiting.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blume, M. E.; Edelen, R. M.
It is widely known that stocks added to the S&amp;P 500 index experience abnormal returns on announcement. Why then do S&amp;P 500 indexers not trade at the opening price immediately following announcement of a change in the index, which would gain them an average of 19.2 additional basis points of return per year? The catch is a much higher standard deviation of tracking error. To achieve the low tracking errors observed in practice, an indexer must closely follow an exact-replication strategy. That two of the largest indexers have enhanced their returns indicates more active management than just holding all 500 stocks in the exact same proportions as the index. Practitioners interviewed suggest - and the empirical evidence confirms - that many indexers are effectively compensated for entering into bilateral agreements with providers of liquidity to trade at the closing price. The patterns of abnormal returns for changes in the index are exactly those that are needed to compensate liquidity providers for the risks that they assume in providing liquidity to indexers.</description><author>Blume, M. E.; Edelen, R. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset return distributions and the investment horizon - Explaining contradictions.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, H.; Duchin, R.
The optimal investment decision rule and asset equilibrium prices depend on the assumed distribution of rates of return. And empirical distributions vary with the assumed time interval ( investment horizon). The authors test the goodness of fit of 11 theoretical distributions including the normal distribution, fat-tailed distributions, and skewed distributions for investment horizons ranging from one day to four years. The normal distribution performs poorly, and never provides the best fit for any time interval. In the 330 goodness of fit tests reported, at least one distribution of the 11 always fits the data better than the normal distribution. As the logistic distribution fits the data best for investment horizons of up to one year, analysis focuses on this distribution and its implications for equilibrium asset prices.</description><author>Levy, H.; Duchin, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analysis of risk-adjusted performance of global market assets - An anticipated consistency between returns and risk.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reilly, F. K.; Wright, D. J.
The broad set of 38 global capital market assets examined here includes U. S. and international stocks and bonds, real estate, commodities, and a composite index of global stocks and bonds. Relationships between returns and risk reported are consistent with theoretical expectations. The risk-adjusted performance measures indicate a wide range of performance for alternative assets. Rankings of alternative assets, though, depend on the specific risk-adjusted performance measure used.</description><author>Reilly, F. K.; Wright, D. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portable alpha - Philosophy, process, and performance.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kung, E.; Pohlman, L.
Active investment managers provide two types of return: the return from market exposure (or beta) and the return from selection skill (or alpha). Active beta returns typically come from market timing - increasing market exposure in up markets and reducing it in down markets; passive beta returns come from index fund exposure. Alpha comes from security selection within an asset class, so the value that stock-picking adds does not depend on the direction of the market. A true stock-picker, that is, would have a beta of 1.0 relative to the market benchmark, and all value-added would come from active risk or stock-picking. "Portable" alpha may be achieved by separating the alpha from the beta and then applying it to other portfolios. Investors can obtain portable alphas through traditional long-only strategies. There are benefits and drawbacks of implementing portable alphas in a variety of investment scenarios.</description><author>Kung, E.; Pohlman, L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investing in global equities - Changing determinants of returns.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cavaglia, S.; Diermeier, J.; Moroz, V.; De Zordo, S.
Accelerating globalization of business enterprise and the integration of capital markets are altering the international equity investment environment. The empirical evidence suggests that security price returns have become more closely associated with industry affiliation than with country of domicile. Within-country comparisons of securities are now a less effective way to identify attractively valued stocks; comparing securities within global industries and across countries appears instead to provide a more powerful approach to identifying future winners. Structural changes like these necessitate a more global approach to equity investing. Plan sponsors, asset managers, and individual investors should respond by altering their investment process to reflect this new economic reality.</description><author>Cavaglia, S.; Diermeier, J.; Moroz, V.; De Zordo, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sell discipline and institutional money management - Depends greatly on market conditions.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faugere, C.; Shawky, H. A.; Smith, D. M.
There has been next to no study in the financial literature of sell decisions. An institutional money management database covering more than 7,000 investment portfolios now facilitates examination of different sell discipline criteria with respect to risk-adjusted returns and downside risk. The evidence indicates that portfolio performance is strongly related to the choice of the sell discipline criterion, even correcting for the potential effects of investment style changes over the period investigated. In rising markets, institutional money managers are likely to benefit from using less restrictive sell discipline criteria, while in declining markets they might benefit from a more restrictive sell discipline criterion. Market conditions, that is, strongly influence the effectiveness of the various sell discipline criteria.</description><author>Faugere, C.; Shawky, H. A.; Smith, D. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimizing selection of credit portfolios - Useful for both managers and investors.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McDermott, G.; Skarabot, J.; Kroujiline, A.
Our ability today to construct a great number of portfolios that all satisfy the same set of static collateralized debt obligation (CDO) investment guideline, can potentially introduce credit hot spots that will not be detected by traditional rating agency measures. As more and more CDO market participants recognize these risks, they are turning to market-based measures such as bond and loan prices and debt-equity models to parse credit aberrations in credit portfolios and detect selection biases. Various market-based information and models will be helpful in CDO and cash-based portfolio selection. New asset selection tools for structured credit products allow investors to benchmark the performance of seasoned CDO tranches.</description><author>McDermott, G.; Skarabot, J.; Kroujiline, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A value at risk approach to risk-return analysis: Comment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, X. T.
nan</description><author>Huang, X. T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A value at risk approach to risk-return analysis: Comment: Response</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dowd, K.
nan</description><author>Dowd, K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Surprising the smoothies once again</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The great alpha tree</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liability-relative investing - Be dual duration-matched and on the surplus efficient frontier</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Waring, M. B.
The notion of duration-matching, well-developed in the 1980s in nominal terms, is here extended to the dual durations of price sensitivity to real interest rates and to inflation rates. All assets (and liabilities) can be characterized more accurately using two durations instead of one. Equities and many other assets and instruments have different real interest rate and inflation durations, as does a liability. Duration-matching offers a secondary pension risk control measure after surplus optimization. The author develops a solution that duration-matches assets with the pension liability, and shows how to integrate it with surplus optimization, achieving better pension risk control in the process.</description><author>Waring, M. B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal active risk budgeting model - Applied to a multiasset class fund.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Figelman, I.
A structured global optimization model budgets a fund's total active risk (tracking error) among its asset classes or across investment managers. Its objective is to maximize total fund expected excess return (over benchmark) for a given level of total fund tracking error (the active risk budget), assuming that total fund and asset class tracking errors are controlled solely through the selection of investment managers with various active risk profiles. The key innovations are, first, that the efficient frontier (expected excess return versus tracking error) of each asset class is fitted to a functional form, and then the optimal active risk level for each asset class is determined using the asset class efficient frontier functions as inputs. The model compares well to a structured global linear model and an unstructured global model that optimizes with respect to A investment managers simultaneously.</description><author>Figelman, I.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Index fundamentalism revisited - The majesty of simplicity?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reinker, K. S.; Tower, E.
Is there any justification for investing in managed mutual funds, or are they only for chumps, as indexing advocatesargue? The authors answer the question by looking at 27 years of real fund returns for Vanguard, a company notable for its low fees on managed funds. Analysis of synthetic portfolios based on the assets of Vanguard's mutual funds indicates that whether index funds or managed funds are the superior buy depends on the time span in question, but managed funds almost always have a lower standard deviation of return than index funds.</description><author>Reinker, K. S.; Tower, E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Active versus passive strategies for EAFE and the S&amp;P 500 - Using an active model to shift between the two.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arshanapalli, B.; Switzer, L. N.; Hung, L. T. S.
The authors establish a dynamic asset allocation strategy investing in EAFE and the S&amp;P 500 indexes to time the market and generate a superior abnormal return on a portfolio. A prediction model built on public information variables can forecast the upcoming movements of the two indexes for 1978 through 1999. Even with transaction costs, out-of-sample tests show an investor can rely on model signals to allocate assets between the indexes and produce significantly more terminal wealth than would passive portfolios invested in either index alone.</description><author>Arshanapalli, B.; Switzer, L. N.; Hung, L. T. S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The EVA style of investing - Emphasizing the fundamentals of wealth creation.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abate, J. A.; Grant, J. L.; Stewart, G. B.
A shift in equity management would define the style of a company in terms of its fundamental ability to create wealth. From an economic value added perspective, a growth company invests for rapid economic profit change, while a value company looks to create wealth through downsizing or restructuring a low-to-negative economic profit spread business. In either case-EVA growth or value-these company types (among profiles between the extremes) represent good stocks when actual expectations of economic profit growth exceed expectations already imbedded in share price. This economic profit style of investing emphasizes the fundamentals of wealth creation and reconciliation of share price with the level realistically achievable.</description><author>Abate, J. A.; Grant, J. L.; Stewart, G. B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal credit allocation for buy-and-hold investors - A top-down, strategic approach.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dynkin, L.; Hyman, J.; Phelps, B. D.
The trade-offs between risk and return are different for buy-and-hold investors and total return investors. For buy-and-hold investors, the portfolio return distribution is asymmetric; the maximum return is the yield, and the maximum loss is represented by default. The standard tools that total return investors use for top-down asset allocation (such as mean-variance optimization) and bottom-up security selection (such as multifactor risk models) are thus inappropriate. A more suitable approach for buy-and-hold investors, given current spreads, default rates and correlations, and loss tolerance, derives an optimal macro allocation across credit qualities. Application of this approach yields an optimized portfolio to minimize expected shortfall due to defaults, subject to a spread target and other portfolio constraints. The results suggest buy-and-hold investors should first determine their allocations to the A and Baa sectors, and then use an optimizer to select individual names.</description><author>Dynkin, L.; Hyman, J.; Phelps, B. D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock ownership decisions in defined-contribution pension plans - High own-company holdings are not explainable.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Douglass, J.; Wu, O.; Ziemba, W.
Why would investors choose a large weighting in the stock of their employer? Holding employer company stock is very risky. It is optimal only for employees with very low risk aversion or with very high return expectations for company stock. Rational one-period models cannot explain high observed weightings in company stock in defined-contribution pension plans. Nor can a behavioral interpretation. Some factors must be missing from rational choice models to explain employer company stock holdings.</description><author>Douglass, J.; Wu, O.; Ziemba, W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Don't worry about the election - Just watch the fed</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beyer, S. B.; Jensen, G. R.; Johnson, R. R.
In this election year, it is interesting to examine historical security market returns in terms of the political party of the President, the general monetary policy stance of the Federal Reserve, and political gridlock, when different political parties control Congress and the executive branch. It is an innovation to evaluate the three variables jointly. Such a combined analysis reveals that long-term security returns are strongly related to shifts in Fed monetary policy but generally invariant to changes in the political landscape. Investors should thus focus their attention on Fed actions rather than political outcomes.</description><author>Beyer, S. B.; Jensen, G. R.; Johnson, R. R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Honey, I shrunk the sample covariance matrix - Problems in mean-variance optimization.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ledoit, O.; Wolf, M.
yThe central message of this article is that no one should use the sample covariance matrix for portfolio optimization. It is subject to estimation error of the kind most likely to perturb a mean-variance optimizer. Instead, a matrix can be obtained from the sample covariance matrix through a transformation called shrinkage. This tends to pull the most extreme coefficients toward more central values, systematically reducing estimation error when it matters most. Statistically, the challenge is to know the optimal shrinkage intensity. Shrinkage reduces portfolio tracking error relative to a benchmark index, and substantially raises the manager's realized information ratio.</description><author>Ledoit, O.; Wolf, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring credit spread risk - Incorporating the tails.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, R.; Huisman, R.
It is widely known that the possibility of default makes the expected return distribution for financial products that are subject to credit risk highly skewed and fat-tailed. Recent development of an unbiased tail index estimator enables modeling of the additional risk presented by changes in swap spreads. Tests on data from the U. S., the U. K., Germany, and Japan indicate that we tend to grossly underestimate the risk of large spread widenings and tightenings. Estimation of swap spread risk is dramatically improved when the severity of the additional downside risk is measured and incorporated into current estimation techniques. These results are crucial in improving credit risk management and pricing out-of-the-money credit derivatives.</description><author>Campbell, R.; Huisman, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stocks, bonds, and hedge funds - Not a free lunch.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amin, G. S.; Kat, H. M.
What are the diversification effects of introducing hedge funds into a portfolio of stocks and bonds? In terms of skewness and kurtosis, equity and hedge funds do not combine very well. Although hedge funds significantly improve a portfolio's mean-variance characteristics, their inclusion can also be expected to lead to significantly lower skewness as well as higher kurtosis. Hedge funds do not provide a free lunch, but rather entail a definite trade-off between profit and loss potential. To have any impact on the overall portfolio, allocations to hedge funds would have to far exceed the typical 1% to 5% that many institutions typically consider.</description><author>Amin, G. S.; Kat, H. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A critical look at the case for hedge funds - Lessons from the bubble.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ennis, R. M.; Sebastian, M. D.
Hedge funds are supposed to be largely market-neutral, meaning their returns exhibit relatively little correlation with market returns. One often hears that they make money in down markets as well as up. To the extent that hedge fund returns are uncorrelated with market returns, and the funds earn a positive risk premium, a hedge fund allocation would be generally indicated for efficiently diversified portfolios. In fact, the evidence is that diversified hedge fund investment is not market-neutral; significant, persistent market exposures and a high degree of market correlation are identified here. Diversified hedge fund portfolios also exhibit a surprising degree of variability in factor exposures over time, revealing the limits of hedge fund style diversification and indicating a herding tendency. Hedge funds have not demonstrated the ability to make money in a down market, but rather a good sense of market timing in coping with the U. S. stock market bubble. Neither performance nor cost considerations warrant hedge fund inclusion in balanced portfolios.</description><author>Ennis, R. M.; Sebastian, M. D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio performance evaluation using value at risk - The reward-to-VaR ratio.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, G. J.; Baptista, A. M.
Developed here is a value at risk-based measure of portfolio performance called the reward-to-VaR ratio. It is demonstrated that, under normality, the reward-to-VaR ratio gives the same ranking for portfolio performance as the frequently used Sharpe ratio. Under non-normality, the reward-to-VaR ratio at one confidence level may give a ranking for portfolio performance different from the ranking obtained at a different confidence level. This indicates that the risk-taking incentives of a portfolio manager in a VaR-based risk management system can be substantially different from the incentives in a Sharpe ratio-based system.</description><author>Alexander, G. J.; Baptista, A. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Index mutual funds and exchange-traded funds - A comparison of two methods of passive investment.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kostovetsky, L.
Exchange-traded funds have proliferated in the last five years, but have not yet received much attention in the academic literature. The author explains the major dif-ferences between ETFs and their traditional index fund competitors, establishing a threshold model to compare their costs. A one-period model expanded to multiple periods helps in analysis of the sorts of investors who would prefer ETFs over index funds, and vice versa. The analysis suggests that ETFs are an especially important tool for larger investors and that long-term retail investors can also use them effectively.</description><author>Kostovetsky, L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value versus growth - Investor styles and stock characteristics.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bourguignon, F.; de Jong, M.
The common practice of classifying stocks as either value or growth on the basis of low or high price-to-book (PB) ratios - or, in general, any classification based on a criterion that includes current stock price - is equivocal. The practice is prone to confuse certain structural characteristics of stocks or firms with what are purely time influences. The PB of a firm may be structurally high (high on average over a long period of time), or high only momentarily (as a result of an exceptional price jump), so it would be a growth stock in the first case but not in the second. It would not be clear whether it is the structural characteristics of a stock or the time influences that are responsible for its performance. An experiment using an alternative definition of value and growth that deliberately separates the structural component from the time effects in PB ratios in six major markets demonstrates that, as soon as the time effects are eliminated in the classification process, value no longer outperforms.</description><author>Bourguignon, F.; de Jong, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the nature of trading - Do speculators leave footprints?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Silber, W. L.
Two types of traders, market makers and speculators, establish their positions and manage their risk exposure differently, but balance sheets are insufficient to let us determine whether a trader is a market maker or a speculator. We want to understand and verify trader behavior, because leveraged trading firms, and individual traders, typically have incentives to mask their risk-taking activities. Without proper monitoring, traders can substitute risky speculation for less risky market-making to reap potential payoffs. Trading records that describe the evolution of a position over time can help us identify the trading strategy pursued. And knowledge of the trading strategy is an aid to evaluate the contract compliance, risk exposure, and capital requirements of trading firms.</description><author>Silber, W. L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal portfolio rebalancing with transaction costs - Improving on calendar- or volatility-based strategies.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Donohue, C.; Yip, K.
Research has proven the optimality of a no-trade region around an investor's desired asset proportions to assure that trading occurs only when asset proportions drift outside this region, and then only to bring proportions back to the boundary of the no-trade region, not to the target proportions. Because current solution methods are complex, managers typically rely on ad hoc heuristics that are either calendar-based or volatility-based and whose performance against an optimal strategy is unknown. The authors characterize the size and shape of the no-trade region as a function of key problem parameters and compare the performance of different rebalancing strategies. The analysis suggests that extraction of key features associ-ated with optimal rebalancing allows development of more tractable rebalancing heuristics that enhance the effectiveness of optimal rebalancing.</description><author>Donohue, C.; Yip, K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Best execution - A candid analysis.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwartz, R. A.; Wood, R. A.
"Best execution," an obligation on equity market professionals that has been a holy grail in the United States since enactment of the Securities Acts Amendments of 1975, is a multifaceted concept that is difficult to define - and even more challenging to measure. The authors delineate the various measurement and implementation problems. They consider advice for the buy-side trader, implications for the providers of trading services, and caveats with regard to public policy. The best execution obligation in fact is shared across buy-side institutions, broker/dealer intermediaries, and the market centers themselves.</description><author>Schwartz, R. A.; Wood, R. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset allocation, decoupling, and the opportunity cost of cash - Enhancing performance in investment portfolios.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harper, R. B.
Investors often increase their cash and near-cash balances during periods of significant equity volatility. Feeling compelled to salvage what they can in the face of adversity, these investors overlook the opportunity to enhance performance by extending duration in the fixed-income portion of their balanced portfolios. They neglect to keep strategic as well as tactical goals in mind. When equities dominate portfolio volatility, the risk profile of the overall portfolio is relatively insensitive to measured duration extensions. Conversely, the portfolio receives the full return benefit of such an extension. The decoupling of liquid Treasury returns from equity returns during periods of crisis can reinforce the beneficial trade-off of extending duration and slightly reducing equity exposure. An analysis of market data over the past 21 years not only documents the risk-adjusted return benefits of extending duration, but also suggests enhanced downside risk protection.</description><author>Harper, R. B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The hierarchy of investment choice - A normative interpretation.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kritzman, M.; Page, S.
Which investment choice is most important? Is it allocation among broad asset classes, country allocation, choice of sector, or selection of individual securities? Many investors have a false impression of the relative importance of these choices for two reasons. First, investors fail to distinguish between the activities they choose to emphasize and those with the greatest potential to influence investment results. Second, to the extent that investors do measure the potential influence of an investment activity, they often base their choices on contrived portfolios that are unobtainable. Simulations including thousands of realistic portfolios help us determine the natural dispersion of performance arising from different investment activities, which makes it possible to evaluate the hierarchy of investment choice from a normative perspective.</description><author>Kritzman, M.; Page, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The design and production of new retirement savings products: A comment - The possible cost of peace of mind.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dert, C.; Lodewijk, M.; Oldenkamp, B.; de Pooter, M.
An earlier contribution to this journal implied that protective floor investment strategies in defined-contribution pension investments beat investments in traditional asset mixes, with respect to both the probability of achieving a minimum target level of future pension income and the expected level of future pension income. These commentators show that protective floor strategies may be attractive to loss-averse investors, but they do not beat traditional investments simultaneously on expected pension income and on the probability of achieving the target pension income.</description><author>Dert, C.; Lodewijk, M.; Oldenkamp, B.; de Pooter, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The accuracy of hedge fund returns - Auditing makes a real difference.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liang, B.
How can the same hedge fund report different performance measures in different places? The answer is that auditing plays an important role in explaining the differences. Although the majority of hedge funds state that they have auditors, a significant proportion of these funds are not effectively audited. Funds that have gone out of business have been particularly less effectively audited than funds that have survived, and audited funds have much smaller return discrepancies than non-audited funds. There is a significantly positive correlation between the fund size and the auditing variable. Large funds tend to be audited and small fund not. Funds listed on exchanges, funds of funds, funds with broad investor representation, funds open to the public, funds invested in a single industrial sector, and unlevered funds have smaller return discrepancies than other funds. These findings suggest a compelling need for hedge fund auditing.</description><author>Liang, B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Appropriate policy allocation for alternative investments - A factor approach and simulation techniques.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Terhaar, K.; Staub, R.; Singer, B.
One of the greatest problems institutional investors face in evaluating alternative investments such as venture capital, real estate, and hedge funds is determining the normal or policy allocation. The typical approach relies on single-period optimization programs, using historical data as key inputs. This is subject to problems such as enormous allocations to private equity and other non-market-priced investments. Instead, the authors use a factor approach to build a consistent set of return and risk characteristics for conventional and alternative asset classes alike. Simulation techniques rather than optimization provide better insight into the characteristics of the portfolio over time as market swings and liquidity constraints force divergence from the desired policy mix.</description><author>Terhaar, K.; Staub, R.; Singer, B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why we all held our breath when the market reopened - The distinction between risk and uncertainty.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Findlay, M. C.; Williams, E. E.; Thompson, J. R.
The distinction that Knight and Keynes made between risk and uncertainty has been all but eliminated from the mainstream finance literature over the past 35 years. Along with construction of the joint hypothesis of efficiency and equilibrium, this has resulted in a generally accepted theory of financial markets where risk is made benign ( i. e., a mildly perturbed certainty) in order to achieve analytical tractability, and where acceptance of the neoclassical model is a test of faith. In fact, the authors argue this theory is a massive edifice built on a pile of authors argue, this theory is a massive edifice built on a pile of assumptions, presumptions, and ignored evidence, whose practical results range from the LTCM collapse to the dot-com bubble to Enron.</description><author>Findlay, M. C.; Williams, E. E.; Thompson, J. R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extreme return reversal in the stock market - Strong support for insightful fundamental analysis.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirschey, M.
According to the efficient markets hypothesis, market returns are unpredictable and random around long-term market norms. In a perfectly efficient market, historical returns offer no useful insight into the formation of future return expectations. Behavioral finance theory suggests otherwise. Even if nobody can predict when the market will take a severe drop (such as down 20%), the overreaction hypothesis suggest that forward-looking returns will be above average after severe market drops. Market evidence presented here shows that severe downturns in the overall market are consistently followed by superior returns during the 12 months following. When investors overreact by giving extreme weight to recent negative returns, they run the risk of missing subsequent above-average rates of return. Going forward, the overreaction hypothesis predicts a reversal of the sharp losses following the collapse of the Internet stock bubble and the terrorist attacks on New York City and Washington.</description><author>Hirschey, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does smart money move markets? Institutional investors play a price-setting role.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gibson, S.; Safieddine, A.
The authors split equity investors into two groups, one of "smart money" institutional investors and the other of individual investors. Using quarterly data, they examine how aggregate ownership flows between the two groups are related to stock returns. Except in one case, increase in institutional ownership are associated with positive returns, and reductions in institutional ownership with negative returns, and the positive relationship between institutional ownership flows and returns is not explained by within-quarter momentum trading. These findings are consistent with the belief that institutional investors play a price-setting leadership role in the equity markets. The exception to the positive association between institutional ownership flows and returns is for small capitalization stocks; increases in institutional ownership of small capitalization stocks that were prior losers are associated with negative returns ( concentrated in the fourth quarter). This different return pattern for small-capitalization stocks is interpreted as consistent with institution buying stocks at price discounts from individuals who are systematically selling to establish tax-deductible capital losses.</description><author>Gibson, S.; Safieddine, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Harry Markowitz and the discretionary wealth hypothesis - A new focus and a relatively simple framework.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wilcox, J.
In his 1959 book, Portfolio Selection, Harry Markowitz showed how return mean and variance combine to determine the expected long-term growth rate of capital. But maximization of that growth rate seems to fit the risk preferences of only a narrow range of aggressive investors unconcerned about shortfalls. The growth rate goal may in fact be generalized to both conservative and aggressive investors by mapping the distribution of returns on total wealth to returns on discretionary wealth. The definition of risk may be broadened to include return skew and kurtosis when required, to fully encompass the concept of downside risk. The resulting change in frame of reference extends Markowitz's criterion to many practical investment decisions involving maximizing long-run wealth while controlling the probability of shortfalls along the way.</description><author>Wilcox, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rebalancing - Establishing a consistent framework.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Masters, S. J.
While the power of rebalancing to improve returns and reduce risk is generally acknowledged, there is relatively little work focused on the best way to implement a rebalancing policy. Most rebalancing policies use arbitrary "one size fits all" rules, and the more sophisticated approaches that have been proposed involve complex calculations. The author's simpler methodology allows investors to tailor their rebalancing policies to their risk tolerance, the cost of rebalancing, and the risk characteristics of each asset class in the portfolio. This approach addresses not only when to rebalance, but also how far back to rebalance. The result is a set of easily implemented rules for adhering to a rebalancing discipline.</description><author>Masters, S. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dimensions of active management - Why alpha and active risk are the only things that matter.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Waring, M. B.; Siegel, L. B.
When one eliminates all the market factors that active managers deliver (and that are available almost for free through index funds), what remains is the pure alpha. The cost of seeking this alpha is that one is forced to take on active risk. The authors draw on these observations to argue that building portfolios of active managers is an optimization problem that may be solved separately from the asset mix optimization problem (because pure active risk is uncorrelated with policy risk). They suggest that portfolios constructed using this approach emphasize index and risk-controlled active funds, while giving lighter allocations to traditional active funds and almost none to highly concentrated funds. For investors who are allowed to sell short, market-neutral long-short funds also have a place in the optimal solution.</description><author>Waring, M. B.; Siegel, L. B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The winner's game - Making your own plan is often quite rewarding.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellis, C. D.
While lots of attention gets paid to avoiding the loser's game of high turnover stock-picking and market timing, all too many investors - and a too many investment professionals - spend all too little time on the winner's game of developing and adhering to the long-term investment policies most likely to achieve the real and specific needs of each investor. Sound investment counseling, made widely available, could save most investors from unnecessary disappointment and could provide professional success and personal satisfaction to investment managers.</description><author>Ellis, C. D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash flows, asset values, and investment returns - Tying return forecasting to uses of cash.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Estep, P. W.
Most methods for forecasting expected returns of stocks are based on earnings. As analysts have justifiably become somewhat wary of earning reports, they are increasingly interested in developing valuation models that are based on sources and uses of cash. There should be some way analyze financial statements to make the two approaches give identical results, since the underlying economics are the same. The author provides a convenient formula that states the return expected by an investor in terms of the cash flow/price ratio, some fraction of the growth rate, and changes in valuation (i. e., PE expansion or contraction). The fraction of growth that ends up in the shareholder's pocket will depend on the size of the company's fixed asset accounts, and whether growth is financed by equity sale or debt issuance.</description><author>Estep, P. W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ethics, earnings, and equity valuation - A crisis of confidence.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arnott, R. D.
Business ethics has been much in the news since the bursting of the bubble in 2000 - but that ethics can have a direct bearing on corporate earnings and on valuation receives too little attention. Many observers draw comfort from the crackdown on fraudulent accounting, although dubious corporate accounting is but the tip of the iceberg. More benign ( or rather more legal) forms of aggressive accounting probably boost U. S corporate earnings by at least 20% even now. This means that valuation levels are higher than they seem by a like margin. A more subtle but pernicious impact of aggressive accounting affects the market indirectly if people don't trust the numbers, they may price assets to reflect both a risk premium, reflecting objective risks in the markets, and a credibility premium, reflecting lingering investor concerns about the merits of the data that form the basis for valuation.</description><author>Arnott, R. D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ignorance is not bliss</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fight the fed model - The relationship between future returns and stock and bond market yields.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asness, C.
The "Fed model" is a popular yardstick for judging whether the stock market is fairly valued. It compares the stock market's earnings yield to the long-term government bond yield, while more traditional methods evaluate stock market valuation without regard to the level of interest rates. The Fed model is theoretically flawed, as it compares a real number to a nominal number, ignoring the fact that over the long term nominal earnings generally move in tandem with inflation. The crucible for testing a valuation indicator is how well it forecasts long-term returns, and the Fed model fails this test-traditional methods ace it. Lack of predictive ability aside, investors have indeed historically required a higher stock market P/E when nominal interest rates have been lower. This does not imply that the Fed model is valid, rather only that investors have historically followed it, perhaps in error. The relationship of stock and bond market yields is more complicated than conceived by the Fed model, varying systematically with perceptions of long-term stock and bond market risk. Addition of risk to the Fed model solves the puzzle of why stocks outperformed bonds for the first half of the 20th century, but have underperformed bonds since.</description><author>Asness, C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset allocation in a lower stock-bond correlation environment - How lower correlation would impact investor decisions and welfare.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dopfel, F. E.
The correlation between stock and bond returns plays a critical role in asset allocation decisions and in the effectiveness of stock-bond diversification in reducing portfolio risk. During the last few years, the realized stock-bond correlation has trended lower than historical norms, and the current 36-month rolling estimate is significantly negative, while most analysts still assume a moderately positive equilibrium estimate for expected correlation. Many investors are now questioning their assumptions about correlation and whether lower correlation will continue. This decoupling of stock and bond returns combined with aggressive as set allocation strategies has contributed to deterioration in pension plan funded ratios, producing unfavorable impacts for investors with an economic liability. The various strategic and tactical asset allocation issues related to a continued low correlation environment have an impact on investor welfare in an asset-only and an asset-liability framework. For investors, low stock-bond correlation is beneficial in an asset-only context, but detrimental in the case of a bond-like liability, especially if there is significant underfunding of the liability.</description><author>Dopfel, F. E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A spectrum approach to active risk budgeting - Rethinking the barbell.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alford, A.; Jones, P.; Winkelmann, K.
Many institutional investors use a barbell strategy to invest their large-cap equity portfolios. This strategy mixes passive managers (who have no tracking error) with traditional concentrated active managers (who usually have high tracking errors) to moderate the total portfolio's active risk. The authors believe investors can achieve better results by including in the mix low-tracking error structured managers (also known as enhanced-index or benchmark-sensitive managers). They call this approach the spectrum strategy, because it allocates risk across the entire active risk spectrum. The historical analysis shows structured managers have generally achieved higher risk-m adjusted returns (i.e., information ratios) than traditional managers. Their relative performance advantage is due to, first, structured managers' focus on risk management (i.e., less noise in the information ratio's denominator), and second, their relative freedom from the no-short constraint (i.e., the no-short constraint is less binding when managers target small active deviations). Perhaps surprisingly, given the expected information ratio advantage, allocations to structured managers should come primarily from the plan's passive allocation rather than from traditional active managers.</description><author>Alford, A.; Jones, P.; Winkelmann, K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tactical asset allocation with pairwise strategies - Using pairwise information to influence weights.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qian, E.
An alternative approach to quantitative tactical asset allocation (TAA) is based on time series forecasting models and mean-variance optimization. The central concept is pairwise TAA, and the correct metric for assessing forecast quality is the pairwise information coefficient. TAA using mean-variance optimization is generally equivalent to a linear combination of pairwise TAA, with the relative weights of the pairs in the combination directly connected to the covariance matrix used in the optimization. TAA managers should avoid using a covariance matrix without knowing its implied pairwise weights, but instead should use pairwise information to influence the choice of the,pairwise weights. The expected long-term performance of TAA strategies for a given set of pair-wise weights as well as optimal sets of pairwise combinations that attain the maximum information ratio is-also derived.</description><author>Qian, E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio construction with qualitative forecasts - It doesn't need to be a black box.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Herold, U.
The vast majority of active portfolio managers use a fundamental investment approach. They do not generate quantitative forecasts but instead express their market views in a qualitative manner. The portfolio construction approach in practice is usually purely ad hoc: overweighting assets with a bullish outlook by some prespecified amount, and underweighting assets for which the view is bearish. A structured approach for portfolio construction leads to a more consistent implementation of market views and to more balanced portfolios in terms of risk profile. This approach incorporates several diagnostic tools and a Bayesian model. It also allows a portfolio manager to compute the shrinkage in the information ratio when implementing a suboptimal portfolio. This mitigates the need for transactions and hence reduces transaction costs.</description><author>Herold, U.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Practical risk analysis - For portfolio managers and traders.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Madhavan, A.; Yang, J.
Once a fairly esoteric subject, risk analysis and measurement has become a critical function for both portfolio managers and traders. Yet, accurate measurement and analysis of risk presents many practical challenges, including the choice of risk model, portfolio optimization pitfalls, horizon mismatches, and but-of-sample testing. This detailed overview I of recent developments in risk analysis and modeling focuses on practical applications. While risk management tools can provide invaluable insights as to portfolio risk, they must be applied with considerable care. Risk analysis, as it stands today, is as much an art as a science.</description><author>Madhavan, A.; Yang, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using statistical process control to monitor active managers - Rapidly identify troubled portfolios with confidence.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Philips, T. K.; Yashchin, E.; Stein, D. M.
Investors and chief investment officers who are invested in (or bear responsibility for) many products face a resource allocation problem. Which products deserve their attention and scrutiny? Ideally investors will focus on products that appear to be in trouble, but these are not easily identified using the classic methods of performance evaluation. In fact, it is often claimed that it takes 40 years to determine whether an active portfolio outperforms its benchmark. The authors demonstrate that a statistical process control scheme known as the CUSUM can be used to detect flat-to-the-benchmark performance in 40 months, and to detect underperformance faster still. By rapidly detecting underperformance, the CUSUM allows investors and CIOs to focus their attention on potential problems before they have a serious impact on the performance of the overall portfolio. The CUSUM procedure is provably optimal; for any given rate of false alarms, no other procedure can detect underperformance as quickly. It is robust to the distribution of excess returns, allowing its use in almost any asset class without modification.</description><author>Philips, T. K.; Yashchin, E.; Stein, D. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global aggregates - An enhancement to local and global bond benchmarks.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jochum, C.; Pagani, G.
With low government interest rates and increased correlation across sovereign markets in Europe and the United States, investors and money managers have been searching for new ways to increase the return of fixed-income portfolios. At the same time, bond markets outside the United States have seen significant growth in non-sovereign sectors like corporates and mortgages. In Europe this development is mainly a consequence of the introduction of a common currency. Global sovereign bond investors can now access credit sectors across markets to expand their investment universe. Single-currency investors, on the other hand, especially those domiciled in small and illiquid markets, profit from the wider global investment-grade markets through multimarket and multisector (global aggregate) portfolios, while hedging currency exposures. Money managers can thus add value to portfolios through a much wider investment opportunity set. Analysis of the advantages of global aggregate portfolios with respect to other types of fixed-income portfolios, especially on a currency-hedged basis, confirms the intuitive assessment that global aggregate portfolios offer a better risk-return trade-off than local or global sovereign portfolios. Money managers, while profiting from a wider opportunity set, have to balance this advantage against the increased complexity and number of strategy dimensions.</description><author>Jochum, C.; Pagani, G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign spreads and emerging market equity returns - Why variation in spreads is useful.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gendreau, B.; Heckman, L.
There is evidence that the information incorporated in sovereign spreads can be used to-improve country allocation strategies in emerging equity markets. Historically, sovereign spreads have been a value-oriented indicator of future equity performance a-cross countries. Wide spreads have tended to signal rising future equity returns, and vice versa. In the backtests reported, sovereign spreads are found to be useful in forecasting equity returns even taking into account measures of equity valuations, real interest rates, and country credit ratings. Divergence of spreads from recent trends also appears to convey information about future equity returns. Countries where spreads have been falling tend to outperform. This effect, however, is not as strong as the tendency of countries with wide spreads to perform well in the future.</description><author>Gendreau, B.; Heckman, L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer confidence and stock returns - What sentiment tells us.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fisher, K. L.; Statman, M.
Consumer confidence predicts economic activity, but does it also predict stock returns? Do stock returns affect consumer confidence? And what is the relationship between consumer confidence and investor sentiment? Answers to these questions are gained through examination of the consumer confidence measures of the University of Michigan and the Conference Board. Consumer confidence rises with high stock returns, but high consumer confidence. is followed by low stock returns. Sentiments of individual investors about the stock market improve with consumer confidence about the economy, as if individuals Were unaware that stock prices are a leading indicator of the economy. No relationship is found between changes in the sentiments of institutional investors and consumer confidence, however.</description><author>Fisher, K. L.; Statman, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real estate matters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why real estate? An expanding role for institutional investors.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hudson-Wilson, S.; Fabozzi, F. J.; Gordon, J. N.
In the beginning real estate was regarded as a diversifier, bolstered by the Employee Retirement Security Act of 1974. However, given real estate's nature as a debt-equity hybrid and the emergence of new ways to invest in real estate markets, it is clear that there could be additional motivations for choosing to include real estate in a mixed asset portfolio. This article explores 5 possible uses for real estate: to reduce overall portfolio risk, to achieve high absolute returns, to hedge unexpected inflation or deflation, to reflect the overall investment universe and/or to deliver strong cash flows to the investor. But first we must re-define real estate to encompass the new public debt and equity markets that have joined the traditional private debt and equity markets for real estate. A new index of overall real estate performance is presented. The article concludes by considering the types of investors who might see a role for real estate; several classes of investor would likely benefit from the inclusion of real estate in their investment portfolio.</description><author>Hudson-Wilson, S.; Fabozzi, F. J.; Gordon, J. N.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Benefits of real estate investment - Some diversification benefit in particular allocations.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Georgiev, G.; Gupta, B.; Kunkel, T.
Real estate investment represents a significant part of many institutional portfolios. Since real estate is not directly traded on a centralized exchange, the physical real estate market is characterized by relative lack of liquidity, large lot size, and high transactions costs with properties that are fixed at a location and heterogeneous. The low transparency of the real estate marketplace also results in potential asymmetric information. This provides a source of relatively high risk-adjusted returns to those individuals who can obtain costless "quality" information. Furthermore, the lack of frequent transaction data for the analysis of return distributions often necessitates the use of appraisal-based series. In this article, the authors examine the benefits of real estate investments as part of an investor's overall asset portfolio.</description><author>Georgiev, G.; Gupta, B.; Kunkel, T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firming property prices and weak cash flows - Rational and not a disconnect.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corcoran, P. J.; Iwai, Y.
Firming property prices in recession and early recovery are consistent with investors expecting income weakness to be temporary. The authors argue that these expectations are supported by anticipated restraint in new construction, restraint that has been in place since the mid-1990s and contrasts sharply with overbuilding that characterized the 1980s. Firm property prices and weak cash flows in the economic downturn since 2001 have resulted in falling cap rates (gross property yields) according to the authors. This pattern represents a profound shift from undisciplined markets of 1980-1995, when cap rates generally declined in expansion (1983-1990) and rose sharply (1990-1995) in retrenching real estate markets.</description><author>Corcoran, P. J.; Iwai, Y.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real estate market fundamentals and asset pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sivitanides, P. S.; Torto, R. G.; Wheaton, W. C.
This article addresses empirically recent concerns about a dichotomy between capital markets and real estate market fundamentals. Motivated by recent decreases in capitalization (cap) rates in light of weak market fundamentals some analysts have argued that the latter no longer matter in real estate asset pricing. Some other analysts argue that these phenomena reflect a structural shift in the way investors' factor market fundamentals in their pricing decisions. Building on the findings of past empirical research, the authors emphasize that the true effect of market fundamentals can be analyzed and understood only after controlling for the effect of interest rates, which recently reached record-low levels. Empirical analysis of cap rate levels and spreads provides evidence of the strong effect of interest rates on cap rate levels, and systematic effects of market fundamentals on both cap rate levels and spreads that reveal a myopic (inefficient) view on the part of real estate investors. No statistically decent evidence is found to point to a weakening of the effect of market fundamentals or a shift towards a forward-looking (efficient) view of such fundamentals in the last two years.</description><author>Sivitanides, P. S.; Torto, R. G.; Wheaton, W. C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should one use leverage in a private equity real estate portfolio? Only carefully and accountably.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anson, M.; Hudson-Wilson, S.
Whenever interest rates fall and positive leverage conditions hold, the subject of the use of leverage in a portfolio of real estate inevitably comes up. When the cost of debt falls below the income yield on an asset or portfolio of assets, there is positive leverage and it can be used to raise the return on the asset(s). While using leverage seems trivial (how can positive leverage be a "bad" thing?), it is, in fact, quite complex and raises some philosophical and operational issues for the investor. In this article the authors discuss the many aspects of the leverage decision and offer a recommendation. Throughout the discussion they assume that leverage can be applied, creating a Positive spread, at least initially. They do not discuss the use of very aggressive leverage as an opportunistic strategy; leverage is considered only in the context of a base real estate portfolio strategy.</description><author>Anson, M.; Hudson-Wilson, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>VaR: A tool to measure leverage risk - More accurate than the Sharpe ratio.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gordon, J. N.; Tse, E. W. K.
When considering how much leverage to use with a real estate portfolio, a good risk measure is needed to evaluate the risk-reward trade-off. The Sharpe ratio, which is not very sensitive to changes in leverage, masks the very different risk/return combinations created by various levels of debt. The authors argue that Value at Risk (VaR) is a far better and more intuitive risk measure to use when making leverage decisions. VaR shows portfolio managers a concrete amount they stand to lose over a specified time horizon and within a pre-determined confidence interval. As such, it can be used.-to set an upper limit on the amount of risk that a portfolio manager is willing to take on when applying leverage. The authors explain that the VaR technique is particularly well suited to institutional real estate portfolios because it captures the full extent of risk for investors less willing to exercise the borrower's put-option and it incorporates information about correlations across property types and regional economies.</description><author>Gordon, J. N.; Tse, E. W. K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global real estate risk index - To capture different levels of market risk.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, J.; Hobbs, P.
Despite ongoing political, economic, and financial uncertainties, the long-term trend of financial market "globalization" continues. This trend has been driven by equity and bond investments, but cross-border real estate investment has increased in recent years. Recent disaffection with stock performance means real estate is at the forefront of many investors' thinking and, increasingly, they are considering real estate as a global asset class. This article seeks to help measure and explain the relative risks of global real estate markets by providing a simple, objective measure of real estate risk based on three components: country, structural real estate, and cyclical real estate risks. Together these measures capture the key dimensions of risk and provide important insights for global real estate strategies. An investor's tolerance for various types of risk varies according to investment strategy. The authors conclude by showing how different combinations of types of risk provide different insights according to the perspective of the investor, whether they are "opportunistic," "core," or "debt focused."</description><author>Chen, J.; Hobbs, P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of structuring on CMBS class performance - Complex interactions between collateral and structure.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacob, D. P.; Fabozzi, F. J.
The structure of a commercial mortgage-backed security-the combination of the characteristics of the underlying loans and the design of the cash flow algorithm that creates the bond classes-can affect the performance of the various bond classes. In a simple pass-through, the affects on the resulting bonds are fairly straightforward. Any resulting complications are a function of the lack of homogeneity of the characteristics of the underlying loans. More typical senior/subordinated multi-class structures with several interest-only bond classes often lead to some less-than-intuitive performance results for the bonds, especially when combined with heterogeneous collateral. In this article, the authors explain the impact of structuring on the bond classes of a CMBS structure. They explain why while there are some similarities between the structuring of commercial and residential mortgage pools, the differences in the features of the underlying loans lead to different considerations in creating commercial versus residential mortgage-backed securities.</description><author>Jacob, D. P.; Fabozzi, F. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CMBS credit migrations - By deal type, vintage, initial rating, and combination of ratings.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adelson, M. H.; Hoyt, E. C.
This article presents empirical evidence of credit migrations of commercial mortgage-backed securities (CMBS). The findings support anecdotal accounts that adverse credit migrations; have been highly concentrated in CMBS from single-borrower lease-backed deals from 1993 and 1994. Favorable credit migrations, in contrast, are much more evenly distributed across the CMBS universe. CMBS rated by multiple rating agencies are less likely to suffer adverse credit migrations. In contrast to earlier findings in the area of asset-backed securities, the author finds that the presence of Fitch ratings on CMBS is correlated with generally stronger- rather than weaker-credit performance.</description><author>Adelson, M. H.; Hoyt, E. C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public versus private real estate equities - A risk-return comparison.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pagliari, J. L.; Scherer, K. A.; Monopoli, R. T.
Comparisons of the performance of public and private real estate equities are provided in this article. In so doing, the authors control for three of the main differences between these investment alternatives: property-type mix, leverage and appraisal smoothing. They then ran tests to determine in a statistical sense whether the restated means and volatilities of the two series were in fact different from one another. The clear answer is that they were not, suggesting a fairly seamless real estate market in which public- and private-market vehicles display a long-run synchronicity. This has two important implications for portfolio management. First, public- and private-market vehicles ought to be viewed as (somewhat interchangeably) offering investors a risk/return continuum of real estate investment opportunities. Second, while the "platform" did not matter in terms of observed return characteristics, the platform may matter with regard to liquidity, governance, transparency, control, executive compensation, and so on, an apparent clientele effect hints that these issues may be valued differently by large and small investors.</description><author>Pagliari, J. L.; Scherer, K. A.; Monopoli, R. T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment policy for securitized and direct real estate - Correcting for liquidity.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feldman, B. E.
In this article the author examines the constant and variable liquidity direct real estate price indexes developed by Fisher, Gatzlaff, Geltner, and Haurin and uses them in asset allocation exercises. Review of these indexes suggests they provide improved measures of direct real estate performance that do much to remedy problems resulting from the appraisal-induced smoothing of the NCREIF property index. Optimization results based on the period from 1987 to 2001 indicate that significant overweighting of both direct and securitized real estate was appropriate and that direct and securitized real estate were complementary investments. These results and related considerations suggest that real estate should receive at least a neutral weighting in contemporary institutional portfolios.</description><author>Feldman, B. E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing real estate volatility - Estimates from adjusted private and public market evidence.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giliberto, M.
Several approaches to assessing the volatility of private market or direct real estate as an asset class are illustrated in this article. These approaches yield reasonably consistent estimates, falling in a range of 6.5%-9.0% annualized standard deviation of total return for a diversified portfolio of unleveraged, core properties. The estimates take into account the lack of statistical independence from quarter to quarter that is characteristic of private market real estate returns. The estimates provide useful guidance for quantifying the risk of direct real estate for purposes of evaluating real estate's potential role in a multi-asset class portfolio. In addition, the empirical estimates have intuitive appeal: they lie between investment-grade bonds and large-cap stocks.</description><author>Giliberto, M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Property, common stock, and property shares - Increased potential for diversification.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brounen, D.; Eichholtz, P.
In this article the authors examine the relationship between private property, the securitized property share market, and the common stock market in the United States and the United Kingdom during the period 1986 to 2002. They find that the correlations between property share returns and common stock returns are show a similar decreasing trend for both countries, indicating increased mixed-asset diversification potential for property shares. After applying standard unsmoothing and hedging techniques, in order to abstract from the underlying market structures, the authors discover increased similarities between the securitized and unsecuritized property performances in both countries. Combining the performance characteristics of both property investment vehicles results in new insights regarding the position of real estate in mixed-asset portfolios.</description><author>Brounen, D.; Eichholtz, P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IRR-Based property-level performance attribution - Helping to evaluate management skill.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Geltner, D.
In this article, the author reviews the concept and practice of property level investment performance attribution. A new approach for performance attribution based on the property level since-acquisition internal rate of return (IRR) is presented, including numerical examples and usage recommendations. A methodology is presented for parsing the IRR into three components: Initial Yield, Cash Flow Change, and Yield Change; and for bench-marking performance in these attributes against NCREIF properties. The relationship is discussed between the three IRR attributes and the four fundamental property level investment management functions of. Property Selection, Acquisition Transaction Execution, Operational Management, and Disposition Transaction Execution. Resulting information and insights should be useful for entities managing large portfolios of real properties, including pension fund advisors and REITs.</description><author>Geltner, D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected returns on stocks and bonds - Investors must moderate their expectations.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ilmanen, A.
There is an ongoing shift in opinion about expected asset returns. Ex antE equity returns are less transparent and thus more open to question than ex ante bond returns. Long-term equity returns have traditionally been predicted from historical average market returns, but today they are increasingly predicted using dividend discount models. Realized average returns are misleading guides for the future when expected returns vary over time, and our recent bear market has made investors more aware of forward-looking expected return measures; the starting price matters. Neither of two types of "expected returns"-objectively feasible long-run returns and subjective (often hoped-for, extrapolative) return expectations-can be directly observed, but we can try to estimate them by analyzing historical returns, investor surveys, and market valuation indicators. Objectively feasible equity returns have been low for several years (5%-8%), but subjective return expectations have begun to moderate only recently. The divergence between objective and hoped-for returns was extraordinarily wide around 2000; while the gap has narrowed since, it may not have fully closed.</description><author>Ilmanen, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the stock/bond risk premium - An alternative approach.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hunt, L. H.; Hoisington, D. M.
New light shed on the risk premium of stocks over long U.S. Treasury bonds indicates that most research has overstated the advantages of stocks over bonds. Over long periods, bonds have actually outperformed equities. Certain conditions are found to have likely produced these results.</description><author>Hunt, L. H.; Hoisington, D. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Advantages of multiperiod portfolio models - Performance enhancements.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mulvey, J. M.; Pauling, W. R.; Madey, R. E.
A multiperiod portfolio model provides significant advantages over traditional single-period approaches-especially for long-term investors. Such a framework can enhance risk-adjusted performance and help investors evaluate the probability of reaching financial goals by linking asset and liability policies. Multiperiod portfolio models consist of three basic components: a stochastic scenario generator; a policy rule simulator; and an optimization module that identifies non-dominated solutions. Useful applications are in pension planning, insurance risk management, hedge funds, and asset allocation for individual investors.</description><author>Mulvey, J. M.; Pauling, W. R.; Madey, R. E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategy benchmarks - From the investment manager's perspective.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuenzi, D. E.
As the investment management industry becomes more sophisticated, investment managers have come to use benchmark indexes in an increasingly complex fashion: as a baseline along which the manager intends to add value and manage risk; for determining which factor bets have most influenced overall portfolio returns (attribution analysis); and for determining the extent to which the manager adds value (through use of the information ratio, for instance). Managers typically use readily available published indexes for these purposes, although these indexes often do not accurately reflect the manager's true investment universe, and thus give rise to distortions and consequently poor information. "Strategy benchmarks" are often beneficial alternatives from the perspectives of client, consultant, and investment manager.</description><author>Kuenzi, D. E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market timing strategies that worked - Based on the E/P ratio of the S&amp;P 500 and interest rates.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shen, P.
There is evidence that a few simple market timing strategies appear to have outperformed a buy-and-hold strategy in the 1970-2000 period. The example here is based on spreads between the E/P ratio of the S&amp;P 500 index and interest rates. Extremely narrow spreads compared to historical ranges appear to predict more frequent market downturns to come. A switching strategy based on extremely narrow spreads and the market index calls for investing in the stock market index unless spreads are narrower than some predefined threshold. Switching strategies like this outperformed the market index in terms of higher mean returns and lower variances. A strategy based on the spread between the E/P ratio and a short-term interest rate comfortably beat the market index in this period, even considering transaction costs.</description><author>Shen, P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overconfidence bias in international stock prices - Consistent across countries and trading environments.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Scott, J.; Stumpp, M.; Xu, P.
This study expands tests of the overconfidence hypothesis to international markets, where the evidence is consistent with the hypothesis that stock prices the world around are also biased by investor overconfidence. A novel aspect of the test here is combination of the overconfidence hypothesis with valuation theory. When stocks are categorized according to how quickly they are expected to grow, there is an interaction effect between earnings growth and the payoffs to contrarian and momentum strategies. Data from France, Germany, Japan, the U.K., and the U.S. show that successful investment strategies differ, depending on a stock's growth rate. A momentum strategy of buying stocks with positive earning estimate revisions and selling stocks with negative estimate revisions is significantly more profitable in fast-growth companies, for instance, while a contrarian strategy of buying low P/E stocks and selling high P/E stocks produces greater and more consistent profits in slow-growth companies. The results suggest that traditional value-oriented managers should focus on slow-growth companies, while successful growth managers should ride winners and be willing to sell when confronted with bad news.</description><author>Scott, J.; Stumpp, M.; Xu, P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Improving the efficient frontier - By pooling investment capital.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kwan, C. C. Y.
Familiar portfolio concepts can explain why pooling of investor capital enables investors to achieve higher expected returns without additional risk exposure. The risk of the pooled investment must be a particular weighted average of the participating investors' preferred risks. Unveiling of the source of expected return improvements provides a clearer picture of what pooling can achieve. A variety of formulas to allocate the realized return from pooling among participating investors should help portfolio managers design effective allocation methods.</description><author>Kwan, C. C. Y.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling credit risk - Currency dependence in global credit markets.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kercheval, A.; Goldberg, L.; Breger, L.
Spreads for credit instruments denominated in euros, sterling, and U.S. dollars over their local swap curves are examined here. The findings indicate that monthly spread changes were strongly currency-dependent during the period May 1999-May 2001. Sector-by-rating factor returns are at best weakly correlated across currencies, and U.S. dollar spread return are generally more volatile than the other two by a factor of two or three This is contrary to what would be expected from covered interest arbitrage. The conclusion is that analysts should estimate credit factor rise models separately in each market, as risk forecasting models using a single set of spread factors for different markets will not be accurate.</description><author>Kercheval, A.; Goldberg, L.; Breger, L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge funds with style - Style analysis and management are crucial to success.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, S. J.; Goetzmann, W. N.
The popular perception is that hedge funds follow a reasonably well-defined market-neutral investment style. Investigation of the monthly return history of hedge funds over 1989-2000, however, finds there are it fact distinct styles of management that account for about 20% of the cross-sectional variability in performance. This result is consistent across the years in the sample and robust as to the way investment style is determined. Appropriate style analysis and style management are crucial to success for investors looking to invest in hedge funds.</description><author>Brown, S. J.; Goetzmann, W. N.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge fund index investing examined - Not a wise choice for several reasons.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liew, J.
Hedge fund indexing, a seemingly attractive way to get general exposure to the hedge fund industry, may instead subject investors to many unskilled managers. After adjustment for market exposure and non-synchronous pricing/liquidity issues, the evidence is that the majority of hedge fund managers examined do not have statistically significant skill. Nor do indexes provide adequate diversification benefits in times of market dislocation. Simulations indicate that an actively managed fund of funds with good discernment can beat a passive hedge fund investment. Investors should thus be wary of taking a passive approach to investing in hedge funds. Passive index funds are not a good alternative to an active search for skilled hedge fund managers.</description><author>Liew, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are gain and loss respectable? Yes.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O'Connor, P.; Rozeff, M. S.
nan</description><author>O'Connor, P.; Rozeff, M. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting the little planned society</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tactical asset allocation and commodity futures - Ways to improve performance.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jensen, G. R.; Johnson, R. R.; Mercer, J. M.
nan</description><author>Jensen, G. R.; Johnson, R. R.; Mercer, J. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge funds and hope - Hedge funds deserve allocations.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lochoff, R.
nan</description><author>Lochoff, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informationless investing and hedge fund performance measurement bias - Dangerous attractions.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weisman, A. B.
nan</description><author>Weisman, A. B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Country, industry, and risk factor loadings in portfolio management - Country effects declining in importance; industry effects growing.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>L'Her, J. F.; Sy, O.; Tnani, M. Y.
nan</description><author>L'Her, J. F.; Sy, O.; Tnani, M. Y.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The price-earnings ratio - An important but imperfect tool.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bierman, H.
nan</description><author>Bierman, H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Confirming or conflicting sales and earnings signals - Differential results for growth and value companies.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ertimur, Y.; Livnat, J.
nan</description><author>Ertimur, Y.; Livnat, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The source of value - It's entirely the result of excess free cash flow.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Philips, T. K.
nan</description><author>Philips, T. K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Will valuation ratios revert to historical means? Some evidence from break point tests.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlson, J. B.; Pelz, E. A.; Wohar, M. E.
nan</description><author>Carlson, J. B.; Pelz, E. A.; Wohar, M. E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Symptoms and Signs - And a challenge and an opportunity.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellis, C. D.
nan</description><author>Ellis, C. D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rethinking pension liabilities and asset allocation - A pension crisis looms.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ryan, R. J.; Fabozzi, F. J.
nan</description><author>Ryan, R. J.; Fabozzi, F. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>In defense of the history of ideas</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The small-cap alpha myth - No evidence that active small-cap managers add value consistently.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ennis, R. M.; Sebastian, M. D.
Investment lore has it that there is more opportunity to earn abnormal profits from small-capitalization stocks than large-capitalization stocks-that the small-cap market is less efficient. The authors find no evidence that active small-cap managers add value consistently. They demonstrate three common performance evaluation errors that contribute to what they call the small-cap myth. They also discuss securities analysts' neglect of small stocks as well as the higher cost of researching and trading them. Whatever the differential in market inefficiency between large and small might be, the authors conclude it is not sufficient to justify the average manager's higher cost of researching and trading smaller stocks.</description><author>Ennis, R. M.; Sebastian, M. D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multistyle rotation strategies - The benefits are considerable.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahmed, P.; Lockwood, L. J.; Nanda, S.
Terminal wealth improves dramatically by shifting from single-factor to multifactor models of portfolio formation. The authors provide simulated results to demonstrate the variability in terminal wealth for each style portfolio. They find that terminal wealth increases more than 50% by rotating across multiple-versus single-investment style portfolios. Their results provide downside risk assessment that is unencumbered by distributional assumptions and time diversification problems, and that lends itself well to value at risk analysis.</description><author>Ahmed, P.; Lockwood, L. J.; Nanda, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An index fund fundamentalist - Goes back to the drawing board.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bogle, J. C.
This article revisits the author's 1998 study, which showed the superiority of low-cost equity funds over their high-cost alternatives for the five years ending 1996. Updating through 2001, the author again demonstrates that low-cost funds outperform high-cost funds on both an absolute and a risk-adjusted basis, and by an even greater margin than the cost differential would suggest. This pattern persists for equity mutual funds as a group, and in each of the nine Morningstar style boxes. Following this logic, as typically the lowest-cost alternatives in their category, index Funds would be expected to rank among the top-performing funds in a category. As in his 1998 article, the author finds this is true index funds outperform their actively managed counterparts in eight of the nine style boxes.</description><author>Bogle, J. C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Controlling institutional trading costs - We have met the enemy, and it is us.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwartz, R. A.; Steil, B.
Analysis of institutional trading costs typically assumes that profit-maximizing fund managers seek to minimize trading costs. The authors suggest that the bundling of non-trading services into institutional trading commissions is far too pervasive for this assumption to hold generally. Bundling reflects an endemic principal-agent problem in the operation of collective investment schemes that acts to discourage efficient implementation of portfolio decisions taken on behalf of fundholders. Bundling results in excessive trade intermediation, generating higher market impact costs and discouraging the use of more efficient trading platforms (particularly for NYSE stocks). Furthermore, the authors argue that the widespread use of inefficient internal trading cost benchmarks, such as VWAP, makes it hard for institutions to detect the damage to fund performance that result, from bundling.</description><author>Schwartz, R. A.; Steil, B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effect of underpricing and lock-up provisions in IPOs - Implications of a classic case of supply and demand.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garfinkle, N.; Malkiel, B. G.; Bontas, C.
This article examines two issues regarding initial equity public offerings (IPOs) of 775 firms that came to market between July 1, 1997, and December 31, 1999. First, a study of the underpricing of new issues indicates that first-day excess returns are greater for venture-backed IPOs, high-tech firms, and firms underwritten by top-rung investment bankers, and in months following high previous-month Nasdaq returns. Second, the authors look at the longer-run performance of IPOs and the effect of the so-called lock-up provision, which restricts initial founders and owners of the IPO from selling their shares for a period of time. They find a statistically significant increase in trading volume on the day following the unlock date. Prices begin to fall, however, prior to the end of the lock-up period as the market anticipates the selling that is likely to follow. There is a substantial negative excess return for shareholders who buy new issues in the open market immediately after the IPO.</description><author>Garfinkle, N.; Malkiel, B. G.; Bontas, C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decoupling - If the US. Treasury repays its debt, what then?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gulko, L.
The returns of U.S. stocks and Treasury bonds are usually positively correlated, or coupled, As the stock market plunges, Treasury bonds tend to rally, and the daily returns become negatively correlated, or decoupled. In this article, the author examines the decoupling that accompanies stock market crashes. He begins by presenting empirical evidence of the stock-bond decoupling and next examines sonic implications. The main practical implication is that U.S. Treasury bonds offer effective diversification during financial crises, at the time it is needed most. The main theoretical implication is that normal probability distributions (both conditional and unconditional) generally misspecify the joint returns of U.S. stocks and Treasury bonds.</description><author>Gulko, L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing credit risk in a corporate bond portfolio - Selecting a portfolio with better return-risk characteristics.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ramaswamy, S.
The author proposes a portfolio selection method to manage market risk and credit risk in a corporate bond portfolio relative to its benchmark. He formulates an optimization problem that minimizes the variance of the loss distribution arising from credit risk with the constraints that the expected return of the portfolio not be below the benchmark and the market risk be identical to the benchmark. Such a problem formulation produces a portfolio that exhibits improved risk-adjusted return characteristics ex ante compared to the benchmark. A practical example illustrates the method.</description><author>Ramaswamy, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value at risk for portfolios with short positions - Do not assume lognormal distributions.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chow, G.; Kritzman, M.
Value at risk is perhaps the most common measure of a portfolio's exposure to loss. The simplest way to estimate value at risk is to calculate it directly from the portfolio's expected return and standard deviation under the assumption that the portfolio's returns are lognormally distributed. If the component returns of the portfolio are themselves lognormally distributed, however, it is incorrect to assume that the portfolio's returns are also lognormal. For portfolios that include only long positions, this technically false assumption is a reasonably good approximation of the portfolios' theoretical return distribution. For portfolios that include short positions, though, the authors explain why the assumption of lognormality for the total portfolio can be seriously misleading. In many typical cases, value at risk is substantially greater than indicated by a lognormal distribution.</description><author>Chow, G.; Kritzman, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Alternative small-cap stock benchmarks - Recent performance and changes in characteristics.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reilly, F. K.; Wright, D. J.
With continuing interest in the small-cap stock anomaly and in the size-related style of investing, several financial services firms have created size-related stock indexes intended to measure the risk-return results for these stocks. The authors compare the alternative benchmarks, and provide updated risk-return results fur the small-cap sector. They note some differences among the small-cap stock benchmarks, but mainly show there are strong similarities among them. The updated risk-adjusted performance results indicate that small-cap stocks lag other asset classes, and there are major differences ill interest rate sensitivity. Finally, there have been significant changes ill the correlations and risk measures over time notable are weaker trends in the correlations with large-cap stocks and in the systematic risk (beta) of the small-cap stocks.</description><author>Reilly, F. K.; Wright, D. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>S&amp;P 500 index replacements - A new game in town.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beneish, M. D.; Whaley, R. E.
Standard &amp; Poor's has become increasingly aggressive in deleting stocks from the S&amp;P 500 index. Where once it made replacements in the index only when a particular stock had to be removed due to merger or acquisition, corporate restructuring, and bankruptcy filing, S&amp;P now voluntarily removes a company for a variety of reasons, which may include low market capitalization, low share price, dwindling market share, or simply the need to find a spot for an up-and-comer. There are a variety of impacts on share price and trading volume for stocks added to and deleted from the S&amp;P 500 during the period January 1996 through December 2001. For additions, abnormal returns and trading volumes are higher than ever. For deletions, share prices are dealt a crippling blow.</description><author>Beneish, M. D.; Whaley, R. E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder value for whom? For what?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commercial real estate loan default frequency - A new perspective on modeling.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pappadopoulos, G. J.; Chen, J.
Capital allocation decisions become an even tougher issue without a consistent measure of credit risk across the entire portfolio. Although available risk management systems are helpful for a number of asset classes, none provides an adequate solution for real estate credit risk. With few appropriate inputs, and a notable lack of data on commercial mortgage default experience, an alternative approach to assessing real estate loan expected default frequency is needed. The authors discuss the calibration of a systematic risk metric to actual historical defaults. A comparison of the disaggregated results to those of past studies of defaults indicates that the metric appears to be a robust and useful tool for exposing opportunities and improving capital allocation decisions.</description><author>Pappadopoulos, G. J.; Chen, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sufficient diversification in credit portfolios - Number of issues and downgrade risk.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dynkin, L.; Hyman, J.; Konstantinovsky, V.
How much diversification is required in an investment-grade credit portfolio to achieve a desired level of risk relative to a broad credit benchmark? Two approaches to optimal portfolio structuring address this fundamental question from different viewpoints. The first seeks to minimize the risk of underperforming a benchmark because of idiosyncratic credit events; the second explores the diversification levels that maximize the information ratio (risk-adjusted outperformance of the benchmark). This study focuses on the impact of rating downgrades on security returns relative to peer groups. Data on the Lehman Brothers Credit Index as well as transition probabilities published by the rating agencies underlie a methodology for estimating portfolio downgrade risk and the optimal diversification levels. Simple models of the value of credit research help the reader analyze the trade-off between increased diversification and diminished performance.</description><author>Dynkin, L.; Hyman, J.; Konstantinovsky, V.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tax savings with mutual fund distributions - A quirk in the tax code.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Singal, V.
Under the current tax code, investors receiving mutual fund distributions are subject to capital gains taxes based on the mutual fund's, not the investor's, holding period. Investors can use this wrinkle in the tax code to their benefit by converting short-term capital gains into long-term capital gains. An investor buys into a mutual fund with long-term capital gains just before its distribution date, and sells it immediately after the distribution. This process captures for the investor the long-term capital gains distributed, but also produces a short-term capital loss as the mutual fund price falls by the amount of the distribution. The short-term capital loss can be offset against other short-term capital gains of the investor. The investor can save on taxes because the capital gains are now long-term, not short-term. Current mutual fund shareholders are not hurt by the actions of these transitory investors, because the distributions are now divided into a greater number of shares, making the per share distribution smaller, and thereby reducing the tax liability of existing shareholders.</description><author>Singal, V.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investing for Growth in 1975 - Philosophy, criteria, and lessons.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barker, R. R.
The one absolute truth in investing is that long-range success comes only from rigorous pursuit of disciplines designed to neutralize emotional pressures. These disciplines differ because investors have different strengths and weaknesses, but all depend upon self-discipline, defining objectives, understanding the reasons underpinning the chosen strategy, recognizing the inevitable problems, and developing the strength to stay the course-and being sensitive to fundamental changes that could make the investor's chosen strategy obsolete. Endowments, despite the many compelling reasons for investing for maximum long-term return, at one time typically put too much emphasis on avoiding losses and on maximizing current returns, yielding results that would be recognized as unacceptable if performance had been accurately measured. The author of this opinion piece, written in the 1970s, led an investment office to acknowledged leadership among growth investors during the second half of the 20th century. His 1972 report on endowment investments for The Ford Foundation had a great impact on changes in endowment investment management.</description><author>Barker, R. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Scope and dynamics of the securities lending industry - New information on market size and behavior.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rich, D.; Moore, J. A.
Prime brokers understand the importance of the securities lending industry in providing liquidity to markets, but most other participants view it simply as a source of incremental income for long-term investors. In fact, securities lending is a fundamental component of the short-selling market, and the income from lending is not trivial. This description of the very important securities lending industry provides the first in-depth exploration of the behavior of daily lending transactions in 24 countries for a two-year period in 2000-2002. The analysis includes cash and non-cash loans of equity securities and non-equity securities, such as corporate debt, government/sovereign debt, and agency debt.</description><author>Rich, D.; Moore, J. A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating stock returns - Should investors expect less in the future?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, C. P.; Wilson, J. W.; Lundstrum, L. L.
How do we quantify the level of return that an investor can expect in the future? An examination of the historical distribution of total returns reveals declines in dividend yields and new likely lower boundaries for price appreciation. It is often asserted that low dividend yields brought about by higher earnings retention should be followed by greater price appreciation as a firm invests retained earnings into new projects. The available recent evidence refutes this assertion. Barring some significant reversal of current conditions, short-term and possibly intermediate-term returns from stocks will be lower than what many investors may be anticipating.</description><author>Jones, C. P.; Wilson, J. W.; Lundstrum, L. L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accounting for uncertainty - When the only thing certain is the date.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Savage, S.; Van Allen, M.
The recent crisis of confidence in the accounting industry has raised issues about the need for reform. In one area the timing and technology are right today for significantly different accounting rules-particularly rules that govern the treatment of uncertainty in financial statements. Discussed here are some basic misconceptions about uncertainty that are actually sanctioned by current accounting practice. A variety of analytical tools are available to improve representation of uncertainty for firms. The authors address some of the legal consequences of relying on accepted but flawed accounting standards, and point to a possible path to reform of accounting practice.</description><author>Savage, S.; Van Allen, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk allocation versus asset allocation - Improving the optimal allocation between risk and return.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clarke, R. G.; de Silva, H.; Wander, B.
Most investors are exposed to both systematic and active risks in their portfolios. Systematic risks stem from consistent exposure to marketwide factors, and are usually associated with marketwide risk premiums. Active risk comes from actively managing underlying security and/or systematic risk exposures. Traditional long-only investment strategies are usually dominated by systematic risk, while alternative investment strategies typically have more active risk than systematic risk. A risk allocation framework that explicitly differentiates between these two sources of risk enables investors to improve the risk/return profile of their portfolios. Such a framework also enables investors to better incorporate non-traditional or alternative investment strategies into portfolios by characterizing them in terms of their systematic and active risk rather than thinking of them as a separate asset class.</description><author>Clarke, R. G.; de Silva, H.; Wander, B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are emerging market equities a separate asset class? Hard to argue that today</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saunders, A.; Walter, I.
Historically, fund managers and investors making portfolio allocation decisions have considered emerging market equities a separate asset class. More recently, a number of economic, legal, accounting, and financial developments have eroded the root differences between emerging and developed country financial markets. These liberalizations include capital market reforms that have reduced the constraints and limits on foreign portfolio investment. The authors find that empirical evidence strongly supports the view that the world's financial markets are becoming increasingly integrated, and that the integration process encompasses emerging markets. As a result, the idea of a rigid separation between emerging market and developed market pools of investible funds (and adoption of separate performance benchmarks) seems no longer appropriate. Indeed, recent moves by international investors to benchmark their portfolios to MSCI's all-country world index and related world indexes, which include both emerging market and developed market securities, seem a step in this direction.</description><author>Saunders, A.; Walter, I.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Visibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Implementing optimal risk budgeting - Managing uncertainty of alpha (vol 28, pg 73, 2001)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, W.; Lam, D. Y.
nan</description><author>Lee, W.; Lam, D. Y.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rebalancing a global policy benchmark - How to profit from necessity.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Plaxco, L. M.; Arnott, R. D.
The need to rebalance institutional assets to a policy benchmark is a simple fact of life. While it may be possible for investors to allow portfolios to drift over a period of time, they will eventually have to address the misallocation this causes, as the mix becomes increasingly concentrated, overexposed to the riskier asset classes and underexposed to the more conservative asset classes. Some investors may rebalance the asset mix by systematically directing new money into the underweight asset classes or by choosing the overweight asset classes as a source for withdrawals. Others may choose to rebalance on a quarterly basis, before they are called upon to report to their investment committee. However loosely the constraints on active moves away from policy benchmark are defined, the authors argue that the fact remains that a fund's assets and liabilities must appropriately balance; drifting too far from the policy benchmark can prove disastrous when markets fail to deliver what one has been conditioned to expect.</description><author>Plaxco, L. M.; Arnott, R. D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The benefits of rebalancing - Worth the effort.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buetow, G. W.; Sellers, R.; Trotter, D.; Hunt, E.; Whipple, W. A.
This article analyzes the effects of various rebalancing decisions on the risk and return of a mufti-asset class portfolio. The findings show that the daily monitoring of a portfolio coupled with interval rebalancing can add to performance net of costs while simultaneously controlling for risk. Implementing a daily monitoring and interval rebalancing system for the mufti-asset class (and multi-managed) portfolio requires attentive professional management with the expertise to address structural obstacles in some asset classes.</description><author>Buetow, G. W.; Sellers, R.; Trotter, D.; Hunt, E.; Whipple, W. A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal benchmark tracking with small portfolios - Using the diversity measure to deal with constraints on number of stocks in a portfolio.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jansen, R.; van Dijk, R.
In this article the authors examine the problem of index tracking. Market capitalization-weighted indexes can be tracked by buying all the constituents at their actual weights, but the higher transaction and administration costs involved with this approach largely make this a non-practical solution. Minimizing a portfolio's tracking error with respect to the benchmark with a relatively small number of stocks is the central focus of the authors. They describe current portfolio optimization methods for the problem, and present a new mathematical optimization method that not only gives better results but also may be able to tackle other problems in portfolio optimization. The findings can easily be extended to solve portfolio construction problems that incorporate expected returns, variance of returns, transaction costs, and additional constraints.</description><author>Jansen, R.; van Dijk, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Perils of Success - The impact of asset growth on small-capitalization investment manager performance.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christopherson, J.; Ding, Z. X.; Greenwood, P.
The authors explore the impact of growth in assets under management on the performance of small-cap investment managers. They find that small-cap manager excess returns have a statistically significant inverse relationship to both the level of assets under management and the annual growth in the amount. The relationship between assets and performance appears to be very consistent and to transcend different substyles within the universe of small-cap managers. The authors discuss the challenges these findings pose for current and prospective clients of small-cap managers.</description><author>Christopherson, J.; Ding, Z. X.; Greenwood, P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity index funds have lost their way - A solution to growing problems.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gastineau, G. L.
The author argues that equity index funds get more credit for low costs and high efficiency than they deserve. The original idea of a low-cost, low-turnover, diversified portfolio has been replaced by funds that deliver only on their pledges of low turnover and diversification. The concentration of trading around index changes causes investors to incur transaction costs far higher than the pioneers of indexing anticipated. The author concludes that index funds based on popular benchmark indexes have become a much more costly way to invest than they used to be and than they need to be.</description><author>Gastineau, G. L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What's a portfolio manager worth? A new style performance measure.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korkie, R. M.; Turtle, H. J.
This article derives and applies a performance measure of a portfolio manager's value-added called "style pricing." The value-added is obtained by treating the per period payoffs from the managed portfolio as a financial claim, contingent on the payoffs from other marketed assets. The relevant marketed assets are those that describe the style of the managed portfolio's returns in a precise way. The price of the contingent claim is obtained using martingale methods so that there is zero arbitrage between the portfolio's payoffs and the payoffs from the replicating contingent claim. As the authors explain, the style pricing approach may be applied to any management style, is directly measured in dollars, and is readily comparable to the portfolio manager's remuneration and the fees payable.</description><author>Korkie, R. M.; Turtle, H. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of reduced supply of treasuries - Implications, for fixed-income risk and portfolio asset allocation.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corridon, S.
The supply of outstanding U.S. Treasury debt is declining because of the recent federal budget surpluses. Should current expectations for future surpluses be met, in the future U.S. Treasuries will constitute a dramatically smaller portion of the overall U.S. fixed-income market. In this article, the author estimates the impact of the expected composition shift on the risk of the fixed-income market and its relationship with other broad asset classes. He concludes that fixed-income risk may actually fall slightly, but its correlation with other asset classes should rise, possibly leading to increased risk at the overall portfolio level.</description><author>Corridon, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Venture capital and its role in strategic asset allocation - Long-term risk-return characteristics.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, P.; Baierl, G. T.; Kaplan, P. D.
With record amounts of money flowing into venture capital investment in recent years, it has become an important asset class in many long-term strategic portfolios. The authors explain the long-term risk-return characteristics of venture capital investment and its role in a long-term strategic asset allocation. While there are limited market performance data on venture capital, they find that from 1960 through 1999, venture capital has had an annual arithmetic average return of 45% with a standard deviation of 115.6%. The geometric average return (compounded average) is estimated to be about 13%. The correlation coefficient between venture capital and public stocks is estimated to be 0.04%. Because of its relatively low correlation with stocks, an allocation to venture capital of 2% to 9% is warranted for an aggressive portfolio (i.e., all-equity).</description><author>Chen, P.; Baierl, G. T.; Kaplan, P. D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Illiquid alternative asset fund modeling - A flexible management tool.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Takahashi, D.; Alexander, S.
A financial model that enables institutional investors to project future asset values and cash flows for funds in illiquid alternative asset classes such as venture capital, lever-aged buyouts, real estate, and natural resources is the subject of this article. The model presented incorporates actual historical information to provide a base for forecasts. It allows investors with a portfolio of alternative assets to assess various scenarios with different fund commitment levels and different assumptions regarding contributions, distributions, and underlying net returns.</description><author>Takahashi, D.; Alexander, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The first price of the day - Auctions are not practical for trading all securities.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Madhavan, A.; Panchapagesan, V.
The opening trading session is arguably the most crucial of the entire day, given the powerful combination at the open of concentrated volume and high uncertainty following the overnight or weekend non-trading period. The authors examine the process of price discovery at the New York Stock Exchange single-price opening auction. The analysis sheds light on the role of the specialist and provides insights into how openings on other markets-such as Nasdaq-might be structured. In particular, the presence of designated dealers facilitates price discovery over an automated call auction market, perhaps because specialists obtain valuable information by observing the evolution of the limit order book. In addition, the specialist's opening trade reflects non-information factors such as price stabilization requirements. Finally, the authors note that it is not feasible to trade thin stocks in call markets without either the presence of a designated dealer or a high degree of transparency.</description><author>Madhavan, A.; Panchapagesan, V.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Emerging markets - Managing the impact of high costs.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Masters, S. J.
Emerging markets investors face annual investment costs that the author estimates at between 2% and 5% annually. At these levels, the costs are enough to alter the balance between potential reward and risk. The author examines three types of investment costs-transaction-related costs, operating costs, and investment management fees-and a variety of strategies that investors can use to help reduce or control these costs. The benefits and limitations of various approaches are examined, including reducing turnover, purchasing non-domestic shares, altering country allocations, using alternative investment vehicles, and indexing. The author advocates a combination of several cost-limiting strategies combined with active management as the most cost-efficient approach to investing in the emerging markets.</description><author>Masters, S. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance measurement and insurance liabilities - A dual benchmark.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Plantinga, A.; Huijgen, C.
In this article, the authors develop an attribution framework for evaluating the investment performance of institutional investors such as insurance companies. The model is useful in identifying the investment skills of insurance companies. This is accomplished by developing a dual benchmark for the investor that is focused toward the two objectives of the investor, namely the maximization of shareholder value and the protection of the value of the policyholders. For each objective, the authors develop a different benchmark portfolio, which are joined together to form the dual benchmark portfolio. As a result, their model achieves a balance between these two objectives and reduces agency costs.</description><author>Plantinga, A.; Huijgen, C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"VaR analytics - Portfolio structure, key rate convexities, and VaR betas": Comment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kroll, Y.; Kaplanski, G.
In the Fall 1996 issue of this journal, Ho, Chen, and Eng claim that under independence between the returns of "blocks" the "square root of the sum of the squares of the blocks' VaRs" is the lower bound of the portfolio's value-at-risk (VaR). The authors prove that this heuristic is correct only under the very limiting assumption of normal distributed returns. The correct lower bound can be above it far non-normal distributions. Thus, the lower bound claimed by Ho, Chen, and Eng may lead to underestimation of portfolio risk.</description><author>Kroll, Y.; Kaplanski, G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal risk-adjusted portfolios with multiple managers - Achieving the best correlation-adjusted performance.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Muralidhar, A. S.
Previous research demonstrated how current measures of risk-adjusted performance are insufficient for ranking investment managers or structuring portfolios, and provided an alternative measure called correlation-adjusted performance (CAP). The new measure accounts for differences in standard deviations, the correlation between portfolios and the benchmark, and the fact that investors have a target relative risk. In this article, the author extends the analysis for institutional investors with multiple manager portfolios. This technique facilitates optimal portfolio construction by combining the risk-free asset, the benchmark, and many investment managers. Since managers are less than perfectly correlated with each other, unattractive managers on a stand-alone basis may be chosen for their diversification properties and overall risk-adjusted performance can be increased over that of the highest yielding manager. The author also shows that the case for passive management is greatly diminished under this paradigm.</description><author>Muralidhar, A. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is there a lottery premium in the stock market? Persistent and significant.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Downs, T. W.; Wen, Q.
This research finds that extreme stock returns are associated with low-priced stocks, which in turn are correlated with a significant decline in average returns. They infer from this finding that investors in low-priced stocks accept lower (even negative) average returns as the premium paid for the chance to earn an extreme return. They refer to this sacrifice in average return the "lottery premium." Their analysis shows that the lottery premium is higher on $1 stocks than on $7 stocks; that the lottery premium, has become greater over time; and that the lottery premium is higher in up markets than in down markets.</description><author>Downs, T. W.; Wen, Q.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Hedge Funds Hedge? Be cautious in analyzing monthly returns.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asness, C.; Krail, R.; Liew, J.
Many hedge funds claim to provide significant diversification for traditional portfolios, besides attractive returns. The authors provide empirical evidence regarding the return and diversification benefits of hedge fund investing using the CSFB/Tremont hedge fund indexes over 1994-2000. Like many others, they find that simple regressions of monthly hedge fund excess returns on monthly S&amp;P 500 excess returns seem to support the claims about the benefits of hedge funds. The regressions show only modest market exposure and positive added value. This type of analysis can produce misleading results, however. Many hedge funds hold, to various degrees and combinations, illiquid exchange-traded securities or difficult-to-price over-the-counter securities. For the purposes of monthly reporting, hedge funds often price these securities using either the last available traded prices or estimates of current market prices. These practices can lead to reported monthly hedge fund returns that are not perfectly synchronous with monthly S&amp;P 500 returns. Non-synchronous return data can lead to understated estimates of actual market exposure. When the authors apply standard techniques that account for this problem, they find that hedge funds in the aggregate have significantly more market exposure than simple estimates indicate. Furthermore, after accounting for this increased market exposure, they find that taken as a whole the broad universe of hedge funds does not add value over this period.</description><author>Asness, C.; Krail, R.; Liew, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal portfolios of foreign currencies - Trading on the forward bias.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baz, J.; Breedon, F.; Naik, V.; Peress, J.
Empirical evidence suggests that forward exchange rates are biased predictors of future spot exchange rates. Currencies with higher nominal interest rates tend to appreciate rather than depreciate as predicted by the forward rates. Simultaneously, exchange rates also turn out to be notoriously difficult to predict using plausible macroeconomic variables. The authors demonstrate how these two hypotheses can be combined with standard mean-variance analysis to construct optimal currency portfolios. They simulate the optimal portfolio strategies on historically observed data for the period 1989-1999 for DEM, JPY, GBP, and CHF (with the USD as the base currency). These portfolios generate positive excess returns. Moreover, the returns on optimal currency portfolios do not appear to be correlated with the returns on major fixed-income and equity indexes. These findings suggest that the methodology can provide a useful benchmark against which to evaluate more elaborate active currency strategies.</description><author>Baz, J.; Breedon, F.; Naik, V.; Peress, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Successful factors to select outperforming corporate bonds - Useful filters in a very large universe.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hottinga, J.; van Leeuwen, E.; van IJserloo, J.
This study presents a method to select corporate bonds that outperform the corporate bond market as a whole. The approach has many similarities to the well-investigated field of stock selection strategies. The literature suggests several variables that are successful for the selection of outperforming stocks. The filters the authors investigate to select outperforming bonds will be even more useful because the fixed-income universe is so much larger, with more than 10,000 issues available. The authors test equity-related and bond-specific variables for selecting outperforming corporate bonds. After testing all the individual variables, they combine the most promising variables into one strategy. They achieve better-than-average performance in a corporate bond portfolio if they select bonds with a high spread valuation, a low spread return in recent months, and positive equity earnings revisions. The promising results are robust to several sensitivity tests.</description><author>Hottinga, J.; van Leeuwen, E.; van IJserloo, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Smith Company - Earn a profit, and pass on a reasonable portion to owners.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anonymous
The Smith Company is a private investment company whose primary investment objective is to provide an endowment-like stream of dividends to approximately 100 members of the Smith family. The company invests primarily in publicly traded equities, although it also owns a few municipal bonds. This shareholders' report for the year 2000 discusses the so-called Great Internet Bubble, the returns to growth and value stocks, the company's pre-tax equity track record since the family sold its operating business in 1974, the dividend behavior of the S&amp;P 500, and the misuse of corporate cash.</description><author>Anonymous</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Implementing optimal risk budgeting - Managing uncertainty of alpha.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, W.; Lam, D. Y.
Risk budgeting has become a buzzword. While there may be no generally accepted definition or approaches for implementation, the underlying concept of risk budgeting remains sound and relevant. Defining risk as "uncertainty of alpha," the authors argue that successful implementation of risk budgeting requires assessment of the quality of one's information under uncertainty (which the authors define as information risks), as well as other statistical risk measurement. Using a global asset allocation portfolio as an example, the authors introduce a simple optimal risk budgeting tool. With information risks, investment views, and total risk budget as inputs, the framework presented provides the optimal combination of information advantage so that the allocation of risks across strategies and assets is consistent with a manager's assessment of information risks and investment views.</description><author>Lee, W.; Lam, D. Y.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The advantages of tax-managed investing - Avoiding the drag.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chincarini, L.; Kim, D.
Recent advances in on-line portfolio trading have brought investors much closer to achieving the frictionless model often assumed in portfolio theory. Taxes, though, remain a significant barrier. The authors show that even a passive equity fund, such as the Vanguard 500, has a significant drag in the form of taxes, leaving an investor with only 54% of pre-tax value after 24 years. They find that passive portfolio investors can reduce taxes substantially by selling losing stocks and replacing them with characteristically matched stocks. The authors provide an analytic framework to quantify the effects of taxes on investment returns. The pre-tax returns are affected by two components: short versus long tax rates, and forgone earnings. They isolate the two effects to assess their extent. Using the effective tax rate as a measure of the tax drag, they find that the theoretical cost of forgone earnings is as high as 30% and that the theoretical cost of realizing short-term gains is as high as 31%. Different real-world equity strategies to reduce the investor's effective tax rates are found to cut taxes by as much as 4.8%, significantly increasing the after-tax return.</description><author>Chincarini, L.; Kim, D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tracking S&amp;P 500 index funds - Getting your money's worth?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frino, A.; Gallagher, D. R.
Although index funds have grown significantly in the 1990s, empirical research concerning these passive investment offerings is surprisingly scarce. While the theory and objectives of an index strategy are both simple and well known, potential difficulties arise for index managers attempting to replicate the returns of the target benchmark. The source of the problem is that the underlying index is measured as a paper portfolio, and there is an implication that simple duplication is achievable without cost. In reality, tracking error in index fund performance is unavoidable because of market frictions. The authors highlight the difficulties faced by index funds. They examine both the extent and the variation of tracking error over time for S&amp;P 500 index mutual funds, and provide a direct performance comparison between index funds and active mutual funds. The findings indicate that S&amp;P 500 index funds, on average, outperformed active funds after expenses over the sample period.</description><author>Frino, A.; Gallagher, D. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High-frequency performance monitoring - Produces unexpected results.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dimson, E.; Jackson, A.
Improvements in technology and increasing emphasis on performance have led many investors to monitor the performance of fund managers on a high-frequency basis: quarterly, monthly, or more frequently. The authors examine the impact that frequency of performance measurement has on the probability distribution of observed outcomes. With more frequent monitoring of rolling returns, there is a greatly increased probability of observing seemingly extreme observations. The authors demonstrate that if performance is appraised by focusing on returns to date, it is important to adjust the definition of extreme performance for the frequency with which returns are monitored. Failure to do so may lead to costly actions such as strategy revisions or manager terminations, which increase transaction costs and have detrimental effects on manager incentives.</description><author>Dimson, E.; Jackson, A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why real estate? An investment rationale for institutional investors: 2001 update.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hudson-Wilson, S.
Institutional investors have traditionally viewed real estate as a risk-reducer, diversifying portfolios in line with the fiduciary responsibilities imposed by ERISA. This is not the oi-dy role that the asset class can fill. Peal estate can obviously help make a portfolio market-neutral and more reflective of the overall investment universe. Can it also reduce the overall risk of a portfolio, provide high absolute returns, act as an inflation hedge, and offer strong cash flows? Recently, the equity market has faltered, and the specters of inflation and recession now haunt the collective psyche of the investor. Why real estate? Is the answer more compelling now than in the late 1990s? The author takes a detailed look.</description><author>Hudson-Wilson, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Staying the course</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge fund and commodity fund investments in bull and bear markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edwards, F. R.; Caglayan, M. O.
A primary motivation for investing in hedge funds and commodity funds is to diversify against falling stock prices. The authors evaluate the performance of 16 different such funds during rising and falling stock markets between 1990 and 1998 both as stand-alone assets and as portfolio assets. They use the Sharpe ratio and alternative safety-first criteria to evaluate performance. The conclusion is that commodity funds generally provide more downside protection than hedge funds. Commodity funds have higher returns in bear markets than hedge funds, and generally have an inverse correlation with stock returns in bear markets. Hedge funds typically exhibit a higher positive correlation with stock returns in bear markets than in bull markets. Three hedge fund styles-market-neutral, event-driven, and global macro-provide fairly good downside protection with more attractive returns over all markets than commodity funds.</description><author>Edwards, F. R.; Caglayan, M. O.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The false teachings of the unbiased expectations hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chance, D. M.; Rich, D.
The unbiased expectations hypothesis is the basis for many current investment strategies, despite its shortcomings. Yet the spot-forward parity theorem and the unbiased expectations hypothesis cannot both hold. Why do some in the investment community continue to believe that there is any more information in forward prices or rates than spot prices or rates? The authors show that forward prices have to be biased predictors of future spot prices, or arbitrage opportunities would arise. The bias is fair compensation for the difference in the timing of the cash flows between the spot and forward markets. The authors argue that the unbiased expectations hypothesis often forms the basis for trading strategies only because of the zero initial value and non-zero future value, the misuse of forwards in performance attribution, and a misunderstanding of the symmetry of risk premiums.</description><author>Chance, D. M.; Rich, D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting mean-variance optimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Uysal, E.; Trainer, F. H.; Reiss, J.
Mean-variance optimization is so well accepted that we often take it for granted. In this article the authors examine the impact of relaxing its assumptions in a fixed-income context. They examine particularly whether the substantial overweighting of non-Treasury bonds that is recommended in a mean-variance context holds up under alternative return distributions and utility functions. They also show how to incorporate scenario forecasting into an optimization framework.</description><author>Uysal, E.; Trainer, F. H.; Reiss, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What we think about the quality of our equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwartz, R. A.; Weaver, D. G.
Have the technological and regulatory changes in the US, equity markets in recent years improved or impaired market quality? As "market quality" is an ambiguous concept that is neither readily quantifiable nor amenable to straightforward empirical analysis, the authors have surveyed the opinions of sell-side and buy-side participants and academic financial economists. Academic respondents in general, and the microstructure subset in particular, are relatively positive about market quality and the efficacy of regulatory initiatives. The predominant response on both the sell-side and the buy-side is that the quality of the U.S. equity markets has deteriorated in recent years. Technology is broadly thought to be a great tool, but many industry participants believe that market structure regulation is not helping.</description><author>Schwartz, R. A.; Weaver, D. G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identifying the factor structure of equity returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Merville, L. J.; Hayes-Yelken, S.; Xu, Y. X.
A challenge for modern portfolio managers and security analysts is understanding the variables or factors that drive security returns. Statistical methods such as principal components analysis are useful but lack meaningful interpretations. Peal economic factors comport with intuitive understanding but lack explanatory power. This study seeks to bridge the gap between these two approaches by interpreting "statistical factors" using economic factors. The authors examine the factor structure of equity portfolio returns widely used in a sample period from 1963 through 1999. They find there are three major factors for equity returns, which can be associated with 1) the market return; 2) market capitalization; and 3) the investment opportunity set. Higher-order factors can be uniquely identified with macroeconomic variables.</description><author>Merville, L. J.; Hayes-Yelken, S.; Xu, Y. X.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beware of index fund fundamentalists</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Minor, D. B.
This article recasts earlier research on index fund performance. A different time period shows the opposite results for index fund superiority over actively managed funds. Over the past 20 years, the end result is that neither passive nor active management as a whole wins, as common sense would suggest. Even if active management as a whole were to lose in the future, it is shown how one may use active management to create superior portfolios.</description><author>Minor, D. B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risks of sector rotation strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cavaglia, S.; Cho, D.; Singer, B.
Global factors are playing an increasingly important role in the pricing of securities. It is a new challenge to identify, the sources of those global factors and to structure portfolios that exploit the reward-to-risk opportunities from variation in these factors. The authors build on research suggesting that industry factors capture an economically important component of the variation in security returns. postulating a risk model that explicitly accounts for regional sector rotation decisions, they find that sensitivities to foreign factors are positively associated with the extent of firms' foreign sales activities. This provides empirical support for a reduced-form structural model, and it suggests that foreign sales data can be used as a conditioning variable to obtain economically sensible risk factor sensitivities.</description><author>Cavaglia, S.; Cho, D.; Singer, B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Parameter estimation techniques, optimization frequency, and portfolio return enhancement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Larsen, G. A.; Resnick, B. G.
Modern portfolio theory dictates that the lower the pairwise correlation between securities, the greater the potential for efficiency enhancement from ex ante optimization. When securities exhibit a high degree of pairwise correlation, ex ante optimization should provide less potential for efficiency enhancement. It is an empirical issue as to whether ex ante return estimation and optimization techniques can provide strict return enhancement in risk-return space. Strict return enhancement, without the use of leverage, may be possible if ex ante portfolio parameter estimation techniques allow securities with higher realized returns to carry greater weights in the ex ante optimal portfolio than in the benchmark portfolio. The authors of this article examine how various ex ante portfolio parameter estimation techniques and optimization/holding-period frequency intervals can enhance managed portfolio returns. Overall, the results suggest that it is possible to consistently achieve enhanced returns at much the same level of return per unit of risk as the benchmark portfolio.</description><author>Larsen, G. A.; Resnick, B. G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tracking error allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blitz, D. C.; Hottinga, J.
This article presents a framework for allocating partial tracking errors to investment decisions in order to maximize the expected information ratio of an actively managed portfolio. The tracking error allocation framework is a three-step process: 1) identifying the independent investment decisions; 2) ranking the forecasting capabilities for the investment decisions; and 3) calculating the optimum partial tracking errors, given an overall tracking error limit. The key result is an understandable and transparent rule that says the target tracking error for each investment decision should be proportional to the corresponding expected information ratio. The authors illustrate the framework using examples that show some interesting practical consequences of an optimum tracking error allocation.</description><author>Blitz, D. C.; Hottinga, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Small is beautiful</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beckers, S.; Vaughan, G.
The authors examine the impact of fund size on investment performance. Ultimately every investment strategy will become self-defeating when too much money chases the same opportunity. It has therefore become common practice among successful fund managers to close funds to new money. It is mostly a mystery as to where and how this line gets drawn, especially since these restrictions are almost invariably lifted (with the pressure of increased client demand). Every asset management strategy has a natural limit beyond which growing a fund will significantly retard performance. The authors use real-life simulations to document how soon a performance drag sets in and how significant it is. They thus provide a framework to establish maximum fund size.</description><author>Beckers, S.; Vaughan, G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mind-sets over matter</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange-traded funds: An introduction - And further likely evolution.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gastineau, G. L.
The phenomenal growth of exchange-traded funds (ETFs) is a frequent topic in the financial press. These funds, with assets more than doubling each year since 1995, have been warmly embraced by most advocates of low-cost index funds. Vanguard, the leading advocate of index funds, has announced plans to add exchange-traded share classes to a number of its domestic index funds. Most of the press coverage has correctly noted the major advantages of ETFs-low-costs, intraday trading and high tax efficiency with no material premiums or discounts to the funds' intraday net asset value. However, there is a fair degree of misusunderstanding about how ETFs work, what sectors of the market are good candidates for ETFs and what sectors are not, why the expense ratios tend to be low, and how most of the funds manage to avoid significant capital gains distributions. In this article, the author attempts to answer these and other questions frequently asked by investors.</description><author>Gastineau, G. L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk budgets: Comment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chow, G.; Kritzman, M.; Van Royen, A. S.
In a previous issue, George Chow and Mark Kritzman discussed the relationship of risk budgeting and asset allocation. A risk budget is defined as the conversion of optimal allocations from mean-variance optimization into value at risk assignments. This comment identifies an error in the formula for the sensitivity of portfolio value at risk with respect to asset weights. The authors demonstrate how to derive VaR sensitivity correctly and extend the analysis to more than three assets.</description><author>Chow, G.; Kritzman, M.; Van Royen, A. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The stock market and monetary policy: Comedy or error?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Will business success spoil the investment management profession? Separate appearances from realities.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellis, C. D.
The healthy balance of two very different disciplines-profession and business-that has made investment management a wonderful realm in which to make our Lives and our livings, now appears to be getting out of balance, according to the author. Business disciplines are increasingly dominant, even dominating. The author argues that this could bring increasingly unhappy consequences for both our clients and ourselves.</description><author>Ellis, C. D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The case for whole-stock portfolios - Failure of the multiple-specialist architecture.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ennis, R. M.
For more than 20 years pension and endowment funds have used multiple active investment managers With complementary styles to manage their U.S. common stocks. Theory tells us that the approach-diversifying with active managers-is suboptimal. Evidence presented by the author supports the theory indicating that the strategy has underperformed by the margin of its cost, which is approximately 1.2% per year. Passive management is one solution, and passive allocations have risen steadily for 20 years. Many funds, however, demonstrate reluctance to pursue a purely passive approach. The author recommends that those funds consider employing one or more whole portfolios in managing their active U.S. equity assets. Successfully employed in managing fixed income and international equities, whole portfolios embrace the totality of the opportunity set represented by the asset class. Whole portfolios allow investment managers to make a broader range of relative-value judgments than occurs under the multiple-specialist model. At the same time their use frees the client h-om having to manage the collective style of several active managers, eliminating in the process fairly arbitrary and rigid boundaries within the active equity portfolio. Using whole portfolios is also conducive to hiring fewer managers, an important step in avoiding "closet indexing.".</description><author>Ennis, R. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is fixed-weight asset allocation really better? In most cases.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arshanapalli, B.; Coggin, T. D.; Nelson, W.
In this article, the authors compare the performance of two long-term fixed-weight asset allocation models with two dynamic models-one based on historical data and one based in part on analysts' forecasts. They find that fixed-weight asset allocation outperformed a dynamic approach that used only historical data. They also include a comparison of the performance of the asset allocation recommendations of eight Wall Street brokerage firms and a "Robot Blend.?' Four of the eight firms nominally outperforIned the Robot Blend after transaction costs, confirming the random chance prediction. The dynamic asset allocation model that used analysts' forecasts outperformed all other models. This result is robust to the application of reasonable constraints to the dynamic models. The authors suggest that dynamic asset allocation models probably will not outperform fixed-weight asset allocation unless they employ superior analyst judgment. In their data, a static 60/30/10 mix of stocks, bonds, and cash appears to be an attractive long-term choice.</description><author>Arshanapalli, B.; Coggin, T. D.; Nelson, W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Active management of equity investment portfolios - Using component VaR, VaR beta, and benchmark VaR.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aragones, J. R.; Blanco, C.; Mascarenas, J.
The main purpose of this article is to show how the VaR methodology can be effectively applied for risk measurement and management of equity portfolios, introducing a sector approach in the analysis. The risk aggregation problem of equity portfolios is addressed by grouping individual positions in the corresponding industry sectors as a first step toward an effective risk management tool to measure the tracking error against a benchmark index.</description><author>Aragones, J. R.; Blanco, C.; Mascarenas, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Style investing: Incorporating growth characteristics in value stocks - Value and growth styles can complement each other.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahmed, P.; Nanda, S.
Several empirical studies show a systematic relationship between stack characteristics (size, earnings yield, dividend yield, etc.) and stock returns. Previous studies that show stocks with high earnings yield produce superior returns use univariate measures (such as E/P or B/P) to classify stocks into value or growth stocks. The authors show that the traditional method of classification ignores instances when value and growth investing strategies, instead of being mutually exclusive, can complement each other in selecting superior performing stocks. Growth in EPS provides a more meaningful way to capture growth than using a measure of low E/P ratio. A strategy focusing on investing in stocks that have the dual characteristics of a high E/P ratio and high growth in EPS outperforms a strategy of high E/P alone. The authors also document some evidence of persistence in performance for stocks having the dual characteristics of high growth in EPS and high E/P ratio.</description><author>Ahmed, P.; Nanda, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The death of the risk premium - Consequences of the 1990s.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arnott, R. D.; Ryan, R. J.
The authors contend that most of the institutional investing community is expecting far higher returns than are realistic fi-om current market levels. Extrapolating the past is the easiest, and worst, way to forecast the future. Unfortunately, most investors' return expectations are shaped by a simple extrapolation of either recent or longterm past returns. If, instead, the constituent parts of equity market returns an examined, we find that it is remarkably difficult to make a case for a positive equity risk premium (the premium of future stock market returns relative to bond yields) from current market levels. None of this analysis is contingent on any assumption that market P/E ratios or dividend yields should return to historical levels. If market levels are fair and are fully sustained in the years ahead, there is still little or no room for a positive equity risk premium. If there is not a positive risk premium, then actuarial return assumptions are likely to be too optimistic, with far-reaching implications for pension funding ratios, corporate earnings, future pension contributions, and appropriate asset allocation policy.</description><author>Arnott, R. D.; Ryan, R. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>MVA and the cross-section of expected stock returns - A strong negative relationship between MVA per share and average returns.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yook, K. C.; McCabe, G. M.
The authors examine the cross-section of expected stock returns between 1985 and 1994 and find a strong negative relationship between market value added per share (MVA) and average returns. When the joint effect of MVA, firm size, and the ratio of price-to-book value is examined, the explanatory power of size and the price-to-book value for the cross-section of average returns is substantially diminished, but MVA is still strongly related to returns. These results suggest three possibilities: that MVA is serving as a proxy for a risk factor that affects equilibrium expected returns, that current poor performance will be reversed in the future as the mean-reverting hypothesis suggests, or that low MVA firms are relatively underpriced.</description><author>Yook, K. C.; McCabe, G. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On arrogance, amalgams, and goofs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The growth of index funds and the pricing of equity securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malkiel, B. G.; Radisich, A.
The authors examine the hypothesis that the popularity of indexing to the S&amp;P 500 had a self-fulfilling effect of inflating the prices of the stocks in the index during the 1990s. They conclude instead that the success of indexing results from the general efficiency of U.S. stock markets, and that the gap between the performance of index funds and active managers can be explained fully by the extra management and transaction costs involved in active management. The authors find no evidence that the success of indexing is self-fulfilling; nor can they substantiate that indexing has any permanent effect on the pricing of securities.</description><author>Malkiel, B. G.; Radisich, A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recovery risk in stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akgun, A.; Gibson, R.
The authors provide evidence that the power of book-to-market and size attributes in explaining the cross-section of stock returns may, in part, lie in the fact that these concepts subsume useful information regarding both the probability of bankruptcy and recovery rates. Other research that focuses primarily on the probability of default concludes that investors do not care about financial distress risk. The authors argue, however, that this conclusion may be premature, as the evidence suggests that investors are concerned, ex ante, about recovery rate risk as well. The findings here have important portfolio management implications.</description><author>Akgun, A.; Gibson, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk diversification benefits of multiple-stock portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Vassal, V.
During the past seven years, not everyone with equity holdings may have profited front the extraordinary bull market. Private investors with large concentrated holdings in only one or a few stocks are vulnerable to significant risk of underperforming. The author of this article provides a useful framework for explaining the risk-return benefits of adding stocks to a portfolio. The analysis uses Monte Carlo techniques to simulate total returns of equity portfolios with varying numbers of holdings for the seven-year period ending December 31, 1999. The universe is based on the original constituents of the Russell 1000 as of December 31, 1992, adjusted for survivorship. The results suggest significant risk reduction benefits can be achieved by adding only a small number of stocks to a nondiversified portfolio.</description><author>de Vassal, V.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Life cycle investing, holding periods, and risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hickman, K.; Hunter, H.; Byrd, J.; Beck, J.; Terpening, W.
This article examines the relative performance of bills, bonds, and stocks over various holding periods. Using a resampling technique that accounts for the cross-sectional correlation between security classes, the authors find that the risk of underperformance for a strategy of investing in higher risk classes of investments is minimal over long holding periods, while the rewards are substantial.</description><author>Hickman, K.; Hunter, H.; Byrd, J.; Beck, J.; Terpening, W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International hedge of fixed-income contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hauser, S.; Rozenkranz, M.; Ben-Zion, U.; Yaari, U.
The fixed-income literature is concerned with hedging strategies for controlling the interest rate risk of assets and liabilities held domestically in a single currency. That there is little research dedicated to international immunization may reflect a view that companies and financial institutions dealing internationally need only replicate a single-currency hedging strategy ill each country. The authors argue that separate immunization in each country is overly restrictive and may be costly to execute. Instead, they propose a less restrictive strategy treating the assets and liabilities held across currencies as portfolios, and matching the duration of those portfolios. Their immunization strategy should directly reduce the cost of international hedging against interest risk, and indirectly reduce the cost of hedging against currency risk. Simulation results suggest that the proposed strategy should be at least as effective as well as cheaper to implement.</description><author>Hauser, S.; Rozenkranz, M.; Ben-Zion, U.; Yaari, U.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing market risk for an emerging market debt portfolio</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martins, L. E.; Petrov, C.; Kelly, J. M.
Investors in the emerging debt market are exposed to a number of different types of risk, most importantly market risk. This article introduces a risk metric called beta spread duration (BSD), which is designed to measure aggregate market risk. BSD builds on two well-known metrics, beta and spread duration, and applies them to the emerging debt market. The authors demonstrate that BSD is a statistically significant measure of overall market risk and identify its limitations. They show that while market risk explains the majority of spread changes, individual country risk still matters. Indeed, they show that large changes in country risk call dominate overall market risk over shorter time frames while also exhibiting statistical significance over longer periods.</description><author>Martins, L. E.; Petrov, C.; Kelly, J. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transaction costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkowitz, S. A.; Logue, D. E.
With rising turnover in institutional portfolios, investment managers are paying increasing attention to transaction costs. The authors provide some insight into managing costs in an approach that assumes trading is a process, not an event. In the process, there are three actors: portfolio manager, in-house trader, and broker, each with its own period of discretion. Costs of transacting should be attributed to the different actors according only to their periods of discretion. High-turnover portfolios should invest in systems that would allow estimation of the costs attributable to each actor's decisions. The authors illustrate how this might be done.</description><author>Berkowitz, S. A.; Logue, D. E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public pension fund power</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ambachtsheer, K. P.
In his testimony on Social Security System reform before Congress in 1999, Alan Greenspan voiced the opinion that it is not feasible to manage public pension funds without political interference. Poor performance is the result. This article's author beg to differ. A recent study shows no difference in the performance of large samples of U.S. public sector and corporate pension funds. It is not the type of sponsorship that drives performance, the author argues, but the quality of a fund's governance and management processes. Public funds are no less likely to be endowed with these qualities than their private sector counterparts.</description><author>Ambachtsheer, K. P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk budgets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chow, G.; Kritzman, M.
While risk budgets are the new fashion among investment managers, the investment community has yet to agree on the precise meaning of the term, or, more important, on how risk budgeting relates to asset allocation. Intuitively, a risk budget conveys the notion that a portfolio's risk is somehow apportioned to various categories, but such disaggregation is impossible for many descriptions of risk. The authors explore the issues associated with risk budgets with a view to arriving at a clear and uniform understanding of risk budgets and their role in the investment process.</description><author>Chow, G.; Kritzman, M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why the low returns to beta and other forms of risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Miller, E. M.
High-beta stocks typically fail to outperform low-beta stocks. Investors have heterogeneous opinions about value, and the difference between the return expected by the marginal investor and by the typical investor increases with the divergence of opinion. The author suggests that the divergence of opinion diminishes following an initial public offering, producing long-run underperformance of such offerings.. Because divergence of opinion, uncertainty, and beta risk are correlated, according to the author, this causes an uncertainty-induced bias that increases with beta, producing a relatively aat security market line, natter than the risk-return relationship anticipated by the typical investor. An implication of this theory is that investors can improve their return relative to risk by exploiting the flatness of the security market line.</description><author>Miller, E. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Integrating active and passive management - To produce superior investment results.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Flood, E.; Ramachandran, N.
Many investors think of active and passive management as mutually exclusive approaches in investment management; they are proponents of either active or passive management. In the view of the authors, it is more useful to think of these investment management approaches as lying along a continuum, with passive management using index replication at one end of the continuum, and active management using aggressively concentrated portfolios at the other end. Both investment management approaches have benefits and shortcomings. By combining active and passive approaches to investment management, plan sponsors, foundations, and endowments can maximize the benefit potential and may minimize the shortcoming; of each to improve overall portfolio results. The authors compare the two approaches, discuss their historical performance, and present a framework for combining the two on a strategic (long-run), tactical (medium-run), and dynamic (short-run) basis.</description><author>Flood, E.; Ramachandran, N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value of skill in security selection versus asset allocation in credit markets - An "imperfect foresight" study.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dynkin, L.; Hyman, J.; Wu, W.
The authors of this article simulate several styles of fixed-income portfolio management using a variation of the "perfect foresight" approach and explore performance at manager skill levels ranging h-om 0% (random selection) to 100% (perfect foresight). The portfolio strategies are designed so as to isolate the management styles: duration allocation, sector allocation, quality allocation, and security selection. Information ratios are reported for each strategy at various levels of manager skill. At equivalent levels of skill, the strategy based on security selection outperforms duration allocation and sector/quality allocation techniques in terms of information ratios. The number of independent decisions in the allocation process is a key determinant of strategy success. The advantage of security selection lies in the diversification of risk provided by making many security selection decisions simultaneously. This does not negate the importance of duration decision-making in fixed-income portfolio management.</description><author>Dynkin, L.; Hyman, J.; Wu, W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The decision tree approach to stock selection - An evolving tree model performs the best.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sorensen, E. H.; Miller, K. L.; Ooi, C. K.
A frequent question regarding quantitative investing is: What are good variables for stock selection? Traditional quantitative strategies are variations of screening techniques. Quantitative investment managers seek to narrow the investable universe to a manageable number of stocks that have desirable characteristics. The authors introduce an alternative approach to traditional methods of stock screening based on a statistical technique known as classification and regression tree (CART). CART allows screening factors to interact on a conditional basis. The end result is a hierarchical (tree) structure that assigns a probability of outperformance (or underperformance) for each stock. The authors apply two alternative CART strategies to the selection of technology stocks, and evaluate their performance. The models demonstrate significant improvement over the more ad hoc stock ranking techniques.</description><author>Sorensen, E. H.; Miller, K. L.; Ooi, C. K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic asset allocation and international investing - The conventional approach misses the potential for risk reduction.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinold, R. C.; Meese, R. A.
Strategic asset allocation studies often deal with international assets on an unhedged basis. The potential hedging of international investments is either not considered at all or is left as a secondary decision after the overall commitment to international assets is established. The authors argue that this practice introduces a systematic and substantial bias against international investing and the use of hedging to reduce currency risk.</description><author>Grinold, R. C.; Meese, R. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification in the presence of taxes - There are substantial risks incurred with concentrated holdings.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stein, D. M.; Siegel, A. F.; Narasimhan, P.; Appeadu, C. E.
A common problem for taxable investors is how much to diversify either a low cost basis single-asset or concentrated portfolio. While tax-exempt theory is clear on the benefits of diversification, and there are useful industry methods for addressing this, in the presence of taxes there are no standard approaches to arriving at a considered choice. The authors propose an analytic and intuitive framework for addressing the problem, considering only two investment alternatives. By defining a tax-deferred equivalent of the taxable investor, they are able to adapt standard analytical methods and view the diversification decision in the presence of taxes as a conventional risk-return trade-off, provided the appropriate tax-deferred performance measures are used. Greater diversification is needed with greater initial asset volatility, with longer investment horizons, with lower expected return of the initial asset, and with a higher cost basis. Less diversification is needed when the investor receives a step-up in basis at the horizon. The results highlight the substantial risks incurred in concentrated holdings and often support high levels of diversification, even in the face of taxes.</description><author>Stein, D. M.; Siegel, A. F.; Narasimhan, P.; Appeadu, C. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cognitive biases in market forecasts - The frailty of forecasting.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fisher, K. L.; Statman, M.
Will the DJIA soar to 36,000 or plummet to 3,600? The desire to know the future is so strong that it blinds us to the fallibility of forecasts. The authors find that P/E ratios and dividend yields provide no help in forecasting one or two-year stock returns, and even ten-year forecasts are far from reliable. They trace the belief that P/E ratios and dividend yields provide reliable forecasts of returns to cognitive errors and discuss statistical and organizational remedies.</description><author>Fisher, K. L.; Statman, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond market volatility compared to stock market volatility - Critical effects for asset allocation.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reilly, F. K.; Wright, D. J.; Chan, K. C.
The high volatility of rates of returns on bonds during the 1980s received a great deal of attention because it is readily acknowledged that bond return volatility is critical to the analysis and management of bonds. Yet there has been no detailed analysis of bond market volatility for the pre-1980 period that would allow the experience during the 1980s and the 1990s to be put into perspective. The authors analyze the changing volatility of the government bond market over the past 50 years and examine how these changes compare to the well-documented volatility changes for the stock market. A comparison of Treasury bond market volatility to stock market volatility indicates that the volatility for these two markets has differed dramatically over time. The difference in volatility is confirmed by an analysis of the systematic risk of bonds versus stocks and the moving correlations between bonds and stock over time. In both instances, the pattern indicates a very cyclical series with wide ranges, but also a positive trend. An analysis of the time series properties of bond and stock volatility like-wise indicates significant differences.</description><author>Reilly, F. K.; Wright, D. J.; Chan, K. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Twentieth century volatility - A review of stock market volatility in the twentieth century.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ineichen, A. M.
The twentieth century was a turbulent time for equity investors. The author reviews price volatility over the past 700 years in general and equity volatility over the past 100 years in particular. The greatest sources of risk to equity investors in the twentieth century were price instability and resulting financial crises, wars, expropriations, and political upheavals. With respect to price volatility, the twentieth century was the most extreme by a wide margin with the most erratic price changes (deflation in the 1930s and inflation in the 1970s) occurring in the past 100 years. Given the unpredictability of past events, the author argues that an investment strategy biased on managing risk in the future could be a better approach to dealing with uncertainty than trying to guess what the future might hold.</description><author>Ineichen, A. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling office returns at the regional level - Plausible and useful forecasts.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hudson-Wilson, S.; Peng, R. J.; Capps, O.
For years, NCREIF has been publishing real estate returns for four property types in eight fairly broadly defined regions of the country. NCREIF also summarizes returns by property type at the national level. These national estimates are generally the data used in returns forecasting. Little use is made of the regional data, at least in terms of future outlook rather than past performance. In this article the authors discuss the return models they created and their forecasts for the office markets in the eight NCREIF regions. Their results show that these models can offer some interesting conclusions about the differences among, and similarities across, real estate markets.</description><author>Hudson-Wilson, S.; Peng, R. J.; Capps, O.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why I shall miss Merton Miller</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is there gold in them thar hills?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Levels of the game - Harder to win when professionals are the market.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellis, C. D.
Institutionalization of securities markets and the increasingly rich research resources of institutional investors and the sophisticated market intermediaries that supply them with data, information, and judgment have profoundly changed the nature of the investor's working enviroment. Winning the "Loser's Game" is getting harder and harder. The author argues that investing can be "unbundled" into different levels of difficulty and cost. Ironically, cost and success are in conflict. He argues that investment professionals and their clients are least likely to succeed at the most costly level of investing: buying and selling individual securities. Both managers and investors would be wise to refocus on the highest level of investing: determining realistic long-term objectives, formulating realistic policies to achieve their objectives, and sustaining wise commitments. At this higher level of the game, everyone can be a winner.</description><author>Ellis, C. D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economics of active management - Pension fund management needs improvement.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Snigaroff, R. G.
The active management industry has supply and demand characteristics and an industry total amount of dollars of produced value that buyers of active management products ought to consider in structuring their efforts to produce alpha. The author considers pension fund buyers of active management. Given that there is a maximum amount of possible excess return available to the pension fund buyers (an amount that can grow at the expense of other alpha producers), in the aggregate this group reduces value if there is oversupply. The author proposes that informed sellers are able to create excess demand because of a principal-agent issue within buyer organizations. Part-ly as a result of their unique history, pension funds have structured themselves suboptimally to produce:alpha; they need to consider ways to address the principal-agent issues and to exploit their competitive advantages to be successful in this business.</description><author>Snigaroff, R. G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Active management - Lessons for investment managers, consultants, and clients.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thomas, L. R.
Most financial markets are mostly efficient most of the the time. Ineffiencies opportunities to;add value dis-proportionate to marginal systematic risk -- appear sporadically and unpredictably. To improve the information ratio, the manager must search constantly and widely for inefficiencies. That is, manager performance depends crucially on broadening manager scope. The author argues that clients and their consultants can help investment managers widen their scope by structuring mandates in ways that are not: currently conventional. Managers can also broaden their scope by organizing themselves as teams with specialist: and generalist portfolio managers who cooperate to diversify across not only countries and currencies but also investment styles. Widening scope should also improve a management team's skill.</description><author>Thomas, L. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling stock market returns - An error correction model.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harasty, H.; Roulet, J.
In this article, the authors develop a two-step econometric model to explain and forecast stock market movements in seventeen countries. Their key assumption is that while a theory such as the dividend discount model is relevant to explain the long-run behavior of stock markets, shortrun fluctuations are driven fry variables that do not enter into the theory, and thus have to be empirically determined. This leads the authors to base their model on the theory of cointegration and error correction for developing the two-step model for long-term behavior and shortterm behavior. They present in- and out-of-sample tests of the model's ability to forecast future stock market results. These results indicate that such a model does have predictive power and can thus be a useful tool in the investment decision process.</description><author>Harasty, H.; Roulet, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Choosing managers and funds - Maximizing your alpha without sacrificing your target.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baierl, G. T.; Chen, P.
The authors describe a method for selecting portfolios of managers or mutual funds to implement a target asset allocation. The goal is to maze alpha for each level of tracking error. This routine is designed to meet manager-imposed minimum investment requirements by using discrete optimization techniques, A step-by-step example illustrates the practical use of the methods that the authors develop.</description><author>Baierl, G. T.; Chen, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of value in strategies based on anticipated earnings surprise - Identifying value stocks likely to perform well.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mozes, H. A.
The author shows that the strategy of buying stocks where the most positive earnings surprises are expected is more effect-rye for high E/P (i.e., value) stocks than for low E/P (i.e., glamour) stocks. Conversely, the strategy of selling shea stocks where the most negative earnings surprises are expected is more. effective for low E/P stocks than for high E/P stocks. These results hold after controlling for firm size, forecast horizon, stock price momentum, and the number of analyst forecasts. To the extent that the results for strategies based on expected earnings surprises are driven by value stocks that react strongly to favorable information, the interpretation of the strategies' success may be that they are forms of value strategies.</description><author>Mozes, H. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are multiple hedging instruments better than one? The case of fixed-rate mortgage-backed securities.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koutmos, G.; Pericli, A.
The authors examine the effectiveness of the ten-year, the five-year, and the two-year Treasury note futures contracts in hedging the price risk of fixed-rate mortgage-backed securities. The ten-year Treasury note futures contract offers superior hedging opportunities across all six coupon MBS examined. Using multiple instruments simultaneously results in minor improvements within-sample. In out-of-sample experiments, however, the use of a single instrument provides better hedging performance than the use of multiple instruments.</description><author>Koutmos, G.; Pericli, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The usefulness of inverse floaters - Income stability for a debt securities investment portfolio.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Babbel, D. F.; Ma, C. W.; Ni, B. J.
Inverse floaters are sometimes characterized by the popular financial press in unfavorable terms, particularly with respect to their reported role in a number of municipal financial crises during the mid-1990s. In this article, the authors show how inverse floaters can be used in conjunction with government bonds and repo leverage to create attractive risk-return profiles and stable income over a wide variety of economic scenarios. Inverse floaters can be particularly attractive during periods of steep yield curves.</description><author>Babbel, D. F.; Ma, C. W.; Ni, B. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Minsky and modern finance - The case of long term capital management.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mehrling, P.
Economic theory offers us two ways of understanding the events of fall 1998:the banking approach (here associated with Minsky), and the finance approach (here associated with Merton, Scholes, and the firm Long Term Capital Management). The main lesson of the LTCM experience is that the modern theory of asset pricing (the finance approach) is incomplete and needs to be supplemented by a theory of liquidity (the banking approach).</description><author>Mehrling, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The DJIA crossed 652,230 - In 1998.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clarke, R. G.; Statman, M.
The DJIA, like most indexes, is a capital index. It excludes dividends. The DJIA was initiated in 1896 at 40.94 and reached 9,181.43 by the end of 1998. The authors show that a wealth DJIA, an index that: accounts for reinvestment of dividends, would have reached 652,230.87 by the end of 1998. Adjusted for inflation, the wealth DJIA. would have reached 31,464.30.</description><author>Clarke, R. G.; Statman, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extreme bound analysis of emerging stock market anomalies - Nothing is robust.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Durham, J. B.
Studies of emerging stock market anomalies are based on underspecified models. Extreme bound analysis (EBA), a technique to remedy specification bias, indicates that no anomaly is robust, given panel data covering sixteen countries from March 1988 through January 1995. Only under a relaxed decision rule does the author fund thar five of the fifteen factors studied are sturdy: price/book long-run lagged returns, population demographics, country risk, and relative market size. What is move sobering, time series EBA produces no sturdy aggregate determinants.</description><author>Durham, J. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Day-of-the-week patterns in volume and prices of Nasdaq high-yield bonds - New ways to capitalize on information.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, G. J.; Ferri, M. G.
The authors investigate newly available data from the Nasdaq's Fixed Income Pricing System on transactions in high-yield corporate bonds. Their tests of daily patterns for sixty issues traded for all or part of the interval between October 1994 and July 1997 show that: 1) the level of trading is consistently higher on Tuesday through Thursday than on either Monday or Friday, and 2) bond prices tend to significantly rise on Tuesday and decline on Friday. They interpret these results as supporting this rule of timing transactions: Investors seeking to sell high-yield corporate bonds should try to do so near the close on Tuesday or on either Wednesday or Thursday, while those who want to buy them should do so near the close on Friday or on Monday.</description><author>Alexander, G. J.; Ferri, M. G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Style timing: Value versus growth - Is value dead?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asness, C. S.; Friedman, J. A.; Krail, R. J.; Liew, J. M.
Both academic and industry research supports the long-term efficacy of value strategies for choosing individual stocks. Value strategies are far from riskless, however. They can have long periods of poor performance. In an effort to improve upon these strategies, the authors have tried to forecast these returns with mixed results. Most of these "style timing" models are based on macroeconomic factors. The authors take a different approach considering two simple factors: 1) the spread in valuation multiples between a value portfolio and a growth portfolio (the value spread), and 2) the spread in expected earnings growth between a growth portfolio and a value portfolio (the earnings growth spread). They find that the greater the value spread and the smaller the earnings growth spread, the better their forecast for value versus growth going forward. These results are statistically and economically strong.</description><author>Asness, C. S.; Friedman, J. A.; Krail, R. J.; Liew, J. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>