<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Journal of Banking &amp; Finance5</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:39 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Convertibility restriction in China's foreign exchange market and its impact on forward pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Yi David
In contrast to the well established markets such as the dollar-euro market, recent CIP deviations observed in the onshore dollar-RMB forward market were primarily caused by conversion restrictions in the spot market rather than by changes in credit risk and/or liquidity constraint. This paper proposes a theoretical framework by which the Chinese authorities impose conversion restrictions in the spot market in an attempt to achieve capital flow balance, but face the tradeoff between achieving such balance and disturbing current account transactions. Consequently, the level of conversion restriction should increase with the amount of capital account transactions and decrease with the amount of current account transactions. Such conversion restriction in turn places a binding constraint on forward traders' ability to cover their forward positions, resulting in the observed CIP deviation. More particularly, the model predicts that the onshore forward rate will equal a weighted average of the CIP-implied forward rate and the market's expectation of the future spot rate, were the weighting is determined by the level of conversion restriction. As a secondary result, the model also implies that offshore non-deliverable forwards reflect the market's expectation of the future spot rate. Our empirical results are consistent with these predictions. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Yi David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Combining accounting data and a structural model for predicting credit ratings: Empirical evidence from European listed firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doumpos, Michael; Niklis, Dimitrios; Zopounidis, Constantin; Andriosopoulos, Kostas
Ratings issued by credit rating agencies (CRAs), play an important role in the global financial environment. Among other issues, past studies have explored the potential for predicting these ratings using a variety of explanatory factors and modeling approaches. This paper describes a multi-criteria classification approach that combines accounting data with a structural default prediction model in order to obtain improved predictions and test the incremental information that a structural model provides in this context. Empirical results are presented for a panel data set of European listed firms during the period 2002 2012. The analysis indicates that a distance-to-default measure obtained from a structural model adds significant information compared to popular financial ratios. Nevertheless, its power is considerably weakened when market capitalization is also considered. The robustness of the results is examined over time and under different rating category specifications. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Doumpos, Michael; Niklis, Dimitrios; Zopounidis, Constantin; Andriosopoulos, Kostas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Herding on fundamental information: A comparative study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Galariotis, Emilios C.; Rong, Wu; Spyrou, Spyros I.
This paper tests for herding towards the market consensus for US and UK leading stocks, and to the best of our knowledge addresses a gap in the literature regarding the importance of major fundamental macroeconomic announcements. The results indicate that US investors tend to herd during days when important macro data are released, and that there have been herding spill-over effects from the US to the UK during earlier financial crises. Further results reveal more differences in herding behavior between the two markets: in the US we find that investors herd due to both fundamentals and non-fundamentals during different crises, when in the UK there is herding only due to fundamentals and only during the Dotcom bubble burst. These results suggest that the drivers of herding behavior are period and country specific. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Galariotis, Emilios C.; Rong, Wu; Spyrou, Spyros I.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which are the SIFIs? A Component Expected Shortfall approach to systemic risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banulescu, Georgiana-Denisa; Durnitrescu, Elena-Ivona
This paper proposes a component approach to systemic risk which allows to decompose the risk of the aggregate financial system (measured by Expected Shortfall) while accounting for the firm characteristics. Developed by analogy with the Component Value-at-Risk concept, our new systemic risk measure, called Component ES, presents several advantages. It is a hybrid measure, which combines the Too Interconnected To Fail and the Too Big To Fail logics. CES relies only on publicly available daily data and encompasses the popular Marginal ES measure. CES can be used to assess the contribution of a firm to systemic risk at a precise date but also to forecast its contribution over a certain period. The empirical application verifies the ability of CES to identify the most systemically risky firms during the 2007-2009 financial crisis. We show that our measure identifies the institutions labeled as SIFIs by the Financial Stability Board. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Banulescu, Georgiana-Denisa; Durnitrescu, Elena-Ivona</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The importance of being systemically important financial institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bongini, Paola; Nieri, Laura; Pelagatti, Matteo
We investigate whether financial markets reacted to the regulatory changes implied by the publication of the list of systemically important financial institutions (SIFI) and the new rules designed to address the too-big-to-fail problem of systemic banks. By applying event study methodology to a sample of 70 of the world's largest banks, we assess whether the stock prices of SIFIs reacted significantly and differently from those of other large banks not deemed to be systemically important following the release of information regarding the methodology used to identify SIFIs and their new capital requirements; the disclosure of the first list of 29 SIFIs; and the publication of the updated list of 28 SIFIs. Overall, we determine that financial markets did not univocally react to the new regulation regarding SIFIs. However markets discriminated between high and low capitalized banks and they correctly estimated the probable effects of the additional capital requirements. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bongini, Paola; Nieri, Laura; Pelagatti, Matteo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of institutional investors on mergers and acquisitions in the United Kingdom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andriosopoulos, Dimitris; Yang, Shuai
In this paper we investigate the impact of institutional ownership on UK mergers and acquisitions. We employ a comprehensive sample of M&amp;As conducted by UK acquirers from 2000 to 2010, thus including a full cycle of peak and trough in M&amp;A waves. We find that institutional investors increase the likelihood of an M&amp;A to be a large, cross-border deal, opting for full control. Moreover, institutional ownership concentration and foreign institutional ownership increase the likelihood of cross-border M&amp;As. In addition, we assess the influence of institutional shareholders' investment horizon and find that while investment horizon have a negative influence in encouraging cross-border M&amp;As, the presence of long-term investors encourages larger M&amp;As. Finally, even after controlling for the 2007-08 financial crisis the market reacts negatively to the announcement of cross-border M&amp;As. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andriosopoulos, Dimitris; Yang, Shuai</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robustness of distance-to-default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jessen, Cathrine; Lando, David
Distance-to-default (DD) is a measure of default risk derived from observed stock prices and book leverage using the structural credit risk model of Merton (1974). Despite the simplifying assumptions that underlie its derivation, DD has proven empirically to be a strong predictor of default. We use simulations to show that the empirical success of DD may well be a result of its strong robustness to model misspecifications. We consider a number of deviations from the Merton model which involve different asset value dynamics and different default triggering mechanisms. We show that, in general, DD is successful in ranking firms' default probabilities, even if the underlying model assumptions are altered. A possibility of large jumps in asset value or stochastic volatility challenge the robustness of DD. We propose a volatility adjustment of the distance-to-default measure that significantly improves the ranking of firms with stochastic volatility, but this measure is less robust to model misspecifications than DD. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jessen, Cathrine; Lando, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The prediction of fund failure through performance diagnostics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cogneau, Philippe; Huebner, Georges
Using an international database featuring 1624 mutual funds over 15 years, this paper analyses the joint abilities of performance measures to predict subsequent fund failure. We examine the probability of disappearance over a time window, and expected fund survival time, and study the circumstances of a fund's disappearance, its currency and domicile. By combining relevant measures, fund failure appears to a significant extent predictable, more than with single classical measures. Survivorship predictability has significant economic value. Such evidence suggests that past performance does not only influence investors' perception of fund quality, but also reflects managers' ability to sustain performance. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cogneau, Philippe; Huebner, Georges</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monitoring the "invisible" hand of market discipline: Capital adequacy revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasan, Iftekhar; Siddique, Akhtar; Sun, Xian
The recent U.S. financial crisis and governmental bailout of financial institutions have intensified the debate on the need for effectively measuring and monitoring the financial institutions' risks. This paper contributes to this discussion by introducing a market-based capital measurement that better captures the dynamics of bank risk and returns. Evidence confirms that these market-based capital adequacy metrics are much more sensitive to risk factors and more responsive to economic events than the traditional accounting/regulatory report based capital models, which often underestimate the true capital needs. The CDS premia, another market-bases solvency measure, seems to overreact to declines in capital adequacy. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hasan, Iftekhar; Siddique, Akhtar; Sun, Xian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of the EU/ECB/IMF bailout programs on the financial and real sectors of the ASE during the Greek sovereign crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kosmidou, Kyriaki V.; Kousenidis, Dimitrios V.; Negakis, Christos I.
Using a broad set of news reports about the Greek sovereign crisis, we tested for the impact of the troika bailout programs on the banking, financial, and real economic sectors of the Athens Stock Exchange (ASE). Our results reveal that the troika's actions caused a shift in the systematic risk of firms in all sectors, suggesting that these actions failed to prevent the financial crisis from turning into a real crisis. The actions of the Greek Government only significantly increased the systematic risk for value banking stocks, most likely because established banking firms in Greece hold large amounts of Greek sovereign debt. We also discuss the implications of our findings. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kosmidou, Kyriaki V.; Kousenidis, Dimitrios V.; Negakis, Christos I.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry characteristics and financial risk contagion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiu, Wan-Chien; Pena, Juan Ignacio; Wang, Chih-Wei
This article proposes a new measure of tail risk spillover: the conditional coexceedance (CCX), defined as the number of joint occurrences of extreme negative returns in an industry, conditional on an extreme negative return in the financial sector. The empirical application provides evidence of significant volatility and tail risk spillovers from the financial sector to many real sectors in the U.S. economy from 2001 to 2011. These spillovers increase in crisis periods. The CCX in a given sector is positively related to its amount of debt financing and negatively related to its valuation and investment. Therefore, real economy sectors which require relatively high debt financing and whose value and investment activity are relatively lower are prime candidates for stock price volatility and depreciation in the wake of a financial sector crisis. Evidence also suggests that the higher the industry's degree of competition, the stronger the tail risk spillover from the financial sector. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chiu, Wan-Chien; Pena, Juan Ignacio; Wang, Chih-Wei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling contagion in the Eurozone crisis via dynamical systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Castellacci, Giuseppe; Choi, Youngna
We recently (Castellacci and Choi, 2013) formulated a theoretical framework for the modeling of financial instability contagion using the theories of dynamical systems. Here, our main goal is to model the Eurozone financial crisis within that framework. The underlying system comprises many economic agents that belong to several subsystems. In each instantiation of this framework, the hierarchy and nesting of the subsystems is dictated by the nature of the problem at hand. We describe in great detail how a suitable model can be set up for the Eurozone crisis. The dynamical system is defined by the evolution of the wealths of the individual agents and can be estimated by solving a nonlinear programming problem that incorporates features of prospect theory. Contagion is formulated in terms of how the market instability indicators for the different subsystems and the global system behave. We present several scenarios tailored to recent financial developments in the Eurozone and discussed within our model. These all point to the key role played by the elasticity coefficients of the wealth dynamical system. Accordingly, we put forward general recommendations on how regulators or other super-systemic agents may act to prevent and forestall the spreading of financial distress. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Castellacci, Giuseppe; Choi, Youngna</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial regulation and systemic risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andriosopoulos, Kostas; Douady, Raphael
nan</description><author>Andriosopoulos, Kostas; Douady, Raphael</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial literacy and the demand for financial advice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calcagno, Riccardo; Monticone, Chiara
The low level of financial literacy across households suggests that they are at risk of making suboptimal financial decisions. In this paper, we analyze the effect of investors' financial literacy on their decision to demand professional, non-independent advice. We find that non-independent advisors are not sufficient to alleviate the problem of low financial literacy. The investors with a low level of financial literacy are less likely to consult an advisor, but they delegate their portfolio choice more often or do not invest in risky assets at all. We explain this evidence with a highly stylized model of strategic interaction between investors and better informed advisors with conflicts of interests. The advisors provide more information to knowledgeable investors, who anticipating this are more likely to consult them. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Calcagno, Riccardo; Monticone, Chiara</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing competition in the banking industry: A multi-product approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barbosa, Klenio; Rocha, Bruno de Paula; Salazar, Fernando
This paper investigates the competitive aspects of multi-product banking operations. Extending Panzar and Rosse's (1987) model to the case of a multi-product banking firm, we show that higher economies of scope in multi-product banking are associated with lower Panzar-Rosse measures of competition in the banking sector. To test this empirical implication and determine the impact of multi-production on market power, we use a new dataset on the Brazilian banking industry. Consistent with our theoretical prediction, we find that banks that offer classic banking products (i.e., loans and credit cards) and other banking products (i.e., brokerage services, insurance and capitalization bonds) have substantially higher market power than banks that offer only classic products. These results suggest a positive bias in the traditional estimates of competition in which multi-output actions are not considered. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barbosa, Klenio; Rocha, Bruno de Paula; Salazar, Fernando</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank ownership and credit over the business cycle: Is lending by state banks less procyclical?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertay, Ata Can; Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Huizinga, Harry
This paper finds that lending by state banks is less procyclical than lending by private banks, especially in countries with good governance. Lending by state banks in high income countries is even countercyclical. On the liability side, state banks expand their total liabilities and, in particular, their non-deposit liabilities relatively little during booms. Public banks also report loan non-performance more evenly over the business cycle. Overall our results suggest that state banks can play a useful role in stabilizing credit over the business cycle as well as during periods of financial instability. However, the track record of state banks in credit allocation remains quite poor, questioning the wisdom of using state banks as a short term countercyclical tool. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bertay, Ata Can; Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Huizinga, Harry</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A macro-financial analysis of the euro area sovereign bond market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dewachter, Hans; Iania, Leonardo; Lyrio, Marco; Perea, Maite de Sola
We estimate the 'fundamental' component of euro area sovereign bond yield spreads, i.e. the part of bond spreads that can be justified by country-specific economic factors, euro area economic fundamentals, and international influences. The yield spread decomposition is achieved using a multi-market, no-arbitrage affine term structure model with a unique pricing kernel. More specifically, we use the canonical representation proposed by Joslin et al. (2011) and introduce next to standard spanned factors a set of unspanned macro factors, as in Joslin et al. (forthcoming). The model is applied to yield curve data from Belgium, France, Germany, Italy, and Spain over the period 2005-2013. Overall, our results show that economic fundamentals are the dominant drivers behind sovereign bond spreads. Nevertheless, shocks unrelated to the fundamental component of the spread have played an important role in the dynamics of bond spreads since the intensification of the sovereign debt crisis in the summer of 2011. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved,</description><author>Dewachter, Hans; Iania, Leonardo; Lyrio, Marco; Perea, Maite de Sola</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic banks and the lender of last resort</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ponce, Jorge; Rennert, Marc
We propose a model where systemic and non-systemic banks are exposed to liquidity shortfalls so that a lender of last resort policy is required. We find that it is socially optimal to override the decision of the central bank by the unconditional provision of liquidity support when the shortfall is large enough, i.e. in crisis times. The existence of systemic banks provides a rationale for the central bank to act as lender of last resort for non-systemic banks in a larger range of their liquidity shortfalls. However, the impact of systemic risk on the optimal allocation of the lender of last resort responsibilities for systemic banks depends on the relative size of counteracting effects. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ponce, Jorge; Rennert, Marc</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk, financial stability and banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tabak, Benjamin Miranda
nan</description><author>Tabak, Benjamin Miranda</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic interaction between markets for leasing and selling automobiles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrikopoulos, Athanasios; Markellos, Raphael N.
We develop a model of dynamic interactions between price variations in leasing and selling markets for automobiles. Our framework assumes a differential game between multiple Bertrand-type competing firms which offer differentiated products to forward-looking agents. Empirical analysis of our model using monthly US data from 2002 to 2011 shows that variations in selling (cash) market prices lead rapidly dissipating changes of leasing market prices in the opposite direction. We discuss the practical implications of these results by augmenting a standard leasing valuation formula. The additional terms represent the leased asset value changes that can be expected on the basis of past variations in automobile selling market prices. (C) 2014 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Andrikopoulos, Athanasios; Markellos, Raphael N.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Privatization, financial development, property rights and growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marcelin, Isaac; Mathur, Ike
This study analyzes how prevailing institutional arrangements i.e., property rights, contracting rights, political institutions, and corporate governance practices affect privatized firms' performance, capital markets development, and economic growth. Most of the studies surveyed show that privatization enhances privatized firms performance, efficiency, and profitability, which percolates to economic growth. Privatized firms performed better in countries with better regulatory and legal frameworks. Partial privatization may be beneficial in countries with weak institutions, namely, the French civil law countries. The stronger the economic and the governing institutions, the easier it is for privatized firms to thrive and contribute to economic growth. Overall, privatization allows firms to achieve improved efficiency while driving the development of the financial sector. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Marcelin, Isaac; Mathur, Ike</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of regulatory credibility in effective bank regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clark, Ephraim; Jokung, Octave
This paper develops a model of regulated Brownian motion with an endogenous profit term to analyze the role of regulatory credibility on the stability and productivity of the banking system. We show that when regulatory intervention is perfect and costless, the volatility of the system can be substantially reduced with no loss of productivity. In fact, perfect credibility can actually reduce the volatility of intrinsically risky banking systems below the volatility of intrinsically less risky systems as banks anticipate intervention and mitigate their investment behaviour accordingly. However, when the credibility of the regime is weakened because of increased uncertainty stemming from regulation, such as random costs or imperfect timing of regulatory intervention, both the stability and productivity of the financial system are impaired. Importantly, we find that in the presence of regulatory costs and imperfect credibility, there is no universal optimal intervention policy rule. The optimal regulatory system depends on the regulator's level of absolute risk aversion. (C) 2014 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Clark, Ephraim; Jokung, Octave</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank regulation, risk and return: Evidence from the credit and sovereign debt crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoque, Hafiz; Andriosopoulos, Dimitris; Andriosopoulos, Kostas; Douady, Raphael
In this paper, we analyze whether regulation reduced risk during the credit crisis and the sovereign debt crisis for a cross section of global banks. In this regard, we examine distance to default (Laeven and Levine, 2008), systemic risk (Acharya et al., 2010), idiosyncratic risk, and systematic risk. We employ World Bank survey data on regulations to test our conjectures. We find that regulatory restrictions, official supervisory power, capital stringency, along with private monitoring can explain bank risk in both crises. Additionally, we find that deposit insurance schemes enhance moral hazard, as this encouraged banks to take on more risk and perform poorly during the sovereign debt crisis. Finally, official supervision and private monitoring explains the returns during both crisis periods. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hoque, Hafiz; Andriosopoulos, Dimitris; Andriosopoulos, Kostas; Douady, Raphael</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reputation, risk-taking, and macroprudential policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aikman, David; Nelson, Benjamin; Tanaka, Misa
This paper examines the role of macroprudential capital requirements in preventing inefficient credit booms in a model with reputational externalities. In our model, unprofitable banks have strong incentives to invest in risky assets when macroeconomic fundamentals are good in order to avoid the stigma of being assessed as low ability by the market. We show that across-the-system countercyclical capital requirements that deter such gambling are constrained optimal when fundamentals are neither extremely weak nor extremely strong. (C) 2014 The Bank of England. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aikman, David; Nelson, Benjamin; Tanaka, Misa</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How likely is contagion in financial networks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glasserman, Paul; Young, B. Peyton
Interconnections among financial institutions create potential channels for contagion and amplification of shocks to the financial system. We estimate the extent to which interconnections increase expected losses and defaults under a wide range of shock distributions. In contrast to most work on financial networks, we assume only minimal information about network structure and rely instead on information about the individual institutions that are the nodes of the network. The key node-level quantities are asset size, leverage, and a financial connectivity measure given by the fraction of a financial institution's liabilities held by other financial institutions. We combine these measures to derive explicit bounds on the potential magnitude of network effects on contagion and loss amplification. Spillover effects are most significant when node sizes are heterogeneous and the originating node is highly leveraged and has high financial connectivity. Our results also highlight the importance of mechanisms that go beyond simple spillover effects to magnify shocks; these include bankruptcy costs, and mark-to-market losses resulting from credit quality deterioration or a loss of confidence. We illustrate the results with data on the European banking system. (C) 2014 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Glasserman, Paul; Young, B. Peyton</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contagious synchronization and endogenous network formation in financial networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aymanns, Christoph; Georg, Co-Pierre
When banks choose similar investment strategies the financial system becomes vulnerable to common shocks. We model a simple financial system in which banks decide about their investment strategy based on a private belief about the state of the world and a social belief formed from observing the actions of peers. Observing a larger group of peers conveys more information and thus leads to a stronger social belief. Extending the standard model of Bayesian updating in social networks, we show that the probability that banks synchronize their investment strategy on a state non-matching action critically depends on the weighting between private and social belief. This effect is alleviated when banks choose their peers endogenously in a network formation process, internalizing the externalities arising from social learning. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aymanns, Christoph; Georg, Co-Pierre</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the use of options by mutual funds: Do they know what they are doing?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cici, Gjergji; Palacios, Luis-Felipe
Given recent regulatory inquiries into the derivative-trading practices of mutual funds, we examine their detailed option holdings to assess how mutual funds employ options, what funds use options, and how that affects performance and risk. Mutual funds' use of options appears consistent with income generation and hedging motives, is systematically related to experience, education, and gender characteristics of portfolio managers, and does not lead to performance benefits, on average. Instead, certain uses of options lead to underperformance. We document no permanent or temporary aggressive risk taking by options users, finding instead that some funds use options to effectively lower risk. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cici, Gjergji; Palacios, Luis-Felipe</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information content of option-implied information for volatility forecasting with investor sentiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Seo, Sung Won; Kim, Jun Sik
This study explores the effect of investor sentiment on the volatility forecasting power of option-implied information. We find that the risk-neutral skewness has the explanatory power regarding future volatility only during high sentiment periods. Furthermore, the implied volatility has varying volatility forecasting ability depending on the level of investor sentiment. Our findings suggest that the effectiveness of volatility forecasting models based on option-implied information varies over time with the level of investor sentiment. We confirm the important role of investor sentiment in volatility forecasting models exploiting option-implied information with strong evidence from in-sample and out-of-sample analyses. We also present improvements in the accuracy of volatility forecasts from volatility forecasting models derived by incorporating investor sentiment in these models. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Seo, Sung Won; Kim, Jun Sik</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>National culture and corporate cash holdings around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yangyang; Dou, Paul Y.; Rhee, S. Ghon; Truong, Cameron; Veeraraghavan, Madhu
This paper examines whether cultural dimensions explain the variation in corporate cash holdings around the world as well as within the United States. We establish four major findings. First, in an international setting, corporate cash holdings are negatively associated with individualism and positively associated with uncertainty-avoidance. Second, individualism and uncertainty avoidance influence the precautionary motive for holding cash. Third, firms in individualistic states in the United States hold less cash than firms in collectivistic states. Fourth, we show that individualism is positively related to the firm's capital expenditures, acquisitions, and repurchases while uncertainty avoidance is negatively related. Our findings remain unchanged after controlling for governance factors, firm attributes, and country characteristics. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Yangyang; Dou, Paul Y.; Rhee, S. Ghon; Truong, Cameron; Veeraraghavan, Madhu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-border banking, bank market structures and market power: Theory and cross-country evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bremus, Franziska M.
Patterns in cross-border banking have changed since the global financial crisis. This may affect domestic bank market structures and macroeconomic stability in the longer term. In this study, I theoretically and empirically analyze how different modes of cross-border banking impact bank concentration and market power. I use a two-country general equilibrium model with heterogeneous banks developed by DeBlas and Russ (2010a) to grasp the effect of cross-border lending and foreign direct investment in the banking sector on bank market structures. The model suggests that both cross-border lending and bank FDI mitigate concentration. Empirical evidence from a panel dataset of 18 OECD countries supports the theoretical predictions: higher volumes or bank FDI and of cross-border lending coincide with lower Herfindahl-indexes in bank credit markets. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bremus, Franziska M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Generalized runs tests to detect randomness in hedge funds returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hentati-Kaffel, Rania; de Peretti, Philippe
The major contribution of this paper is to make use of generalized runs tests (Cho and White, 2011) to analyze the randomness, i.e. the lack of persistence, in both absolute and relative returns of hedge funds. We find that about 42% of the HFR universe exhibit iid absolute returns over the period spanning 2000 to 2012. These funds are mainly found in proportions within the Macro and Equity Hedge strategies. A similar result holds for relative returns. We also find that funds having non-iid returns often exhibit ARCH effects and structural breaks, with largest breaks located within financial crises. Also, only a small percentage displays persistence in their relative performance, 8.2% to 16.7% of the universe, mainly found in proportions within the Relative Value and Event-Driven strategies. The robustness of results is challenged by implementing the tests on a crisis-free period. We find similar results for absolute returns. For relative ones, differences appear across strategies and benchmarks, but still both ARCH and breaks are present. Our work contributes to the hedge fund literature in terms of methodology, portfolio allocation, and performance measurement. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hentati-Kaffel, Rania; de Peretti, Philippe</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Order-to-trade ratios and market liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Friederich, Sylvain; Payne, Richard
We study the impact on market liquidity of the introduction of a penalty for high order-to-trade ratios (OTRs), implemented by the Italian Stock Exchange to curtail high-frequency quote submission. We find that the fee is associated with a collapse in the quoted depth of the stocks that make up the bulk of trading in Italian equities and with an increase in price impacts of trading across the treated stocks. Spreads do not change, however. Stocks from a pan-European control sample show no such liquidity changes. Thus, the Italian OTR fee had the effect of making Italian stocks markets more shallow and less resilient. Large stocks are more severely affected than midcaps. We also find evidence of a limited decrease in turnover. Consolidated liquidity, constructed by aggregating across all electronic trading venues for these stocks, decreases just like that on the main exchange. Thus, liquidity was not simply diverted from the main exchange, it was reduced in aggregate. (C) 2014 Elsevier BAT. All rights reserved.</description><author>Friederich, Sylvain; Payne, Richard</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How corporate governance affect firm value? Evidence on a self-dealing channel from a natural experiment in Korea</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Black, Bernard S.; Kim, Woochan; Jang, Hasung; Park, Kyung-Suh
Prior work in emerging markets provides evidence that better corporate governance predicts higher market value, but very little evidence on the specific channels through which governance can increase value. We provide evidence, from a natural experiment in Korea, that reduced tunneling is an important channel. Korean legal reform in 1999 changed the board structure of "large" firms (assets &gt; 2 trillion won) relative to smaller firms. In event studies of the reform events, we show that large firms whose controllers have incentive to tunnel earn strong positive returns, relative to mid-sized firms. In panel regressions over 1998-2004, we also show that better governance moderates the negative effect of related-party transactions on value and increases the sensitivity of firm profitability to industry profitability (consistent with less tunneling). (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Black, Bernard S.; Kim, Woochan; Jang, Hasung; Park, Kyung-Suh</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wall of cash: The investment-cash flow sensitivity when capital becomes abundant</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andren, Niclas; Jankensgard, Hakan
In the mid 2000s the oil and gas industry was hit by what might be best described as a 'wall of cash' as oil prices successively reached new record levels and access to external financing improved greatly. In this article we investigate what this sudden abundance of liquidity implied for the investment-cash flow relationship, the interpretation of which continues to generate controversy in the literature. For financially constrained firms we find that the investment-cash flow sensitivity decreases in the abundance period (2005-2008), suggesting that the financing constraints became less binding in this period. For financially unconstrained firms the investment-cash flow sensitivity instead increases over time, suggesting that this relationship is driven by agency problems related to free cash flow. Our paper is the first in the investment-cash flow literature to bring evidence from a natural experiment in which there was an unexpected, exogenous, substantial, and persistent decrease in the cost of external financing. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andren, Niclas; Jankensgard, Hakan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing risk in multi-asset class, multimarket central counterparties: The CORE approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vicente, L. A. B. G.; Cerezetti, F. V.; De Faria, S. R.; Iwashita, T.; Pereira, O. R.
Multi-asset class, multimarket central counterparties (CCPs) are becoming less uncommon as a result of merges between specialized (single-asset class, single market) CCPs and market demands for greater capital efficiency. Yet, traditional CCP risk management models often lack the necessary sophistication to estimate potential losses relative to the closeout process of a defaulter's portfolio in a multi-asset class, multimarket environment. As a result, multi-asset class, multimarket CCPs usually rely on a simplified silo approach for risk calculation which not only fails to deliver efficiency, but may also increase systemic risk. The CORE (Closeout Risk Evaluation) approach, on the other hand, provides conceptual and mathematical tools necessary for robust and efficient central counterparty risk evaluation in multi-asset class and multimarket environments, acknowledging the portfolio dynamics involved in the closeout process as well as important "real life" market frictions. (C) 2014 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Vicente, L. A. B. G.; Cerezetti, F. V.; De Faria, S. R.; Iwashita, T.; Pereira, O. R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Costs and benefits of financial regulation: Short-selling bans and transaction taxes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lensberg, Terje; Schenk-Hoppe, Klaus Reiner; Ladley, Dan
We quantify the effects of financial regulation in an equilibrium model with delegated portfolio management. Fund managers trade stocks and bonds in an order-driven market, subject to transaction taxes and constraints on short-selling and leverage. Results are obtained on the equilibrium properties of portfolio choice, trading activity, market quality and price dynamics under the different regulations. We find that these measures are neither as beneficial as some politicians believe nor as damaging as many practitioners fear. (C) 2014 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Lensberg, Terje; Schenk-Hoppe, Klaus Reiner; Ladley, Dan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital adequacy tests and limited liability of financial institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koch-Medina, Pablo; Moreno-Bromberg, Santiago; Munari, Cosimo
The theory of acceptance sets and their associated risk measures plays a key role in the design of capital adequacy tests. The objective of this paper is to investigate the class of surplus-invariant acceptance sets. We argue that surplus invariance is a reasonable requirement from a regulatory perspective, since the corresponding capital adequacy tests do not depend on the surplus of a financial institution, which benefits exclusively its shareholders, but only on the default profile, which affects its liability holders. We provide a detailed analysis of surplus-invariant acceptance sets and their associated risk measures and we discuss the link with loss-based and excess-invariant risk measures, recently studied by Cant et al. (2013) and by Staum (2013), respectively. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koch-Medina, Pablo; Moreno-Bromberg, Santiago; Munari, Cosimo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment-based financing constraints and debt renegotiation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shibata, Takashi; Nishihara, Michi
We consider how equity holders' bargaining power during financial distress influences the interactions between financing and investment decisions when the firm faces the upper limit of debt issuance. We obtain four results. First, weaker equity holders' bargaining power is more likely that the firm is financially constrained. Second, the investment quantity is independent of equity holders' bargaining power. Third, the constrained credit spreads are increasing with equity holders' bargaining power, contrary to the unconstrained ones. Fourth, higher volatility and weaker equity holders' bargaining power are likely that the firm prefers to issue debt with renegotiation, compared with debt without renegotiation. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shibata, Takashi; Nishihara, Michi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of underwriter peer networks in IPOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chuluun, Tuugi
This study examines how various aspects of underwriter peer network affect IPOs. We use different network measures to capture underwriter centrality in the global network, cohesion and diversity within network, and prior industry experience of network partners. Our results show that IPOs underwritten by book managers with more central and cohesive networks and partners with previous industry experience are associated with a higher likelihood of an offer price revision and larger price revisions. We also find book managers with more central networks and partners with previous industry experience are associated with higher short-run stock returns, while book managers that maintain more reciprocated peer relationships tend to underprice more. These results indicate that underwriters use peer networks to produce infotmation and place securities, and network structure and characteristics have implications for the quantity and quality of information and the level of cooperative efforts shared among underwriters. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chuluun, Tuugi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank funding stability, pricing strategies and the guidance of depositors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schlueter, Tobias; Sievers, Soenke; Hartmann-Wendels, Thomas
Banks face a 'behavioralization' of their balance sheets since deposit funding increasingly consists of nonmaturing deposits with uncertain cash flows exposing them to asset liability (ALM) risk. Thus, this study examines the behavior of banks' retail customers regarding non-maturing deposits. Our unique sample comprises the contract and cash flow data for 2.2 million individual contracts from 1991 to 2010. We find that contractual rewards, i.e., qualified interest payments, and government subsidies, effectively stabilize saving behavior and thus bank funding. The probability of an early deposit withdrawal decreases by approximately 40%, and cash flow volatility drops by about 25%. Our findings provide important insights for banks using pricing incentives to steer desired saving patterns for their non-maturing deposit portfolios. Finally, these results are informative regarding the bank liquidity regulations (Basel III) concerning the stability of deposits and the minimum requirements for risk management (European Commission DIRECTIVE 2006/48/EC). (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schlueter, Tobias; Sievers, Soenke; Hartmann-Wendels, Thomas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retail clientele and option returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choy, Siu-Kai
Does the retail clientele matter for option returns? By delta-hedging options and trading straddles, thus allowing a focus on volatility, this paper empirically shows that a higher retail trading proportion (RTP) is related to lower option returns. Long-short portfolios involving options on low and high RTP stocks generate significantly positive abnormal returns. The results suggest that retail investors speculate and pay a lottery premium on the expected future volatility, resulting in more expensive options with higher implied volatilities. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Choy, Siu-Kai</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity, credit quality, and the relation between volatility and trading activity: Evidence from the corporate bond market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Junbo; Wu, Chunchi
This paper investigates the roles of illiquidity and credit risk in determining the relations between price volatility of a bond and its trading frequency and trade size based on a large transaction dataset from October 2004 to June 2012. We find a positive relation between volatility and trading frequency and a negative relation between volatility and trade size. Consistent with the prediction of the search-based theory, the relations are much stronger for illiquid and risky bonds. Furthermore, both liquidity and credit risk become more important in times of stress and their effects are reinforcing. Results strongly suggest that search frictions and credit risk are important factors driving the relation between volatility and trading activity in the corporate bond market. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Junbo; Wu, Chunchi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum is really short-term momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gong, Qiang; Liu, Ming; Liu, Qianqiu
We demonstrate the estimation biases that arise when stock returns from 12 month prior and 2 month prior are included within intermediate and recent past momentum profits. These biases lead to an overestimation of intermediate past momentum but an underestimation of recent past momentum in the US market. There is no significant difference between the predictability of stock performance in the intermediate past and the recent past once we exclude these two months from the construction of momentum strategies in the US and each of the 26 major international markets. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gong, Qiang; Liu, Ming; Liu, Qianqiu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does microfinance change informal lending in village economies? Evidence from Bangladesh</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Islam, Asadul; Nguyen, Chau; Smyth, Russell
This paper examines how availability of microfinance influences households' borrowing from informal sources in village economies. It uses a unique household level panel data set, which spans more than two decades (1987-2008), from rural Bangladesh. We find that households' access to microfinance reduces the incidence of borrowing from informal sources, but not the amount of borrowing. We find that less poor households benefit more in terms of reducing their reliance on informal borrowing and that the benefit accrues over time. We also find that having access to microfinance increases women's informal borrowing for small consumption usage, without facilitating access to new business opportunities. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Islam, Asadul; Nguyen, Chau; Smyth, Russell</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit spreads with dynamic debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Das, Sanjiv R.; Kim, Seoyoung
This paper extends the baseline Merton (1974) structural default model, which is intended for static debt spreads, to a setting with dynamic debt, where leverage can be ratcheted up as well as written down through pre-specified exogenous policies. We provide a different and novel solution approach to dynamic debt than in the extant literature. For many dynamic debt covenants, ex-ante credit spread term structures can be derived in closed-form using modified barrier option mathematics, whereby debt spreads can be expressed using combinations of single barrier options (both knock-in and knock-out), double barrier options, double-touch barrier options, in-out barrier options, and one-touch double barrier binary options. We observe that debt principal swap down covenants decrease the magnitude of credit spreads but increase the slope of the credit curve, transforming downward sloping curves into upward sloping ones. On the other hand, ratchet covenants increase the magnitude of ex-ante spreads without dramatically altering the slope of the credit curve. These covenants may be optimized by appropriately setting restructuring boundaries, which entails a trade-off between the reduction in spreads against restructuring costs. Overall, explicitly modeling this latent option to alter debt leads to term structures of credit spreads that are more consistent with observed empirics. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Das, Sanjiv R.; Kim, Seoyoung</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Convergence of European retail payments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martikainen, Emmi; Schmiedel, Heiko; Takalo, Tuomas
We estimate convergence in the European retail payments market during the period 1995-2011 for the most popular retail payment instruments: cash, debit card, credit card, direct debit, credit transfer, cheque and e-money. To estimate convergence, we employ the concepts of beta and sigma convergence. There is some evidence of convergence for all payment instruments, except for cheques and e-money. The results suggest that the cross-country dispersion of the use of payment instruments has declined over time in Europe, and the pace of convergence has picked up since the introduction of the single currency. We also find evidence for beta convergence for card payments, direct debits and credit transfers. The results indicate that convergence in European retail payments has progressed despite the financial crisis. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Martikainen, Emmi; Schmiedel, Heiko; Takalo, Tuomas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-border LBOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Jerry X.; Cumming, Douglas; Qian, Meijun; Wang, Xiaoming
We examine cross-border private equity (PE) sponsored leveraged buyout (LBO) transactions in 43 countries in relation to creditor rights and other legal and institutional variables. Cross-border LBO investment is more common from strong creditor rights countries to weak creditor rights countries. Club deals are less common in countries with stronger creditor rights, and less common in cross-border LBOs. Premiums are lower in countries with stronger creditor rights, and among cross-border deals. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cao, Jerry X.; Cumming, Douglas; Qian, Meijun; Wang, Xiaoming</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multinational banks in the crisis: Foreign affiliate lending as a mirror of funding pressure and competition on the internal capital market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frey, Rainer; Kerl, Cornelia
We investigate how the lending activities abroad of a multinational bank's local and hub affiliates have been affected by funding difficulties during the financial crisis. We find that affiliates' local deposits and performance have been stabilizing loan supply. By contrast, relying on short-term wholesale funding has increasingly proven to be a disadvantage in the crisis, which has seen inter-bank and capital markets freeze. By introducing a liable approximate measure for intra-bank flows, we detect competition for intra-bank funding between the affiliates abroad as well as an increasing focus on the parent bank's home market activities. In addition, the more an affiliate abroad relies on intra-bank funding in the crisis, the greater its dependence on its parent bank having a stable deposit and long-term wholesale funding position. We consider changes in long-term lending to the private sectors of 40 countries by the affiliates of the 68 largest German banks. To obtain a more precise picture, we clean our lending data from valuation effects. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frey, Rainer; Kerl, Cornelia</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identifying, valuing and hedging of embedded options in non-maturity deposits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blochlinger, Andreas
Non-maturity deposits like savings accounts or demand deposits contain significant option risks caused by the bank's discretionary pricing and the customers' withdrawal right. Option risks follow from inherent non-linear factor exposures. I propose an ordinal response model for deposit rate jumps to identify non-linear factor exposures and a discrete-time term structure model to value the resulting option risks and to derive hedge measures "outside the model". My delta profile resembles a constant maturity swap, but vega and gamma are more pronounced, which demonstrates that the widespread practice of static hedging with zero bonds is inadequate. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blochlinger, Andreas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of life insurance in an emerging economy: Human capital protection, assets allocation and social interaction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shi, Xiaojun; Wang, Hung-Jen; Xing, Chunbing
In this paper, we provide micro-econometric evidence on the determinants of life insurance demand in China, the largest emerging market in the world. We employ the China Household Income Project (CHIP) dataset for the year 2002 in the analysis. The timing is ideal, because of the nature of the less well developed capital markets and social security systems in China in 2002, which sets a suitable stage to study the insurance demand behavior of emerging markets. The results indicate that both the human capital protection motive and the asset allocation motive are important in explaining the purchase of life insurance in China. In addition, we present three empirical regularities: (1) the positive correlation between the returns to human capital and the returns to market portfolio decrease the demand for life insurance; (2) both the current wealth and future income of a household exert curvilinear impacts on life insurance demand; (3) the breadth of a households social connections has substantial impacts on life insurance demand. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shi, Xiaojun; Wang, Hung-Jen; Xing, Chunbing</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring the liquidity part of volume</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Darolles, Serge; Le Fol, Gaelle; Mero, Gulten
Based on the concept that the presence of liquidity frictions can increase the daily traded volume, we develop an extended version of the mixture of distribution hypothesis model (MDH) along the lines of Tauchen and Pitts (1983) to measure the liquidity portion of volume. Our approach relies on a structural definition of liquidity frictions arising from the theoretical framework of Grossman and Miller (1988), which explains how liquidity shocks affect the way in which information is incorporated into daily trading characteristics. In addition, we propose an econometric setup exploiting the volatility-volume relationship to filter the liquidity portion of volume and infer the presence of liquidity frictions using daily data. Finally, based on FTSE 100 stocks, we show that the extended MDH model proposed here outperforms that of Andersen (1996) and that the liquidity frictions are priced in the cross-section of stock returns. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Darolles, Serge; Le Fol, Gaelle; Mero, Gulten</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Large shocks in the volatility of the Dow Jones Industrial Average index: 1928-2013</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Charles, Amelie; Darne, Olivier
We determine the events that cause large shocks in volatility of the DJIA index over the period 1928-2013, using a new semi-parametric test based on conditional heteroscedasticity models. We find that these large shocks can be associated with particular events (financial crashes, elections, wars, monetary policies, etc.). We show that some shocks are not identified as extraordinary movements by the investors due to their occurring during high volatility episodes, especially the 1929-1934, 1937-1938 and 2007-2011 periods. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Charles, Amelie; Darne, Olivier</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating and using GARCH models with VIX data for option valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kanniainen, Juho; Lin, Binghuan; Yang, Hanxue
This paper uses information on VIX to improve the empirical performance of GARCH models for pricing options on the S&amp;P 500. In pricing multiple cross-sections of options, the models' performance can clearly be improved by extracting daily spot volatilities from the series of VIX rather than by linking spot volatility with different dates by using the series of the underlying's returns. Moreover, in contrast to traditional returns-based Maximum Likelihood Estimation (MLE), a joint MLE with returns and VIX improves option pricing performance, and for NGARCH, joint MLE can yield empirically almost the same out-of-sample option pricing performance as direct calibration does to in-sample options, but without costly computations. Finally, consistently with the existing research, this paper finds that non-affine models clearly outperform affine models. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved,</description><author>Kanniainen, Juho; Lin, Binghuan; Yang, Hanxue</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance evaluation of optimized portfolio insurance strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zieling, Daniel; Mahayni, Antje; Balder, Sven
We use S&amp;P 500 index return data for the time period 1985-2013 to evaluate the performance of portfolio insurance strategies. We shed light on the question if the performance of a constant proportion portfolio insurance (CPPI) strategy can be improved by means of a time-varying multiplier which depends on the estimated future volatility. Neglecting any inter-temporal hedging demand, the theoretical foundation of the strategies is given by maximizing the expected utility of a HARA investor in a diffusion model setup. If the risk premium is assumed to be proportional to the variance, the optimal strategy is a CPPI strategy. Otherwise, the multiple is time-varying (PPI). It turns out that even time-varying multiple strategies based on a rolling window of historical volatility estimates give a significant improvement of CPPI strategies. The out-performance is robust w.r.t. alternative performance measures and is also true for proportional transaction costs and adequate trigger trading. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zieling, Daniel; Mahayni, Antje; Balder, Sven</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The sources of shareholder wealth gains from going private transactions: The role of controlling shareholders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boubaker, Sabri; Cellier, Alexis; Rouatbi, Wael
The present study investigates the sources of shareholder wealth gains - as measured by cumulative abnormal returns and premiums - from going private transactions (GPTs). Using data for 314 GPTs from 18 Western European countries, we find that the announcements of GPTs generate a cumulative average abnormal return of about 22% and that pre-transaction shareholders on average receive a raw premium of about 36%. We further find that these shareholder wealth gains increase with the degree of separation of cash-flow and control rights of the pre-transaction ultimate owner and decrease with its ownership interests and with the presence of a second large shareholder. Taken together, these findings support the view that GPTs are expected to mitigate the inefficiencies induced by pre-transaction agency problems between controlling and minority shareholders. Thus, shareholder wealth gains from GPTs reflect the potential additional value that will be created under private ownership. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boubaker, Sabri; Cellier, Alexis; Rouatbi, Wael</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate social responsibility and stock price crash risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Yongtae; Li, Haidan; Li, Siqi
This study investigates whether corporate social responsibility (CSR) mitigates or contributes to stock price crash risk. Crash risk, defined as the conditional skewness of return distribution, captures asymmetry in risk and is important for investment decisions and risk management. If socially responsible firms commit to a high standard of transparency and engage in less bad news hoarding, they would have lower crash risk. However, if managers engage in CSR to cover up bad news and divert shareholder scrutiny, CSR would be associated with higher crash risk. Our findings support the mitigating effect of CSR on crash risk. We find that firms' CSR performance is negatively associated with future crash risk after controlling for other predictors of crash risk. The result holds after we account for potential endogeneity. Moreover, the mitigating effect of CSR on crash risk is more pronounced when firms have less effective corporate governance or a lower level of institutional ownership. The results are consistent with the notion that firms that actively engage in CSR also refrain from bad news hoarding behavior, thus reducing crash risk. This role of CSR is particularly important when governance mechanisms, such as monitoring by boards or institutional investors, are weak. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Yongtae; Li, Haidan; Li, Siqi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of enterprise risk management on the marginal cost of reducing risk: Evidence from the insurance industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eckles, David L.; Hoyt, Robert E.; Miller, Steve M.
We test the hypothesis that practicing enterprise risk management (ERM) reduces firms' cost of reducing risk. Adoption of ERM represents a radical paradigm shift from the traditional method of managing risks individually to managing risks collectively allowing ERM-adopting firms to better recognize natural hedges, prioritize hedging activities towards the risks that contribute most to the total risk of the firm, and optimize the evaluation and selection of available hedging instruments. We hypothesize that these advantages allow ERM-adopting firms to produce greater risk reduction per dollar spent. Our hypothesis further predicts that, after implementing ERM, firms experience profit maximizing incentives to lower risk. Consistent with this hypothesis, we find that firms adopting ERM experience a reduction in stock return volatility. We also find that the reduction in return volatility for ERM-adopting firms becomes stronger over time. Further, we find that operating profits per unit of risk (ROA/retum volatility) increase post ERM adoption. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eckles, David L.; Hoyt, Robert E.; Miller, Steve M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discrete stochastic autoregressive volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cordis, Adriana S.; Kirby, Chris
We use Markov chain methods to develop a flexible class of discrete stochastic autoregressive volatility (DSARV) models. Our approach to formulating the models is straightforward, and readily accommodates features such as volatility asymmetry and time-varying volatility persistence. Moreover, it produces models with a low-dimensional state space, which greatly enhances computational tractability. We illustrate the proposed methodology for both individual stock and stock index returns, and show that simple first- and second-order DSARV models outperform generalized autoregressive conditional heteroscedasticity and Markov-switching multifractal models in forecasting volatility. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cordis, Adriana S.; Kirby, Chris</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information content of option ratios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blau, Benjamin M.; Nguyen, Nga; Whitby, Ryan J.
A broad stream of research shows that information flows into underlying stock prices through the options market. For instance, prior research shows that both the Put-Call Ratio (P/C) and the Option-to-Stock Volume Ratio (O/S) predict negative future stock returns. In this paper, we compare the level of information contained in these two commonly used option volume ratios. First, we find that P/C ratios contain more predictability about future stock returns at the daily level than O/S ratios. Second, in contrast to our first set of results, O/S ratios contain more predictability about future returns at the weekly and monthly levels than P/C ratios. In fact, our tests show that while P/C ratios contain predictability about future daily returns and, to some extent, future weekly returns, the return predictability in P/C ratios is fleeting. O/S ratios, on the other hand, significantly predict negative returns at all levels: daily, weekly, and monthly. While Pan and Poteshman (2006) show that signed P/C ratios, which require proprietary data, have predictive power, we find that unsigned P/C ratios, which do not require proprietary data, also have predictive power. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blau, Benjamin M.; Nguyen, Nga; Whitby, Ryan J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-varying, heterogeneous risk aversion and dynamics of asset prices among boundedly rational agents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Park, Beum-Jo
Besides the heterogeneity of agents' beliefs, we perceive that, contrary to the constant short-term risk attitude of fundamentalists, the risk attitude for chartists varies over time due to psychological factors such as prospect theory's reflection effect, which refers to the reversing of risk aversion/risk loving in the case of gains/losses. Thus, this paper assumes that complicated dynamics in recent asset markets are attributed to the significant effects of time-varying and heterogeneous risk attitudes as well as agents' herd behavior, and generalizes an adaptive beliefs system in order to characterize them. This paper also analyzes the existence of stable steady states of the generalized adaptive beliefs system, providing a new psychological insight into excessive and asymmetric volatility. Given the dynamic system, numerical simulations find that, when the chartists are less risk averse than the fundamentalists and their herding propensity increases, time variation in risk attitudes gives rise to large amplitude changes in proportion to agent groups and expand price fluctuations through chaotic dynamics. Along these lines, this paper highlights that psychological factors serve as decisive source of asymmetry in volatility as well as excess volatility, which are observed in the return data. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Park, Beum-Jo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quality of PIN estimates and the PIN-return relationship</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yan, Yuxing; Zhang, Shaojun
This paper provides new evidence concerning the probability of informed trading (PIN) and the PIN-return relationship. We take measures to overcome known estimation biases and improve the quality of quarterly PIN estimates. We use the average of a firm's PIN estimates in four consecutive quarters to smooth out the effect of seasonal variation in trading activities. We find that when high-quality PIN estimates are used, the firm's Fama-MacBeth cross-sectional regressions show stronger evidence for the positive PIN-return relationship than documented in the prior literature. This finding is robust to controls for the January, liquidity, and momentum effects. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yan, Yuxing; Zhang, Shaojun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A jackknife-type estimator for portfolio revision</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fuess, Roland; Miebs, Felix; Truebenbach, Fabian
This article proposes a novel approach to portfolio revision. The current literature on portfolio optimization uses a somewhat naive approach, where portfolio weights are always completely revised after a predefined fixed period. However, one shortcoming of this procedure is that it ignores parameter uncertainty in the estimated portfolio weights, as well as the biasedness of the in-sample portfolio mean and variance as estimates of the expected portfolio return and out-of-sample variance. To rectify this problem, we propose a jackknife procedure to determine the optimal revision intensity, i.e. the percent of wealth that should be shifted to the new, in-sample optimal portfolio. We find that our approach leads to highly stable portfolio allocations over time, and can significantly reduce the turnover of several well established portfolio strategies. Moreover, the observed turnover reductions lead to statistically and economically significant performance gains in the presence of transaction costs. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fuess, Roland; Miebs, Felix; Truebenbach, Fabian</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do leveraged exchange-traded products deliver their stated multiples?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loviscek, Anthony; Tang, Hongfei; Xu, Xiaoqing Eleanor
Using the longest history of a U.S. equity market index, this paper simulates the return deviation and multiple deviation for Leveraged Exchange-Traded Products (LETPs) with different rebalancing frequencies, including daily, monthly, annually, and every five years, over various holding periods. We find that the general perception that daily-rebalanced LETPs are not suitable for long-term strategies is not substantiated. Advancing the analysis, we construct a comprehensive framework that determines the deviation of an LETP's effective multiple from its stated product multiple under various rebalancing frequencies and holding period scenarios. The empirical framework and results from this paper hold the promise of guiding regulators, policy makers, and investors in their understanding of the tracking performance of LETPs. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Loviscek, Anthony; Tang, Hongfei; Xu, Xiaoqing Eleanor</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does information sharing reduce the role of collateral as a screening device?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karapetyan, Artashes; Stacescu, Bogdan
Information sharing and collateral are both devices that help banks reduce the cost of adverse selection. We examine whether they are likely to be used as substitutes (information sharing reduces the need for collateral) or complements. We show that information sharing via a credit bureaus and registers may increase, rather than decrease, the role of collateral: it can be required in loans to high-risk borrowers in cases when it is not in the absence of information sharing. Higher adverse selection makes the use of collateral more likely both with and without information sharing. Our results are in line with recent empirical evidence. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Karapetyan, Artashes; Stacescu, Bogdan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance of international and global equity mutual funds: Do country momentum and sector momentum matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breloer, Bernhard; Scholz, Hendrik; Wilkens, Marco
This is the first paper analyzing the impact of index momentum factors on the performance of international and global equity funds. Extending an international, index-based version of the Fama and French (1993) three-factor model by adding the factors of country momentum and sector momentum, we find that more than 50% of funds exhibit significant exposure to at least one of these factors. Including both new factors in performance evaluation clearly impacts results when analyzing (i) the risk-adjusted performance, (ii) the performance persistence of funds, and (iii) luck versus skill in the cross-section of funds. Our main results are robust against models which additionally cover a stock-based momentum factor as well as single country, regional and sector factors. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Breloer, Bernhard; Scholz, Hendrik; Wilkens, Marco</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of corporate bailout on firm performance: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Zhan; Kim, Kenneth A.; Zhang, Hao
Not all corporate bailouts are the same. We study corporate bailouts from around the world during 1987-2005. Among these bailed-out firms, some firms are economically distressed while others are financially distressed. Some firms are bailed out with cash (either as equity or as loans) while others are bailed out with debt relief. Some firms are bailed out by the government while others are bailed out by other stakeholders. We examine these firms' operating performance before and after their bailouts, but specifically across different bailout types, and we also measure their stock returns surrounding their bailout announcements. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, Zhan; Kim, Kenneth A.; Zhang, Hao</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign exchange exposure and multinationality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hutson, Elaine; Laing, Elaine
We examine the relation between firms' foreign exchange exposure and the extent of their multinationality as a proxy for operational hedging. Using a sample of 953 US firms over the period 1999-2006, we show that there is a nonlinear relation between operational and financial hedging, confirming anecdotal evidence that many highly multinational firms do not hedge with derivatives. We find that operational hedging and financial hedging are significantly inversely related to firms' foreign exchange exposure, providing evidence that the two hedging techniques are complementary for all but the most highly operationally hedged firms. By comparing our findings for 1999-2006 with 1999-2009, we show that this complementarity breaks down when exchange rate volatility is high - as the effectiveness of financial hedging diminishes. An important message for firms is that operational hedges work, and they potentially provide better protection than financial hedging during times of stress. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hutson, Elaine; Laing, Elaine</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Large versus small foreign exchange interventions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fatum, Rasmus; Yamamoto, Yohei
We use non-temporal threshold analysis to investigate the exchange rate effects of large versus small interventions. More than two decades of official daily data on intervention in the JPY/USD market facilitate our analysis. We find no evidence that small interventions exert a discernible influence on the exchange rate while large interventions significantly influence the exchange rate in the theoretically consistent manner. We conclude that small interventions may not be considered a determinant of the exchange rate while large interventions constitute an important element in our understanding, and modeling, of the exchange rate. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fatum, Rasmus; Yamamoto, Yohei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect on competition of banking sector consolidation following the financial crisis of 2008</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perez Montes, Carlos
Consolidation of the Spanish banking sector after the financial crisis of 2008 raises concerns about potential negative effects on competition. I use structural econometric methods to examine these anti-competitive concerns in the Spanish mortgage market. I estimate a mixed-logit model of mortgage demand and recover bank-level cost information with a strategic model of price competition. Counterfactual experiments reveal that the observed increase in concentration is associated only with small variations in mortgage rates and market shares, staying far from collusive levels. This moderate change in industry conduct implies a small direct effect of consolidation on bank exposures to mortgage risk. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Perez Montes, Carlos</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign exchange risk and the predictability of carry trade returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cenedese, Gino; Sarno, Lucio; Tsiakas, Ilias
This paper provides an empirical investigation of the time-series predictive ability of foreign exchange risk measures on the return to the carry trade, a popular investment strategy that borrows in low-interest currencies and lends in high-interest currencies. Using quantile regressions, we find that higher market variance is significantly related to large future carry trade losses, which is consistent with the unwinding of the carry trade in times of high volatility. The decomposition of market variance into average variance and average correlation shows that the predictive power of market variance is primarily due to average variance since average correlation is not significantly related to carry trade returns. Finally, a new version of the carry trade that conditions on market variance generates performance gains net of transaction costs. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cenedese, Gino; Sarno, Lucio; Tsiakas, Ilias</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-term US infrastructure returns and portfolio selection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bianchi, Robert J.; Bornholt, Graham; Drew, Michael E.; Howard, Michael F.
Our understanding of the long-term return behavior and portfolio characteristics of public infrastructure investments is limited by a relatively short history of empirical data. We re-construct U.S. listed infrastructure index returns by mapping their monthly performance to received systematic and industry risk factors from 1927 through 2010. Our findings reveal that the infrastructure returns in recent years may understate the tail-risk that investors could experience over the long-term, however, this tail-risk is commensurate with holding a broad portfolio of U.S. stocks. For mean-variance and mean-CVaR investors, we report the benefits of holding public infrastructure assets in investment portfolios. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bianchi, Robert J.; Bornholt, Graham; Drew, Michael E.; Howard, Michael F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Close form pricing formulas for Coupon Cancellable CoCos</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Manuel Corcuera, Jose; De Spiegeleer, Jan; Fajardo, Jose; Jonsson, Henrik; Schoutens, Wim; Valdivia, Arturo
Contingent Convertibles ("CoCos") are contingent capital instruments which convert into shares, or have a principal write down, if a trigger event takes place. CoCos exhibit the undesirable so-called death-spiral effect: by actively hedging the equity risk, investors can (unintentionally) force the conversion by making the share price deteriorate and eventually trigger the conversion. In this paper we introduce and analyse Coupon Cancellable CoCos ("CoCa CoCos"), a new type of CoCo where coupons can be cancelled during the lifetime of the note. We provide closed-form pricing formulas for CoCa CoCos, we study the impact of coupon cancellations in the price of the bond and we show that death-spiral effect is reduced. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Manuel Corcuera, Jose; De Spiegeleer, Jan; Fajardo, Jose; Jonsson, Henrik; Schoutens, Wim; Valdivia, Arturo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of mandatory convertibles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Nandy, Debarshi; Yan, An; Jiao, Jie
The objective of this paper is to develop a theoretical analysis of "mandatory convertibles," which are securities that automatically ("mandatorily") convert to common stock on a pre-specified date. We consider a firm facing a financial market characterized by asymmetric information and significant costs in the event of financial distress. The firm can raise capital either by issuing mandatory convertibles, or by issuing more conventional securities like straight debt, ordinary convertibles, or equity. We show that, in equilibrium, the firm issues straight debt or ordinary convertibles if the extent of asymmetric information facing it is large, but the probability of being in financial distress is relatively small; it issues mandatory convertibles if it faces a smaller extent of asymmetric information but a greater probability of financial distress. Our model provides a rationale for the three commonly observed features of mandatory convertibles: mandatory conversion, capped (or limited) capital appreciation, and a higher dividend yield compared to common stock. We also characterize the equilibrium design of mandatory convertibles. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Nandy, Debarshi; Yan, An; Jiao, Jie</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Differentiated use of small business credit scoring by relationship lenders and transactional lenders: Evidence from firm-bank matched data in Japan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ono, Arito; Hasumi, Ryo; Hirata, Hideaki
This paper examines the ex-post performance of small and medium enterprises (SMEs) that obtained small business credit scoring (SBCS) loans, using a unique Japanese firm-bank matched dataset. The ex-post probability of default after the SBCS loan was provided significantly increased for SMEs that obtained an SBCS loan from a transactional lender. Also, the lending attitude of relationship lenders during the recent global financial crisis was more severe if a firm had received an SECS loan from a transactional lender. These findings suggest that SBCS loans by transactional lenders are more prone to type II errors and detrimental to relationship lenders' incentive to provide "liquidity insurance." (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ono, Arito; Hasumi, Ryo; Hirata, Hideaki</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economic consequences of regulatory changes in employee stock options on corporate bond holders: SFAS No.123R and structural credit model perspectives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Tsung-Kang; Liao, Hsien-Hsing; Chi, Cheng-Ming
Based upon structural credit models, we investigate the changes of the effects of employee stock options (ESOs) on bond yield spreads due to the revision of SFAS No. 123R (No.123R) which requires expensing ESO amounts. Using American bond observations from year 1995 to 2007, we find that the revision decreases the information benefits of ESOs disclosure. When controlling for credit ratings and potential endogeneity problems, we also find that ESOs are significantly and positively related to bond yield spreads in post-No.123R period while have an opposite effect in pre-No.123R period. We conclude that information effect mainly drives the ESO's effects on credit risk in both pre- and post-No.123R periods. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Tsung-Kang; Liao, Hsien-Hsing; Chi, Cheng-Ming</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The MAX effect: European evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Walkshaeusl, Christian
The maximum daily return over the previous month (MAX) of Bali et al. (2011) is a strong and significant predictor of future stock returns in non-U.S. equity markets. Once it is controlled for MAX in the cross-section of average returns, the puzzling negative idiosyncratic volatility-return relation disappears. Consistent with the assumption that MAX is the true effect, for which idiosyncratic volatility is just a proxy, we find that MAX can be traced back to firm fundamentals in the manner of idiosyncratic volatility. The negative MAX-return relation is stronger among firms with high cash flow volatility and weaker among firms with high profitability. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Walkshaeusl, Christian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of derivatives hedging on the stock market: Evidence from Taiwan's covered warrants market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, San-Lin; Liu, Wen-Rang; Tsai, Wei-Che
We examine the impact of derivatives hedging on the spot market using accurate hedge ratios of covered warrants traded in the Taiwan Stock Exchange (TWSE). Results present significant positive abnormal returns and trading volumes before the announcement of a warrant's issuance, and the effect is stronger when the hedging demand is larger. Moreover, a significantly positive relationship exists between stock return volatility and the price elasticity of hedging demand. Finally, we observe a significantly negative price effect upon the underlying stock after a call warrant has expired in-the-money due to the liquidation of hedging portfolios. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, San-Lin; Liu, Wen-Rang; Tsai, Wei-Che</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor sentiment and return predictability of disagreement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Jun Sik; Ryu, Doojin; Seo, Sung Won
This study examines the influence of investor sentiment on the relationship between disagreement among investors and future stock market returns. We find that the relationship between disagreement and future stock market returns time-varies with the degree of investor sentiment. Higher disagreement among investors' opinions predicts significantly lower future stock market returns during high-sentiment periods, but it has no significant effect on future stock market returns during low-sentiment periods. Our findings imply that investor sentiment is related to several causes of short-sale impediments suggested in the previous literature on investor sentiment, and that the stock return predictability of disagreement is driven by investor sentiment. We demonstrate that investor sentiment has a significant impact on the stock market return predictability of disagreement through in-sample and out-of-sample analyses. In addition, the profitability of our suggested trading strategy exploiting disagreement and investor sentiment level confirms the economic significance of incorporating investor sentiment into the relationship between disagreement among investors and future stock market returns. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Jun Sik; Ryu, Doojin; Seo, Sung Won</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The behavioral foundations of corporate dividend policy a cross-country analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breuer, Wolfgang; Rieger, M. Oliver; Soypak, K. Can
We study a model that relates dividend payout policy to behavioral issues based on the ideas of mental accounting. A panel analysis across 29 countries and over 43,000 firm-years demonstrates that our model studying the relation between dividends and patience, loss aversion, and ambiguity aversion can be verified empirically. Our paper seems to be the first that highlights empirically in a straightforward way the relevance of behavioral patterns as important determinants for corporate dividend policy, while previous empirical studies could tackle this issue only indirectly. With several robustness tests we also address potential doubts concerning the quality of our data and analyze further implications of our theory. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Breuer, Wolfgang; Rieger, M. Oliver; Soypak, K. Can</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limited attention, share repurchases, and takeover risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Ji-Chai; Stephens, Clifford P.; Wu, YiLin
We hypothesize that announcing open market share repurchases (OMRs) to counter negative valuation shocks reveals repurchasing firms' lost growth opportunities or underperforming assets to potential bidders, making them more likely to become takeover targets. This also leads their investors to face higher takeover risk, a systematic risk associated with economic fundamentals that drive takeover waves, as proposed by Cremers et al. (2009). Indeed, we find that repurchasing firms tend to face higher takeover probability in the first few years following their OMR announcements, and that the increase in takeover risk can largely explain their post-announcement long-run abnormal returns documented in the literature. The increase in takeover risk is larger for smaller firms, firms with poorer pre-announcement stock performance, and those attracting more attention of market participants. Our results suggest that OMRs, which are used by many firms to counter undervaluation, could make the firms more sensitive to takeover waves and raise their cost of equity capital. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lin, Ji-Chai; Stephens, Clifford P.; Wu, YiLin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are unsolicited ratings biased? Evidence from long-run stock performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Byoun, Soku; Fulkerson, Jon A.; Han, Seung Hun; Shin, Yoon S.
We test the biasedness of unsolicited ratings relative to solicited ratings using the ex post firm performance measured by the long-run stock performance of firms following rating announcements and changes. We find that the announcements of new unsolicited ratings are followed by negative long-run stock performance, while those of new solicited ratings are followed by insignificant long-run stock performance. These results are inconsistent with the conservatism hypothesis that suggests that unsolicited ratings are downward biased. We further demonstrate that firms with solicited upgraded (downgraded) ratings experience subsequent positive (negative) abnormal stock performance, while those with unsolicited rating changes have zero abnormal stock performance. The differential stock performance following rating changes between solicited and unsolicited ratings reflect the differential information carried by each type of rating rather than the biasedness in ratings. Specifically, while solicited ratings are based on both public and private information, unsolicited ratings are mainly based on public information. Overall, we find no evidence for a downward bias in unsolicited ratings. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Byoun, Soku; Fulkerson, Jon A.; Han, Seung Hun; Shin, Yoon S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should I stay or should I go? Bank productivity and internationalization decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buch, Claudia M.; Koch, Catherine T.; Koetter, Michael
Differences in firm-level productivity explain international activities of non-financial firms quite well. We test whether differences in bank productivity determine international activities of banks. Based on a dataset that allows tracking banks across countries and across different modes of foreign entry, we model the ordered probability of maintaining a commercial presence abroad and the volume of banks' international assets empirically. Our research has three main findings. First, more productive banks are more likely to enter foreign markets in increasingly complex modes. Second, more productive banks also hold larger volumes of foreign assets. Third, higher risk aversion renders entry less likely, but it increases the volume of foreign activities conditional upon entry. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buch, Claudia M.; Koch, Catherine T.; Koetter, Michael</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The financial crisis and bank-client relationships: Foreign ownership, transparency, and portfolio selection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pennathur, Anita; Vishwasrao, Sharmila
Using a unique dataset that matches banks with their client firms, we investigate the differences between foreign and domestic banks in a developing country. In particular, we are interested in examining how foreign banks solve the information asymmetries that characterize lending relationships and whether those relationships have changed since the financial crisis of 2008. Foreign banks are likely to limit their lending activity to larger firms or more transparent firms because they are at an informational disadvantage relative to domestic banks. We find that foreign banks focus on relationships with foreign, listed, and larger firms. In addition, their portfolio is more heavily weighted towards firms in less competitive industries and exporting firms. Comparing outcomes for 2006 and 2009, we find that banks are more concerned with leverage in 2009 and have reduced the number of firms in their portfolio post-crisis. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pennathur, Anita; Vishwasrao, Sharmila</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>SEC enforcement in the PIPE market: Actions and consequences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bengtsson, Ola; Dai, Na; Henson, Clifford
In 2002, the SEC launched enforcement actions against investors involved in PIPE (Private Investments in Public Equity) transactions. We describe the legal ramifications of this enforcement initiative, and document dramatic contemporaneous market-wide changes in the contractual structure of PIPEs. PIPEs in the post-action period included fewer aggressive repricing rights and more trading restrictions. However, PIPEs in the post-action period also included more investor protections and fewer issuer rights. These results suggest that the SEC's enforcement enticed investors to substitute non-SEC-targeted contractual features for targeted ones. Our paper sheds new light on the role of legal enforcement on financial contract design. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Bengtsson, Ola; Dai, Na; Henson, Clifford</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leverage-induced systemic risk under Basle II and other credit risk policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Poledna, Sebastian; Thurner, Stefan; Farmer, J. Doyne; Geanakoplos, John
We use a simple agent based model of value investors in financial markets to test three credit regulation policies. The first is the unregulated case, which only imposes limits on maximum leverage. The second is Basle II and the third is a hypothetical alternative in which banks perfectly hedge all of their leverage-induced risk with options. When compared to the unregulated case both Basle II and the perfect hedge policy reduce the risk of default when leverage is low but increase it when leverage is high. This is because both regulation policies increase the amount of synchronized buying and selling needed to achieve deleveraging, which can destabilize the market. None of these policies are optimal for everyone: risk neutral investors prefer the unregulated case with low maximum leverage, banks prefer the perfect hedge policy, and fund managers prefer the unregulated case with high maximum leverage. No one prefers Basle II. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Poledna, Sebastian; Thurner, Stefan; Farmer, J. Doyne; Geanakoplos, John</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Human capital, household capital and asset returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ren, Yu; Yuan, Yufei; Zhang, Yang
Sousa (2010a) shows that the residuals from the common trend among consumption, financial wealth, housing wealth and human capital, cday, can predict quarterly stock market returns better than cay from Lettau and Ludvigson (2001), which considers aggregate wealth instead. In this paper, we use a more appropriate proxy of human capital, which alleviates the potential correlation between the residuals and the regressors and makes the estimation more precise. In addition, we extend housing wealth to household capital by taking durable goods into consideration. The new predictor is proposed accordingly. Empirically, we find that our predictor is superior to the other alternatives. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ren, Yu; Yuan, Yufei; Zhang, Yang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do target CEOs trade premiums for personal benefits?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qiu, Buhui; Trapkov, Svetoslav; Yakoub, Fadi
Using a sample of 2198 completed M&amp;A transactions between 1994 and 2010 in which both target and acquirer are public US firms supplemented with hand-collected data for target CEO retention, we uncover a significantly negative relation between target CEO retention and takeover premiums received by target shareholders. Further, when the target CEO was not retained, we document a significantly negative relation between the relative importance of the severance pay received by the target CEO and takeover premium. Taken together, our findings, which hold in various robustness tests, suggest that target CEOs bargain shareholder value for personal benefits during corporate takeovers. Our findings have important policy implications for takeover disclosures. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Qiu, Buhui; Trapkov, Svetoslav; Yakoub, Fadi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value of strategic alliances: Evidence from the bond market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chou, Ting-Kai; Ou, Chin-Shyh; Tsai, Shu-Huan
The objective of this study is to examine the relationship between strategic alliances and the cost of debt, proxied by the at-issue yield spread of bond offerings. We hypothesize that the participation of strategic alliances lowers a firm's cost of debt because it improves the level and stability of future profit streams and reduces information asymmetry among investors. Based on 2150 bond-issuing firms during the period 1985-2009, we find evidence consistent with this argument. Furthermore, we find that the mitigating effect of strategic alliances on the debt cost is much more pronounced for firms with higher product market competition, more severe financial constraints, and greater R&amp;D investments. Taken together, this is the first paper to examine the importance of strategic alliances in the bond market and our results highlight that corporate alliance activity is valued outside the equity market and creates additional benefits that result in lower cost of debt financing. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chou, Ting-Kai; Ou, Chin-Shyh; Tsai, Shu-Huan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Female leadership, performance, and governance in microfinance institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Strom, Reidar Oystein; D'Espallier, Bert; Mersland, Roy
This paper investigates the relations between female leadership, firm performance, and corporate governance in a global panel of 329 Microfinance Institutions (MFIs) in 73 countries covering the years 1998-2008. The microfinance industry is particularly suited for studying the impact of female leadership on governance and performance because of its mission orientation, its entrepreneurial nature, diverse institutional conditions, and high percentage of female leaders. We find female leadership to be significantly associated with larger boards, younger firms, a non-commercial legal status, and more female clientele. Furthermore, we find that a female chief executive officer and a female chairman of the board are positively related to MFI performance, but this result is not driven by improved governance. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Strom, Reidar Oystein; D'Espallier, Bert; Mersland, Roy</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Developed markets' business cycle dynamics and time-variation in emerging markets' asset returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nitschka, Thomas
This paper empirically studies the predictability of emerging markets' stock returns by business cycle variables and the role of developed markets' business cycle dynamics in this respect. The evidence shows that the link between business cycles and future stock market returns among emerging markets is considerably weaker than among developed markets. By contrast, I find strong evidence of stock return predictability by the respective country's dividend-price ratio. This latter finding could reflect that variation in dividend-price ratios potentially reflects both the temporary impact of "hot money" inflows on emerging markets' asset prices and rational expectations of future returns. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nitschka, Thomas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm cash holdings and CEO inside debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Yixin; Mauer, David C.; Zhang, Yilei
We examine the effect of CEO pensions and deferred compensation (inside debt) on firm cash holdings and the value of cash. We document a positive relation between CEO inside debt and firm cash holdings. This positive effect is magnified by firm leverage and mitigated by the presence of financial constraints. We further find that the marginal value of cash to shareholders declines as CEO inside debt increases. Our evidence supports the view that inside debt tilts managerial incentives toward bondholders and helps balance the competing interests of stockholders and bondholders. The evidence also suggests, however, that inside debt can harm shareholder value by encouraging excess cash holdings. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Yixin; Mauer, David C.; Zhang, Yilei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contrarian flows, consumption and expected stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Yuzhao
We investigate the relation between contrarian flows, consumption growth, and market risk premium. We construct a contrarian flows measure by summing up the capital flows to stocks that go against the total flow of the aggregate market. We show that the contrarian flows are negatively influenced by the same-quarter consumption growth. During bad times, the majority of investors who are affected by the negative shock reduce their equity exposure, and these extra supplies of risky assets are absorbed by contrarian investors who are least affected by the consumption shock. Using quarterly stock market data, we find that the contrarian flows forecast market returns at short-to-intermediate horizons. The predictability stems from the component that is explained by the consumption growth, and therefore the consumption growth contains valuable information about the market risk premium. Moreover, the predictability is stronger for growth stocks than for value stocks, and hence it negatively predicts the value premium. This is because the contrarian flows measure the market risk premium and growth stocks bear more discount rate risk than value stocks. Out-of-sample tests show that the main results are robust to data-snooping bias. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhang, Yuzhao</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Catalysts for price discovery in the European Union Emissions Trading System</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schultz, Emma; Swieringa, John
We provide the first evidence on catalysts for price discovery in the European Union Emissions Trading System. Specifically, by employing high frequency data across a wide range of fungible securities, we find that trading costs are a more important determinant of price discovery than either the implicit provision of leverage in securities such as futures and options or the existence of market segmentation. Moreover, securities with low trading costs display greater price discovery than those with high trading costs. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schultz, Emma; Swieringa, John</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dynamics of spillover effects during the European sovereign debt turmoil</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alter, Adrian; Beyer, Andreas
In this paper we modify and extend the framework of Diebold and Yilmaz (2011) to quantify spillovers between sovereign credit markets and banks in the euro area. Spillovers are estimated recursively from a vector autoregressive model of daily changes in credit default swap (CDS) spreads with exogenous common factors. We account for interdependencies between sovereign and bank CDS spreads and derive generalized impulse response functions. Specifically, we assess the systemic effect of an unexpected shock to the creditworthiness of a sovereign or country-specific bank index on other sovereigns and bank CDSs between October 2009 and July 2012. Channels of shock transmission from or to sovereigns and banks are summarized in a Contagion Index and its four components: (i) among sovereigns, (ii) among banks, (iii) from sovereigns to banks, and (iv) from banks to sovereigns. We also highlight the impact of policy-related events on the Contagion Index. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alter, Adrian; Beyer, Andreas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unveiling the embedded coherence in divergent performance rankings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Teresa Bosch-Badia, Maria; Montllor-Serrats, Joan; Tarrazon-Rodon, Maria-Antonia
This paper focuses on analyzing functional relationships among performance measures, centered on the adjusted differential risk premium between the asset and the benchmark and on Sharpe-1994 ratio. First, we develop a risk normalization procedure for variance and Aumann-Serrano riskiness which turns contradictory rankings into coherent ones, and combines the effects of correlation and outliers into the analysis. On this basis, we deduce functional connections among performance measures, arriving at a new indicator which expresses performance as the addition of three effects due to Sharpe ratio, correlation and outliers. We show it is a strictly increasing function of Homm-Pigorsch ratio. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Teresa Bosch-Badia, Maria; Montllor-Serrats, Joan; Tarrazon-Rodon, Maria-Antonia</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information asymmetries and spillover risk in settlement systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foote, Elizabeth
I show how information asymmetries between agents in different settlement systems can increase the risk that a problem in one may spill over to another. I focus on the strategic behavior of participants who operate in multiple systems as they choose how best to manage their liquidity across the systems. In the event of an operational shock in one system, these participants may continue to make payments in order to avoid delay costs, thereby risking a liquidity sink, if they believe they can recycle liquidity from the other, unaffected system. They are more likely to risk a liquidity sink if they believe banks in the unaffected system will continue making payments early, unaware of the operational problem. I show that a liquidity-saving mechanism (LSM) in one system may reduce the probability of spillover into the other; in this sense, I identify a positive externality from the introduction of an LSM. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Foote, Elizabeth</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Integration of European bond markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christiansen, Charlotte
I investigate the time variation in the integration of EU government bond markets. The integration is measured by the explanatory power of European factor portfolios for the individual bond markets for each year. The integration of the government bond markets is stronger for EMU than non-EMU members and stronger for old than new EU members. For EMU countries, the integration is weaker the lower the credit rating is. During the recent crisis periods, the integration is weaker, particularly for EMU countries. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christiansen, Charlotte</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic prediction of hedge fund survival in crisis-prone financial markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Hee Soo; Kim, Tae Yoon
This study focuses on dynamic changes in survival probabilities over the lifetimes of hedge funds. To model such probabilities, a mixed Cox proportional hazards (CPH) model-specifically, a survival/hazard model with time-varying covariates and fixed covariates- is employed. Resulting dynamic survival probabilities show that the mixed CPH model provides significantly higher accuracy in predicting hedge fund failure than other models in the literature, including fixed covariate CPH models and discrete logit models. Our results are useful to investors and regulators of hedge funds in crisis-prone financial markets. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Hee Soo; Kim, Tae Yoon</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The financial cycle and macroeconomics: What have we learnt?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borio, Claudio
It is high time we rediscovered the role of the financial cycle in macroeconomics. In the environment that has prevailed for at least three decades now, it is not possible to understand business fluctuations and the corresponding analytical and policy challenges without understanding the financial cycle. This calls for a rethink of modelling strategies and for significant adjustments to macroeconomic policies. This essay highlights the stylised empirical features of the financial cycle, conjectures as to what it may take to model it satisfactorily, and considers its policy implications. In the discussion of policy, the essay pays special attention to the bust phase, which is less well explored and raises much more controversial issues. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Borio, Claudio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Guarantees, transparency and the interdependency between sovereign and bank default risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koenig, Philipp; Anand, Kartik; Heinemann, Frank
Bank debt guarantees have traditionally been viewed as costless measures to prevent bank runs. However, as recent experiences in some European countries have demonstrated, guarantees may link the coordination problems of bank and sovereign creditors and induce a functional interdependence between the likelihoods of a government default and bank illiquidity. Employing a global-game approach, we model this link, showing the existence and uniqueness of the joint equilibrium and derive its comparative statics properties. In equilibrium, the guarantee reduces the probability of a bank run, while it increases the probability of a sovereign default. The latter erodes the guarantee's credibility and thus its effectiveness ex ante. By setting the guarantee optimally, the government balances these two effects in order to minimize expected costs of crises. Our results show that the optimal guarantee has clear-cut welfare gains which are enhanced through policies that promote greater balance sheet transparency. Crown Copyright (C) 2014 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koenig, Philipp; Anand, Kartik; Heinemann, Frank</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The spillover effects of unremunerated reserve requirements: Evidence from Thailand</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vithessonthi, Chaiporn; Tongurai, Jittima
We examine the spillover effects of the unremunerated reserve requirement (URR), which had been implemented in Thailand during 2006-2007, on stock returns through the Thai baht (THB) exchange rate against the euro (EUR) and the Japanese yen (JPY). Based on a sample of 270 firms listed on the Stock Exchange of Thailand (SET), we find that the imposition of the URR appears to affect the first- and second-moment exchange rate exposure to the EUR and the JPY of some firms, but the evidence does not strongly support the notion that there are spillover effects of the URR on exchange rate exposure. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vithessonthi, Chaiporn; Tongurai, Jittima</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deciphering robust portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Woo Chang; Kim, Jang Ho; Fabozzi, Frank J.
Robust portfolio optimization has been developed to resolve the high sensitivity to inputs of the Markowitz mean variance model. Although much effort has been put into forming robust portfolios, there have not been many attempts to analyze the characteristics of portfolios formed from robust optimization. We investigate the behavior of robust portfolios by analytically describing how robustness leads to higher dependency on factor movements. Focusing on the robust formulation with an ellipsoidal uncertainty set for expected returns, we show that as the robustness of a portfolio increases, its optimal weights approach the portfolio with variance that is maximally explained by factors. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Woo Chang; Kim, Jang Ho; Fabozzi, Frank J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do regulatory changes affect the underpricing of European IPOs?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akyol, Ali C.; Cooper, Tommy; Meoli, Michele; Vismara, Silvio
We use a sample of 3677 European IPOs during the period 1998-2012 to examine how the adoptions of corporate governance codes by Member States of the European Union (EU) have affected IPO underpricing on Member State-regulated markets, where issuers are subject to corporate governance rules instituted by Member States, relative to a control sample of IPOs on exchange-regulated markets, where issuers are exempt from Member State corporate governance codes. Using this control sample approach facilitated by the existence of second-tier, exchange-regulated markets in the EU, we find that, on average, IPO underpricing declined on Member State-regulated markets after Member States adopted corporate governance codes containing SOX-like provisions. We do not find a similar reduction in IPO underpricing on exchange-regulated markets. Our results are robust to alternative specifications, and our findings support the view that elevating corporate governance standards increases transparency and reduces information asymmetries that affect IPO valuations. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Akyol, Ali C.; Cooper, Tommy; Meoli, Michele; Vismara, Silvio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity risk in stock returns: An event-study perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Charles; Petrasek, Lubomir
We examine in an event-study context what factors affect the relative performance of stocks during liquidity crises. We find that market risk, measured by the market beta, is not a good measure of expected abnormal stock returns on days with liquidity crises. Instead, abnormal stock returns during liquidity crises are strongly negatively related to liquidity risk, measured by the co-movement of stock returns with market liquidity. The degree of informational asymmetry and the ownership structure of the firm also help to explain abnormal stock returns on crisis days. Our findings have important implications for managing the liquidity risk of equity portfolios. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cao, Charles; Petrasek, Lubomir</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting distress in European banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Betz, Frank; Oprica, Silviu; Peltonen, Tuomas A.; Sarlin, Peter
The paper develops an early-warning model for predicting vulnerabilities leading to distress in European banks using both bank and country-level data. As outright hank failures have been rare in Europe, the paper introduces a novel dataset that complements bankruptcies and defaults with state interventions and mergers in distress. The signals of the early-warning model are calibrated not only according to the policymaker's preferences between type I and II errors, but also to take into account the potential systemic relevance of each individual financial institution. The key findings of the paper are that complementing bank-specific vulnerabilities with indicators for macro-financial imbalances and banking sector vulnerabilities improves model performance and yields useful out-of-sample predictions of bank distress during the current financial crisis. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Betz, Frank; Oprica, Silviu; Peltonen, Tuomas A.; Sarlin, Peter</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mapping the UK interbank system</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Langfield, Sam; Liu, Zijun; Ota, Tomohiro
We present new evidence on the structure of interbank connections across key markets: derivatives, marketable securities, repo, unsecured lending and secured lending. Taken together, these markets comprise two networks: a network of interbank exposures and a network of interbank funding. Network structure varies across and within these two networks, for reasons related to markets' different economic functions. Credit risk and liquidity risk therefore propagate in the interbank system through different network structures. We discuss the implications for financial stability. (C) 2014 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Langfield, Sam; Liu, Zijun; Ota, Tomohiro</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systematic liquidity and the funding liquidity hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qian, Xiaolin; Tam, Lewis H. K.; Zhang, Bohui
In order to reconcile weak evidence of supply-side determinants of commonality in liquidity in previous studies, we examine commonality in liquidity in China over the period 1995-2012. Consistent with supply-side explanations, we find that market declines and market volatility increase liquidity commonality. To identify the direct relationship between the supply-side determinants and commonality in liquidity, we provide two specific tests and show that an increase in market participants has a negative effect on liquidity commonality, while the split-share-structure reform in 2005-2007 that results in a large increase in shares supply has a positive impact on liquidity commonality. Finally, we find that commonality in liquidity also has a real impact on the economy. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Qian, Xiaolin; Tam, Lewis H. K.; Zhang, Bohui</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring systemic risk-adjusted liquidity (SRL)-A model approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jobst, Andreas A.
Little progress has been made so far in addressing in a comprehensive way the negative externalities caused by excessive maturity transformation and the implications for effective liquidity regulation of banks. The SRL model combines option pricing theory with market information and balance sheet data to generate probabilistic measure of systemic liquidity risk. It enhances price-based liquidity regulation by linking a bank's maturity mismatch impacting the stability of its funding with those characteristics of other banks, subject to individual changes in risk profiles and common changes in market conditions impacting funding and market liquidity risk. This approach can then be used (i) to quantify an individual institution's time-varying contribution to expected losses from system-wide liquidity shortfalls and (ii) to price insurance premia that provide incentives for banks to internalize the social cost of their individual funding decisions. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jobst, Andreas A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual monitoring and corporate governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Zhichuan
Mutual monitoring in a well-structured authority system can mitigate the agency problem. I empirically examine whether the number two executive in a firm, if given authority, incentive, and channels for communication and influence, is able to monitor and constrain the potentially self-interested CEO. I find strong evidence that: (1) measures of the presence and extent of mutual monitoring from the No. 2 executive are positively related to future firm value (Tobin's Q); (2) the beneficial effect is more pronounced for firms with stronger incentives for the No. 2 to monitor and with higher information asymmetry between the boards and the CEOs; and (3) mutual monitoring is a substitute for other governance mechanisms. The results suggest that mutual monitoring provides important checks and balances on CEO power. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Zhichuan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The limits of granularity adjustments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fermanian, Jean-David
We provide a rigorous proof of granularity adjustment (GA) formulas to evaluate loss distributions and risk measures (value-at-risk) in the case of heterogenous portfolios, multiple systematic factors and random recoveries. As a significant improvement with respect to the literature, we detail all the technical conditions of validity and provide an upper bound of the remainder term for finite portfolio sizes. Moreover, we deal explicitly with the case of general loss distributions, possibly with masses. For some simple portfolio models, we prove empirically that the granularity adjustments do not always improve the infinitely granular first-order approximations. This stresses the importance of checking some conditions of regularity before relying on such techniques. Smoothing the underlying loss distributions through random recoveries or exposures improves the GA performances in general. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fermanian, Jean-David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning and incentive: A study on analyst response to pension underfunding</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Xuanjuan; Yao, Tong; Yu, Tong; Zhang, Ting
There is a long-standing debate on whether sell-side analysts learn from their experience to improve earnings forecast skills. This study shows that incentive is an important factor for understanding the "learning by doing" effect by analysts. We examine analysts' response to a complex type of information - corporate pension underfunding. Pension underfunding negatively impacts future earnings and analysts on average underreact to such information in their earnings forecasts. More importantly, when there is a strong incentive for analysts to deliver accurate forecasts, analyst learning effectively reduces their underreaction to pension underfunding information. On the other hand, when such an incentive is absent, the analyst learning effect is not discernible in the data. Further evidence suggests that analyst learning and incentive jointly reduce stock market mispricing associated with corporate pension underfunding. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Xuanjuan; Yao, Tong; Yu, Tong; Zhang, Ting</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity Risk, Reform of Bank Regulation, and Risk Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Ho-Mou; Chen, Ren-Raw
nan</description><author>Wu, Ho-Mou; Chen, Ren-Raw</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A study on risk retention regulation in asset securitization process</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, Guixia; Wu, Ho-Mou
We study the impacts of the recently proposed risk retention regulation for asset securitization, i.e. the issuer has to retain a certain proportion of securitized assets. We also consider the frequently discussed measure to require the issuer disclose certain information of the securitized assets. In a dynamic model with asymmetric information between a risk-averse originating bank and a continuum of risk-averse investors, we find that it is impossible for a flat-rate retention requirement to be optimal for all asset types. Although both risk retention and information disclosure regulations are effective in reducing investors' informational loss, neither can unconditionally enhance social welfare upon the unregulated case. For both measures, there are associated regulatory cost: risk retention regulation aggravates adverse selection problem because it undermines the channel of informational revelation by the choice of securitization intensity, and information disclosure requirement incurs a signalling cost by distorting banks' securitization intensity in sending signals. Under an appropriate set of conditions we find that information disclosure requirement complements risk retention regulation when investors are sufficiently risk averse. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guo, Guixia; Wu, Ho-Mou</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Derivatives holdings and systemic risk in the US banking sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mayordomo, Sergio; Rodriguez-Moreno, Maria; Ignacio Pena, Juan
This paper studies the impact of the banks' portfolio holdings of financial derivatives on the banks' individual contribution to systemic risk over and above the effect of variables related to size, interconnectedness, substitutability, and other balance sheet information. Using a sample of 95 U.S. bank holding companies from 2002 to 2011, we compare five measures of the banks' contribution to systemic risk and find that the new measure proposed in this study, Net Shapley Value, outperforms the others. Using this measure we find that banks' aggregate holdings of five classes of derivatives do not exhibit a significant effect on the bank's contribution to systemic risk. On the contrary, the banks' holdings of certain specific types of derivatives such as foreign exchange and credit derivatives increase the banks contributions to systemic risk whereas holdings of interest rate derivatives decrease it. Nevertheless, the proportion of non-performing loans over total loans and the leverage ratio have much stronger impact on systemic risk than derivatives holdings. Therefore, the derivatives' impact plays a second fiddle in comparison with traditional banking activities related to the former two items. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mayordomo, Sergio; Rodriguez-Moreno, Maria; Ignacio Pena, Juan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity effects in corporate bond spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Helwege, Jean; Huang, Jing-Zhi; Wang, Yuan
Corporate bond spreads are affected by both credit risk and liquidity and it is difficult to disentangle the two factors empirically. In this paper we separate out the credit risk component by examining bonds that are issued by the same firm and that trade on the same day, allowing us to examine the effects of liquidity in a sample of bond pairs. We examine standard liquidity measures to determine how well they explain the differences in the two bonds' yield spreads and find that the proxies do a poor job of measuring liquidity effects. Incorporating liquidity proxies related to other bonds issued by the firm and those for bonds of other firms can significantly improve the explanatory power. Still, a significant portion of the spread is left unexplained and it is largely driven by a common unknown factor. We conclude that good proxies for the liquidity component of corporate bond spreads remain elusive. Crown Copyright (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Helwege, Jean; Huang, Jing-Zhi; Wang, Yuan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity, leverage, and Lehman: A structural analysis of financial institutions in crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Ren-Raw; Chidambaran, N. K.; Imerman, Michael B.; Sopranzetti, Ben J.
This paper presents a flexible, lattice-based structural credit risk model that uses equity market information and a detailed depiction of a financial institution's liability structure to analyze default risk. The model is applied to examine the term structure of default probabilities for Lehman Brothers prior to its demise. The results indicate, as early as March, that the firm would likely lose access to external capital within two years. The model can be used as both a diagnostic tool for the early detection of financial distress and a prescriptive tool for addressing the sources of risk in large, complex financial institutions. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Ren-Raw; Chidambaran, N. K.; Imerman, Michael B.; Sopranzetti, Ben J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity provision and stock return predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hendershott, Terrence; Seasholes, Mark S.
This paper examines the trading behavior of two groups of liquidity providers (specialists and competing market makers) using a six-year panel of NYSE data. Trades of each group are negatively correlated with contemporaneous price changes. To test for return predictability, we sort stocks into quintiles based on each group's past trades and then form long-short portfolios. Stocks most heavily bought have significantly higher returns than stocks most heavily sold over the two weeks following a sort. Cross-sectional analysis shows smaller, more volatile, less actively traded, and less liquid stocks more often appear in the extreme quintiles. Time series analysis shows the long-short portfolio returns are positively correlated with a market-wide measure of liquidity. A double sort using past trades of specialists and competing market makers produces a long-short portfolio that earns 88 basis points per week (act as complements). Finally, we identify a "chain" of liquidity provision. Designated market makers (NYSE specialists) initially trade against order flows and prices changes. Specialists later mean revert their inventories by trading with competing market makers who appear to spread trades over a number of days. Alternatively, specialists may trade with competing market makers who arrive to market with delay. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hendershott, Terrence; Seasholes, Mark S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reprint of: Market liquidity in the financial crisis: The role of liquidity commonality and flight-to-quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roesch, Christoph G.; Kaserer, Christoph
We examine the dynamics and the drivers of market liquidity during the financial crisis, using a unique volume-weighted spread measure. According to the literature we find that market liquidity is impaired when stock markets decline, implying a positive relation between market and liquidity risk. Moreover, this relationship is the stronger the deeper one digs into the order book. Even more interestingly, this paper sheds further light on so far puzzling features of market liquidity: liquidity commonality and flight-to-quality. We show that liquidity commonality varies over time, increases during market downturns, peaks at major crisis events and becomes weaker the deeper we look into the limit order book. Consistent with recent theoretical models that argue for a spiral effect between the financial sector's funding liquidity and an asset's market liquidity, we find that funding liquidity tightness induces an increase in liquidity commonality which then leads to market-wide liquidity dry-ups. Therefore our findings corroborate the view that market liquidity can be a driving force for financial contagion. Finally, we show that there is a positive relationship between credit risk and liquidity risk, i.e., there is a spread between liquidity costs of high and low credit quality stocks, and that in times of increased market uncertainty the impact of credit risk on liquidity risk intensifies. This corroborates the existence of a flight-to-quality or flight-to-liquidity phenomenon also on the stock markets. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Roesch, Christoph G.; Kaserer, Christoph</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity shocks, governance, systemic risk and financial stability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellis, Luci; Haldane, Andy; McAndrews, James; Moshirian, Fariborz
nan</description><author>Ellis, Luci; Haldane, Andy; McAndrews, James; Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic risk, governance and global financial stability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellis, Luci; Haldane, Andy; Moshirian, Fariborz
The paper argues that while attempts have been made to reform four of the five key pillars of banks' operation, (i.e. competition, resolution, supervisory, and auditing and valuation policies), less attention has been paid to the role of bank governance and systemic risk, despite a strong link between governance and risk-taking. The paper offers four solutions to strengthen bank governance. First, the regulatory capital base of banks could be increased. Second, the compensation structure of managers could be reformed. Third, effort could be focussed on creating and implementing resolution regimes which offer the credible prospect of "bailing-in" creditors in the event of stress and fourth solution is to reform the structure of company law for example, by extending control rights beyond shareholders. Furthermore, the paper argues that given the diversity of the whole financial system, it is expected that the risks individual financial institutions face are also diverse. It cannot be assumed that the appropriate capitalisation is constant across all risks. While leverage ratios are a useful backstop measure and guard against potential gaming of risk-weights, their appropriate role is as a backstop. The diversity within the financial system also supports the fact that a single measure of systemic risk is unlikely to be universally applicable, nor is a single instrument of financial stability policy. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ellis, Luci; Haldane, Andy; Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of financial stress in emerging market economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Park, Cyn-Young; Mercado, Rogelio V.
The global financial crisis of 2008-2009 illustrates how financial turmoil in advanced economies could trigger severe financial stress in emerging markets. Previous studies dealing with financial crises and contagion show the linkages through which financial stress are transmitted from advanced to emerging markets. This paper extends the existing literature on the use of financial stress index (FSI) in understanding the channels of financial transmission in emerging market economies. Using FSI of 25 emerging markets, our panel regression estimates show that not only advanced economies FSI, but also regional and nonregional emerging market FSIs significantly increase domestic financial stress. Our findings also suggest that there is a common regional factor significantly affecting domestic FSI in emerging Asia and emerging Europe. Furthermore, the results from a structural vector autoregression model with contemporaneous restrictions indicate that although a domestic financial shock still accounts for most of the variation in domestic FSI, regional shocks play an important role in emerging Asia. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Park, Cyn-Young; Mercado, Rogelio V.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risky adjustments or adjustments to risks: Decomposing bank leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koch, Catherine Tahmee
By use of cointegration analysis, this paper splits bank leverage into a short- and long-run dimension. Regarding the long run, if banks' leverage ratios or related liability shares are stable over time, they form a cointegrating relationship. Thus, cointegration tests indicate whether banks' liability ratios were stable or subject to structural breaks during the financial crisis in 2007 and 2008. By endogenous identification of structural breaks, my analysis tracks the precise channels of banks' leverage adjustments. Findings on the long run suggest that banks cut their leverage twice. In June 2007 banks significantly reduced their foreign debt, while in April 2008 they withdrew from interbank borrowing. Regarding the short run, I study how banks adjust to the dynamics of risk proxies from distinct financial markets. Findings on the short run point out that banks' reactions to risks differ considerably across different types of financial markets. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Koch, Catherine Tahmee</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk models-at-risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boucher, Christophe M.; Danielsson, Jon; Kouontchou, Patrick S.; Maillet, Bertrand B.
The experience from the global financial crisis has raised serious concerns about the accuracy of standard risk measures as tools for the quantification of extreme downward risks. A key reason for this is that risk measures are subject to a model risk due, e.g. to specification and estimation uncertainty. While regulators have proposed that financial institutions assess the model risk, there is no accepted approach for computing such a risk. We propose a remedy for this by a general framework for the computation of risk measures robust to model risk by empirically adjusting the imperfect risk forecasts by outcomes from backtesting frameworks, considering the desirable quality of VaR models such as the frequency, independence and magnitude of violations. We also provide a fair comparison between the main risk models using the same metric that corresponds to model risk required corrections. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boucher, Christophe M.; Danielsson, Jon; Kouontchou, Patrick S.; Maillet, Bertrand B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Of religion and redemption: Evidence from default on Islamic loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baele, Lieven; Farooq, Moazzam; Ongena, Steven
We compare default rates on conventional and Islamic loans using a comprehensive monthly dataset from Pakistan that follows more than 150,000 loans over the period 2006:04 to 2008:12. We find robust evidence that the default rate of Islamic loans is less than half the default rate of conventional loans. Islamic loans are less likely to default during Ramadan and in big cities if the share of votes to religious-political parties increases, suggesting that religion - either through individual piousness or network effects - may play a role in determining loan default. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baele, Lieven; Farooq, Moazzam; Ongena, Steven</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition of socially responsible and conventional mutual funds and its impact on fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>In, Francis; Kim, Martin; Park, Raphael Jonghyeon; Kim, Sangbae; Kim, Tong Suk
This paper examines the impact of both socially responsible (SR) and conventional entrant funds on SR incumbent funds using an overlap in portfolio holdings to measure the impact of competition in the US mutual fund industry. This paper's findings indicate that over the past decade the increase in competition from SR entrants has been associated with an increase in fees but not in capital flow. Moreover, our results show that the increase in the number of SR fund entrants does not have a negative impact on fund performance. This finding implies that despite the significant increase in the number of SR funds entering the market, open and free competition fosters the performance of SR fund participants. Our study concludes that despite the recent growth in the number of SR funds, the SR mutual fund market does not exhibit the key features of a competitive market. (C) 2014 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>In, Francis; Kim, Martin; Park, Raphael Jonghyeon; Kim, Sangbae; Kim, Tong Suk</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment performance of "environmentally-friendly" firms and their initial public offers and seasoned equity offers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Pak To; Walter, Terry
We employ a sample of 748 environmentally-friendly (or "green") firms listed on U.S. stock exchanges to extend studies of the effects of socially responsible investment (SRI) on stock investment returns and the performance of initial public offerings (IPOs) and seasoned equity offerings (SEOs). Our empirical tests document positive and statistically significant excess returns for our environmentally-friendly firms and their IPOs and SEOs, in contrast to our control IPO and SEO samples which underperform. In summary, a "green" equity premium is evident in returns calculated from a variety of benchmarks. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chan, Pak To; Walter, Terry</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do small businesses still prefer community banks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; Goulding, William; Rice, Tara
We formulate and test hypotheses about the role of bank type - small versus large, single-market versus multimarket, and local versus nonlocal banks - in banking relationships. The conventional paradigm suggests that "community banks" - small, single-market, local institutions - are better able to form strong relationships with informationally opaque small businesses, while "megabanks" - large, multimarket, nonlocal institutions - tend to serve more transparent firms. Using the 2003 Survey of Small Business Finance (SSBF), we conduct two sets of tests. First, we test for the type of bank serving as the "main" relationship bank for small businesses with different firm and owner characteristics. Second, we test for the strength of these main relationships by examining the probability of an exclusive relationship and main bank relationship length as functions of main bank type and financial fragility, as well as firm and owner characteristics. The results are often not consistent with the conventional paradigm, perhaps because of changes in lending technologies and deregulation of the banking industry. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; Goulding, William; Rice, Tara</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The risk of financial intermediaries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delis, Manthos D.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Tsionas, Efthymios G.
This paper reconsiders the formal estimation of bank risk using the variability of the profit function. In our model, point estimates of the variability of profits are derived from a model where this variability is endogenous to other bank characteristics, such as capital and liquidity. We estimate the new model on the entire panel of US banks, spanning the period 1985q1-2012q4. The findings show that bank risk was fairly stable up to 2001 and accelerated quickly thereafter up to 2007. We also establish that the risk of the relatively large banks and banks that failed in the subprime crisis is higher than the industry's average. Thus, we provide a new leading indicator, which is able to forecast future solvency problems of banks. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Delis, Manthos D.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Tsionas, Efthymios G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The good and bad news about the new liquidity rules of Basel III in Western European countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dietrich, Andreas; Hess, Kurt; Wanzenried, Gabrielle
New liquidity rules phased in under Basel III define the new net stable funding ratio (NSFR) to promote sustainable funding structures at financial institutions. In this paper, we analyze characteristics and drivers of NSFR for a sample of 921 Western European banks between 1996 and 2010. We find that a majority of banks have historically not fulfilled NSFR minimum requirements, in particular larger and faster growing institutions as well as banks also active in asset management and investment banking. Many of them have started increasing NSFR with the onset of financial crisis 2008 while this ratio had been sliding in earlier years. Interestingly, potential advantages in funding costs for low NSFR banks do not seem to translate into higher profitability and results of these banks are more volatile. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dietrich, Andreas; Hess, Kurt; Wanzenried, Gabrielle</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does public information affect the frequency of trading in airline stocks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nowak, Sylwia; Anderson, Heather M.
This paper examines how firm specific and macroeconomic announcements affect transaction rates in U.S. airline stocks. Using a version of the autoregressive conditional hazard framework of Hamilton and Jorda (2002) that incorporates market microstructure variables, we show that on average, trading intensity spikes prior and consequent to macroeconomic announcements, but decreases around firm-specific releases. Further, when we use intraday crude oil futures returns as a proxy for industry relevant and globally important news we find that their effects are statistically significant, with higher oil futures returns increasing the probability of trade. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nowak, Sylwia; Anderson, Heather M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do asset encumbrance and debt regulations affect bank capital and bond risk?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Helberg, Stig; Lindset, Snorre
We study how optimal bank capital and bond risk are influenced by asset encumbrance, depositor preference, and bail-in resolution frameworks. Due to changes in optimal capital structure, the net effect on bond debt risk and valuation is small. The effects on shareholder value and public sector liability value are significant. A gap between optimal and required capital represents a cost to shareholders and increases the risk of regulatory arbitrage. The features of bank debt financing we analyze here may explain the stable cross-sectional variation in bank capital documented in literature. Based on a small sample of European banks, we find support for the central model predictions. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Helberg, Stig; Lindset, Snorre</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of competition and information on intraday trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malinova, Katya; Park, Andreas
In a dynamic model of financial market trading multiple heterogeneously informed traders choose when to place orders. Better informed traders trade immediately, worse informed delay - even though they expect the market to move against them. This behavior generates intraday patterns with decreasing spreads, decreasing probability of informed trading (PIN), and increasing volume. We predict that policies that foster market entry improve the welfare of uninformed traders and lead to increased market participation by incumbent traders. Technological advances that lead to better signal processing also encourage market participation and increase volume but at the expense of uninformed traders' welfare. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Malinova, Katya; Park, Andreas</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Options-implied variance and future stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, Hui; Qiu, Buhui
Using options-implied variance, a forward-looking measure of conditional variance, we revisit the debate on the idiosyncratic risk-return relation. In both cross-sectional (for individual stocks) and time-series (for the market index) regressions, we find a negative relation between options-implied variance and future stock returns. Consistent with Miller's (1977) divergence of opinion hypothesis, the negative relation gets stronger (1) for stocks with more stringent short-sale constraints or (2) when shorting stocks becomes more difficult. Moreover, the negative correlation of realized idiosyncratic variance or analyst forecast dispersion with future stock returns mainly reflects their close correlation with our conditional idiosyncratic variance measure. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guo, Hui; Qiu, Buhui</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macro-financial determinants of the great financial crisis: Implications for financial regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caprio, Gerard; D'Apice, Vincenzo; Ferri, Giovanni; Puopolo, Giovanni Walter
We provide a cross-country and cross-bank analysis of the financial determinants of the Great Financial Crisis using data on 83 countries from the period 1998 to 2006. First, our cross-country results show that the probability of suffering the crisis in 2008 was larger for countries having higher levels of credit deposit ratio whereas it was lower for countries characterized by higher levels of: (i) net interest margin, (ii) concentration in the banking sector, (iii) restrictions to bank activities, (iv) private monitoring. The bank-level analysis reinforces these results and shows that the latter factors are also key determinants across banks, thus explaining the probability of bank crisis. Our findings contribute to extend the analytical toolkit available for macro and micro-prudential regulation. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Caprio, Gerard; D'Apice, Vincenzo; Ferri, Giovanni; Puopolo, Giovanni Walter</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analytical pricing of discrete arithmetic Asian options with mean reversion and jumps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Shing Fung; Wong, Hoi Ying
Empirical evidence indicates that commodity prices are mean reverting and exhibit jumps. As some commodity option payoffs involve the arithmetic average of historical commodity prices, we derive an analytical solution to arithmetic Asian options under a mean reverting jump diffusion process. The analytical solution is implemented with the fast Fourier transform based on the joint characteristic function of the terminal asset price and the realized average value. We also examine the accuracy and computational efficiency of the proposed method through numerical studies. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, Shing Fung; Wong, Hoi Ying</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Subscribing to transparency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Yinghua; Nielsson, Ulf; Guo, Hong; Yang, Jiong
The paper empirically explores how more trade transparency affects market liquidity. The analysis takes advantage of a unique setting in which the Shanghai Stock Exchange offered more trade transparency to market participants subscribing to a new software package. First, the results show that the additional data disclosure increased trading activity, but also increased transactions costs through wider bid-ask spreads. Thus, in contrast to popular policy belief, the paper finds that more transparency need not improve market liquidity. Second, the paper finds a particularly strong immediate liquidity impact accompanied by altered trading behavior, which suggests a significant impact on institutional traders subscribing relatively early. Lastly, since the effective level of market transparency is bound to depend on how many traders are subscribing to the data, the study can empirically establish the functional form between market-wide transparency and liquidity. The relationship is non-monotonic, which can explain the lack of consensus in the existing literature where each empirical study is naturally confined to specific parts of the transparency domain. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>He, Yinghua; Nielsson, Ulf; Guo, Hong; Yang, Jiong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm quality or market sentiment: What matters more for IPO investors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neupane, Suman; Paudyal, Krishna; Thapa, Chandra
This paper investigates the investment decisions of IPO investors when equipped with information on both the quality of the firm and the market sentiment. Unique regulatory provisions allow IPO investors in India to have access to the independent assessment of firm quality and information on the participation of other investors, including institutional investors. At the same time, an active grey market reveals market sentiment before the application for subscription is closed. The results, which are robust to alternative model specifications, suggest that the institutional investors' decision is guided almost exclusively by firm quality while the retail investors' decision to participate in IPOs is strongly influenced by market sentiment, even in a highly transparent market where both sets of information are freely available. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Neupane, Suman; Paudyal, Krishna; Thapa, Chandra</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the investment factor a proxy for time-varying investment opportunities? The US and international evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Lin; Wang, Zijun
Motivated from Fama's (1991) conjecture of an explicit link between the cross-sectional and time-series stock return predictability, we investigate whether the investment factor constructed from the cross-section of stocks also has time-series predictive power for stock returns within Merton's (1973) ICAPM framework. The evidence from both US and other G-7 countries (except Japan) suggests that the investment factor is a proxy for time-varying investment opportunities. We also find that the risk-return relation is positive and statistically significant after controlling for the covariance between the market factor and the investment factor. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Lin; Wang, Zijun</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of US banks' international activities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Temesvary, Judit
This paper develops a model and structural dynamic estimation of bank behavior to map the relationship between U.S. banks' choices of foreign banking activities, and bank and foreign market traits. This estimation framework is applied to a unique bank-level dataset compiled from regulatory sources, covering U.S. banks' foreign activities in 83 host markets over the 2003-2013 period. Bank traits are better able to explain the evolving patterns of foreign banking than host market characteristics. After controlling for these traits, the post-financial crisis period shows a structural shift away from cross-border claims towards foreign affiliate activities. Structural estimates of foreign market entry costs and regulatory attitudes towards risk are derived. Simulation exercises confirm the strong impact of banks' and regulators' risk stance on bank profits and portfolio composition. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Temesvary, Judit</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The choice between informal and formal restructuring: The case of French banks facing distressed SMEs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blazy, Regis; Martel, Jocelyn; Nigam, Nirjhar
This empirical paper investigates the paths leading to the resolution of financial distress for a sample of small and medium-sized French firms in default, focusing in particular on their decisions between bankruptcy and informal (out-of-court) renegotiations. The procedure is depicted as a sequential game in which stakeholders first decide whether to engage in an informal renegotiation. Second, conditional on opting for renegotiation, the debtor and its creditors may succeed or fail in reaching an agreement to restructure the firm's capital structure. We test different hypotheses that capture (i) coordination and bargaining power issues, (ii) informational problems, (iii) firm characteristics, and (iv) loan characteristics. The empirical implementation is based on sequential LOGIT regressions. First, we find that the likelihood of informal renegotiations increases with loan size and the proportion of long-term debt. These two results support the argument that size matters when deciding whether to opt for informal renegotiation. Second, the probability of a successful renegotiation decreases when (i) the bank in charge of handling the process is the debtor's "main" creditor and when (ii) the firm is badly rated and its management is considered faulty. Third, the estimations show that collateral plays a significant role in the first stage of the renegotiation process. However, it does not impact the likelihood of success in reaching a renegotiated agreement. Finally, some banks are clearly better than others at leading successful renegotiation processes. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blazy, Regis; Martel, Jocelyn; Nigam, Nirjhar</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Impact of ethical behavior on syndicated loan rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Moshe; Surroca, Jordi; Tribo, Josep A.
This paper shows that borrowers' ethical behavior leads lending banks to loosen financing conditions when setting loan rates. We advance the banking literature by stressing that the previous financing loosening is enhanced when there is similarity of lenders and borrowers along their ethical domain given that such similarity brings about familiarity and trust in non-opportunistic behavior between them, thereby contributing to lower information frictions. Unique data composed of 12,545 syndicated loan facilities from 19 countries for the period 2003-2007 indicate a 24.8% reduction in the mean spread associated with an increase of one standard deviation in the degree of borrowers' ethical behavior from its mean value. Such reduction is enhanced to 37.6% when lenders also behave in an ethical way. Results withstand a battery of robustness tests including the use of alternative databases that capture the effect of the 2008 financial crisis, financing alternatives such as equity financing as well as nonparametric estimations. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Moshe; Surroca, Jordi; Tribo, Josep A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of accruals quality in the access to bank debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garcia-Teruel, Pedro J.; Martinez-Solano, Pedro; Pedro Sanchez-Ballesta, Juan
This work analyses the effect of accruals quality in the access of firms to bank debt in a panel data of SME Spanish firms. The results show a positive association between accruals quality and bank debt, even when controlling for other determinants of bank debt and for possible endogeneity between bank debt and accruals quality, which suggests that higher precision of earnings reduces information asymmetries with banks and favors the access of firms to bank loans. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garcia-Teruel, Pedro J.; Martinez-Solano, Pedro; Pedro Sanchez-Ballesta, Juan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateral requirements of SMEs: The evidence from less-developed countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanedar, Elmas Yaldiz; Broccardo, Eleonora; Bazzana, Flavio
This paper aims to investigate the determinants of collateral requirements for loans that are extended to small and medium-sized enterprises in less-developed countries. Our primary data source consists of the results from firms in Eastern Europe and Central Asia from the Business Environment and Enterprise Performance Survey, which is compiled by the World Bank and the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development. The results show that borrower-specific variables are more important than country-specific variables in determining collateral requirements on loan contracts. The strongest evidence in our paper emphasises the importance of borrower risk and loan cost in collateral determinants. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hanedar, Elmas Yaldiz; Broccardo, Eleonora; Bazzana, Flavio</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Speed, algorithmic trading, and market quality around macroeconomic news announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Scholtus, Martin; van Dijk, Dick; Frijns, Bart
This paper documents that speed is crucially important for high-frequency trading strategies based on U.S. macroeconomic news releases. Using order-level data on the highly liquid S&amp;P 500 ETF traded on NASDAQ from January 6, 2009 to December 12, 2011, we find that a delay of 300 ms or more significantly reduces returns of news-based trading strategies. This reduction is greater for high impact news and on days with high volatility. In addition, we assess the effect of algorithmic trading on market quality around macroeconomic news. In the minute following a macroeconomic news arrival, algorithmic activity increases trading volume and depth at the best quotes, but also increases volatility and leads to a drop in overall depth. Quoted half-spreads decrease (increase) when we measure algorithmic trading over the full (top of the) order book. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Scholtus, Martin; van Dijk, Dick; Frijns, Bart</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank competition and financial stability in Asia Pacific</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fu, Xiaoqing; Lin, Yongjia; Molyneux, Philip
Analysis, of the tradeoff between competition and financial stability has been at the center of academic and policy debate for over two decades and especially since the 2007-2008 global financial crises. Here we use information on 14 Asia Pacific economies from 2003 to 2010 to investigate the influence of bank competition, concentration, regulation and national institutions on individual bank fragility as measured by the probability of bankruptcy and the bank's Z-score. The results suggest that greater concentration fosters financial fragility and that lower pricing power also induces bank risk exposure after controlling for a variety of macroeconomic, bank-specific, regulatory and institutional factors. In terms of regulations and institutions, the results show that tougher entry restrictions may benefit bank stability, whereas stronger deposit insurance schemes are associated with greater bank fragility. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fu, Xiaoqing; Lin, Yongjia; Molyneux, Philip</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling the joint dynamics of risk-neutral stock index and bond yield volatilities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhou, Yinggang
This study examines the joint evolution of risk-neutral stock index and bond yield volatilities by using the Chicago Board Option Exchange S&amp;P500 volatility index (VIX) and the Bank of America Merrill Lynch Treasury Option Volatility Estimate Index (MOVE). I use bivariate regime-switching models to investigate the alternation of "high-risk" and "low-risk" markets, where the high-risk regime is characterized by higher and more volatilities with weaker cross-market linkages. Common information about economic and financial conditions appears to drive VIX and MOVE fluctuations between the two risk regimes. Two-regime specifications also distinguish between information spillover and common information effects. Ignoring regime shifts leads to spurious extreme persistence and incomplete inferences about asymmetric volatility. The findings carry important implications for asset allocation. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zhou, Yinggang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility spreads and earnings announcement returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atilgan, Yigit
Prior research documents that volatility spreads predict stock returns. If the trading activity of informed investors is an important driver of volatility spreads, then the predictability of stock returns should be more pronounced during major information events. This paper investigates whether the predictability of equity returns by volatility spreads is stronger during earnings announcements. Volatility spreads are measured by the implied volatility differences between pairs of strike price and expiration date matched put and call options and capture price pressures in the option market. During a two-day earnings announcement window, the abnormal returns to the quintile that includes stocks with relatively expensive call options is more than 1.5% greater than the abnormal returns to the quintile that includes stocks with relatively expensive put options. This result is robust after measuring volatility spreads in alternative ways and controlling for firm characteristics and lagged equity returns. The degree of announcement return predictability is stronger when volatility spreads are measured using more liquid options, the information environment is more asymmetric, and stock liquidity is low. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Atilgan, Yigit</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric responses of ask and bid quotes to information in the foreign exchange market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yu-Lun; Gau, Yin-Feng
We study the price discovery in a foreign exchange electronic limit order market on a daily basis, by examining the informativeness of ask and bid quotes in the process of price formation. Using the data of prices and trades in the Euro-Dollar spot market via Electronic Broking Services (EBS), we find bid quotes provide more price discovery. This dominance of bid quotes in price discovery is stronger on Monday, and is weaker on Friday. Asymmetries in the responses of ask and bid quotes to trade-related information evolve with daily order flow, daily return, the interactive term between spread and order flow, and the volatility, skewness, and kurtosis in the distribution of efficient exchange rate changes. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Yu-Lun; Gau, Yin-Feng</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does revenue momentum drive or ride earnings or price momentum?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hong-Yi; Chen, Sheng-Syan; Hsin, Chin-Wen; Lee, Cheng-Few
This paper examines the profits of revenue, earnings, and price momentum strategies in an attempt to understand investor reactions when facing multiple information of firm performance in various scenarios. We first offer evidence that there is no dominating momentum strategy among the revenue, earnings, and price momentums, suggesting that revenue surprises, earnings surprises, and prior returns each carry some exclusive unpriced information content. We next show that the profits of momentum driven by firm fundamental performance information (revenue or earnings) depend upon the accompanying firm market performance information (price), and vice versa. The robust monotonicity in multivariate momentum returns is consistent with the argument that the market does not only underestimate the individual information but also the joint implications of multiple information on firm performance, particularly when they point in the same direction. A three-way combined momentum strategy may offer monthly return as high as 1.44%. The information conveyed by revenue surprises and earnings surprises combined account for about 19% of price momentum effects, which finding adds to the large literature on tracing the sources of price momentum. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Hong-Yi; Chen, Sheng-Syan; Hsin, Chin-Wen; Lee, Cheng-Few</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>SOX, corporate transparency, and the cost of debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrade, Sandro C.; Bernile, Gennaro; Hood, Frederick M.
We investigate the impact of the Sarbanes-Oxley (SOX) Act on the cost of debt through its effect on the reliability of financial reporting. Using Credit Default Swap (CDS) spreads and a structural CDS pricing model, we calibrate a firm-level corporate opacity parameter in the pre- and post-SOX periods. Our analysis shows that corporate opacity and the cost of debt decrease significantly after SOX. The median firm in our sample experiences an 18 bp reduction on its five-year CDS spread as a result of lower opacity following SOX, amounting to total annual savings of $ 844 million for the 252 firms in our sample. Furthermore, the reduction in opacity tends to be larger for firms that in the pre-SOX period have lower accrual quality, less conservative earnings, lower number of independent directors, lower S&amp;P Transparency and Disclosure ratings, and are more likely to benefit from SOX-compliance according to Chhaochharia and Grinstein's (2007) criteria. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andrade, Sandro C.; Bernile, Gennaro; Hood, Frederick M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The tax benefit of income smoothing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rydqvist, Kristian; Schwartz, Steven T.; Spizman, Joshua D.
A worker can reduce tax liability by contributing to a private pension plan when marginal tax rates are high and withdraw pension benefits when marginal tax rates are low. We quantify the tax benefit of income smoothing through the private retirement system and find that it is negligible. This conclusion is important to households, investment advisers, tax policymakers, and scholars engaged in financial retirement planning. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rydqvist, Kristian; Schwartz, Steven T.; Spizman, Joshua D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>News spillovers from the Greek debt crisis: Impact on the Eurozone financial sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhanot, Karan; Burns, Natasha; Hunter, Delroy; Williams, Michael
We examine the impact of changes in Greek sovereign yield spreads on abnormal returns of financial sector stocks for a sample of Eurozone countries, during the Greek debt crisis. We find that increases in yield spreads are associated with negative abnormal returns on financial stocks in the Portugal, Spain and Netherlands. These abnormal returns are driven in part by ratings downgrades and other unfavorable news announcements about Greece. We isolate the effects of known transmission channels-impairment of financial firms' asset base due to cross-holdings of Greek bonds, from increases in domestic interest rates and higher funding costs. Our analysis indicates that news events lead to spillovers in excess of what can be explained by these channels of transmission. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bhanot, Karan; Burns, Natasha; Hunter, Delroy; Williams, Michael</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Indian bank efficiency and productivity changes with undesirable outputs: A disaggregated approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fujii, Hidemichi; Managi, Shunsuke; Matousek, Roman
The objective of this study is to examine technical efficiency and productivity growth in the Indian banking sector over the period from 2004 to 2011. We apply an innovative methodological approach introduced by Chen et al. (2011) and Barros et al. (2012), who use a weighted Russell directional distance model to measure technical inefficiency. We further modify and extend that model to measure TFP change with NPLs. We find that the inefficiency levels are significantly different among the three ownership structure of banks in India. Foreign banks have strong market position in India and they pull the production frontier in a more efficient direction. SPBs and domestic private banks show considerably higher inefficiency. We conclude that the restructuring policy applied in the late 1990s and early 2000s by the Indian government has not had a long-lasting effect. Crown Copyright (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fujii, Hidemichi; Managi, Shunsuke; Matousek, Roman</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dwarf banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernykh, Lucy
This study examines the business model and the viability of very small commercial banks in emerging market context. Using a unique sample of 141 Russian banks with less than a $10 million in assets, I trace performance, survival, recapitalization and growth patterns of these dwarf banks in response to the sharp increase in the minimum capital requirements. I find that dwarf banks are, on average, low-risk financial intermediaries that perform simple operations and have significantly higher survival rates in local markets with poor economic and banking services outreach characteristics. I also find that the average dwarf banks withstand the regulatory capital shock surprisingly well by securing fresh capital injection followed by a twofold asset size increase. The results of this study contribute to the literature on the relationship between the small bank business model, local banking markets characteristics and long-term viability. They also provide new evidence on the expected and unexpected outcomes of the "too small to survive" regulatory intervention into the banking market size structures. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chernykh, Lucy</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Acquisition pricing in India during 1995-2011: Have Indian acquirers really beaten the odds?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Pradip; Banerjee, Prithviraj; De, Soumen; Jindra, Jan; Mukhopadhyay, Jayanta
We examine the announcement returns of acquisitions made by Indian firms during the period 1995-2011. Our results confirm that the announcement returns to Indian acquirers are on average significantly positive. However, we are first to document that the announcement returns to Indian acquirers decline over time and become, on average, negative towards the end of our sample period. We analyze several hypotheses for such decline and find that the decline, while robust to a variety of explanations, is related to the intensity of the market for corporate control in India. Finally, the post-acquisition long-run returns for acquirers are, on average, consistently positive, do not change over time, and are unrelated to the initial market reaction to the acquisition announcement. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Banerjee, Pradip; Banerjee, Prithviraj; De, Soumen; Jindra, Jan; Mukhopadhyay, Jayanta</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anxious periods and bank lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delis, Manthos D.; Kouretas, Georgios P.; Tsoumas, Chris
We examine the lending behavior of banks during anxious periods. The main characteristic of anxious periods is that the perceptions and expectations about economic conditions worsen for economic agents even though the economy is not in a recession. We identify distinct periods of anxiety for consumers, CEOs (firms) and analysts. Subsequently, we study the lending behavior of US banks during the anxious quarters from 1985 to 2010, using bank-level data. The results show that banks' lending falls when consumers and analysts are anxious, and this effect is more pronounced when banks hold a higher level of credit risk. These effects are more pronounced in anxious periods that were followed by recessions, and in these periods loan growth also responds negatively to the anxiety of CEOs. Yet, these effects are quite less prevalent in the period after 2001. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Delis, Manthos D.; Kouretas, Georgios P.; Tsoumas, Chris</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CDOs and the financial crisis: Credit ratings and fair premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wojtowicz, Marcin
We study risk and return characteristics of CDOs using the market standard models. We find that fair spreads on CDO tranches are much higher than fair spreads on similarly-rated corporate bonds. Our results imply that credit ratings are not sufficient for pricing, which is surprising given their central role in structured finance markets. This illustrates limitations of the rating methodologies that are solely based on real-world default probabilities or expected losses and do not capture risk premia. We also demonstrate that CDO tranches have large exposure to systematic risk and thus their ratings and prices are likely to decline substantially when credit conditions deteriorate. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wojtowicz, Marcin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An intertemporal capital asset pricing model with bank credit growth as a state variable</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harnmami, Yacine; Lindahl, Anna
An ICAPM which includes bank credit growth as a state variable explains 94% of the cross-sectional variation in the average returns on the 25 Fama-French portfolios. We find compelling evidence that bank credit growth is priced in the cross-section of expected stock returns, even after controlling for well-documented asset pricing factors. These results are robust to the inclusion of industry portfolios in the set of test assets. They are also robust to the addition of firm characteristics and lagged instruments in the factor model. Bank credit growth is important because of its ability to predict business cycle variables as well as future labor income growth. These findings underscore the relevance of bank credit growth in stock pricing. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harnmami, Yacine; Lindahl, Anna</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Style chasing by hedge fund investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>ter Horst, Jenke; Salganik, Galla
This paper examines whether investors chase hedge fund investment styles. We find that better-performing and more popular styles are rewarded with higher inflows in subsequent periods. This indicates that investors compare hedge fund styles in terms of recent performance and popularity, and they subsequently reallocate funds from less successful to more successful styles. Furthermore, we find evidence of competition between individual hedge funds of the same style. Funds outperforming the other funds in their styles and funds whose inflows exceed the average flows in their styles experience higher inflows in subsequent periods. One of the reasons for competition among same-style funds is investors' search for the best managers. The high minimum investment required to invest in a hedge fund limits investors' diversification opportunities and makes this search particularly important. Finally, we show that hedge fund investors' implementation of style chasing in combination with intra-style fund selection represents a smart strategy. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>ter Horst, Jenke; Salganik, Galla</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial development and barriers to the cross-border diffusion of financial innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, James B.; Kumar, Sanjesh
This paper explores the determinants of financial development by focusing on the role played by barriers to the diffusion of financial technology. These barriers are measured using human genetic distance from the technology frontier. The results based on cross-sectional data for 123 countries suggest that genetic distance to the global frontier has an economically and statistically significant effect on financial development, in that countries that are genetically far from the technology leader tend to have lower levels of financial development. Genetic distance is found to have the largest effect, even after controlling for other determinants of financial development established in the literature. These findings indicate that cultural barriers to the diffusion of financial technology across borders impact financial development by influencing the follower countries' ability to adopt and adapt innovations from the frontier. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ang, James B.; Kumar, Sanjesh</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trust and the provision of trade credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Wenfeng; Firth, Michael; Rui, Oliver M.
State-controlled listed firms in China receive preferential treatment when borrowing from commercial banks; in contrast, private controlled firms rely on informal finance and on trade credit. We argue for and find evidence that private firms located in higher social trust regions use more trade credit from suppliers, extend more trade credit to customers, and collect receivables and pay payables more quickly. These findings are enhanced for firms located in provinces with weak protection of property rights. Our results are robust to different measures of social trust, legal environment, and endogeneity. Overall, our results show that social trust helps private firms overcome institutional difficulties in financing their activities. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wu, Wenfeng; Firth, Michael; Rui, Oliver M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effects of international institutional factors on earnings quality of banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kanagaretnam, Kiridaran; Lim, Chee Yeow; Lobo, Gerald J.
We examine the relation between legal, extra-legal and political institutional factors and earnings quality of banks across countries. We predict that earnings quality is higher in countries with legal, extra-legal and political systems that reduce the consumption of private control benefits by insiders and afford outside investors greater protection. Using a sample of banks from 35 countries during the pre-crisis period from 1993 to 2006, we find that all five measures of earnings quality studied are higher in countries with stronger legal, extra-legal and political institutional structures. We also find that banks in countries with stronger institutions are less likely to report losses, have lower loan loss provisions, and higher balance sheet strength during the 2007-2009 crisis period. Our findings highlight the implications of country level institutional factors for financial reporting quality and are relevant to bank regulators who are considering additional regulations on bank financial reporting. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kanagaretnam, Kiridaran; Lim, Chee Yeow; Lobo, Gerald J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does a leverage ratio requirement increase bank stability?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kiema, Ilkka; Jokivuolle, Esa
Basel III has introduced a non-risk-weighted leverage ratio requirement (LRR) which complements the internal ratings based (IRB) capital requirements. It provides a backstop against model risk which arises if some loans get incorrectly rated and become toxic. We study the effects of the LRR on lending strategies and its implications for banks' stability. We show that the LRR might induce banks with low-risk lending strategies to diversify their portfolios into high-risk loans until the LRR is no longer the binding capital constraint on them. If the LRR is lower than the average bank's IRB requirement, the aggregate capital costs of banks do not increase. However, because the diversification makes banks' portfolios more alike the banking sector as a whole may become more exposed to model risk in each loan category. This may undermine banking sector stability. On balance, our calibrated model motivates a significantly higher LRR than the current one. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kiema, Ilkka; Jokivuolle, Esa</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity crisis, relationship lending and corporate finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dewally, Michael; Shao, Yingying
This paper investigates the consequences of the liquidity shocks in wholesale funding markets during the 2007-2009 financial crisis on bank lending and corporate financing. We show that banks that relied more heavily on wholesale funding contracted lending more severely than banks that relied more on insured deposits. We then examine the effects of loan contraction on the financial positions of publicly traded firms. We find that both during and after the crisis, the change in leverage of bank-dependent firms is less than that of firms with access to public debt markets. In addition, bank-dependent firms rely more on cash than net equity issuance to finance operations. We also find that firms with established bank lending relationships weather the crisis better. Such firms are able to attain higher levels of leverage during the crisis, add to their cash holdings, secure new bank credit, and achieve higher profitability as a result. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dewally, Michael; Shao, Yingying</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The strategic reallocation of IPO shares</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertoni, Fabio; Giudici, Giancarlo
In this work, we study the reallocation of shares to retail and institutional investors, measured as the difference between the allocation declared before the initial public offering (IPO) and the effective allotment decided by the underwriter after the bookbuilding process. The reallocation is disaggregated into three components, two of which are under the direct control of the underwriter: the initial allocation, and the demand satisfaction ratio. The empirical analysis is based on a sample of 193 hybrid IPOs issued in Italy between 1997 and 2012. Controlling for firm and IPO characteristics, we find that the IPO shares are typically shifted toward institutional investors when positive information is collected during the bookbuilding process. The IPO pricing and share reallocation are found to be interdependent, and reallocation is used in combination with partial adjustment to reward institutional investors. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bertoni, Fabio; Giudici, Giancarlo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loss given default of residential mortgages in a low LTV regime: Role of foreclosure auction process and housing market cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Park, Yun W.; Bang, Doo Won
Using loan-level foreclosure auction data we study the loss given default (LGD) of defaulted residential mortgages originated in Korea, a low LTV regime. We find that senior mortgages generate very low loss rates (5-10%) while losses of subordinated claims are in 30-50% range. We document the effects of housing market cycles on loss severity by showing that collateral characteristics that are overvalued during the boom increase loss severity during the market downturn. We also investigate how a broad set of time-of-origination and post-origination information on loan, collateral and borrower characteristics and foreclosure auction process influence the LGD of residential mortgages. (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Park, Yun W.; Bang, Doo Won</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate financial structure, misallocation and total factor productivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Uras, Burak R.
This paper studies the quantitative relevance of the cross-sectional dispersion of corporate financial structure in explaining the intra-industry allocation efficiency of productive factors. I solve a heterogeneous firms model with financial constraints and distortions to the marginal rental-rate of capital, and develop a measure for the intra-industry misallocation of factors of production. The distribution of capital rental rate and two types of firm-level balance sheet characteristics (pledgeability and liquid asset positions) determine the extent of misallocation and industry level total factor productivity (TFP). I calibrate the model using firm-level balance sheet data from seven major industry clusters of the US economy. The counterfactual policy experiments show that weakening the observed balance sheet positions for financially constrained firms leads to a reallocation of production factors from firms with high cost distortions to firms with low cost distortions and cause quantitatively important industry level TFP losses. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Uras, Burak R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional development and bank stability: Evidence from transition countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fang, Yiwei; Hasan, Iftekhar; Marton, Katherin
This paper takes advantage of the dynamic nature of institutional reforms in transition economies and explores the causal effects of those reforms on bank risk. Using a difference-in-difference approach, we show that banks' financial stability increases substantially after these countries reform their legal institutions, liberalize banking, and restructure corporate governance. We also find that the effects of legal and governance reforms on bank risk may critically depend on the progress of banking reforms. A further examination of alternative risk measures reveals that the increases in financial stability among banks mainly come from the reduction of asset risk. Banks tend to have lower ROA volatility and fewer non-performing loans after reforming the institutional environment. Finally, we split our sample into foreign and domestic banks and find that the enhancement of financial stability is more pronounced for domestic banks. Crown Copyright (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fang, Yiwei; Hasan, Iftekhar; Marton, Katherin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Returns to scale at large banks in the US: A random coefficient stochastic frontier approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feng, Guohua; Zhang, Xiaohui
This paper investigates the returns to scale of large banks in the US over the period 1997-2010. This investigation is performed by estimating a random coefficient stochastic distance frontier model in the spirit of Tsionas (2002) and Greene (2005,2008). The primary advantage of this model is that its coefficients can vary across banks, thereby allowing for unobserved technology heterogeneity among large banks in the US We find that failure to consider unobserved technology heterogeneity results in a misleading ranking of banks and mismeasured returns to scale. Our results show that the majority of large banks in the US exhibit constant returns to scale. In addition, our results suggest that banks of the same size can have different levels of returns to scale and there is no clear pattern among large banks in the US concerning the relationship between asset size and returns to scale, due to the presence of technology heterogeneity. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Feng, Guohua; Zhang, Xiaohui</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange rates and fundamentals: Co-movement, long-run relationships and short-run dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekiros, Stelios D.
The present study builds upon the seminal work of Engel and West (2005) and in particular on the relationship between exchange rates and fundamentals. The paper discusses the well-known puzzle that fundamental variables such as money supply and interest rate, provide help in predicting changes in floating rates. It also tests the theoretical result of Engel and West (2005) that in a rational expectations present-value model, the asset price manifests near-random walk behaviour if the fundamentals are 1(1) and the factor for discounting future fundamentals is near one. The study explores the direction and nature of causal interdependencies among the most widely traded currencies in the world, their country-specific fundamentals and their US-differentials. A new VAR/VECM-GARCH multivariate filtering approach is implemented, whilst linear and nonlinear non-causality is tested and validated on simulated and empirical data. The evidence implies that there is no indication of a prevailing causal behaviour and when nonlinear effects are accounted for, the pattern of leads and lags changes over time. The variations in this linkage can be attributed to parameter instability in structural models, which may have little effect on FX forecastability over short horizons, yet it is significant for long-run cointegrating relationships. While it is difficult to reconcile these findings with the Rational Expectations hypothesis, the theory of Consistent Expectations or Bounded Rationality matches simulation and empirical findings more efficiently. Overall, fundamentals may be important determinants of FX rates, however there may be some other unobservable variables driving the currency rates that current asset-pricing models have not yet captured. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bekiros, Stelios D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market microstructure of the European climate exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mizrach, Bruce; Otsubo, Yoichi
This paper analyzes the market microstructure of the European Climate Exchange, the largest EU ETS trading venue. The ECX captures 2/3 of the screen traded market in EUA and more than 90% in CER. Volume growth has averaged 277% in EUA between 2005 and 2009 and 724% in CER since 2007. Spreads range from (sic)0.0188 to (sic)0.0406 for EUA and (sic)0.0276 to (sic)0.0796 for CER. The median proportion of the spread due to adverse selection reaches 76% for EUA and 75% for CER. Realized volatility, bid-ask spreads and adverse selection costs decline with verified emission releases. Market impact estimates imply that an average trade will move the EUA market by 1.06 euro centimes and the CER market 1.45. The ECX is providing between 75% and 88% of price discovery for EUA trading and between 64% and 72% for CER. We find imbalances in the order book help predict returns for up to three days. A simple trading strategy that enters the market long or short when the order imbalance is strong is profitable even after accounting for spreads and market impact. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mizrach, Bruce; Otsubo, Yoichi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are founding families special blockholders? An investigation of controlling shareholder influence on firm performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Isakov, Dusan; Weisskopf, Jean-Philippe
This paper examines how family and non-family ownership affects the performance of Swiss listed firms from 2003 to 2010. We distinguish between these two types of controlling shareholders since they have different objectives. We hypothesise that only family shareholders have a real incentive to reduce agency costs whereas non-family blockholders are similar to widely held companies. Our results show that family firms are more profitable than companies that are widely held or have a non-family blockholder. For market valuations we find that the family stake plays a critical role and document a concave relationship between family ownership and Tobin's Q, We also investigate the impact of different features of family firms on performance, and document that the generation of the family and the active involvement of the family play an important role for market valuation. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Isakov, Dusan; Weisskopf, Jean-Philippe</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank-SMEs relationships and banks' risk-adjusted profitability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fredriksson, Antti; Moro, Andrea
This research investigates how SME performance, the typology of loans and the length and scope of relationships between small banks and SMEs affect the margin adjusted for the risk that each customer generates. After analysing 4285 firm-year observations from Finnish banks, the quality of a SME's performance is found to be the major factor in explaining the risk-adjusted profitability of banks. However, the length and scope of a relationship and the loan dimensions also play an important role. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fredriksson, Antti; Moro, Andrea</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board changes and CEO turnover: The unanticipated effects of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dah, Mustafa A.; Frye, Melissa B.; Hurst, Matthew
The board independence requirements enacted in conjunction with the Sarbanes Oxley Act of 2002 (SOX) provided motivation for firms that were already compliant with the regulations to alter their board structure. We consider actual board changes made by compliant firms and how such changes affect the monitoring efficiency of the boards. We find that the majority of compliant firms (approximately 56%) add independent directors following SOX. However, we find a nontrivial number of firms (approximately 26%) actually decrease the number of independent directors to move closer to the stated 50% requirement. For firms that decrease independence, the CEO turnover performance sensitivity significantly decreases following SOX. We also find that large board independence changes seem to be most detrimental to the monitoring function of the board. Our results highlight that SOX may have had unintended consequences. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dah, Mustafa A.; Frye, Melissa B.; Hurst, Matthew</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial optimism and earnings smoothing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bouwman, Christa H. S.
This paper empirically examines how CEO optimism affects earnings smoothing and earnings surprises. The main finding is that optimistic managers smooth earnings more than rational managers and are associated with smaller (in absolute value) earnings surprises. A possible theoretical explanation is offered for these results based on a combination of the "torpedo effect," the innate behavior of optimists, and the risk of litigation/prosecution for over-reporting earnings. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bouwman, Christa H. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of CDS spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Galil, Koresh; Shapir, Offer Moshe; Amiram, Dan; Ben-Zion, Uri
This study proposes models that can be used as shorthand analysis tools for CDS spreads and CDS spread changes. For this purpose, we examine the determinants of CDS spreads and spread changes on a broad database of 718 US firms during the period from early 2002 to early 2013. Contrary to previous studies, we find that market variables have explanatory power after controlling for firm-specific variables inspired by structural models. Three explanatory variables appear to outperform the other variables examined in this paper: Stock Return, the change in stock return volatility, and the change in the median CDS spread in the rating class. We also find that models used in the event study literature to explain spread changes can be improved by adding market variables. Furthermore, we show that ratings explain cross-sectional variation in CDS spreads even after controlling for structural model variables. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Galil, Koresh; Shapir, Offer Moshe; Amiram, Dan; Ben-Zion, Uri</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor attention, index performance, and return predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vozlyublennaia, Nadia
We investigate a link between the performance of several security indexes in broad investment categories and investor attention as measured by Google search probability. We find that there is a significant short-term change in index returns following an increase in attention. Conversely, a shock to returns leads to a long-term change in attention. Given this evidence, we hypothesize that a change in index return or the sign of its return in the past can indicate the nature of the information that investors are paying attention to. Therefore, past returns should determine the impact of attention on the future returns and volatility. Indeed, we find significant interaction effects between lagged returns and attention. This result suggests that attention can alter predictability of index returns. Specifically, we demonstrate that increased investor attention diminishes return predictability and, therefore, improves market efficiency. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vozlyublennaia, Nadia</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does too much finance harm economic growth?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Law, Siong Hook; Singh, Nirvikar
This study provides new evidence on the relationship between finance and economic growth using an innovative dynamic panel threshold technique. The sample consists of 87 developed and developing countries. The empirical results indicate that there is a threshold effect in the finance-growth relationship. In particular, we find that the level of financial development is beneficial to growth only up to a certain threshold; beyond the threshold level further development of finance tends to adversely affect growth. These findings reveal that more finance is not necessarily good for economic growth and highlight that an "optimal" level of financial development is more crucial in facilitating growth. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Law, Siong Hook; Singh, Nirvikar</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking deregulation, consolidation, and corporate cash holdings: US evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Francis, Bill; Hasan, Iftekhar; Wang, Haizhi
This paper tests the effects of banking deregulation on the cash policies of nonbanking firms in the United States. We document a significant and negative relation between intrastate banking deregulation and corporate cash holdings. We show that the negative relation is driven by financially constrained firms, especially by constrained firms with low hedging needs. Further, we construct indexes measuring the intensity of bank consolidation in local markets. We find that the intensity of in-market bank mergers is negatively related to corporate cash holdings. However, in-market bank mergers in highly concentrated markets tend to be positively related to corporate cash holdings. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Francis, Bill; Hasan, Iftekhar; Wang, Haizhi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Almost marginal conditional stochastic dominance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Denuit, Michel M.; Huang, Rachel J.; Tzeng, Larry Y.; Wang, Christine W.
Marginal Conditional Stochastic Dominance (MCSD) developed by Shalit and Yitzhaki (1994) gives the conditions under which all risk-averse individuals prefer to increase the share of one risky asset over another in a given portfolio. In this paper, we extend this concept to provide conditions under which most (and not all) risk-averse investors behave in this way. Instead of stochastic dominance rules, almost stochastic dominance is used to assess the superiority of one asset over another in a given portfolio. Switching from MCSD to Almost MCSD (AMCSD) helps to reconcile common practices in asset allocation and the decision rules supporting stochastic dominance relations. A financial application is further provided to demonstrate that using AMCSD can indeed improve investment efficiency. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Denuit, Michel M.; Huang, Rachel J.; Tzeng, Larry Y.; Wang, Christine W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What factors drive systemic risk during international financial crises?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weiss, Gregor N. F.; Bostandzic, Denefa; Neumann, Sascha
We analyze the determinants of the contribution of international banks to both global and local systemic risk during prominent financial crises. We find no empirical evidence supporting conjectures that bank size, leverage, non-interest income or the quality of the bank's credit portfolio are persistent determinants of systemic risk across financial crises. In contrast, our results show that global systemic risk in particular is predominantly driven by characteristics of the regulatory regime. We also confirm for the subprime crisis that the banks' contribution to moderately bad tail events in the past predicts the financial sector's crash risk. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Weiss, Gregor N. F.; Bostandzic, Denefa; Neumann, Sascha</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing for a break in the persistence in yield spreads of EMU government bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sibbertsen, Philipp; Wegener, Christoph; Basse, Tobias
This study tests for a break in the persistence of EMU government bond yield spreads examining data from France, Italy and Spain and using German interest rates as a kind of benchmark. The results reported here provide evidence for breaks between 2006 and 2008. The persistence of the yield spreads against German government bonds has increased significantly after this period. This could be a sign of higher sovereign credit risk (and possibly even redenomination risk) caused by the debt crisis in the euro area. We find clear indications for non-stationary behavior after the breakpoints and empirical evidence for positive excess kurtosis and GARCH-effects when persistence increases. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sibbertsen, Philipp; Wegener, Christoph; Basse, Tobias</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How important is the credit channel? An empirical study of the US banking crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Chunping; Minford, Patrick
We examine whether by adding a credit channel to the standard New Keynesian model we can account better for the behaviour of US macroeconomic data up to and including the banking crisis. We use the method of indirect inference which evaluates statistically how far a model's simulated behaviour mimics the behaviour of the data. We find that the model with credit dominates the standard model by a substantial margin. Credit shocks are the main contributor to the variation in the output gap during the crisis. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Chunping; Minford, Patrick</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium credit: The reference point for macroprudential supervisors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buncic, Daniel; Melecky, Martin
Equilibrium credit is an important concept because it helps to identify excessive credit provision in an economy. This paper proposes a structural approach to determine equilibrium credit which is based on the long-run through-the-cycle transaction demand for credit. Using a panel data set consisting of 49 high and middle-income countries from 1980 to 2010, we show that there exists considerable variation in the cross-country estimates of the income and price elasticities of credit and that the unit elasticity restriction implicitly imposed by the credit-to-GDP ratio is strongly rejected by the data. This suggests that the credit-to-GDP ratio is not appropriate to measure equilibrium credit. We show further that the cross-sectional variation in the income and price elasticities of credit can be related to a set of relevant economic, financial and institutional development indicators of a country. The main determinants that explain the cross-sectional variation in the income and price elasticities are financial depth, access to financial services, use of capital markets, efficiency and funding of domestic banks, central bank independence, the degree of supervisory integration, and the experience of a financial crisis. As an empirical illustration, we compute equilibrium credit and credit gaps for eleven new EU member states using our structural framework and compare it to credit gaps based on the Basel III approach. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buncic, Daniel; Melecky, Martin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Has market discipline on banks improved after the Dodd-Frank Act?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balasubramnian, Bhanu; Cyree, Ken B.
We investigate whether or not market discipline on banking firms changed after the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (DFA) of 2010. If market discipline is improved, we should see a lower discount for size on yield spreads, particularly for banks identified as too-big-to-fail (TBTF) or systemically important (SIFI). Using secondary market subordinated debt transactions we find that the size discount is reduced by 47% and TBTF discount is reduced by 94% after the DFA. The DFA has been effective in reducing, but not in eliminating the size and TBTF discounts on yield spreads. Market discipline of banks appears to have improved further after the rating criteria changes by Moody's. (C) 2014 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Balasubramnian, Bhanu; Cyree, Ken B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of price discovery from panel data models of CDS and equity returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Narayan, Paresh Kumar; Sharma, Susan Sunila; Thuraisamy, Kannan Sivananthan
We propose a panel data model of price discovery. We find that the stock market contributes to price discovery in most sectors while the Credit Default Swap (CDS) market contributes to price discovery in only a few sectors. We discover that in sectors where both the stock market and the CDS market contribute to price discovery, it is the stock market that dominates the price discovery process. When we consider investment grade stocks, the importance of the CDS market in price discovery improves but the stock market still dominates the price discovery process. The results for different sizes of stocks generally suggest that both markets are important for price discovery but it is the stock market that dominates. We also find that while the price discovery process was affected by the 2007 global financial crisis, the stock market still dominated the price discovery process. Finally, in an economic significance analysis, we show that investors in the CDS market are able to make relatively more profits from a forecasting model that takes into account price discovery compared to a model that simply ignores the role of price discovery. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Narayan, Paresh Kumar; Sharma, Susan Sunila; Thuraisamy, Kannan Sivananthan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition, premature trading and excess volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deb, Pragyan; Koo, Bonsoo; Liu, Zijun
A substantial body of research suggests that it is difficult to account for all of the volatility of asset prices in terms of news. This paper attempts to explain the excess volatility puzzle as a consequence of competitive interaction between market participants in the presence of noisy information. We develop a model of competitive interaction between market participants in response to unverified information. Our model shows that in the presence of competitive pressures, market participants find it optimal to act prematurely on unverified information. This premature reaction leads to lower total profits and excess market volatility in equilibrium. Our model also shows that the spike in volatility at the closing time of the market can be modelled as a direct consequence of premature trading. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Deb, Pragyan; Koo, Bonsoo; Liu, Zijun</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tax evasion, financial development and inflation: Theory and empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bittencourt, Manoel; Gupta, Rangan; Stander, Lardo
Using a standard overlapping generations monetary production economy, faced with endogenously determined tax evasion by heterogeneous agents in the economy, we provide a theoretical model that indicates that both a lower (higher) level of financial development and a higher (lower) level of inflation leads to a bigger (smaller) shadow economy. These findings are empirically tested within a panel econometric framework, using data collected for 150 countries over the period 1980-2009 to enable a broad generalisation of the results. The results support the developed theoretical model, even after having accounted for the differences in the levels of economic development, the level of institutional quality that includes different tax regimes and regulatory frameworks, central bank participation in the economy as well as different macroeconomic policies. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bittencourt, Manoel; Gupta, Rangan; Stander, Lardo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impacts of Gramm-Leach-Bliley bank diversification on value and risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Filson, Darren; Olfati, Saman
Combined abnormal returns from U.S. bank holding company acquisitions during 2001-2011 suggest that diversification into investment banking, securities brokerage and insurance under the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act of 1999 creates value. Exceptional returns depend on contributing factors; the most robust are that the acquirer is large and has experienced negative returns over the prior year (characteristics consistent with models of optimal diversification). Results are inconclusive on whether the impact of acquirer size is a too-big-to-fail effect, but acquirer characteristics are associated with adverse consequences: large size is associated with increasing systematic risk, and falling acquirer values are associated with increasing idiosyncratic risk. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Filson, Darren; Olfati, Saman</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Clustering of intraday order-sizes by uninformed versus informed traders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garvey, Ryan; Wu, Fei
We examine quantity choice patterns by equity traders across trading hours in the U.S. Controlling for intraday variations in trading activity, we find that traders submit more non-rounded order sizes and more order sizes overall leading up to a day's market close. Traders who submit more distinct order sizes pay a higher cost to trade, and they are also less informed about future prices. Our results suggest that the goal to satisfy specific quantity demands rises across the day. This differs from total trading demand, which resembles a U-shape pattern intraday, but is consistent with less trade-size clustering at the ends of fiscal quarters. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Garvey, Ryan; Wu, Fei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Subprime cohorts and loan performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhardwaj, Geetesh; Sengupta, Rajdeep
Loan performance of subprime originations during the boom years of 2004-2006 is contrasted with that of subprime originations during the early period of 2000-2002. A counterfactual technique is developed to determine how originations during the early period would perform in a different environment, namely, the environment faced by originations of 2004,2005, and 2006. In an environment where house prices are increasing rapidly, low credit score originations do not show high rates of default as was witnessed for 2000-2002 cohorts. However, in an environment of stagnant or deteriorating home prices, low credit score originations show significantly higher rates of default than high credit score originations. With a greater proportion of low credit score originations, earlier cohorts of 2000-2002 were no less vulnerable to the environment faced by cohorts of 2004-2006. In essence, these results raise concerns about the viability of all cohorts of subprime originations because of their reliance on the appreciation of the underlying collateral rather than the creditworthiness of the borrower. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bhardwaj, Geetesh; Sengupta, Rajdeep</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank income smoothing, ownership concentration and the regulatory environment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bouvatier, Vincent; Lepetit, Laetitia; Strobel, Frank
We empirically examine whether the way a bank might use loan loss provisions to smooth its income is influenced by its ownership concentration and the regulatory environment. Using a panel of European commercial banks, we find evidence that banks with more concentrated ownership use discretionary loan loss provisions to smooth their income. This behavior is less pronounced in countries with stronger supervisory regimes or higher external audit quality. Banks with low levels of ownership concentration do not display such discretionary income smoothing behavior. This suggests the need to improve existing or implement new corporate governance mechanisms. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bouvatier, Vincent; Lepetit, Laetitia; Strobel, Frank</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The rise and fall of technical trading rule success</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, Nick
The purpose of this paper is to examine the performance of an important set of momentum-based technical trading rules (TTRs) applied to all members of the Dow Jones Industrial Average (DJIA) stock index over the period 1928-2012. Using a set of econometric models that permit time-variation in risk-adjusted returns to TTR portfolios, the results reveal that profits evolve slowly over time, are confined to particular episodes primarily from the mid-1960s to mid-1980s, and rely on the ability of investors to short-sell stocks. These findings are demonstrated to be consistent with theoretical models that predict a relationship between TTR performance and market conditions. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Taylor, Nick</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The importance of the volatility risk premium for volatility forecasting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Prokopczuk, Marcel; Simen, Chardin Wese
In this paper, we study the role of the volatility risk premium for the forecasting performance of implied volatility. We introduce a non-parametric and parsimonious approach to adjust the model-free implied volatility for the volatility risk premium and implement this methodology using more than 20 years of options and futures data on three major energy markets. Using regression models and statistical loss functions, we find compelling evidence to suggest that the risk premium adjusted implied volatility significantly outperforms other models, including its unadjusted counterpart. Our main finding holds for different choices of volatility estimators and competing time-series models, underlying the robustness of our results. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Prokopczuk, Marcel; Simen, Chardin Wese</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The empirical similarity approach for volatility prediction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golosnoy, Vasyl; Hamid, Alain; Okhrin, Yarema
In this paper we adapt the empirical similarity (ES) concept for the purpose of combining volatility forecasts originating from different models. Our ES approach is suitable for situations where a decision maker refrains from evaluating success probabilities of forecasting models but prefers to think by analogy. It allows to determine weights of the forecasting combination by quantifying distances between model predictions and corresponding realizations of the process of interest as they are perceived by decision makers. The proposed ES approach is applied for combining models in order to forecast daily volatility of the major stock market indices. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Golosnoy, Vasyl; Hamid, Alain; Okhrin, Yarema</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive compensation structure and the motivations for seasoned equity offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brisker, Eric R.; Autore, Don M.; Colak, Gonul; Peterson, David R.
We hypothesize that managers who receive high equity-based compensation have greater incentive to avoid ownership dilution by timing their seasoned equity offers to periods when investors temporarily overvalue their stock. We provide empirical support for this hypothesis using a measure of equity-based compensation that reflects the sensitivity of the top five executives' wealth (based on ownership of stock, options, and restricted shares) to a 1% change in stock price. We find that firms associated with high equity-based compensation for top executives experience abnormally low stock returns and relatively unfavorable changes in operating performance in the three-year period following the issue. Overall, the findings support the premise that managers whose wealth is most sensitive to stock price changes are more likely to act in the interest of current shareholders by issuing equity when they believe their stock is overvalued. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brisker, Eric R.; Autore, Don M.; Colak, Gonul; Peterson, David R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are there common factors in individual commodity futures returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Daskalaki, Charoula; Kostakis, Alexandros; Skiadopoulos, George
We explore whether there are common factors in the cross-section of individual commodity futures returns. We test various asset pricing models which have been employed for the equities market as well as models motivated by commodity pricing theories. The use of these families of models allows us also to test whether the commodities and equities market are integrated. In addition, we employ principal components factor models which do not require a priori specification of factors. We find that none of the models is successful. Our results imply that commodity markets are segmented from the equities market and they are considerably heterogeneous per se. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Daskalaki, Charoula; Kostakis, Alexandros; Skiadopoulos, George</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loss given default for leasing: Parametric and nonparametric estimations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hartmann-Wendels, Thomas; Miller, Patrick; Toews, Eugen
This study employs a dataset from three German leasing companies with 14,322 defaulted leasing contracts to analyze different approaches to estimating the loss given default (LGD). Using the historical average LGD and simple OLS-regression as benchmarks, we compare hybrid finite mixture models (FMMs), model trees and regression trees and we calculate the mean absolute error, root mean squared error, and the Theil inequality coefficient. The relative estimation accuracy of the methods depends, among other things, on the number of observations and whether in-sample or out-of-sample estimations are considered. The latter is decisive for proper risk management and is required for regulatory purposes. FMMs aim to reproduce the distribution of realized LGDs and, therefore, perform best with respect to in-sample estimations, but they show poor performance with respect to out-of-sample estimations. Model trees, by contrast, are more robust and outperform all other methods if the sample size is sufficiently large. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hartmann-Wendels, Thomas; Miller, Patrick; Toews, Eugen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Audit committees' oversight of bank risk-taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Jerry; Liu, Guoping
This study examines whether audit committee effectiveness affects bank risk-taking and risk management effectiveness. We find that banks with long board tenure audit committees have lower total risk and idiosyncratic risk, and banks with busy directors on their audit committees have higher total risk and idiosyncratic risk. These suggest that high audit committee effectiveness may constrain bank risk-taking activities. We also find that firm performance is more positively associated with bank risk for banks with long board tenure, more female audit committee members, or large size audit committees than for other banks, consistent with the notion that audit committee effectiveness may increase risk management effectiveness. However, this finding should be interpreted cautiously as it is contrary to the results on audit committee busyness.(C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sun, Jerry; Liu, Guoping</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of risk-taking behavior for public defined benefit pension plans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mohan, Nancy; Zhang, Ting
This paper presents the first comprehensive study on the determinants of public pension fund investment risk and reports several new important findings. Unlike private pension plans, public funds undertake more risk if they are underfunded and have lower investment returns in the previous years, consistent with the risk transfer hypothesis. Furthermore, pension funds in states facing fiscal constraints allocate more assets to equity and have higher betas. There also appears to be a herding effect in that CalPERS equity allocation or beta is mimicked by other pension funds. Finally, our results suggest that government accounting standards strongly affect pension fund risk, as higher return assumptions (used to discount pension liabilities) are associated with higher equity allocation and portfolio beta. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mohan, Nancy; Zhang, Ting</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>