<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Journal of Financial Economics3</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Dynamic debt runs and financial fragility: Evidence from the 2007 ABCP crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schroth, Enrique; Suarez, Gustavo A.; Taylor, Lucian A.
We use the 2007 asset-backed commercial paper (ABCP) crisis as a laboratory to study the determinants of debt runs. Our model features dilution risk: maturing short-term lenders demand higher yields in compensation for being diluted by future lenders, making runs more likely. The model explains the observed tenfold increase in yield spreads leading to runs and the positive relation between yield spreads and future runs. Results from structural estimation show that runs are very sensitive to leverage, asset values, and asset liquidity, but less sensitive to the degree of maturity mismatch, the strength of guarantees, and asset volatility. (C) 2014 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. This is an open access article under the CC BY license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/).</description><author>Schroth, Enrique; Suarez, Gustavo A.; Taylor, Lucian A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The internal capital markets of business groups: Evidence from intra-group loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buchuk, David; Larrain, Borja; Munoz, Francisco; Urzua, Francisco
We study business groups' internal capital markets using a unique data set on intra-group lending in Chile (1990-2009). In line with groups financing advantage, firms that borrow internally have higher investment, leverage, and return on equity (ROE) than other firms. At the margin, controlling shareholders have higher cash-flow rights in borrowing firms than in lending firms. However, there is no robust evidence of minority shareholders losing out from intra-group loans as tunneling predicts. Our evidence is consistent with the idea that strict regulation and disclosure requirements for intra-group loans, which are features of the Chilean market, reduce the risk of expropriation in pyramids. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Buchuk, David; Larrain, Borja; Munoz, Francisco; Urzua, Francisco</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The price of skill: Performance evaluation by households</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Savoy, Alexi
Skilled investors make money off uninformed investors. By acting as intermediaries, they provide a hedge to the uninformed investors themselves. I present a model in which households have imperfect information about expected returns. Non-traded income shocks lead them to rebalance, sometimes at the wrong time. Active funds hedge this risk by trading on superior information. In equilibrium, they pay off when non-traded income disappoints, earning a premium that makes them appear to underperform index funds after fees. Empirical results using aggregate fund flows support the model. A corresponding asset pricing test can account for the apparent underperformance of active funds. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Savoy, Alexi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Birds of a feather: Value implications of political alignment between top management and directors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Jongsub; Lee, Kwang J.; Nagarajan, Nandu J.
For 2,695 US corporations from 1996 to 2009, we find that alignment in political orientation between the chief executive officer (CEO) and independent directors is associated with lower firm valuations, lower operating profitability, and increased internal agency conflicts such as a reduced likelihood of dismissing poorly performing CEOs, a lower CEO pay-performance sensitivity, and a greater likelihood of accounting fraud. Importantly, we show that our results are driven neither by the effects associated with various measures of similarity and diversity within the board nor the effects of local director labor market and political conditions on board structure. We provide evidence that our measure of individual political orientation reflects the person's political beliefs rather than opportunistic attempts to seek political favor. Overall, our results suggest that diversity in political beliefs among corporate board members is valuable. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Lee, Jongsub; Lee, Kwang J.; Nagarajan, Nandu J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Elections, political competition and bank failure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Wai-Man; Ngo, Phong T. H.
We exploit exogenous variation in the scheduling of gubernatorial elections to study the timing of bank failure in the US. Using hazard analysis, we show that bank failure is about 45% less likely in the year leading up to an election. Political control (i.e., lack of competition) can explain all of this average election year fall in the hazard rate. In particular, we show that the reduction in hazard rate doubles in magnitude for banks operating in states where the governor has simultaneous control of the upper and lower houses of the state legislature (i.e., complete control) heading into an election. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Wai-Man; Ngo, Phong T. H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing: A tale of two days</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Savor, Pavel; Wilson, Mungo
We show that asset prices behave very differently on days when important macroeconomic news is scheduled for announcement. In addition to significantly higher average returns for risky assets on announcement days, return patterns are much easier to reconcile with standard asset pricing theories, both cross-sectionally and over time. On such days, stock market beta is strongly related to average returns. This positive relation holds for individual stocks, for various test portfolios, and even for bonds and currencies, suggesting that beta is after all an important measure of systematic risk. Furthermore, a robust risk-return trade-off exists on announcement days. Expected variance is positively related to future aggregated quarterly announcement day returns, but not to aggregated non-announcement day returns. We explore the implications of our findings in the context of various asset pricing models. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Savor, Pavel; Wilson, Mungo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market returns and annuitization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Previtero, Alessandro
I investigate the strong negative relation between recent stock returns and the annuitization of retirement savings using a novel data set with over 100,000 actual payout decisions. After controlling for several standard explanations (e.g., wealth effects), I present evidence supporting naive beliefs and extrapolation from past returns. The effect of recent returns on annuitization dramatically increases with age, confirming that the elderly rely most heavily on recent information. My results provide insights into how beliefs are formed in old age and have implications for the design of public policies seeking to promote annuitization. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Previtero, Alessandro</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The genetics of investment biases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cronqvist, Henrik; Siegel, Stephan
For a long list of investment "biases," including lack of diversification, excessive trading, and the disposition effect, we find that genetic differences explain up to 45% of the remaining variation across individual investors, after controlling for observable individual characteristics. The evidence is consistent with a view that investment biases are manifestations of innate and evolutionary ancient features of human behavior. We find that work experience with finance reduces genetic predispositions to investment biases. Finally, we find that even genetically identical investors, who grew up in the same family environment, often differ substantially in their investment behaviors due to individual-specific experiences or events. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cronqvist, Henrik; Siegel, Stephan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading networks and liquidity provision</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen-Cole, Ethan; Kirilenko, Andrei; Patacchini, Eleonora
We study the profitability of traders in two fully electronic and highly liquid markets: the Dow and Standard &amp; Poor's 500 e-mini futures markets. Using unique information that identify counterparties to a transaction, we show and seek to explain the fact that the network pattern of trades captures the relations between behavior in the market and returns. Our approach includes a simple representation of how much a shock is amplified by the network and how widely it is transmitted. This representation provides a possible shorthand for understanding the consequences of a fat-finger trade, a withdrawing of liquidity, or other market shock. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cohen-Cole, Ethan; Kirilenko, Andrei; Patacchini, Eleonora</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Idealized Electoral College voting mechanism and shareholder power</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Van Wesep, Edward D.
Increasing concern over corporate governance has led to calls for more shareholder influence over corporate decisions, but allowing shareholders to vote on more issues may not affect the quality of governance. We should expect instead that, under current rules, shareholder voting will implement the preferences of the majority of large shareholders and management. This is because majority rule offers little incentive for small shareholders to vote. I offer a potential remedy in the form of a new voting rule, the Idealized Electoral College (IEC), modeled on the American Electoral College, that significantly increases the expected impact that a given shareholder has on election. The benefit of the mechanism is that it induces greater turnout, but the cost is that it sometimes assigns a winner that is not preferred by a majority of voters. Therefore, for issues on which management and small shareholders are likely to disagree, the IEC is superior to majority rule. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Van Wesep, Edward D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Safer ratios, riskier portfolios: Banks' response to government aid</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duchin, Ran; Sosyura, Denis
Using novel data on bank applications to the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP), we study the effect of government assistance on bank risk taking. Bailed-out banks initiate riskier loans and shift assets toward riskier securities after receiving government support. However, this shift in risk occurs mostly within the same asset class and, therefore, remains undetected by regulatory capital ratios, which indicate improved capitalization at bailed-out banks. Consequently, these banks appear safer according to regulatory ratios, but show an increase in volatility and default risk. These findings are robust to controlling for credit demand and account for selection of TARP recipients by exploiting banks' geography-based political connections as an instrument for bailout approvals. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duchin, Ran; Sosyura, Denis</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Winners in the spotlight: Media coverage of fund holdings as a driver of flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Solomon, David H.; Soltes, Eugene; Sosyura, Denis
We show that media coverage of mutual fund holdings affects how investors allocate money across funds. Fund holdings with high past returns attract extra flows, but only if these stocks were recently featured in the media. In contrast, holdings that were not covered in major newspapers do not affect flows. We present evidence that media coverage tends to contribute to investors' chasing of past returns rather than facilitate the processing of useful information in fund portfolios. Our evidence suggests that media coverage can exacerbate investor biases and that it is the primary mechanism that makes fund window dressing effective. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Solomon, David H.; Soltes, Eugene; Sosyura, Denis</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beauty is in the eye of the beholder: The effect of corporate tax avoidance on the cost of bank loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasan, Iftekhar; Hoi, Chun Keung; Wu, Qiang; Zhang, Hao
We find that firms with greater tax avoidance incur higher spreads when obtaining bank loans. This finding is robust in a battery of sensitivity analyses and in two quasi-experimental settings including the implementation of Financial Accounting Standards Board Interpretation No. 48 and the revelation of past tax sheltering activity. Firms with greater tax avoidance also incur more stringent nonprice loan terms, incur higher at-issue bond spreads, and prefer bank loans over public bonds when obtaining debt financing. Overall, these findings indicate that banks perceive tax avoidance as engendering significant risks. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hasan, Iftekhar; Hoi, Chun Keung; Wu, Qiang; Zhang, Hao</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tailspotting: Identifying and profiting from CEO vacation trips</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yermack, David
This paper shows connections between chief executive officers' (CEOs') absences from headquarters and corporate news disclosures. I identify CEO absences by merging records of corporate jet flights and CEOs' property ownership near leisure destinations. CEOs travel to their vacation homes just after companies report favorable news, and CEOs return to headquarters right before subsequent news releases. When CEOs are away, companies announce less news, mandatory disclosures occur later, and stock volatility falls sharply. Volatility increases when CEOs return to work. CEOs spend fewer days out of the office when ownership is high and when weather is bad at their vacation homes. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yermack, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predatory lending and the subprime crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit; Amromin, Gene; Ben-David, Itzhak; Chomsisengphet, Souphala; Evanoff, Douglas D.
We measure the effect of a 2006 antipredatory pilot program in Chicago on mortgage default rates to test whether predatory lending was a key element in fueling the subprime crisis. Under the program, risky borrowers or risky mortgage contracts or both triggered review sessions by housing counselors who shared their findings with the state regulator. The pilot program cut market activity in half, largely through the exit of lenders specializing in risky loans and through a decline in the share of subprime borrowers. Our results suggest that predatory lending practices contributed to high mortgage default rates among subprime borrowers, raising them by about a third. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; Amromin, Gene; Ben-David, Itzhak; Chomsisengphet, Souphala; Evanoff, Douglas D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comovement and investment banking networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grullon, Gustavo; Underwood, Shane; Weston, James P.
We test the hypothesis that investment banking networks affect stock prices and trading behavior. Consistent with the notion that investment banks serve as information hubs for segmented groups of investors, the stock prices of firms that use the same lead underwriter during their equity offerings tend to move together. We also find that when firms switch underwriters between their initial public offering (IPO) and a seasoned equity offering (SEO), they comove less with the stocks associated with the old bank and more with the stocks associated with the new bank. This change in comovement is greater for stocks completing their first SEO and for those experiencing large changes in institutional ownership. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grullon, Gustavo; Underwood, Shane; Weston, James P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance evaluation with high moments and disaster risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kadan, Ohad; Liu, Fang
Traditional performance evaluation measures do not account for tail events and rare disasters. To address this issue, we reinterpret the riskiness measures of Aumann and Serrano (2008) and Foster and Hart (2009) as performance indices. We derive the moment properties of these indices and their sensitivity to rare disasters and show that they are consistent with the asset pricing literature. As applications, we show that "anomalous" investment strategies such as "momentum" or investment in private equity lose much of their glamour when accounting for high moments and rare events. Furthermore, using the indices to select mutual funds results in desirable high-moment properties out of sample. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kadan, Ohad; Liu, Fang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A dynamic limit order market with fast and slow traders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoffmann, Peter
This paper considers the role of high-frequency trading in a dynamic limit order market. Fast traders' ability to revise their quotes quickly after news arrivals helps to reduce the inefficiency that is rooted in the risk of being picked off, which increases trade. However, their presence induces slow traders to strategically submit limit orders with a lower execution probability, thereby reducing trade. Because speed is a source of market power, it enables fast traders to extract rents from other market participants and triggers a costly arms race that reduces social welfare. The model generates a number of testable implications concerning the effects of high-frequency trading in limit order markets. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hoffmann, Peter</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mortgage convexity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanson, Samuel G.
Most home mortgages in the United States are fixed-rate loans with an embedded prepayment option. When long-term rates decline, the effective duration of mortgage-backed securities (MBS) falls due to heightened refinancing expectations. I show that these changes in MBS duration function as large-scale shocks to the quantity of interest rate risk that must be borne by professional bond investors. I develop a simple model in which the risk tolerance of bond investors is limited in the short run, so these fluctuations in MBS duration generate significant variation in bond risk premia. Specifically, bond risk premia are high when aggregate MBS duration is high. The model offers an explanation for why long-term rates could appear to be excessively sensitive to movements in short rates and explains how changes in MBS duration act as a positive-feedback mechanism that amplifies interest rate volatility. I find strong support for these predictions in the time series of US government bond returns. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hanson, Samuel G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Income hedging and portfolio decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bonaparte, Yosef; Korniotis, George M.; Kumar, Alok
We examine whether the decision to participate in the stock market and other related portfolio decisions are influenced by income hedging motives. Economic theory predicts that the market participation propensity should increase as the correlation between income growth and stock market returns decreases. Surprisingly, empirical studies find limited support for the income hedging motive. Using a rich, unique Dutch data set and the National Longitudinal Survey of the Youth (NLSY) from the United States, we show that when the income-return correlation is low, individuals exhibit a greater propensity to participate in the market and allocate a larger proportion of their wealth to risky assets. Even when the income risk is high, individuals exhibit a higher propensity to participate in the market when the hedging potential is high. These findings suggest that income hedging is an important determinant of stock market participation and asset allocation decisions. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bonaparte, Yosef; Korniotis, George M.; Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Networks and productivity: Causal evidence from editor rotations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brogaard, Jonathan; Engelberg, Joseph; Parsons, Christopher A.
Using detailed publication and citation data for over 50,000 articles from 30 major economics and finance journals, we investigate whether network proximity to an editor influences research productivity. During an editor's tenure, his current university colleagues publish about 100% more papers in the editor's journal, compared to years when he is not editor. In contrast to editorial nepotism, such "inside" articles have significantly higher ex post citation counts, even when same-journal and self-cites are excluded. Our results thus suggest that despite potential conflicts of interest faced by editors, personal associations are used to improve selection decisions. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brogaard, Jonathan; Engelberg, Joseph; Parsons, Christopher A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-changed Levy LIBOR market model: Pricing and joint estimation of the cap surface and swaption cube</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leippold, Markus; Stromberg, Jacob
We propose a novel time-changed Levy LIBOR (London Interbank Offered Rate) market model for jointly pricing of caps and swaptions. The time changes are split into three components. The first component allows matching the volatility term structure, the second generates stochastic volatility, and the third accommodates for stochastic skew. The parsimonious model is flexible enough to accommodate the behavior of both caps and swaptions. For the joint estimation we use a comprehensive data set spanning the financial crisis of 2007-2010. We find that, even during this period, neither market is as fragmented as suggested by the previous literature. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Leippold, Markus; Stromberg, Jacob</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk tolerance and entrepreneurship</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hvide, Hans K.; Panos, Georgios A.
A theoretical tradition argues that more risk tolerant individuals are more likely to become entrepreneurs but perform worse. We test and confirm these predictions with several risk tolerance proxies. Using investment data for 400,000 individuals, we find that common stock investors are around 50% more likely to subsequently start up a firm. Firms started up by common stock investors have about 25% lower sales and 15% lower return on assets. The results are similar using personal leverage and other risk-tolerance proxies. We do not find support for alternative explanations such as unobserved wealth or behavioral effects. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hvide, Hans K.; Panos, Georgios A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of diffusing information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Manela, Asaf
How does the speed by which information diffuses affect its value to a stock market investor? In a structural model solved in closed-form, this speed has two opposing effects on the empirically dominant term of the value of information. Faster-diffusing information means quicker and less noisy profits, but, also increases competing informed trading, impounding more information into prices and eroding profits. Structural empirical analysis of stock market reaction to drug approvals using media coverage as a proxy for the transmission rate of information finds that the value of information is hump-shaped in its future transmission rate. Moreover, the estimated amount of noise trading is small. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Manela, Asaf</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are red or blue companies more likely to go green? Politics and corporate social responsibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Di Giuli, Alberta; Kostovetsky, Leonard
Using the firm-level corporate social responsibility (CSR) ratings of Kinder, Lydenberg, Domini, we find that firms score higher on CSR when they have Democratic rather than Republican founders, CEOs, and directors, and when they are headquartered in Democratic rather than Republican-leaning states. Democratic-leaning firms spend $20 million more on CSR than Republican-leaning firms ($80 million more within the sample of S&amp;P 500 firms), or roughly 10% of net income. We find no evidence that firms recover these expenditures through increased sales. Indeed, increases in firm CSR ratings are associated with negative future stock returns and declines in firm ROA, suggesting that any benefits to stakeholders from social responsibility come at the direct expense of firm value. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Di Giuli, Alberta; Kostovetsky, Leonard</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment busts, reputation, and the temptation to blend in with the crowd</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grenadier, Steven R.; Malenko, Andrey; Strebulaev, Ilya A.
We provide a real-options model of an industry in which agents time abandonment of their projects in an effort to protect their reputations. Agents delay abandonment attempting to signal quality. When a public common shock forces abandonment of a small fraction of projects irrespective of agents' quality, many agents abandon their projects strategically even if they are unaffected by the shock. Such "blending in with the crowd" effect creates an additional incentive to delay abandonment ahead of the shock, leading to accumulation of "living dead" projects, which further amplifies the shock. The potential for moderate public common shocks often improves agents' values. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grenadier, Steven R.; Malenko, Andrey; Strebulaev, Ilya A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Politicians and the IPO decision: The impact of impending political promotions on IPO activity in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Piotroski, Joseph D.; Zhang, Tianyu
This paper shows that incentives created by the impending turnover of local politicians can accelerate the pace of initial public offering (IPO) activity in certain politicized environments. Focusing on China, we exploit a research setting where politicians are rewarded for capital market development, firms rely on political connections for access to capital, rent-seeking behavior is rampant, and the objectives of the state might not be to maximize capital market efficiency. We find that the rate of exchange eligible firms engaging in an IPO temporarily increases in advance of impending political promotion events. This effect holds for both state-owned and non-state-owned entities. For state-owned firms, the effect is strongest in those provinces where the politicians are more likely to be rewarded for market development activity. For non-state-owned firms, the temporary increase in IPO activity appears to be (rationally) opportunistic in nature, with the effect stronger around events more likely to disrupt the firms' political connections. Promotion period IPOs underperform non-promotion period IPOs in terms of both future financial performance and long-run stock returns, have controlling shareholders who retain a larger fraction of the company, and are more likely to divert proceeds away from their intended use after the offering. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Piotroski, Joseph D.; Zhang, Tianyu</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of stock ownership by US members of Congress on the market for political favors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tahoun, Ahmed
I examine whether stock ownership by politicians helps to enforce noncontractible quid pro quo relations with firms. The ownership by US Congress members in firms contributing to their election campaigns is higher than in noncontributors. This bias toward contributors depends on the financial incentives of politicians and the relation's value. Firms with a stronger ownership-contribution association receive more government contracts. The financial gains from these contracts are economically large. When politicians divest stocks, firms discontinue contributions to the politicians, lose future contracts, and perform poorly. Politicians divest the stocks in contributors, but not in noncontributors, in anticipation of retirement. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tahoun, Ahmed</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government policy and ownership of equity securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rydqvist, Kristian; Spizman, Joshua; Strebulaev, Ilya
Since World War II, direct stock ownership by households across the globe has largely been replaced by indirect stock ownership by financial institutions. We argue that tax and retirement policies are among the factors behind these changes. We develop empirical measures of two tax incentives of holding stocks inside tax-deferred plans, tax-free investment income and the smoothing benefit. Using long time-series from eight countries, we show that the fraction of household ownership decreases with these measures of the tax benefits. This finding contributes to policy debates on effective taxation and to financial economics research on the long-term effects of taxation on corporate finance and asset prices. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rydqvist, Kristian; Spizman, Joshua; Strebulaev, Ilya</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Syndicated loan spreads and the composition of the syndicate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lim, Jongha; Minton, Bernadette A.; Weisbach, Michael S.
During the past decade, non-bank institutional investors are increasingly taking larger roles in the corporate lending than they historically have played. These non-bank institutional lenders typically have higher required rates of return than banks, but invest in the same loan facilities. In a sample of 20,031 leveraged loan facilities originated between 1997 and 2007, facilities including a non-bank institution in their syndicates have higher spreads than otherwise identical bank-only facilities. Contrary to risk-based explanations of this finding, non-bank facilities are priced with premiums relative to bank-only facilities in the same loan package. These non-bank premiums are substantially larger when a hedge or private equity fund is one of the syndicate members. Consistent with the notion that firms are willing to pay a premium when loan facilities are particularly important to them, the non-bank premiums are larger when borrowing firms face financial constraints and when capital is less available from banks. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lim, Jongha; Minton, Bernadette A.; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overcoming limits of arbitrage: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hombert, Johan; Thesmar, David
Limits to arbitrage arise because financial intermediaries may face funding constraints when mispricing worsens. Using a model with limits to arbitrage, where we allow arbitrageurs to secure capital even in case of underperformance, we show that arbitrageurs that are more protected from withdrawals have more mean-reverting and volatile returns. Using data on hedge fund performance, we find robust support for these hypotheses: Funds with contractual impediments to withdrawals, and funds with performance-insensitive outflows, recover more quickly after a bad year and have more volatile returns. Our evidence is consistent with the idea that some hedge funds overcome the limits to arbitrage. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hombert, Johan; Thesmar, David</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Betting against beta</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frazzini, Andrea; Pedersen, Lasse Heje
We present a model with leverage and margin constraints that vary across investors and time. We find evidence consistent with each of the model's five central predictions: (I) Because constrained investors bid up high-beta assets, high beta is associated with low alpha, as we find empirically for US equities, 20 international equity markets, Treasury bonds, corporate bonds, and futures. (2) A betting against beta (BAB) factor, which is long leveraged low-beta assets and short high-beta assets, produces significant positive risk-adjusted returns. (3) When funding constraints tighten, the return of the BAB factor is low. (4) Increased funding liquidity risk compresses betas toward one. (5) More constrained investors hold riskier assets. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frazzini, Andrea; Pedersen, Lasse Heje</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can investor-paid credit rating agencies improve the information quality of issuer-paid rating agencies?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xia, Han
This paper examines how the information quality of ratings from an issuer-paid rating agency (Standard and Poor's) responds to the entry of an investor-paid rating agency, the Egan-Jones Rating Company (EJR). By comparing S&amp;P's ratings quality before and after EJR initiates coverage of each firm, I find a significant improvement in S&amp;P's ratings quality following EJR's coverage initiation. S&amp;P's ratings become more responsive to credit risk and its rating changes incorporate higher information content. These results differ from the existing literature documenting a deterioration in the incumbents' ratings quality following the entry of a third issuer-paid agency. I further show that the issuer-paid agency seems to improve the ratings quality because EJR's coverage has elevated its reputational concerns. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xia, Han</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm boundaries matter: Evidence from conglomerates and R&amp;D activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Seru, Amit
This paper examines the impact of the conglomerate form on the scale and novelty of corporate Research and Development (R&amp;D) activity. I exploit a quasi-experiment involving failed mergers to generate exogenous variation in acquisition outcomes of target firms. A difference-in-differences estimation reveals that, relative to failed targets, firms acquired in diversifying mergers produce both a smaller number of innovations and also less-novel innovations, where innovations are measured using patent-based metrics. The treatment effect is amplified if the acquiring conglomerate operates a more active internal capital market and is largely driven by inventors becoming less productive after the merger rather than inventor exits. Concurrently, acquirers move R&amp;D activity outside the boundary of the firm via the use of strategic alliances and joint ventures. There is complementary evidence that conglomerates with more novel R&amp;D tend to operate with decentralized R&amp;D budgets. These findings suggest that conglomerate organizational form affects the allocation and productivity of resources. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Seru, Amit</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic risk management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rampini, Adriano A.; Sufi, Amir; Viswanathan, S.
Both financing and risk management involve promises to pay that need to be collateralized, resulting in a financing versus risk management trade-off. We study this trade-off in a dynamic model of commodity price risk management and show that risk management is limited and that more financially constrained firms hedge less or not at all. We show that these predictions are consistent with the evidence using panel data for fuel price risk management by airlines. More constrained airlines hedge less both in the cross section and within airlines over time. Risk management drops substantially as airlines approach distress and recovers only slowly after airlines enter distress. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rampini, Adriano A.; Sufi, Amir; Viswanathan, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Did CDS trading improve the market for corporate bonds?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Das, Sanjiv; Kalimipalli, Madhu; Nayak, Subhankar
Financial innovation through the creation of new markets and securities impacts related markets as well, changing their efficiency, quality (pricing error), and liquidity. The credit default swap (CDS) market was undoubtedly one of the salient new markets of the past decade. In this paper we examine whether the advent of CDS trading was beneficial to the underlying secondary market for corporate bonds. We employ econometric specifications that account for information across CDS, bond, equity, and volatility markets. We also develop a novel methodology to utilize all observations in our data set even when continuous daily trading is not evidenced, because bonds trade much less frequently than equities. Using an extensive sample of CDS and bond trades over 2002-2008, we find that the advent of CDS was largely detrimental. Bond markets became less efficient, evidenced no reduction in pricing errors, and experienced no improvement in liquidity. These findings are robust to various slices of the data set and specifications of our tests. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Das, Sanjiv; Kalimipalli, Madhu; Nayak, Subhankar</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The evolution of capital structure and operating performance after leveraged buyouts: Evidence from US corporate tax returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohn, Jonathan B.; Mills, Lillian F.; Towery, Erin M.
This study uses corporate tax return data to examine the evolution of firms' financial structure and performance after leveraged buyouts (LBOs) for a comprehensive sample of 317 LBOs taking place between 1995 and 2007. We find little evidence of operating improvements subsequent to an LBO, although consistent with prior studies, we do observe operating improvements in the set of LBO firms that have public financial statements. We also find that firms do not reduce leverage after LBOs, even if they generate excess cash flow. Our results suggest that effecting a sustained change in capital structure is a conscious objective of the LBO structure. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cohn, Jonathan B.; Mills, Lillian F.; Towery, Erin M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accountability of independent directors: Evidence from firms subject to securities litigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brochet, Francois; Srinivasan, Suraj
We examine which independent directors are held accountable when investors sue firms for financial and disclosure-related fraud. Investors can name independent directors as defendants in lawsuits, and they can vote against their reelection to express displeasure over the directors' ineffectiveness at monitoring managers. In a sample of securities class action lawsuits from 1996 to 2010, about 11% of independent directors are named as defendants. The likelihood of being named is greater for audit committee members and directors who sell stock during the class period. Named directors receive more negative recommendations from Institutional Shareholder Services, a proxy advisory firm, and significantly more negative votes from shareholders than directors in a benchmark sample. They are also more likely than other independent directors to leave sued firms. Overall, shareholders use litigation along with director elections and director retention to hold some independent directors more accountable than others when firms experience financial fraud. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brochet, Francois; Srinivasan, Suraj</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Independent director incentives: Where do talented directors spend their limited time and energy?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Masulis, Ronald W.; Mobbs, Shawn
We study reputation incentives in the director labor market and find that directors with multiple directorships distribute their effort unequally based on the directorship's relative prestige. When directors experience an exogenous increase in a directorship's relative ranking, their board attendance rate increases and subsequent firm performance improves. Also, directors are less willing to relinquish their relatively more prestigious directorships, even when firm performance declines. Finally, forced Chief Executive Officer departure sensitivity to poor performance rises when a larger fraction of independent directors view the board as relatively more prestigious. We conclude that director reputation is a powerful incentive for independent directors. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Masulis, Ronald W.; Mobbs, Shawn</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Composition of wealth, conditioning information, and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roussanov, Nikolai
Value stocks covary with aggregate consumption more than growth stocks during periods when financial wealth is low relative to consumption. However, the conditional value premium does not exhibit such countercyclical behavior. Consequently, a one-factor conditional consumption-based asset pricing model can be rejected without making any arbitrary assumptions on the dynamics of the price of risk or the conditional moments. Empirical evidence is somewhat more consistent with a consumption-based model augmented with an aggregate wealth growth factor, which can be motivated by either recursive preferences or relative wealth concerns. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Roussanov, Nikolai</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial risk taking incentives and corporate pension policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anantharaman, Divya; Lee, Yong Gyu
We examine whether the compensation incentives of top management affect the extent of risk shifting versus risk management behavior in pension plans. We find that risk shifting through pension underfunding (and, to a lesser extent, through pension asset allocation to risky securities) is stronger with compensation structures that create high wealth-risk sensitivity (vega) and weaker with high wealth-price sensitivity (delta). These findings are stronger for chief financial officers (CFOs) than for chief executive officers (CEOs), suggesting that pension policy falls within the CFO's domain. Risk shifting through pension underfunding is also lower when the CFO's personal stake in the pension plan is larger. Overall, these findings show that top managers' compensation structure is an important driver of corporate pension policy. They also highlight firms within which the moral hazard concerns fueled by Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation insurance are most relevant. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anantharaman, Divya; Lee, Yong Gyu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are hedge fund managers systematically misreporting? Or not?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jorion, Philippe; Schwarz, Christopher
A discontinuity, or kink, at zero in the hedge fund net return distribution has been interpreted as evidence of managers manipulating returns to avoid showing small losses. Instead, we propose alternative explanations for this phenomenon. In particular, we show that incentive fees can mechanistically create a kink in the net return distribution. This mechanism accounts for almost the entire kink observed in the large, liquid Long-Short Equity style. Furthermore, we show that asset illiquidity and the bounding of yields at zero can generate distribution discontinuities as well. Therefore, we conclude that the observed hedge fund return discontinuities are not direct proof of manipulation. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jorion, Philippe; Schwarz, Christopher</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic effects of corporate default crisis: A long-term perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giesecke, Kay; Longstaff, Francis A.; Schaefer, Stephen; Strebulaev, Ilya A.
Using an extensive data set on corporate bond defaults in the US from 1866 to 2010, we study the macroeconomic effects of bond market crises and contrast them with those resulting from banking crises. During the past 150 years, the US has experienced many severe corporate default crises in which 20-50% of all corporate bonds defaulted. Although the total par amount of corporate bonds has at times rivaled the amount of bank loans outstanding, we find that corporate default crises have far fewer real effects than do banking crises. These results provide empirical support for current theories that emphasize the unique role that banks and the credit and collateral channels play in amplifying macroeconomic shocks. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Giesecke, Kay; Longstaff, Francis A.; Schaefer, Stephen; Strebulaev, Ilya A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund performance evaluation with active peer benchmarks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hunter, David; Kandel, Eugene; Kandel, Shmuel; Wermers, Russ
We propose a simple approach to account for commonalities in mutual fund strategies that relies solely on information on fund returns and investment objectives. Our approach augments commonly used factor models with an additional benchmark that represents an equal investment in all same-category funds, which we call an active peer benchmark (APB). We find that APBs substantially reduce the average time series correlation of residuals between individual funds within a group when added to a four-factor equity model (or to a seven-factor fixed-income model). Importantly, adding this APB significantly improves the selection of funds with future outperformance. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hunter, David; Kandel, Eugene; Kandel, Shmuel; Wermers, Russ</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Money and liquidity in financial markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nyborg, Kjell G.; Oestberg, Per
We argue that there is a connection between the interbank market for liquidity and the broader financial markets, which has its basis in demand for liquidity by banks. Tightness in the market for liquidity leads banks to engage in what we term "liquidity pull-back," which involves selling financial assets either by banks directly or by levered investors. Empirical tests on the stock market are supportive. Tighter interbank markets are associated with relatively more volume in more liquid stocks; selling pressure, especially in more liquid stocks; and transitory negative returns. We control for market-wide uncertainty and in the process also contribute to the literature on portfolio rebalancing. Our general point is that money matters in financial markets. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nyborg, Kjell G.; Oestberg, Per</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Levy jump risk: Evidence from options and returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ornthanalai, Chayawat
Using index options and returns from 1996 to 2009, I estimate discrete-time models where asset returns follow a Brownian increment and a Levy jump. Time variations in these models are generated with an affine GARCH, which facilitates the empirical implementation. I find that the risk premium implied by infinite-activity jumps contributes to more than half of the total equity premium and dominates that of the Brownian increments suggesting that it is more representative of the risks present in the economy. Overall, my findings suggest that infinite-activity jumps, instead of the Brownian increments, should be the default modeling choice in asset pricing models. Crown Copyright (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ornthanalai, Chayawat</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of central clearing on counterparty risk, liquidity, and trading: Evidence from the credit default swap market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loon, Yee Cheng; Zhong, Zhaodong Ken
This paper examines the impact of central clearing on the credit default swap (CDS) market using a sample of voluntarily cleared single-name contracts. Consistent with central clearing reducing counterparty risk, CDS spreads increase around the commencement of central clearing and are lower than settlement spreads published by the central clearinghouse. Furthermore, the relation between CDS spreads and dealer credit risk weakens after central clearing begins, suggesting a lowering of systemic risk. These findings are robust to controls for frictions in both CDS and bond markets. Finally, matched sample analysis reveals that the increased post-trade transparency following central clearing is associated with an improvement in liquidity and trading activity. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Loon, Yee Cheng; Zhong, Zhaodong Ken</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board composition and CEO power</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baldenius, Tim; Melumad, Nahum; Meng, Xiaojing
We study the optimal composition of corporate boards. Directors can be either monitoring or advisory types. Monitoring constrains the empire-building tendency of chief executive officers (CEOs). If shareholders control the board nomination process, a non-monotonic relation ensues between agency problems and board composition. To preempt CEO entrenchment, shareholders may assemble an adviser-heavy board. If a powerful CEO influences the nomination process, this may result in a more monitor-heavy board. Regulations strengthening the monitoring role of boards can be harmful in precisely those cases in which agency problems are severe or in which CEO entrenchment is a threat to corporate governance. (C) 2014 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Baldenius, Tim; Melumad, Nahum; Meng, Xiaojing</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial development and innovation: Cross-country evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hsu, Po-Hsuan; Tian, Xuan; Xu, Yan
We examine how financial market development affects technological innovation. Using a large data set that includes 32 developed and emerging countries and a fixed effects identification strategy, we identify economic mechanisms through which the development of equity markets and credit markets affects technological innovation. We show that industries that are more dependent on external finance and that are more high-tech intensive exhibit a disproportionally higher innovation level in countries with better developed equity markets. However, the development of credit markets appears to discourage innovation in industries with these characteristics. Our paper provides new insights into the real effects of financial market development on the economy. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Hsu, Po-Hsuan; Tian, Xuan; Xu, Yan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning from peers' stock prices and corporate investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foucault, Thierry; Fresard, Laurent
Peers' valuation matters for firms' investment: a one standard deviation increase in peers' valuation is associated with a 5.9% increase in corporate investment. This association is stronger when a firm's stock price informativeness is lower or when its managers appear less informed. Also, the sensitivity of a firm's investment to its stock price is lower when its peers' stock price informativeness is higher or when demands for its products and its peers' products are more correlated. Furthermore, the sensitivity of firms' investment to their peers' valuation drops significantly after going public. These findings are uniquely predicted by a model in which managers learn information from their peers' valuation. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Foucault, Thierry; Fresard, Laurent</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Countercyclical currency risk premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lustig, Hanno; Roussanov, Nikolai; Verdelhan, Adrien
We describe a novel currency investment strategy, the 'dollar carry trade,' which delivers large excess returns, uncorrelated with the returns on well-known carry trade strategies. Using a no-arbitrage model of exchange rates we show that these excess returns compensate U.S. investors for taking on aggregate risk by shorting the dollar in bad times, when the U.S. price of risk is high. The countercyclical variation in risk premia leads to strong return predictability: the average forward discount and U.S. industrial production growth rates forecast up to 25% of the dollar return variation at the one-year horizon. The estimated model implies that the variation in the exposure of U.S. investors to worldwide risk is the key driver of predictability. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lustig, Hanno; Roussanov, Nikolai; Verdelhan, Adrien</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Motivating innovation in newly public firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baranchuk, Nina; Kieschnick, Robert; Moussawi, Rabih
Prior research suggests that executive option grants that do not quickly vest provide managers with better incentives to pursue long-term, instead of short-term, objectives. Previous research also suggests that the pursuit of long-term objectives could be undermined by the risk of early termination. We conjecture that these arguments jointly suggest that managers are better motivated to pursue innovation when they are given more incentive compensation with longer vesting periods for unexercised options and yet some protection from disruptive takeover threats. Our evidence for a sample of newly public firms is consistent with more innovative firms jointly choosing such a combination. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baranchuk, Nina; Kieschnick, Robert; Moussawi, Rabih</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading in derivatives when the underlying is scarce</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Snehal; Graveline, Jeremy J.
Regulatory restrictions and market frictions can constrain the aggregate quantity of long and short positions in a security. When these constraints bind, we refer to the security as scarce, and its price becomes distorted relative to its value in a frictionless market. We show that an otherwise redundant derivative can reduce the price distortion of the underlying security by relaxing its scarcity. We also show that it is especially important to analyze the underlying and derivative markets jointly when evaluating the impact of regulation, such as short-sales bans and position limits in derivatives, that restricts trade. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Banerjee, Snehal; Graveline, Jeremy J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Speculating on home improvements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Hyun-Soo; Hong, Harrison; Scheinkman, Jose
We develop a speculation-based theory of home improvements. Housing services are produced from a mix of land and structures. Homeowners optimistic about future prices for these services speculate by making improvements, which we model as them increasing their structures holding fixed their land. The recoup value (the difference between the resale value of improvements and construction costs) is simultaneously increasing in home price appreciation and falls with construction cost growth. This prediction stands in contrast to a consumption-cum-financial constraints motive in which rising home prices loosen financial constraints and lead to lower recoup values. We provide evidence consistent with a speculative motive using data on the costs and recoup values of remodeling projects across US cities. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Choi, Hyun-Soo; Hong, Harrison; Scheinkman, Jose</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crises and confidence: Systemic banking crises and depositor behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Osili, Una Okonkwo; Paulson, Anna
We show that individuals who have experienced a systemic banking crisis are 11 percentage points less likely to use banks in the U.S. than otherwise similar individuals who emigrated from the same country but did not live through a crisis. This finding is robust to controlling for exposure to other macroeconomic events and to various methods for addressing potential bias due to migrant self-selection. Consistent with the view that personal experience plays an important role in decision-making, the effects are larger for individuals who were older and more likely to have had wealth entrusted to the banking system at the time of the crisis and for people who experienced crises in countries without deposit insurance. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Osili, Una Okonkwo; Paulson, Anna</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fund Manager Allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fang, Jieyan; Kempf, Alexander; Trapp, Monika
We show that fund families allocate their most skilled managers to market segments in which manager skill is rewarded best. In efficient markets, even skilled managers cannot generate excess returns. In less efficient markets, skilled managers can exploit inefficiencies and generate higher performance than unskilled managers. Fund families seem to be aware of the relation between skill, efficiency, and performance, and allocate more skilled managers to inefficient markets. They pursue this strategy when hiring new fund managers and when reassigning managers to funds within the family. Overall, we conclude that fund families allocate fund managers in an efficient way. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fang, Jieyan; Kempf, Alexander; Trapp, Monika</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does option trading convey stock price information?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Jianfeng
After executing option orders, options market makers turn to the stock market to hedge away the underlying stock exposure. As a result, the stock exposure imbalance in option transactions translates into an imbalance in stock transactions. This paper decomposes the total stock order imbalance into an imbalance induced by option transactions and an imbalance independent of options. The analysis shows that the option-induced imbalance significantly predicts future stock returns in the cross section controlling for the past stock and options returns, but the imbalance independent of options has only a transitory price impact. Further investigation suggests that options order flow contains important information about the underlying stock value. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hu, Jianfeng</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO optimism and incentive compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Otto, Clemens A.
I study the effect of chief executive officer (CEO) optimism on CEO compensation. Using data on compensation in US firms, I provide evidence that CEOs whose option exercise behavior and earnings forecasts are indicative of optimistic beliefs receive smaller stock option grants, fewer bonus payments, and less total compensation than their peers. These findings add to our understanding of the interplay between managerial biases and remuneration and show how sophisticated principals can take advantage of optimistic agents by appropriately adjusting their compensation contracts. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Otto, Clemens A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Access to management and the informativeness of analyst research</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, T. Clifton; Jame, Russell; Markov, Stanimir; Subasi, Musa
We examine whether access to management at broker-hosted investor conferences leads to more informative research by analysts. We find analyst recommendation changes have larger immediate price impacts when the analyst's firm has a conference-hosting relation with the company. The effect increases with hosting frequency and is strongest in the days following the conference. Conference-hosting brokers also issue more informative, accurate, and timely earnings forecasts than non-hosts. Our findings suggest that access to management remains an important source of analysts' informational advantage in the post-Regulation Fair Disclosure world. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Green, T. Clifton; Jame, Russell; Markov, Stanimir; Subasi, Musa</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Did going public impair Moody's credit ratings?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kedia, Simi; Rajgopal, Shivaram; Zhou, Xing
We investigate a prominent allegation in congressional hearings that Moody's loosened its rating standards to chase revenue after it went public in 2000. Consistent with this allegation, Moody's ratings for both corporate bonds and structured finance products are significantly more favorable to issuers, relative to S&amp;P's, after Moody's IPO. Moreover, Moody's ratings are more favorable for clients subject to greater conflict of interest. There is little evidence that Moody's higher ratings, post-IPO, are more informative, measured as expected default frequencies (EDFs) or as the probability of default. Our findings inform the debate on whether financial gatekeepers should be publicly traded. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kedia, Simi; Rajgopal, Shivaram; Zhou, Xing</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder democracy in play: Career consequences of proxy contests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fos, Vyacheslav; Tsoutsoura, Margarita
This paper shows that proxy contests have a significant adverse effect on careers of incumbent directors. Following a proxy contest, directors experience a significant decline in the number of directorships not only in the targeted company, but also in other nontargeted companies. The results are established using the universe of all proxy contests during 1996-2010. To isolate the effect of the proxy contest, our empirical strategy uses within-firm variation in directors' exposure to the possibility of being voted out and exploits the predetermined schedule of staggered boards that allows only a fraction of directors to be nominated for election every year. We find that nominated directors relative to non-nominated ones lose 58% more seats on other boards. The evidence suggests the proxy-contest mechanism imposes a significant career cost on incumbent directors. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fos, Vyacheslav; Tsoutsoura, Margarita</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dispersion in beliefs among active mutual funds and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Hao; Sun, Zheng
We propose a measure of dispersion in fund managers' beliefs about future stock returns based on their active holdings, i.e., deviations from benchmarks. We find that both the level of and the change in dispersion positively predict subsequent stock returns on a risk-adjusted basis. This effect is particularly pronounced among stocks with high information asymmetry and binding short-sale constraints. These results suggest that a subgroup of informed managers drives up the dispersion in active holdings when they place large bets after receiving positive private information. Binding short-sale constraints, however, prevent them from fully using their negative private information, leading to low dispersion in active holdings. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiang, Hao; Sun, Zheng</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditional risk premia in currency markets and other asset classes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lettau, Martin; Maggiori, Matteo; Weber, Michael
The downside risk capital asset pricing model (DR-CAPM) can price the cross section of currency returns. The market-beta differential between high and low interest rate currencies is higher conditional on bad market returns, when the market price of risk is also high, than it is conditional on good market returns. Correctly accounting for this variation is crucial for the empirical performance of the model. The DR-CAPM can jointly rationalize the cross section of equity, equity index options, commodity, sovereign bond and currency returns, thus offering a unified risk view of these asset classes. In contrast, popular models that have been developed for a specific asset class fail to jointly price other asset classes. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lettau, Martin; Maggiori, Matteo; Weber, Michael</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disagreement and asset prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlin, Bruce I.; Longstaff, Francis A.; Matoba, Kyle
How do differences of opinion affect asset prices? Do investors earn a risk premium when disagreement arises in the market? Despite their fundamental importance, these questions are among the most controversial issues in finance. In this paper, we use a novel data set that allows us to directly measure the level of disagreement among Wall Street mortgage dealers about prepayment speeds. We examine how disagreement evolves over time and study its effects on expected returns, return volatility, and trading volume in the mortgage-backed security market. We find that increased disagreement is associated with higher expected returns, higher return volatility, and larger trading volume. These results imply that there is a positive risk premium for disagreement in asset prices. We also show that volatility in and of itself does not lead to higher trading volume. Instead, only when disagreement arises in the market is higher uncertainty associated with more trading. Finally, we are able to distinguish empirically between two competing hypotheses regarding how information in markets gets incorporated into asset prices. We find that sophisticated investors appear to update their beliefs through a rational expectations mechanism when disagreement arises. (C) 2014 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Carlin, Bruce I.; Longstaff, Francis A.; Matoba, Kyle</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate distress and lobbying: Evidence from the Stimulus Act</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adelino, Manuel; Dinc, I. Serdar
The literature on distressed firms has focused on these firms' investment, capital structure, and labor decisions. This paper investigates a novel aspect of firm behavior in distress: how financial health affects a firm's lobbying and, consequently, its relationship with the government. We exploit the shock to nonfinancial firms during the 2008 financial crisis and the availability of the stimulus package in the first quarter of 2009. We find that firms with weaker financial health, as measured by credit default swap spreads, lobbied more. We also show that the amount spent on lobbying was associated with a greater likelihood of receiving stimulus funds. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adelino, Manuel; Dinc, I. Serdar</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Did bank distress stifle innovation during the Great Depression?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nanda, Ramana; Nicholas, Tom
We find a negative relationship between bank distress and the level, quality and trajectory of firm-level innovation during the Great Depression, particularly for R&amp;D firms operating in capital intensive industries. However, we also show that because a sufficient number of R&amp;D intensive firms were located in counties with lower levels of bank distress, or were operating in less capital intensive industries, the negative effects were mitigated in aggregate. Although Depression era bank distress was associated with the stifling of innovation, our results also help to explain why technological development was still robust following one of the largest shocks in the history of the U.S. banking system. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nanda, Ramana; Nicholas, Tom</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price pressures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hendershott, Terrence; Menkveld, Albert J.
We study price pressures, i.e., deviations from the efficient price due to risk-averse intermediaries supplying liquidity to asynchronously arriving investors. Empirically, New York Stock Exchange intermediary data reveals economically large price pressures, 0.49% on average with a half life of 0.92 days. Theoretically, a simple dynamic inventory model captures an intermediary's use of price pressure to mean-revert inventory. She trades off revenue loss due to price pressure against price risk associated with staying in a nonzero inventory state. The closed-form solution identifies the intermediary's risk aversion and the investors' private value distribution from the observed time series patterns of prices and inventories. These parameters imply a relative social cost due to price pressure, a deviation from constrained Pareto efficiency, of approximately 10% of the cost of immediacy. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hendershott, Terrence; Menkveld, Albert J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Refinancing, profitability, and capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Danis, Andras; Rettl, Daniel A.; Whited, Toni M.
We revisit the well-established puzzle that leverage is negatively correlated with measures of profitability. In contrast, we find that at times when firms are at or close to their optimal level of leverage, the cross-sectional correlation between profitability and leverage is positive. At other times, it is negative. These results are consistent with dynamic trade-off models in which infrequent capital structure rebalancing is optimal. The time series of market leverage and profitability in the quarters prior to rebalancing events match the patterns predicted by these models. Our results are not driven by investment layouts, market timing, payout, or mechanical mean reversion of leverage. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Danis, Andras; Rettl, Daniel A.; Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fails-to-deliver, short selling, and market quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fotak, Veljko; Raman, Vikas; Yadav, Pradeep K.
We investigate the aggregate market quality impact of equity shares that fail to deliver (hereafter "FTDs"). For a sample of 1,492 NYSE stocks over a 42-month period from 2005 to 2008, greater FTDs lead to higher liquidity and pricing efficiency, and their impact is similar to our estimate of delivered short sales. Furthermore, during the operative period of a Security and Exchange Commission (SEC) order mandating stock borrowing prior to short sales, the securities affected display relatively lower liquidity and higher pricing errors. Finally, we do not find any evidence that FTDs caused price distortions or the failure of financial firms during the 2008 financial crisis. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fotak, Veljko; Raman, Vikas; Yadav, Pradeep K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Preemptive bidding, target resistance, and takeover premiums</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dimopoulos, Theodosios; Sacchetto, Stefano
We evaluate empirically two sources of large takeover premiums: preemptive bidding and target resistance. We develop an auction model that features costly sequential entry of bidders in takeover contests and encompasses both explanations. We estimate the model parameters by simulated method of moments for a sample of US takeovers. Our estimates imply that target resistance explains the entire magnitude of the premium in 74% of successful single-bidder contests. Simulation experiments show that initial bidders have, on average, a higher valuation for the target than rival bidders, so that a relatively low initial bid is sufficient to deter a rival from entry. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dimopoulos, Theodosios; Sacchetto, Stefano</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting stock returns under economic constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pettenuzzo, Davide; Timmermann, Allan; Valkanov, Rossen
We propose a new approach to imposing economic constraints on time series forecasts of the equity premium. Economic constraints are used to modify the posterior distribution of the parameters of the predictive return regression in a way that better allows the model to learn from the data. We consider two types of constraints: non-negative equity premia and bounds on the conditional Sharpe ratio, the latter of which incorporates time-varying volatility in the predictive regression framework. Empirically, we find that economic constraints systematically reduce uncertainty about model parameters, reduce the risk of selecting a poor forecasting model, and improve both statistical and economic measures of out-of-sample forecast performance. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pettenuzzo, Davide; Timmermann, Allan; Valkanov, Rossen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO deal-making activities and compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fich, Eliezer M.; Starks, Laura T.; Yore, Adam S.
Using transactions generally overlooked in the compensation literature joint ventures, strategic alliances, seasoned equity offerings (SEOs), and spin-offs we find that, beyond compensation for increases in firm size or complexity, chief executive officers (CEOs) are rewarded for their deal-making activities. Boards pay CEOs for the core motivation of the deal, as well as for deal volume. We find that compensating for volume instead of core value creation occurs under weak board monitoring and that in deal-making firms, neither CEO turnover nor pay-for-performance responds to underperformance. We introduce an input monitoring explanation for these results: boards compensate for deal volume because of their inability to perfectly monitor outputs. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fich, Eliezer M.; Starks, Laura T.; Yore, Adam S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The euro and corporate financing before the crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bris, Arturo; Koskinen, Yrjoe; Nilsson, Mattias
We study the financing policies of European public corporations prior to the euro crisis. Using data from 11 euro countries and a control group of five other European countries over 1991-2006, we show that nonfinancial firms from euro countries with previously weak currencies considerably increased their debt financing after the introduction of the euro. The results are stronger for large firms, firms dependent on external financing, and for the latter part of the post-euro time period. Overall, the results support the hypothesis that the supply of capital increased following the introduction of the euro. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bris, Arturo; Koskinen, Yrjoe; Nilsson, Mattias</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fact or friction: Jumps at ultra high frequency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christensen, Kim; Oomen, Roel C. A.; Podolskij, Mark
This paper shows that jumps in financial asset prices are often erroneously identified and are, in fact, rare events accounting for a very small proportion of the total price variation. We apply new econometric techniques to a comprehensive set of ultra high-frequency equity and foreign exchange tick data recorded at millisecond precision, allowing us to examine the price evolution at the individual order level. We show that in both theory and practice, traditional measures of jump variation based on lower-frequency data tend to spuriously assign a burst of volatility to the jump component. As a result, the true price variation coming from jumps is overstated. Our estimates based on tick data suggest that the jump variation is an order of magnitude smaller than typical estimates found in the existing literature. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Christensen, Kim; Oomen, Roel C. A.; Podolskij, Mark</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Advancing the universality of quadrature methods to any underlying process for option pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Ding; Haerkoenen, Hannu J.; Newton, David P.
Exceptional accuracy and speed for option pricing are available via quadrature (Andricopoulos, Widdicks, Duck, and Newton, 2003), extending into multiple dimensions with complex path-dependency and early exercise (Andricopoulos, Widdicks, Newton, and Duck, 2007). However, the exposition is incomplete, leaving many modelling processes outside the Black-Scholes-Merton framework unattainable. We show how to remove the remaining major block to universal application. Although this had appeared highly problematic, the solution turns out to be conceptually simple and implementation is straightforward (we provide code on the Journal of Financial Economics website at http://jfe.rochester.edu). Crucially, the method retains its speed and flexibility across complex combinations of option features but is now applicable across other underlying processes. (C) 2014 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Chen, Ding; Haerkoenen, Hannu J.; Newton, David P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The long of it: Odds that investor sentiment spuriously predicts anomaly returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stambaugh, Robert F.; Yu, Jianfeng; Yuan, Yu
Extremely long odds accompany the chance that spurious-regression bias accounts for investor sentiment's observed role in stock-return anomalies. We replace investor sentiment with a simulated persistent series in regressions reported by Stambaugh, Yu, and Yuan (2012), who find higher long-short anomaly profits following high sentiment, due entirely to the short leg. Among 200 million simulated regressors, we find none that support those conclusions as strongly as investor sentiment. The key is consistency across anomalies. Obtaining just the predicted signs for the regression coefficients across the 11 anomalies examined in the above study occurs only once for every 43 simulated regressors. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stambaugh, Robert F.; Yu, Jianfeng; Yuan, Yu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The death of the deal: Are withdrawn acquisition deals informative of CEO quality?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobsen, Stacey
To examine the market response to positive revelations of chief executive officer (CEO) quality, this study focuses on CEOs who withdraw acquisition bids when the price becomes increasingly expensive. Firms that withdrawal for price-related reasons earn higher withdrawal returns than firms that withdraw for other reasons. This relation is stronger when CEO uncertainty and discretion is high. CEOs unwilling to increase the offer price are less likely to be replaced and more likely to advance to a larger firm than a control group of CEOs. The finding that the market attaches value to CEO-specific information suggests that unobservable manager characteristics can meaningfully impact firm outcomes. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jacobsen, Stacey</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do independent directors cause improvements in firm transparency?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Armstrong, Christopher S.; Core, John E.; Guay, Wayne R.
Although recent research documents a positive relation between corporate transparency and the proportion of independent directors, the direction of causality is unclear. We examine a regulatory shock that substantially increased board independence for some firms, and find that information asymmetry, and to some extent management disclosure and financial intermediation, changed at firms affected by this shock. We also examine whether these effects vary as a function of management entrenchment, information processing costs, and required changes to audit committee independence. Our results suggest that firms can alter their corporate transparency to suit the informational demands of a particular board structure. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Armstrong, Christopher S.; Core, John E.; Guay, Wayne R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>China's secondary privatization: Perspectives from the Split-Share Structure Reform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liao, Li; Liu, Bibo; Wang, Hao
The Split-Share Structure Reform granted legitimate trading rights to the state-owned shares of listed state-owned enterprises (SOEs), opening up the gate to China's secondary privatization. The expectation of privatization quickly boosted SOE output, profits, and employment, but did not change their operating efficiency and corporate governance. The improvements to SOE performance are positively correlated to government agents' privatization-led incentive of increasing state-owned share value. In terms of privatization methodology, the reform adopted a market mechanism that played an effective information discovery role in aligning the interests of the government and public investors. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liao, Li; Liu, Bibo; Wang, Hao</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crash-neutral currency carry trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jurek, Jakub W.
Currency carry trades exploiting violations of uncovered interest rate parity in G10 currencies deliver significant excess returns with annualized Sharpe ratios equal to or greater than those of equity market factors (1990-2012). Using data on out-of-the-money foreign exchange options, I compute returns to crash-hedged portfolios and demonstrate that the high returns to carry trades are not due to peso problems. A comparison of the returns to hedged and unhedged trades indicates crash risk premia account for at most one-third of the excess return to currency carry trades. (C) 2014 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Jurek, Jakub W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt covenant renegotiations and creditor control rights</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Denis, David J.; Wang, Jing
Using a large sample of private debt renegotiations from 1996 to 2011, we report that, even in the absence of any covenant violation, debt covenants are frequently renegotiated. These renegotiations primarily relax existing restrictions and result in economically large changes in existing limits. Renegotiations of specific covenants are a response to both the distance the covenant variable is from its contractual limit and the firm's specific operating conditions and prospects. Moreover, the borrower's post-renegotiation investment and financial policies are strongly associated with the covenant changes resulting from the renegotiation. Overall, the findings imply that, even outside of default states, creditors have strong control rights over the borrower's operating and financial policies, and they exercise these rights in a state contingent manner through covenant renegotiations. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Denis, David J.; Wang, Jing</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The international transmission of bank capital requirements: Evidence from the UK</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aiyar, Shekhar; Calomiris, Charles W.; Hooley, John; Korniyenko, Yevgeniya; Wieladek, Tomasz
We use data on UK banks' minimum capital requirements to study the impact of changes to bank-specific capital requirements on cross-border bank loan supply from 1999Q1 to 2006Q4. By examining a sample in which each recipient country has multiple relationships with UK-resident banks, we are able to control for demand effects. We find a negative and statistically significant effect of changes to banks' capital requirements on cross-border lending: a 100 basis point increase in the requirement is associated with a reduction in the growth rate of cross-border credit of 5.5 percentage points. We also find that banks tend to favor their most important country relationships, so that the negative cross-border credit supply response in "core" countries is significantly less than in others. Banks tend to cut back cross-border credit to other banks (including foreign affiliates) more than to firms and households, consistent with shorter maturity, wholesale lending which is easier to roll off and may be associated with weaker borrowing relationships. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aiyar, Shekhar; Calomiris, Charles W.; Hooley, John; Korniyenko, Yevgeniya; Wieladek, Tomasz</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distracted directors: Does board busyness hurt shareholder value?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Falato, Antonio; Kadyrzhanova, Dalida; Lel, Ugur
We use the deaths of directors and chief executive officers as a natural experiment to generate exogenous variation in the time and resources available to independent directors at interlocked firms. The loss of such key co-employees is an attention shock because it increases the board committee workload only for some interlocked directors the 'treatment group'. There is a negative stock market reaction to attention shocks only for treated director-interlocked firms. Interlocking directors' busyness, the importance of their board roles, and their degree of independence magnify the treatment effect. Overall, directors' busyness is detrimental to board monitoring quality and shareholder value. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Falato, Antonio; Kadyrzhanova, Dalida; Lel, Ugur</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary policy regimes: Implications for the yield curve and bond pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Filipova, Kameliya; Audrino, Francesco; De Giorgi, Enrico
We develop a multivariate dynamic term structure model, which takes into account the nonlinear (time-varying) relation between interest rates and the state of the economy. In contrast to the classical term structure literature, in which nonlinearities are captured by increasing the number of latent state variables or by latent regime shifts, in our no-arbitrage framework the regimes are governed by thresholds and are directly linked to economic fundamentals. Specifically, starting from a simple monetary policy model for the short rate, we introduce a parsimonious and tractable model for the yield curve, which takes into account the possibility of regime shifts in the behavior of the Federal Reserve. In our empirical analysis, we show the merit of our approach three dimensions: interpretable bond dynamics, accurate short end yield curve pricing, and yield curve implications. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Filipova, Kameliya; Audrino, Francesco; De Giorgi, Enrico</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Death and jackpot: Why do individual investors hold overpriced stocks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Conrad, Jennifer; Kapadia, Nishad; Xing, Yuhang
Campbell, Hilscher, and Szilagyi (2008) show that firms with a high probability of default have abnormally low average future returns. We show that firms with a high potential for default (death) also tend to have a relatively high probability of extremely large (jackpot) payoffs. Consistent with an investor preference for skewed, lottery-like payoffs, stocks with high predicted probabilities for jackpot returns earn abnormally low average returns. Stocks with high death or jackpot probabilities have relatively low institutional ownership and the jackpot effect we find is much stronger in stocks with high limits to arbitrage. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Conrad, Jennifer; Kapadia, Nishad; Xing, Yuhang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uncertainty, market structure, and liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Kee H.; Chuwonganant, Chairat
In this study we show that market uncertainty [measured by the Chicago Board Options Exchange Market Volatility Index (VIX)] exerts a large market-wide impact on liquidity, which gives rise to co-movements in individual asset liquidity. The effect of VIX on stock liquidity is greater than the combined effects of all other common determinants of stock liquidity. We show that the uncertainty elasticity of liquidity (UEL: percent change in liquidity given a 1% change in VIX) has increased around regulatory changes in the US markets that increased the role of public traders in liquidity provision, reduced the minimum allowable price variation, weakened the affirmative obligation of NASDAQ dealers, and abolished the specialist system on the NYSE. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, Kee H.; Chuwonganant, Chairat</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial expert CEOs: CEO's work experience and firm's financial policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Custodio, Claudia; Metzger, Daniel
We study CEOs with a career background in finance. Firms with financial expert CEOs hold less cash, more debt, and engage in more share repurchases. Financial expert CEOs are more financially sophisticated: they are less likely to use one companywide discount rate instead of a project-specific one, they manage financial policies more actively, and their firm investments are less sensitive to cash flows. Financial expert CEOs are able to raise external funds even when credit conditions are tight, and they were more responsive to the dividend and capital gains tax cuts in 2003. Analyzing CEO-firm matching based on financial experience, we find that financial expert CEOs tend to be hired by more mature firms. Our results are consistent with employment histories of CEOs being relevant for corporate policies. However, we cannot formally rule out that our findings are partly explained by endogenous CEO-firm matching. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Custodio, Claudia; Metzger, Daniel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic risk and hedge fund returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Brown, Stephen J.; Caglayan, Mustafa O.
This paper estimates hedge fund and mutual fund exposure to newly proposed measures of macroeconomic risk that are interpreted as measures of economic uncertainty. We find that the resulting uncertainty betas explain a significant proportion of the cross-sectional dispersion in hedge fund returns. However, the same is not true for mutual funds, for which there is no significant relationship. After controlling for a large set of fund characteristics and risk factors, the positive relation between uncertainty betas and future hedge fund returns remains economically and statistically significant. Hence, we argue that macroeconomic risk is a powerful determinant of cross-sectional differences in hedge fund returns. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Brown, Stephen J.; Caglayan, Mustafa O.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of recovery rates in the US corporate bond market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jankowitsch, Rainer; Nagler, Florian; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.
We examine recovery rates of defaulted bonds in the US corporate bond market, based on a complete set of traded prices and volumes. A study of the trading microstructure around various types of default events is provided. We document temporary price pressure with high trading volumes on the default day and the following 30 days, and low trading activity thereafter. Based on this analysis, we determine market-based recovery rates and quantify various liquidity measures. We study the relation between the recovery rates and these measures, considering additionally a comprehensive set of bond characteristics, firm fundamentals, and macroeconomic variables. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jankowitsch, Rainer; Nagler, Florian; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does PIN affect equity prices around the world?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lai, Sandy; Ng, Lilian; Zhang, Bohui
This study examines the empirical controversy over the pricing effect of the Easley, Hvidkjaer, and O'Hara (2002) probability of information-based trading, PIN, on a sample of 30,095 firms from 47 countries worldwide. Contrary to the empirical evidence of Easley, Hvidkjaer, and O'Hara, but consistent with that of Duarte and Young (2009), we do not find that PIN exhibits a positive effect on a cross section of expected stock returns in international markets. Alternative information-based trading measures also display no effect on expected stock returns, corroborating our finding that information risk proxied by PIN, in general, has no pricing effect in world markets. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lai, Sandy; Ng, Lilian; Zhang, Bohui</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the systematic volatility of unpriced earnings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, Timothy C.; Lee, Jaehoon
Some important puzzles in macro finance can be resolved in a model featuring systematically varying volatility of unpriced shocks to firms' earnings. In the data, the correlation between corporate debt and stock market valuations is low. The model accounts for this via the opposing effect of unpriced earnings risk on levered debt and equity prices. The model also explains the low (or nonexistent) risk-reward relation for the market portfolio of levered equity via the opposing effects of unpriced and priced uncertainty (both components of stock volatility) on the levered equity risk premium. Versions of the model calibrated to empirical measures of both types of fundamental risk can quantitatively substantiate these explanations. Variation in residual earning dispersion accounts for a significant fraction of observed disagreement between debt and equity valuations and of realized stock volatility. The implication that the two components of risk should forecast the levered equity risk premium with opposite signs is also supported in the data. The results are a notable advance for risk-based asset pricing. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Johnson, Timothy C.; Lee, Jaehoon</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What do firms do when dividend tax rates change? An examination of alternative payout responses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanlon, Michelle; Hoopes, Jeffrey L.
This paper investigates whether investor-level taxes affect corporate payout policy decisions. We predict and find a surge of special dividends in the final months of 2010 and 2012, immediately before individual-level dividend tax rates were expected to increase. We also find evidence that immediately before the expected tax increases, firms altered the timing of their regular dividend payments by shifting what would normally be January regular dividend payments into the preceding December. To our knowledge this is the first evidence in the literature about changes in the timing of regular dividend payments in response to tax law changes. For both actions (specials and shifting), we find that it was more likely for a firm to respond to individual-level tax rates if insiders owned a relatively large amount of the firm. Overall, our paper provides evidence that managers consider individual-level taxes in making corporate payout decisions. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hanlon, Michelle; Hoopes, Jeffrey L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price informativeness and stock return synchronicity: Evidence from the pricing of seasoned equity offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Kalok; Chan, Yue-Cheong
We investigate what stock return synchronicity reflects in terms of price informativeness by examining its effect on the pricing of seasoned equity offerings (SEOs). Based on 5,087 SEOs from 1984 to 2007, we find a significantly negative relation between stock return synchronicity (estimated as the logit transformation of the R-squared statistic from a two-factor regression) and SEO discounts (the percentage differences between pre-offer day closing prices and offer prices). The negative relation is strongest when there is no analyst coverage, and it declines as analyst coverage increases. This shows that stock price is more informative when stock return synchronicity is higher and also that information asymmetry can be mitigated by analyst coverage. We further decompose stock return synchronicity into the market comovement and industry comovement components and find that both components are equally important in affecting SEO discounts. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chan, Kalok; Chan, Yue-Cheong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>News-driven return reversals: Liquidity provision ahead of earnings announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>So, Eric C.; Wang, Sean
This study documents a six-fold increase in short-term return reversals during earnings announcements relative to non-announcement periods. Following prior research, we use reversals as a proxy for expected returns market makers demand for providing liquidity. Our findings highlight significant time-series variation in the magnitude of short-term return reversals and suggest that market makers demand higher expected returns prior to earnings announcements because of increased inventory risks that stem from holding net positions through the release of anticipated earnings news. Collectively, our findings suggest that uncertainty regarding anticipated information events elicits predictable increases in the compensation demanded for providing liquidity and that these increases significantly affect the dynamics and information content of market prices. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>So, Eric C.; Wang, Sean</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of shorting, firm size, and time on market anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Israel, Ronen; Moskowitz, Tobias J.
We examine the role of shorting, firm size, and time on the profitability of size, value, and momentum strategies. We find that long positions make up almost all of size, 60% of value, and half of momentum profits. Shorting becomes less important for momentum and more important for value as firm size decreases. The value premium decreases with firm size and is weak among the largest stocks. Momentum profits, however, exhibit no reliable relation with size. These effects are robust over 86 years of US equity data and almost 40 years of data across four international equity markets and five asset classes. Variation over time and across markets of these effects is consistent with random chance. We find little evidence that size, value, and momentum returns are significantly affected by changes in trading costs or institutional and hedge fund ownership over time. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Israel, Ronen; Moskowitz, Tobias J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Connecting two markets: An equilibrium framework for shorts, longs, and stock loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blocher, Jesse; Reed, Adam V.; Van Wesep, Edward D.
We analyze a reduced-form framework for understanding the equity loan market's impact on share prices. We show that hard-to-borrow stocks will have distinct return patterns, responding more to shocks in the supply of shares available, and to changes in the heterogeneity of investor beliefs, than other stocks. We conduct two empirical tests in which we find strong support for these equilibrium predictions. In our first test, we take advantage of a tax-driven exogenous shock to share loan supply and find that when supply is reduced around dividend record dates, prices of hard-to-borrow stocks increase 1.1% while prices of easy-to-borrow stocks are unaffected. In our second test, we find that hard-to-borrow stocks have 4.8% lower three-month returns than other stocks, with negative returns concentrated in stocks with high heterogeneity in investor beliefs. Thus, we extend the Diether, Malloy, and Scherbina (2002) result that stocks with a greater dispersion of investor beliefs have lower returns. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Blocher, Jesse; Reed, Adam V.; Van Wesep, Edward D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What do boards really do? Evidence from minutes of board meetings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwartz-Ziv, Miriam; Weisbach, Michael S.
We analyze a unique database from a sample of real-world boardrooms - minutes of board meetings and board-committee meetings of eleven business companies for which the Israeli government holds a substantial equity interest. We use these data to evaluate the underlying assumptions and predictions of models of boards of directors. These models generally fall into two categories: "managerial models" that assume boards play a direct role in managing the firm, and "supervisory models" that assume that boards monitor top management but do not make business decisions themselves. Consistent with the supervisory models, our minutes-based data suggest that boards spend most of their time monitoring management: approximately two-thirds of the issues boards discussed were of a supervisory nature, they were presented with only a single option in 99% of the issues discussed, and they disagreed with the CEO only 2.5% of the time. Nevertheless, at times boards do play a managerial role: Boards requested to receive further information or an update for 8% of the issues discussed, and they took an initiative with respect to 8.1% of them. In 63% of the meetings, boards took at least one of these actions or did not vote in line with the CEO. Taken together our results suggest that boards can be characterized as active monitors. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schwartz-Ziv, Miriam; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation of VIX derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mencia, Javier; Sentana, Enrique
We conduct an extensive empirical analysis of VIX derivative valuation models before, during, and after the 2008-2009 financial crisis. Since the restrictive mean-reversion and heteroskedasticity features of existing models yield large distortions during the crisis, we propose generalisations with a time-varying central tendency, jumps, and stochastic volatility, analyse their pricing performance, and implications for term structures of VIX futures and volatility "skews." We find that a process for the log of the observed VIX combining central tendency and stochastic volatility reliably prices VIX derivatives. We also uncover a significant risk premium that shifts the long-run volatility level. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mencia, Javier; Sentana, Enrique</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor unemployment risk and corporate financing decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agrawal, Ashwini K.; Matsa, David A.
This paper presents evidence that firms choose conservative financial policies partly to mitigate workers' exposure to unemployment risk. We exploit changes in state unemployment insurance laws as a source of variation in the costs borne by workers during layoff spells. We find that higher unemployment benefits lead to increased corporate leverage, particularly for labor-intensive and financially constrained firms. We estimate the ex ante, indirect costs of financial distress due to unemployment risk to be about 60 basis points of firm value for a typical BBB-rated firm. The findings suggest that labor market frictions have a significant impact on corporate financing decisions. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agrawal, Ashwini K.; Matsa, David A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economics of club bidding and value creation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marquez, Robert; Singh, Rajdeep
Many acquisitions are conducted by clubs, i.e., coalitions of acquirers that submit a single bid. We present a novel analysis of club bidding where the club creates value by aggregating, at least partially, bidders' values. We show that club formation can lead to higher acquisition prices when the number of bidders is exogenously fixed and large. However, when entry costs require bidders to optimize their participation decisions, club formation acts as an endogenous limit on competition and reduces the target's premium. In contrast, social efficiency with club bidding is always higher. Our findings can reconcile the contradictory evidence on club bidding. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Marquez, Robert; Singh, Rajdeep</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund risk and market share-adjusted fund flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spiegel, Matthew; Zhang, Hong
Several papers use a fractional specification (net inflow/assets under management) to infer a convex relation between flow and past performance. However, heterogeneous linear response functions combined with the pooled analysis commonly used in these studies can yield false convexity estimates. We show that such heterogeneity obtains in practice. Along these same lines, the paper also finds that several previously unexamined implications of a convex flow-performance relation fail to hold. Moreover, convexity with fractional flows (which we confirm) largely disappears in a conditional analysis that controls for heterogeneity. Market shares offer an alternative specification for flow that is more resilient to heterogeneity. Using this alternative specification, we again find no evidence of convexity in the flow-performance relation. We conclude that the widely held belief that the flow response function is convex is due solely to misspecification of the empirical model. The flow-return relation is linear. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Spiegel, Matthew; Zhang, Hong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The asset growth effect: Insights from international equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Watanabe, Akiko; Xu, Yan; Yao, Tong; Yu, Tong
Firms with higher asset growth rates subsequently experience lower stock returns in international equity markets, consistent with the U.S. evidence. This negative effect of asset growth on returns is stronger in more developed capital markets and markets where stocks are more efficiently priced, but is unrelated to country characteristics representing limits to arbitrage, investor protection, and accounting quality. The evidence suggests that the cross-sectional relation between asset growth and stock return is more likely due to an optimal investment effect than due to overinvestment, market timing, or other forms of mispricing. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Watanabe, Akiko; Xu, Yan; Yao, Tong; Yu, Tong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are mutual funds sitting ducks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shive, Sophie; Yun, Hayong
We find that patient traders profit from the predictable, flow-induced trades of mutual funds. In anticipation of a 1%-of-volume change in mutual fund flows into a stock next quarter, the institutions in the same 13F category as hedge funds trade 0.29-0.45% of volume in the current quarter. A third of the trading is associated with the subset of 504 identified hedge funds. The effect is stronger when quarterly mutual fund portfolio disclosure is required and among hedge funds with more patient capital. A one standard deviation higher measure of anticipatory trading by a hedge fund is associated with a 0.9% higher annualized four-factor alpha. A one standard deviation higher measure of anticipation of a mutual fund's trades by institutions is associated with a 0.07-0.15% lower annualized four-factor alpha. The effect is stronger for more constrained mutual funds. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Shive, Sophie; Yun, Hayong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diagnosing affine models of options pricing: Evidence from VIX</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Gang; Zhang, Chu
Affine jump-diffusion models have been the mainstream in options pricing because of their analytical tractability. Popular affine jump-diffusion models, however, are still unsatisfactory in describing the options data and the problem is often attributed to the diffusion term of the unobserved state variables. Using prices of variance-swaps (i.e., squared VIX) implied from options prices, we provide fresh evidence regarding the misspecification of affine jump-diffusion models, as variance-swap prices are affine functions of the state variables in a broader class of models that do not restrict the diffusion term of the state variables. We apply the nonparametric methodology used by Ait-Sahalia (1996b), supplemented with bootstrap tests and other parametric tests, to the S&amp;P 500 index options data from January 1996 to September 2008. We find that, while the affine diffusion term of the state variables may contribute to the misspecification as the literature has suggested, the affine drift of the state variables, jump intensities, and risk premiums are also sources of misspecification. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Gang; Zhang, Chu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A nonlinear wealth transfer from shareholders to creditors around Chapter 11 filing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Yuanzhi
Past literature has assumed that negative stock returns around Chapter 11 filing are solely due to new adverse information about firm value. This paper argues that there is also a nonlinear wealth transfer from shareholders to creditors causing shareholder loss. The magnitude of the wealth transfer can be quantified in a setting where equity is a call option on firm assets as in the Merton (1974) model. The wealth transfer originates from maturity shortening of the call option as a result of Chapter 11 filing. I present a parsimonious model to explain why Chapter 11 can be voluntarily filed by managers acting in the interest of shareholders with the existence of the wealth transfer. The model-predicted stock return has comparable magnitude as observed stock returns around filing, and explains the cross-sectional variation of the latter. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Yuanzhi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market for borrowing corporate bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asquith, Paul; Au, Andrea S.; Covert, Thomas; Pathak, Parag A.
This paper describes the market for borrowing corporate bonds using a comprehensive data set from a major lender. The cost of borrowing corporate bonds is comparable to the cost of borrowing stock, between 10 and 20 basis points, and both have fallen over time. Factors that influence borrowing costs are loan size, percentage of inventory lent, rating, and borrower identity. There is no evidence that bond short sellers have private information. Bonds with Credit Default Swaps (CDS) contracts are more actively lent than those without. Finally, the 2007 Credit Crunch does not affect average borrowing costs or loan volume, but does increase borrowing cost variance. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Asquith, Paul; Au, Andrea S.; Covert, Thomas; Pathak, Parag A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Style investing, comovement and return predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wahal, Sunil; Yavuz, M. Deniz
Barberis and Shleifer (2003) argue that style investing generates momentum and reversals in style and individual asset returns, as well as comovement between individual assets and their styles. Consistent with these predictions, in some specifications, past style returns help explain future stock returns after controlling for size, book-to-market and past stock returns. We also use comovement to identify style investing and assess its impact on momentum. High comovement momentum portfolios have significantly higher future returns than low comovement momentum portfolios. Overall, our results suggest that style investing plays a role in the predictability of asset returns. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wahal, Sunil; Yavuz, M. Deniz</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal incentives and securitization of defaultable assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malamud, Semyon; Rui, Huaxia; Whinston, Andrew
We study optimal securitization in the presence of an initial moral hazard. A financial intermediary creates and then sells to outside investors defaultable assets, whose default risk is determined by the unobservable costly effort exerted by the intermediary. We calculate the optimal contract for any given effort level and show the natural emergence of extreme punishment for defaults, under which investors stop paying the intermediary after the first default. With securitization contracts optimally designed, we find securitization improves the intermediary's screening incentives. Furthermore, the equilibrium effort level and the surplus converge to their first best levels with sufficiently many assets. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Malamud, Semyon; Rui, Huaxia; Whinston, Andrew</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do stock prices influence corporate decisions? Evidence from the technology bubble</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campello, Murillo; Graham, John R.
We study the capital investment, stock issuance, and cash savings behavior of non-tech manufacturers (old economy firms) during the 1990s technology bubble. Our empirical results show that high stock prices affect corporate policies because they relax financing constraints. During the tech bubble, constrained non-tech firms' investment responded strongly to "high stock prices" (specifically, the component of price that is not captured by fundamentals). They also issued stock in response to that overvaluation effect, saving part of the proceeds in their cash accounts. We find no such patterns for unconstrained non-tech firms, nor for tech firms. Our findings are not consistent with the notion that managers systematically issue overvalued stocks and invest in ways that transfer wealth from new to old shareholders. More broadly, they suggest that what appears to be overvaluation in one sector of the economy may have positive externalities for other sectors. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Campello, Murillo; Graham, John R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Riding the merger wave: Uncertainty, reduced monitoring, and bad acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duchin, Ran; Schmidt, Breno
We show that acquisitions initiated during periods of high merger activity ("merger waves") are accompanied by poorer quality of analysts' forecasts, greater uncertainty, and weaker CEO turnover-performance sensitivity. These conditions imply reduced monitoring and lower penalties for initiating inefficient mergers. Therefore, merger waves may foster agency-driven behavior, which, along with managerial herding, could lead to worse mergers. Consistent with this hypothesis, we find that the average long-term performance of acquisitions initiated during merger waves is significantly worse. We also find that corporate governance of in-wave acquirers is weaker, suggesting that agency problems may be present in merger wave acquisitions. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duchin, Ran; Schmidt, Breno</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market skewness risk and the cross section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Bo Young; Christoffersen, Peter; Jacobs, Kris
The cross section of stock returns has substantial exposure to risk captured by higher moments of market returns. We estimate these moments from daily Standard &amp; Poor's 500 index option data. The resulting time series of factors are genuinely conditional and forward-looking. Stocks with high exposure to innovations in implied market skewness exhibit low returns on average. The results are robust to various permutations of the empirical setup. The market skewness risk premium is statistically and economically significant and cannot be explained by other common risk factors such as the market excess return or the size, book-to-market, momentum, and market volatility factors, or by firm characteristics. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Bo Young; Christoffersen, Peter; Jacobs, Kris</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Laying off credit risk: Loan sales versus credit default swaps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parlour, Christine A.; Winton, Andrew
How do markets for debt cash flow rights, with and without accompanying control rights, affect the efficiency of lending? A bank makes a loan, learns if it needs monitoring, and then decides whether to lay off credit risk. The bank can transfer credit risk by either selling the loan or buying a credit default swap (CDS). With a CDS, the originating bank retains the loan's control rights; with loan sales, control rights pass to the loan buyer. Credit risk transfer leads to excessive monitoring of riskier credits and insufficient monitoring of safer credits. Increases in banks' cost of equity capital exacerbate these effects. For riskier credits, loan sales typically dominate CDS but not for safer credits. Once repeated lending and consequent reputation concerns are modeled, although CDSs remain dominated by loan sales for riskier credits, for safer credits they can dominate loan sales, supporting better monitoring (albeit to a limited extent) while allowing efficient risk sharing. Restrictions on the bank's ability to sell the loan expand the range in which CDSs are used and monitoring is too low. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Parlour, Christine A.; Winton, Andrew</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Payout taxes and the allocation of investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, Bo; Jacob, Marcus; Jacob, Martin
When corporate payout is taxed, internal equity (retained earnings) is cheaper than external equity (share issues). If there are no perfect substitutes for equity finance, payout taxes may therefore have an effect on the investment of firms. High taxes will favor investment by firms who can finance internally. Using an international panel with many changes in payout taxes, we show that this prediction holds well. Payout taxes have a large impact on the dynamics of corporate investment and growth. Investment is "locked in" in profitable firms when payout is heavily taxed. Thus, apart from any level effects, payout taxes change the allocation of capital. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Becker, Bo; Jacob, Marcus; Jacob, Martin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The mystery of zero-leverage firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Strebulaev, Ilya A.; Yang, Baozhong
We present the puzzling evidence that, from 1962 to 2009, an average 10.2% of large public nonfinancial US firms have zero debt and almost 22% have less than 5% book leverage ratio. Zero-leverage behavior is a persistent phenomenon. Dividend-paying zero-leverage firms pay substantially higher dividends, are more profitable, pay higher taxes, issue less equity, and have higher cash balances than control firms chosen by industry and size. Firms with higher Chief Executive Officer (CEO) ownership and longer CEO tenure are more likely to have zero debt, especially if boards are smaller and less independent. Family firms are also more likely to be zero-levered. (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Strebulaev, Ilya A.; Yang, Baozhong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Acquisitions driven by stock overvaluation: Are they good deals?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fu, Fangjian; Lin, Leming; Officer, Micah S.
Theory and recent evidence suggest that overvalued firms can create value for shareholders if they exploit their overvaluation by using their stock as currency to purchase less overvalued firms. We challenge this idea and show that, in practice, overvalued acquirers significantly overpay for their targets. These acquisitions do not, in turn, lead to synergy gains. Moreover, these acquisitions seem to be concentrated among acquirers with the largest governance problems. CEO compensation, not shareholder value creation, appears to be the main motive behind acquisitions by overvalued acquirers. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fu, Fangjian; Lin, Leming; Officer, Micah S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are busy boards detrimental?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Field, Laura; Lowry, Michelle; Mkrtchyan, Anahit
Busy directors have been widely criticized as being ineffective. However, we hypothesize that busy directors offer advantages for many firms. While busy directors may be less effective monitors, their experience and contacts arguably make them excellent advisors. Among IPO firms, which have minimal experience with public markets and likely rely heavily on their directors for advising, we find busy boards to be common and to contribute positively to firm value. Moreover, these positive effects of busy boards extend to all but the most established firms. Benefits are lowest among Forbes 500 firms, which likely require more monitoring than advising. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Field, Laura; Lowry, Michelle; Mkrtchyan, Anahit</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial attitudes and corporate actions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, John R.; Harvey, Campbell R.; Puri, Manju
We administer psychometric tests to senior executives to obtain evidence on their underlying psychological traits and attitudes. We find US CEOs differ significantly from non-US CEOs in terms of their underlying attitudes. In addition, we find that CEOs are significantly more optimistic and risk-tolerant than the lay population. We provide evidence that CEOs' behavioral traits such as optimism and managerial risk-aversion are related to corporate financial policies. Further, we provide new empirical evidence that CEO traits such as risk-aversion and time preference are related to their compensation. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Graham, John R.; Harvey, Campbell R.; Puri, Manju</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The deep-pocket effect of internal capital markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boutin, Xavier; Cestone, Giacinta; Fumagalli, Chiara; Pica, Giovanni; Serrano-Velarde, Nicolas
We provide evidence that incumbent and entrant firms' access to business group deep pockets affects the entry patterns in product markets. Relying on a unique French data set on business groups, our paper shows that entry into manufacturing industries is negatively related to the cash hoarded by incumbent affiliated groups and positively related to entrant groups' cash. In line with theoretical predictions, we find that the impact of group cash holdingson entry is more important in environments where financial constraints are pronounced. The cash holdings of incumbent and entrant groups also affect the survival rate of entrants in the three- to five-year post-entry window. Overall, our findings suggest that internal capital markets operate within corporate groups and affect the product market behavior of affiliated firms by mitigating financial constraints. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boutin, Xavier; Cestone, Giacinta; Fumagalli, Chiara; Pica, Giovanni; Serrano-Velarde, Nicolas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does capital affect bank performance during financial crises?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; Bouwman, Christa H. S.
This paper empirically examines how capital affects a bank's performance (survival and market share) and how this effect varies across banking crises, market crises, and normal times that occurred in the US over the past quarter century. We have two main results. First, capital helps small banks to increase their probability of survival and market share at all times (during banking crises, market crises, and normal times). Second, capital enhances the performance of medium and large banks primarily during banking crises. Additional tests explore channels through which capital generates these effects. Numerous robustness checks and additional tests are performed. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; Bouwman, Christa H. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are there too many safe securities? Securitization and the incentives for information production</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanson, Samuel G.; Sunderam, Adi
We present a model that helps explain several past collapses of securitization markets. Originators issue too many informationally insensitive securities in good times, blunting investor incentives to become informed. The resulting endogenous scarcity of informed investors exacerbates primary market collapses in bad times. Inefficiency arises because informed investors are a public good from the perspective of originators. All originators benefit from the presence of additional informed investors in bad times, but each originator minimizes his reliance on costly informed capital in good times by issuing safe securities. Our model suggests regulations that limit the issuance of safe securities in good times. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hanson, Samuel G.; Sunderam, Adi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New evidence on the first financial bubble</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frehen, Rik G. P.; Goetzrnann, William N.; Rouwenhorst, K. Geert
The Mississippi Bubble, South Sea Bubble and the Dutch Windhandel of 1720 together represent the world's first global financial bubble. We hand-collect cross-sectional price data and investor account data from 1720 to test theories about market bubbles. Our tests suggest that innovation was a key driver of bubble expectations. We present evidence against the currently prevailing debt-for-equity conversion hypothesis and relate stock returns to innovations in Atlantic trade and insurance. We find evidence consistent with the innovation-driven bubble dynamics documented by Pastor and Veronesi (2009) for new economy stocks. Our evidence seems inconsistent with clientele-based theories that emphasize bubble-riding and short-sales restrictions. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frehen, Rik G. P.; Goetzrnann, William N.; Rouwenhorst, K. Geert</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of state and foreign owners in corporate risk-taking: Evidence from privatization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boubakri, Narjess; Cosset, Jean-Claude; Saffar, Walid
Using a unique database of 381 newly privatized firms from 57 countries, we investigate the impact of shareholders' identity on corporate risk-taking behavior. We find strong and robust evidence that state (foreign) ownership is negatively (positively) related to corporate risk-taking. Moreover, we find that high risk-taking by foreign owners depends on the strength of country-level governance institutions. Our results suggest that relinquishment of government control, openness to foreign investment, and improvement of country-level governance institutions are key determining factors of corporate risk-taking in newly privatized firms. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boubakri, Narjess; Cosset, Jean-Claude; Saffar, Walid</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO contract design: How do strong principals do it?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cronqvist, Henrik; Fahlenbrach, Ruediger
We study changes in chief executive officer (CEO) contracts when firms transition from public ownership with dispersed owners to private ownership with strong principals in the form of private equity sponsors. The most significant changes are that a significant portion of equity grants performance-vests based on prespecified measures and that unvested equity is forfeited by fired CEOs. Private equity sponsors do not reduce base salaries, bonuses, and perks, but redesign contracts away from qualitative measures. They use some subjective performance evaluation, do not use indexed or premium options, and do not condition vesting on relative industry performance. We compare the contracts to predictions from contracting theories, and relate our results to discussions of executive compensation reform. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cronqvist, Henrik; Fahlenbrach, Ruediger</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor unions and tax aggressiveness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chyz, James A.; Leung, Winnie Siu Ching; Li, Oliver Zhen; Rui, Oliver Meng
We examine the impact of unionization on firms' tax aggressiveness. We find a negative association between firms' tax aggressiveness and union power and a decrease in tax aggressiveness after labor union election wins. This relation is consistent with labor unions influencing managers' in one, or both, of two ways: (1) constraining managers' ability to invest in tax aggressiveness through increased monitoring: or (2) decreasing returns to tax aggressiveness that arise from unions' rent seeking behavior. We also find preliminary evidence that the market expects these reductions around union elections and discounts firms that likely add shareholder value via aggressive tax strategies. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chyz, James A.; Leung, Winnie Siu Ching; Li, Oliver Zhen; Rui, Oliver Meng</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cross section of conditional mutual fund performance in European stock markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banegas, Ayelen; Gillen, Ben; Timmermann, Allan; Wermers, Russ
This paper implements strategies that use macroeconomic variables to select European equity mutual funds, including Pan-European, country, and sector funds. We find that several macro-variables are useful in locating funds with future outperformance and that country-specific mutual funds provide the best opportunities for fund rotation strategies using macroeconomic information. Specifically, our baseline long-only strategies that exploit time-varying predictability provide four-factor alphas of 12-13% per year over the 1993-2008 period. Our study provides new evidence on the skills of local versus Pan-European asset managers, as well as how macroeconomic information can be used to locate and time these local fund manager skills. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Banegas, Ayelen; Gillen, Ben; Timmermann, Allan; Wermers, Russ</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"When the cat's away the mice will play": Does regulation at home affect bank risk-taking abroad?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ongena, Steven; Popov, Alexander; Udell, Gregory F.
This paper provides the first empirical evidence that bank regulation is associated with cross-border spillover effects through the lending activities of large multinational banks. We analyze business lending by 155 banks to 9,613 firms in 1,976 different localities across 16 countries. We find that lower barriers to entry, tighter restrictions on bank activities, and to a lesser degree higher minimum capital requirements in domestic markets are associated with lower bank lending standards abroad. The effects are stronger when banks are less efficiently supervised at home, and are observed to exist independently from the impact of host-country regulation. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ongena, Steven; Popov, Alexander; Udell, Gregory F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exploring the role Delaware plays as a domestic tax haven</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dyreng, Scott D.; Lindsey, Bradley P.; Thornock, Jacob R.
We examine whether Delaware is a domestic tax haven. We find that taxes play an economically important role in determining whether U.S. firms locate subsidiaries in Delaware and that a Delaware-based state tax avoidance strategy lowers state effective tax rates by between 0.7 and 1.1 percentage points, on average. The tax savings represent a 15-24% decrease in the state income tax burden and translate to an increase in net income of 1.04-1.47%. However, we find that the tax benefits of Delaware tax strategies are diminishing over time in response to initiatives by state governments to limit multistate tax avoidance. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dyreng, Scott D.; Lindsey, Bradley P.; Thornock, Jacob R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional trading and stock resiliency: Evidence from the 2007-2009 financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anand, Amber; Irvine, Paul; Puckett, Andy; Venkataraman, Kumar
We examine the impact of institutional trading on stock resiliency during the financial crisis of 2007-2009. We show that buy-side institutions have different exposure to liquidity factors based on their trading style. Liquidity supplying institutions absorb the long-term order imbalances in the market and are critical to recovery patterns after a liquidity shock. We show that these liquidity suppliers withdraw from risky securities during the crisis and their participation does not recover for an extended period of time. The illiquidity of specific stocks is significantly affected by institutional trading patterns; participation by liquidity supplying institutions can ameliorate illiquidity, while participation by liquidity demanding institutions can exacerbate illiquidity. Our results provide guidance on why some stocks take longer to recover in a crisis. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anand, Amber; Irvine, Paul; Puckett, Andy; Venkataraman, Kumar</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Adoptive expectations: Rising sons in Japanese family firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mehrotra, Vikas; Morck, Randall; Shim, Jungwook; Wiwattanakantang, Yupana
We find inherited family firms more important in postwar Japan than generally realized, and also performing well on average. Non-consanguineous heir-run firms outperform blood heirs' firms, and roughly match founder-run listed firms, while blood heirs surpass professional managers at running family firms. Further, succession events suggest that adopted heirs "cause" elevated performance. We suggest that heir-run firms do well because non-consanguineous heirs displace the least talented blood heirs, the non-consanguineous heir "job" motivates professional managers, and the threat of displacement encourages blood heirs' effort and human capital accumulation, mitigating the "Carnegie conjecture" that inherited wealth deadens talent. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mehrotra, Vikas; Morck, Randall; Shim, Jungwook; Wiwattanakantang, Yupana</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>General equilibrium with heterogeneous participants and discrete consumption times</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vasicek, Oldrich Alfons
The paper investigates the term structure of interest rates imposed by equilibrium in a production economy consisting of participants with heterogeneous preferences. Consumption is restricted to an arbitrary number of discrete times. The paper contains an exact solution to market equilibrium and provides an explicit constructive algorithm for determining the state price density process. The convergence of the algorithm is proven. Interest rates and their behavior are given as a function of economic variables. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vasicek, Oldrich Alfons</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A new approach to predicting analyst forecast errors: Do investors overweight analyst forecasts?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>So, Eric C.
I provide evidence that investors overweight analyst forecasts by demonstrating that prices do not fully reflect predictable components of analyst errors, which conflicts with conclusions in prior research. I highlight estimation bias in traditional approaches and develop a new approach that reduces this bias. I estimate characteristic forecasts that map current firm characteristics into forecasts of future earnings. Contrasting characteristic and analyst forecasts predicts analyst forecast errors and revisions. I find abnormal returns to strategies that sort firms by predicted forecast errors, consistent with investors overweighting analyst forecasts and predictable biases in analyst forecasts influencing the information content of prices. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>So, Eric C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pyramidal ownership and the creation of new firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bena, Jan; Ortiz-Molina, Hernan
We study the role of pyramidal ownership structures in the creation of new firms. Our results suggest that pyramids arise because they provide a financing advantage in setting up new firms when the pledgeability of cash flows to outside financiers is limited. Parent companies supply inside funds to new firms that, due to large investment requirements and low pledgeable cash flows, cannot raise enough external financing. The financing advantage of pyramidal structures is pervasive in many countries, exists regardless of whether new firms are set up by business groups or by smaller organizations, and is an important underpinning of entrepreneurial activity. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bena, Jan; Ortiz-Molina, Hernan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gender and corporate finance: Are male executives overconfident relative to female executives?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Jiekun; Kisgen, Darren J.
We examine corporate financial and investment decisions made by female executives compared with male executives. Male executives undertake more acquisitions and issue debt more often than female executives. Further, acquisitions made by firms with male executives have announcement returns approximately 2% lower than those made by female executive firms, and debt issues also have lower announcement returns for firms with male executives. Female executives place wider bounds on earnings estimates and are more likely to exercise stock options early. This evidence suggests men exhibit relative overconfidence in significant corporate decision making compared with women. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Jiekun; Kisgen, Darren J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why are US firms using more short-term debt?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Custodio, Claudia; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Laureano, Luis
We show that corporate use of long-term debt has decreased in the US over the past three decades and that this trend is heterogeneous across firms. The median percentage of debt maturing in more than 3 years decreased from 53% in 1976 to 6% in 2008 for the smallest firms but did not decrease for the largest firms. The decrease in debt maturity was generated by firms with higher information asymmetry and new firms issuing public equity in the 1980s and 1990s. Finally, we show that demand-side factors do not fully explain this trend and that public debt markets' supply-side factors play an important role. Our findings suggest that the shortening of debt maturity has increased the exposure of firms to credit and liquidity shocks. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Custodio, Claudia; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Laureano, Luis</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The inefficiency of refinancing: Why prepayment penalties are good for risky borrowers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mayer, Chris; Piskorski, Tomasz; Tchistyi, Alexei
This paper provides a theoretical analysis of the efficiency of prepayment penalties in a dynamic competitive lending model with risky borrowers and costly default. When considering improvements in the borrower's creditworthiness as one of the reasons for refinancing mortgages, we show that refinancing penalties can be welfare improving and that they can be particularly beneficial to riskier borrowers in the form of lower mortgage rates, reduced defaults, and increased availability of credit. Thus, a high concentration of prepayment penalties among the riskiest borrowers can be an outcome of efficient equilibrium in a mortgage market. We also provide empirical evidence that is consistent with the key predictions of our model. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mayer, Chris; Piskorski, Tomasz; Tchistyi, Alexei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political activism, information costs, and stock market participation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bonaparte, Yosef; Kumar, Alok
This paper examines whether political activism increases people's propensity to participate in the stock market. Our key conjecture is that politically active people follow political news more actively, which increases their chance of being exposed to financial news. Consequently, their information gathering costs are likely to be lower and the propensity to participate in the market would be higher. We find support for this hypothesis using multiple micro-level data sets, state-level data from the US, and cross-country data from Europe. Irrespective of their political affiliation, politically active individuals are 9-25% more likely to participate in the stock market. Using residence in "battleground" states and several other geographic instruments, we demonstrate that greater political activism reduces information gathering costs and causes higher market participation rates. Further, consistent with our conjecture, we find that politically active individuals spend about 30 minutes more on news daily and appear more knowledgeable about the economy and the markets. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bonaparte, Yosef; Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inequality, stock market participation, and the equity premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Favilukis, Jack
The last 30 years saw substantial increases in wealth inequality and stock market participation, smaller increases in consumption inequality and the fraction of indebted households, a decline in interest rates and the expected equity premium, as well as a prolonged stock market boom. In an incomplete markets, overlapping generations model I jointly explain these trends by the observed rise in wage inequality, decrease in participation costs, and loosening of borrowing constraints. After accounting for these changes, I show that the stock market played a major role in increasing wealth inequality. Crucially, these phenomena must be considered jointly; studying one independently leads to counterfactual predictions about others. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Favilukis, Jack</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prospect theory, the disposition effect, and asset prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Yan; Yang, Liyan
We build a general equilibrium model to examine the implications of prospect theory for the disposition effect, asset prices, and trading volume. Diminishing sensitivity predicts a disposition effect, price momentum, a reduced return volatility, and a positive return-volume correlation. Loss aversion generally predicts the opposite. In calibrated economies, there is a nontrivial range of preference parameters for prospect theory to simultaneously explain the disposition effect, the momentum effect, and the equity premium puzzle. Our model is helpful for understanding a wide range of financial phenomena and it also suggests new testable predictions. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Yan; Yang, Liyan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic alliances, venture capital, and exit decisions in early stage high-tech firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ozmel, Umit; Robinson, David T.; Stuart, Toby E.
We study the trade-offs that biotech start-ups face in the private equity market when they choose between raising firm-level capital from venture capitalists or project-level capital from strategic alliance partners. Increased alliance activity makes future alliances more likely, but future VC activity less likely. In contrast, venture capital (VC) activity makes both future alliance and future VC activity more likely. Both types of private capital raise the hazard of going public. Acquisition as an alternative to initial public offering is made more likely by increased VC activity, but the link between acquisition probabilities and alliance activity is less clear-cut. These results highlight both the importance of alliance partners in resolving asymmetric information problems in the capital acquisition process and the potential conflict of interest between different sources of private equity. (C) 2012 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Ozmel, Umit; Robinson, David T.; Stuart, Toby E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The costs of shareholder activism: Evidence from a sequential decision model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gantchev, Nickolay
This paper provides benchmarks for monitoring costs and evaluates the net returns to shareholder activism. I model activism as a sequential decision process consisting of demand negotiations, board representation, and proxy contest and estimate the costs of each activism stage. A campaign ending in a proxy fight has average costs of $10.71 million. I find that the estimated monitoring costs reduce activist returns by more than two-thirds. The mean net activist return is close to zero but the top quartile of activists earns higher returns on their activist holdings than on their non-activist investments. The large-sample evidence presented in this paper aids in understanding the nature and evolution of activist engagements. (C) Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gantchev, Nickolay</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inventory investment and the cost of capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, Christopher S.; Tuzel, Selale
We examine the relation between inventory investment and the cost of capital in the time series and the cross section. We find consistent evidence that risk premiums, rather than real interest rates, are strongly negatively related to future inventory growth at the aggregate, industry, and firm levels. The effect is stronger for firms in industries that produce durables rather than nondurables, exhibit greater cyclicality in sales, require longer lead times, and are subject to more technological innovation. We then construct a production-based asset pricing model with two types of capital, fixed capital and inventories, to explain these empirical findings. Convex adjustment costs and a countercyclical price of risk lead to negative time series and cross-sectional relations between expected returns and inventory growth. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jones, Christopher S.; Tuzel, Selale</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The "out-of-sample" performance of long run risk models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferson, Wayne; Nallareddy, Suresh; Xie, Biqin
This paper studies the ability of long-run risk models to explain out-of-sample asset returns during 1931-2009. The long-run risk models perform relatively well on the momentum effect. A cointegrated version of the model outperforms the classical, stationary version. Both the long-run and the short-run consumption shocks in the models are empirically important for the models' performance. The models' average pricing errors are especially small in the decades from the 1950s to the 1990s. When we restrict the risk premiums to identify structural parameters, this results in larger average pricing errors but often smaller error variances. The mean squared errors are not substantially better than those of the classical CAPM, except for Momentum. (C) 2012 Elsevier BA. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferson, Wayne; Nallareddy, Suresh; Xie, Biqin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross section of option returns and idiosyncratic stock volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Jie; Han, Bing
This paper presents a robust new finding that delta-hedged equity option return decreases monotonically with an increase in the idiosyncratic volatility of the underlying stock. This result cannot be explained by standard risk factors. It is distinct from existing anomalies in the stock market or volatility-related option mispricing. It is consistent with market imperfections and constrained financial intermediaries. Dealers charge a higher premium for options on high idiosyncratic volatility stocks due to their higher arbitrage costs. Controlling for limits to arbitrage proxies reduces the strength of the negative relation between delta-hedged option return and idiosyncratic volatility by about 40%. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Cao, Jie; Han, Bing</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning from repetitive acquisitions: Evidence from the time between deals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aktas, Nihat; de Bodt, Eric; Roll, Richard
Knowledge gleaned from previous acquisitions may confer valuation expertise and other benefits. But numerous acquisitions also entail costs, due to problems of incorporating diverse units into an ever larger firm. Such benefits and costs are not directly observable from outside the firm. This article proposes a simple model to infer their relative importance, using the time between successive deals. The data requirements are minimal and allow the use of all mergers and acquisitions during 1992-2009 (more than 300,000 deals). The results provide evidence of learning gains through repetitive acquisitions, especially under CEO continuity and when successive deals are more similar. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aktas, Nihat; de Bodt, Eric; Roll, Richard</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rating agencies in the face of regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Opp, Christian C.; Opp, Marcus M.; Harris, Milton
This paper develops a theoretical framework to shed light on variation in credit rating standards over time and across asset classes. Ratings issued by credit rating agencies serve a dual role: they provide information to investors and are used to regulate institutional investors. We show that introducing rating-contingent regulation that favors highly rated securities may increase or decrease rating informativeness, but unambiguously increases the volume of highly rated securities. If the regulatory advantage of highly rated securities is sufficiently large, delegated information acquisition is unsustainable, since the rating agency prefers to facilitate regulatory arbitrage by inflating ratings. Our model relates rating informativeness to the quality distribution of issuers, the complexity of assets, and issuers' outside options. We reconcile our results with the existing empirical literature and highlight new, testable implications, such as repercussions of the Dodd-Frank Act. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Opp, Christian C.; Opp, Marcus M.; Harris, Milton</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The earnings announcement premium around the globe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barber, Brad M.; De George, Emmanuel T.; Lehavy, Reuven; Trueman, Brett
U.S. stocks have been shown to earn higher returns during earnings announcement months than during non-announcement months. We document that this earnings announcement premium exists across the globe. Moreover, it is not isolated to a few countries. Of the 20 countries with enough data to conduct a within-country analysis, nine exhibit a significantly positive premium. A cross-country analysis finds that the premium is strongest in countries with the greatest increase in idiosyncratic volatility around the time of their firms' earnings announcements, suggesting that uncertainty over the earnings information to be disclosed is a primary driver of the global announcement premium. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barber, Brad M.; De George, Emmanuel T.; Lehavy, Reuven; Trueman, Brett</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO wage dynamics: Estimates from a learning model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, Lucian A.
The level of Chief Executive Officer (CEO) pay responds asymmetrically to good and bad news about the CEO's ability. The average CEO captures approximately half of the surpluses from good news, implying CEOs and shareholders have roughly equal bargaining power. In contrast, the average CEO bears none of the negative surplus from bad news, implying CEOs have downward rigid pay. These estimates are consistent with the optimal contracting benchmark of Harris and Holmstrom (1982) and do not appear to be driven by weak governance. Risk-averse CEOs accept significantly lower compensation in return for the insurance provided by downward rigid pay. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Taylor, Lucian A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ratings quality over the business cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bar-Isaac, Heski; Shapiro, Joel
Credit rating agencies (CRAs) have long held that reputational concerns discipline their behavior. The value of reputation, however, depends on economic fundamentals that vary over the business cycle. In a model of ratings incorporating endogenous reputation and a market environment that varies, we find that ratings quality is countercyclical. Specifically, a CRA is more likely to issue less-accurate ratings when fee-income is high, competition in the labor market for analysts is tough, and securities' default probabilities are low. Persistence in economic conditions can diminish our results, while mean reversion exacerbates them. The presence of naive investors reduces overall quality, but quality remains countercyclical. Finally, we demonstrate that competition among CRAs yields similar results. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bar-Isaac, Heski; Shapiro, Joel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic risk and the refinancing ratchet effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khandani, Amir E.; Lo, Andrew W.; Merton, Robert C.
The combination of rising home prices, declining interest rates, and near-frictionless refinancing opportunities can create unintentional synchronization of homeowner leverage, leading to a "ratchet" effect on leverage because homes are indivisible and owner-occupants cannot raise equity to reduce leverage when home prices fall. Our simulation of the U.S. housing market yields potential losses of $1.7 trillion from June 2006 to December 2008 with cash-out refinancing vs. only $330 billion in the absence of cash-out refinancing. The refinancing ratchet effect is a new type of systemic risk in the financial system and does not rely on any dysfunctional behaviors. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Khandani, Amir E.; Lo, Andrew W.; Merton, Robert C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Generalists versus specialists: Lifetime work experience and chief executive officer pay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Custodio, Claudia; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro
We show that pay is higher for chief executive officers (CEOs) with general managerial skills gathered during lifetime work experience. We use CEOs' resumes of Standard and Poor's 1,500 firms from 1993 through 2007 to construct an index of general skills that are transferable across firms and industries. We estimate an annual pay premium for generalist CEOs (those with an index value above the median) of 19% relative to specialist CEOs, which represents nearly a million dollars per year. This relation is robust to the inclusion of firm- and CEO-level controls, including fixed effects. CEO pay increases the most when firms externally hire a new CEO and switch from a specialist to a generalist CEO. Furthermore, the pay premium is higher when CEOs are hired to perform complex tasks such as restructurings and acquisitions. Our findings provide direct evidence of the increased importance of general managerial skills over firm-specific human capital in the market for CEOs in the last decades. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Custodio, Claudia; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Flow and stock effects of large-scale treasury purchases: Evidence on the importance of local supply</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>D'Amico, Stefania; King, Thomas B.
The Federal Reserve's 2009 program to purchase $300 billion of US Treasury securities represented an unprecedented intervention in the Treasury market and provides a natural experiment with the potential to shed light on the price elasticities of Treasuries and theories of supply effects in the term structure. Using security-level data on Treasury prices and quantities during the course of this program, we document a 'local supply' effect in the yield curve yields within a particular maturity sector responded more to changes in the amounts outstanding in that sector than to similar changes in other sectors. We find that this phenomenon was responsible for a persistent downward shift in yields averaging about 30 basis points over the course of the program (the "stock effect"). In addition, except at very long maturities, purchase operations caused an average decline in yields in the sector purchased of 3.5 basis points on the days when those operations occurred (the "flow effect"). The sensitivity of our results to security characteristics generally supports a view of segmentation or imperfect substitution within the Treasury market during this time. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>D'Amico, Stefania; King, Thomas B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk and return: Long-run relations, fractional cointegration, and return predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollerslev, Tim; Osterrieder, Daniela; Sizova, Natalia; Tauchen, George
Univariate dependencies in market volatility, both objective and risk neutral, are best described by long-memory fractionally integrated processes. Meanwhile, the ex post difference, or the variance swap payoff reflecting the reward for bearing volatility risk, displays far less persistent dynamics. Using intraday data for the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 and the volatility index (VIX), coupled with frequency domain methods, we separate the series into various components. We find that the coherence between volatility and the volatility-risk reward is the strongest at long-run frequencies. Our results are consistent with generalized long-run risk models and help explain why classical efforts of establishing a naive return-volatility relation fail. We also estimate a fractionally cointegrated vector autoregression (CFVAR). The model-implied long-run equilibrium relation between the two variance variables results in nontrivial return predictability over interdaily and monthly horizons, supporting the idea that the cointegrating relation between the two variance measures proxies for the economic uncertainty rewarded by the market. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bollerslev, Tim; Osterrieder, Daniela; Sizova, Natalia; Tauchen, George</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real effects of stock underpricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hau, Harald; Lai, Sandy
This paper provides evidence for a causal effect of equity prices on corporate investment and employment. We use fire sales by distressed equity funds during the 2007-2009 financial crisis to identify substantial exogenous underpricing. Firms whose stocks are most underpriced have considerably lower investment and employment than industry peers not subject to any fire sale discount. The causal effect of underpricing on investment is found to be largely concentrated on the most financially constrained firms. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hau, Harald; Lai, Sandy</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning and the disappearing association between governance and returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bebchuk, Lucian A.; Cohen, Alma; Wang, Charles C. Y.
The correlation between governance indices and abnormal returns documented for 1990-1999 subsequently disappeared. The correlation and its disappearance are both due to market participants' gradually learning to appreciate the difference between good-governance and poor-governance firms. Consistent with learning, the correlation's disappearance was associated with increases in market participants' attention to governance; market participants and security analysts were, until the beginning of the 2000s but not subsequently, more positively surprised by the earning announcements of good-governance firms; and, although governance indices no longer generated abnormal returns during the 2000s, their negative association with firm value and operating performance persisted. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bebchuk, Lucian A.; Cohen, Alma; Wang, Charles C. Y.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anomalies and financial distress</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avramov, Doron; Chordia, Tarun; Jostova, Gergana; Philipov, Alexander
This paper explores commonalities across asset pricing anomalies. In particular, we assess implications of financial distress for the profitability of anomaly-based trading strategies. Strategies based on price momentum, earnings momentum, credit risk, dispersion, idiosyncratic volatility, and capital investments derive their profitability from taking short positions in high credit risk firms that experience deteriorating credit conditions. In contrast, the value-based strategy derives most of its profitability from taking long positions in high credit risk firms that survive financial distress and subsequently realize high returns. The accruals anomaly is an exception. It is robust among high and low credit risk firms in all credit conditions. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Avramov, Doron; Chordia, Tarun; Jostova, Gergana; Philipov, Alexander</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Peer choice in CEO compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albuquerque, Ana M.; De Franco, Gus; Verdi, Rodrigo S.
Current research shows that firms are more likely to benchmark against peers that pay their Chief Executive Officers (CEOs) higher compensation, reflecting self serving behavior. We propose an alternative explanation: the choice of highly paid peers represents a reward for unobserved CEO talent. We test this hypothesis by decomposing the effect of peer selection into talent and self serving components. Consistent with our prediction, we find that the association between a firm's selection of highly paid peers and CEO pay mostly represents compensation for CEO talent. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Albuquerque, Ana M.; De Franco, Gus; Verdi, Rodrigo S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does shareholder coordination matter? Evidence from private placements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chakraborty, Indraneel; Gantchev, Nickolay
We propose a new role for private investments in public equity (PIPEs) as a mechanism to reduce coordination frictions among existing equity holders. We establish a causal link between the coordination ability of incumbent shareholders and PIPE issuance. This result obtains even after controlling for alternative explanations such as information asymmetry and access to public markets. Improved equity coordination following a private placement leads to favorable debt renegotiations within one year of issuance. Mitigating coordination frictions among shareholders ultimately decreases the odds of firm default in half. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chakraborty, Indraneel; Gantchev, Nickolay</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The other side of value: The gross profitability premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Novy-Marx, Robert
Profitability, measured by gross profits-to-assets, has roughly the same power as book-to-market predicting the cross section of average returns. Profitable firms generate significantly higher returns than unprofitable firms, despite having significantly higher valuation ratios. Controlling for profitability also dramatically increases the performance of value strategies, especially among the largest, most liquid stocks. These results are difficult to reconcile with popular explanations of the value premium, as profitable firms are less prone to distress, have longer cash flow durations, and have lower levels of operating leverage. Controlling for gross profitability explains most earnings related anomalies and a wide range of seemingly unrelated profitable trading strategies. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Novy-Marx, Robert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The acquisitiveness of youth: CEO age and acquisition behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yim, Soojin
I demonstrate that acquisitions are accompanied by large, permanent increases in Chief Executive Officer (CEO) compensation, which create strong financial incentives for CEOs to pursue acquisitions earlier in their career. Accordingly, I document that a firm's acquisition propensity is decreasing in the age of its CEO: a firm with a CEO who is 20 years older is similar to 30% less likely to announce an acquisition. This negative effect of CEO age on acquisitions is strongest among firms where CEOs likely anticipate or can influence high post-acquisition compensation, and is absent for other investment decisions that are not rewarded with permanent compensation gains. The age effect cannot be explained by the selection of young CEOs by acquisition-prone firms, nor by a story of declining overconfidence with age. This paper underscores the relevance of CEO personal characteristics and CEO-level variation in agency problems for corporate decisions. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yim, Soojin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of securitization on the expansion of subprime credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nadauld, Taylor D.; Sherlund, Shane M.
This paper investigates the relationship between securitization activity and the extension of subprime credit. The analysis is motivated by two sets of compelling empirical facts. First, the origination of subprime mortgages exploded between the years 2003 and 2005. Second, the securitization of subprime loans increased substantially over the same time period, driven primarily by the five largest independent broker/dealer investment banks. We argue that the relative shift in the securitization activity of investment banks was driven by forces exogenous to factors impacting lending decisions in the primary mortgage market and resulted in lower ZIP code denial rates, higher subprime origination rates, and higher subsequent default rates. Consistent with recent findings in the literature, we provide evidence that the increased securitization activity of investment banks reduced lenders' incentives to carefully screen borrowers. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nadauld, Taylor D.; Sherlund, Shane M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contagion of a liquidity crisis between two firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oh, Frederick Dongchuhl
This paper presents a model in which the contagion of a liquidity crisis between two nonfinancial institutions occurs because of learning activity within a common creditor pool. After creditors observe what occurs in a rollover game for a firm, they conjecture one another's "type" or attitude toward the risk associated with the firm's investment project. Creditors' inference about one another's type then influences their decision to lend to the next firm. By providing an analysis of the "incidence of failure" (the threshold for a liquidity crisis) for each firm, this paper demonstrates that the risk of contagion increases sharply if it originates ex ante from a firm facing a low probability of failure. In addition, the paper proposes some policy measures for mitigating the severity of contagion during a liquidity crisis. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Oh, Frederick Dongchuhl</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Growth options, macroeconomic conditions, and the cross section of credit risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arnold, Marc; Wagner, Alexander F.; Westermann, Ramona
This paper develops a structural equilibrium model with intertemporal macroeconomic risk, incorporating the fact that firms are heterogeneous in their asset composition. Compared with firms that are mainly composed of invested assets, firms with growth options have higher costs of debt because they are more volatile and have a greater tendency to default during recession when marginal utility is high and recovery rates are low. Our model matches empirical facts regarding credit spreads, default probabilities, leverage ratios, equity premiums, and investment clustering. Importantly, it also makes predictions about the cross section of all these features. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Arnold, Marc; Wagner, Alexander F.; Westermann, Ramona</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Realizing smiles: Options pricing with realized volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corsi, Fulvio; Fusari, Nicola; La Vecchia, Davide
We develop a discrete-time stochastic volatility option pricing model exploiting the information contained in the Realized Volatility (RV), which is used as a proxy of the unobservable log-return volatility. We model the RV dynamics by a simple and effective long-memory process, whose parameters can be easily estimated using historical data. Assuming an exponentially affine stochastic discount factor, we obtain a fully analytic change of measure. An empirical analysis of Standard and Poor's 500 index options illustrates that our model outperforms competing time-varying and stochastic volatility option pricing models. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Corsi, Fulvio; Fusari, Nicola; La Vecchia, Davide</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capacity constraints, investor information, and hedge fund returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ramadorai, Tarun
To identify capacity constraints in hedge funds and simultaneously gauge how well-informed hedge fund investors are, we need measures of investor demand that do not affect deployed hedge fund assets. Using new data on investor interest from a secondary market for hedge funds, this paper verifies the existence of capacity constraints in hedge funds. There is more mixed evidence on the information available to hedge fund investors. Buy and sell indications arrive following fund outperformance. While buy indications have little incremental power to predict hedge fund performance over and above well-known forecasting variables, sell indications do somewhat better. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ramadorai, Tarun</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Changes to the ownership and control of East Asian corporations between 1996 and 2008: The primacy of politics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carney, Richard W.; Child, Travers Barclay
We investigate changes to the ownership and control of East Asia's largest companies in 1996 and 2008. Newly compiled data for 1386 publicly traded companies at the end of 2008 are supplemented with existing data on 1,606 publicly traded companies at the end of 1996. Two main findings stand out. First, where status quo political arrangements persist, preexisting ownership arrangements go unchanged or become more entrenched. Where major political changes occurred, corporate ownership would undergo substantial changes. Second, the state has become increasingly important as an owner of domestic firms as well as foreign firms. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carney, Richard W.; Child, Travers Barclay</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO compensation contagion: Evidence from an exogenous shock</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bereskin, Frederick L.; Cicero, David C.
We examine how Chief Executive Officer (CEO) compensation increased at a subset of firms in response to a governance shock that affected compensation levels at other firms in the economy. We first show that Delaware-incorporated firms with staggered boards and no outside blockholders increased CEO compensation following the mid-1990s Delaware legal cases that strengthened their ability to resist hostile takeovers. Consistent with the Gabaix and Landier (2008) contagion hypothesis, non-Delaware firms subsequently increased CEO compensation when the rulings affected a substantial number of firms in their industries. We further show how these legal developments contributed significantly to the rapid increase in CEO compensation in the late 1990s. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bereskin, Frederick L.; Cicero, David C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonlinear incentives and mortgage officers' decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tzioumis, Konstantinos; Gee, Matthew
In the aftermath of the recent financial crisis, banks should ensure that their incentive compensation policies appropriately balance long-term risk with short-term rewards. Using daily output data from mortgage officers in a US commercial bank, we test the notion that nonlinear contracts create time-varying incentives for the employees and impose costs on the firm. We provide empirical evidence that mortgage officers greatly increase their output toward the end of each month, when the minimum monthly quota is assessed. This occurs through a combination of reducing the processing time and approving some marginal applications. We also find that mortgages originated on the last working day of the month have a higher likelihood of delinquency. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Tzioumis, Konstantinos; Gee, Matthew</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of investor protection law on corporate policy and performance: Evidence from the blue sky laws</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agrawal, Ashwini K.
Recent studies have debated the impact of investor protection law on corporate behavior and value. I exploit the staggered passage of state securities fraud statutes ("blue sky laws") in the United States to estimate the causal effects of investor protection law on firm financing decisions and investment activity. The statutes induce firms to increase dividends, issue equity, and grow in size. The laws also facilitate improvements in operating performance and market valuations. Overall, the evidence is strongly supportive of theoretical models that predict investor protection law has a significant impact on corporate policy and performance. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agrawal, Ashwini K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Growth to value: Option exercise and the cross section of equity returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ai, Hengjie; Kiku, Dana
We propose a general equilibrium model to study the link between the cross section of expected returns and book-to-market characteristics. We model two primitive assets: value assets and growth assets that are options on assets in place. The cost of option exercise, which is endogenously determined in equilibrium, is highly procyclical and acts as a hedge against risks in assets in place. Consequently, growth options are less risky than value assets, and the model features a value premium. Our model incorporates long-run risks in aggregate consumption and replicates the empirical failure of the conditional capital asset pricing model (CAPM) prediction. The model also quantitatively accounts for the pattern in mean returns on book-to-market sorted portfolios, the magnitude of the CAPM-alphas, and other stylized features of the cross-sectional data. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ai, Hengjie; Kiku, Dana</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government spending, political cycles, and the cross section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Belo, Frederico; Gala, Vito D.; Li, Jun
Using a novel measure of industry exposure to government spending, we show predictable variation in cash flows and stock returns over political cycles. During Democratic presidencies, firms with high government exposure experience higher cash flows and stock returns, while the opposite pattern holds true during Republican presidencies. Business cycles, firm characteristics, and standard risk factors do not account for the pattern in returns across presidencies. An investment strategy that exploits the presidential cycle predictability generates abnormal returns as large as 6.9% per annum. Our results suggest market underreaction to predictable variation in the effect of government spending policies. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Belo, Frederico; Gala, Vito D.; Li, Jun</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is there price discovery in equity options?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Muravyev, Dmitriy; Pearson, Neil D.; Broussard, John Paul
We use tick-by-tick quote data for 39 liquid US stocks and options on them, and we focus on events when the two markets disagree about the stock price in the sense that the option-implied stock price obtained from the put-call parity relation is inconsistent with the actual stock price. Option market quotes adjust to eliminate the disagreement, while the stock market quotes behave normally, as if there were no disagreement. The disagreement events are typically precipitated by stock price movements and display signed option volume in the direction that tends to eliminate the disagreements. These results show that option price quotes do not contain economically significant information about future stock prices beyond what is already reflected in current stock prices, i.e., no economically significant price discovery occurs in the option market. We also find no option market price discovery using a much larger sample of disagreement events based on a weaker definition of a disagreement, which verifies that the findings for the primary sample are not due to unusual or unrepresentative market behavior during the put-call parity violations. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Muravyev, Dmitriy; Pearson, Neil D.; Broussard, John Paul</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Delegated asset management, investment mandates, and capital immobility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Zhiguo; Xiong, Wei
This paper develops a model to explain the widely used investment mandates in the institutional asset management industry based on two insights: first, giving a manager more investment flexibility weakens the link between fund performance and his effort in the designated market, and thus increases agency cost. Second, the presence of outside assets with negatively skewed returns can further increase the agency cost if the manager is incentivized to pursue outside opportunities. These effects motivate narrow mandates and tight tracking error constraints to most fund managers except those with exceptional talents. Our model sheds light on capital immobility and market segmentation that are widely observed in financial markets, and highlights important effects of negatively skewed risk on institutional incentive structures. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>He, Zhiguo; Xiong, Wei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Alliances and corporate governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bodnaruk, Andriy; Massa, Massimo; Simonov, Andrei
We study the link between a firm's quality of governance and its alliance activity. We consider alliances as a commitment technology that helps a company' Chief Executive Officer overcome agency problems that relate to the inability to ex ante motivate division managers. We show that well-governed firms are more likely to avail themselves of this technology to anticipate ex post commitment problems and resolve them. The role of governance is particularly important when the commitment problems are more acute, such as for significantly risky/long-horizon projects ("Iongshots") or firms more prone to inefficient internal redistribution of resources (conglomerates), as well as in the absence of alternative disciplining devices (e.g., low product market competition). Governance also mitigates agency issues between alliance partners; dominant alliance partners agree to a more equal split of power with junior partners that are better governed. An "experiment" that induces cross-sectional variation in the cost of the alliance commitment technology provides evidence of a causal link between governance and alliances. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bodnaruk, Andriy; Massa, Massimo; Simonov, Andrei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Innovative efficiency and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, David; Hsu, Po-Hsuan; Li, Dongmei
We find that innovative efficiency (IE), patents or citations scaled by research and development expenditures, is a strong positive predictor of future returns after controlling for firm characteristics and risk. The IE-return relation is associated with the loading on a mispricing factor, and the high Sharpe ratio of the Efficient Minus Inefficient (EMI) portfolio suggests that mispricing plays an important role. Further tests based upon attention and uncertainty proxies suggest that limited attention contributes to the effect. The high weight of the EMI portfolio return in the tangency portfolio suggests that IE captures incremental pricing effects relative to well-known factors. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hirshleifer, David; Hsu, Po-Hsuan; Li, Dongmei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Probability weighting functions implied in options prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Polkovnichenko, Valery; Zhao, Feng
The empirical pricing kernels estimated from index options are non-monotone (Rosenberg and Engle, 2002; Bakshi, Madan, and Panayotov, 2010) and the corresponding risk-aversion functions can be negative (Nit-Sahalia and Lo, 2000; Jackwerth, 2000). We show theoretically that these and several other properties of empirical pricing kernels are consistent with rank-dependent utility model with probability weighting function, which overweights tail events. We also estimate the pricing kernels nonparametrically from the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 index options and construct empirical probability weighting functions. The estimated probability weights typically have the inverse-S shape, which overweights tail events and is widely supported by the experimental decision theory. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Polkovnichenko, Valery; Zhao, Feng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization without risk transfer</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Schnabl, Philipp; Suarez, Gustavo
We analyze asset-backed commercial paper conduits, which experienced a shadow-banking run and played a central role in the early phase of the financial crisis of 2007-2009. We document that commercial banks set up conduits to securitize assets worth $1.3 trillion while insuring the newly securitized assets using explicit guarantees. We show that regulatory arbitrage was an important motive behind setting up conduits. In particular, the guarantees were structured so as to reduce regulatory capital requirements, more so by banks with less capital, and while still providing recourse to bank balance sheets for outside investors. Consistent with such recourse, we find that conduits provided little risk transfer during the run, as losses from conduits remained with banks instead of outside investors and banks with more exposure to conduits had lower stock returns. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Schnabl, Philipp; Suarez, Gustavo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock returns and the Miller Modigliani valuation formula: Revisiting the Fama French analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aharoni, Gil; Grundy, Bruce; Zeng, Qi
Fama and French (2006) use the dividend-discount model to develop the role of expected profitability, expected investment, and the book-to-market ratio as predictors of stock returns. One reported empirical result is anomalous. The valuation model establishes that the comparative static relation between expected returns and expected investment is negative, yet it appears to be positive and insignificant. We show that the posited valuation relations apply at the firm level, and not at the per share level at which they were tested. Once the variables are measured at the firm level, all the Fama French predictions are validated. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aharoni, Gil; Grundy, Bruce; Zeng, Qi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Untitled</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, David; Schwert, G. William; Singleton, Kenneth J.
nan</description><author>Hirshleifer, David; Schwert, G. William; Singleton, Kenneth J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Access to capital, investment, and the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kahle, Kathleen M.; Stulz, Rene M.
During the recent financial crisis, corporate borrowing and capital expenditures fall sharply. Most existing research links the two phenomena by arguing that a shock to bank lending (or, more generally, to the corporate credit supply) caused a reduction in capital expenditures. The economic significance of this causal link is tenuous, as we find that (1) bank-dependent firms do not decrease capital expenditures more than matching firms in the first year of the crisis or in the two quarters after Lehman Brother's bankruptcy; (2) firms that are unlevered before the crisis decrease capital expenditures during the crisis as much as matching firms and, proportionately, more than highly levered firms; (3) the decrease in net debt issuance for bank-dependent firms is not greater than for matching firms; (4) the average cumulative decrease in net equity issuance is more than twice the average decrease in net debt issuance from the start of the crisis through March 2009; and (5) bank-dependent firms hoard cash during the crisis compared with unlevered firms. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kahle, Kathleen M.; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economics of hedge funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lan, Yingcong; Wang, Neng; Yang, Jinqiang
Hedge fund managers trade off the benefits of leveraging on the alpha-generating strategy against the costs of inefficient fund liquidation. In contrast to the standard risk-seeking intuition, even with a constant-return-to-scale alpha-generating strategy, a risk-neutral manager becomes endogenously risk-averse and decreases leverage following poor performance to increase the fund's survival likelihood. Our calibration suggests that management fees are the majority of the total compensation. Money flows, managerial restart options, and management ownership increase the importance of high-water-mark-based incentive fees but management fees remain the majority. Investors' valuation of fees are highly sensitive to their assessments of the manager's skill. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lan, Yingcong; Wang, Neng; Yang, Jinqiang</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The performance of corporate alliances: Evidence from oil and gas drilling in the Gulf of Mexico</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beshears, John
I use data on oil and gas drilling in the Gulf of Mexico to measure how a corporate alliance-a group of firms that jointly develops an offshore tract performs relative to a solo firm. I employ a regression discontinuity strategy based on bids in first-price sealed-bid auctions for the rights to develop leases. By focusing on leases where one organizational form narrowly outbids the other, I measure drilling outcomes while controlling for the endogenous matching of projects and organizational forms. Solo firm leases are less profitable than alliance leases because alliance members combine their information and expertise. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beshears, John</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity risk of corporate bond returns: conditional approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Amihud, Yakov; Bharath, Sreedhar T.
We study the exposure of the US corporate bond returns to liquidity shocks of stocks and Treasury bonds over the period 1973-2007 in a regime-switching model. In one regime, liquidity shocks have mostly insignificant effects on bond prices, whereas in another regime, a rise in illiquidity produces significant but conflicting effects: Prices of investment-grade bonds rise while prices of speculative-grade (junk) bonds fall substantially (relative to the market). Relating the probability of these regimes to macroeconomic conditions we find that the second regime can be predicted by economic conditions that are characterized as "stress." These effects, which are robust to controlling for other systematic risks (term and default), suggest the existence of time-varying liquidity risk of corporate bond returns conditional on episodes of flight to liquidity. Our model can predict the out-of-sample bond returns for the stress years 2008-2009. We find a similar pattern for stocks classified by high or low book-to-market ratio, where again, liquidity shocks play a special role in periods characterized by adverse economic conditions. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Amihud, Yakov; Bharath, Sreedhar T.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of local political connections in a low-corruption environment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amore, Mario Daniele; Bennedsen, Morten
We use exogenous changes in Danish local municipality sizes to identify a large positive effect of political power on the profitability of firms related by family to local politicians. Our difference-in-differences estimate is consistent with a unitary elasticity of connected firms' performance to political power (as measured by population per elected politician). Increasing power boosts firms' operating returns, especially in industries relying heavily on public demand. Focusing on arguably the world's least corrupt country, we highlight the importance of corporate rent seeking at local governmental levels, which account for nearly half of total public expenditures. (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Amore, Mario Daniele; Bennedsen, Morten</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of the media in corporate governance: Do the media influence managers' capital allocation decisions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Baixiao; McConnell, John J.
Using 636 large acquisition attempts that are accompanied by a negative stock price reaction at their announcement ("value-reducing acquisition attempts") from 1990 to 2010, we find that, in deciding whether to abandon a value-reducing acquisition attempt, managers' sensitivity to the firm's stock price reaction at the announcement is influenced by the level and the tone of media attention to the proposed transaction. We interpret the results to imply that managers have reputational capital at risk in making corporate capital allocation decisions and that the level and tone of media attention heighten the impact of a value-reducing acquisition on the managers' reputational capital. To the extent that value-reducing acquisition attempts are more likely to be abandoned, the media can play a role in aligning managers' and shareholders' interests. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Baixiao; McConnell, John J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the director labor market offer ex post settling-up for CEOs? The case of acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harford, Jarrad; Schonlau, Robert J.
We examine the rewards for experience and ability in the director labor market. We show that large acquisitions are associated with significantly higher numbers of subsequent board seats for the acquiring CEO, target CEO, and the directors. We also find that, in the case of acquisitions, experience is more important than ability. Both value-destroying and value-increasing acquisitions have significant and positive effects on a CEO's future prospects in the director labor market. In addition to increasing our understanding of the director labor market, these results suggest that the ex post settling-up incentives thought to exist in the director labor market are weak for acquisitions. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harford, Jarrad; Schonlau, Robert J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Directors' and officers' liability insurance and loan spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Chen; Officer, Micah S.; Wang, Rui; Zou, Hong
We analyze the effect of directors' and officers' liability insurance (D&amp;O insurance) on the spreads charged on bank loans. We find that higher levels of D&amp;O insurance coverage are associated with higher loan spreads and that this relation depends on loan characteristics in economically sensible ways and is attenuated by monitoring mechanisms. This association between loan spreads and D&amp;O insurance coverage is robust to controlling for endogeneity (because both could be related to firm risk). Our evidence suggests that lenders view D&amp;O insurance coverage as increasing credit risk (potentially via moral hazard or information asymmetry). Further analyses show that higher levels of D&amp;O insurance coverage are associated with greater risk taking and higher probabilities of financial restatement due to aggressive financial reporting. While greater use of D&amp;O insurance increases the cost of debt, we find some evidence that D&amp;O insurance coverage appears to improve the value of large increases in capital expenditure for firms with better internal and external governance. (c) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Lin, Chen; Officer, Micah S.; Wang, Rui; Zou, Hong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are small firms less vulnerable to overpriced stock offers?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vijh, Anand M.; Yang, Ke
We show an inverted-U relation between targetiveness (probability of being targeted) and firm size. However, this pattern describes stock offers and is more pronounced during hot markets characterized by higher stock valuations. For cash offers we find a negative and monotonic relation. These contrasting patterns suggest that small firms (in the bottom NYSE size quartile) are less vulnerable to overpriced stock offers. In addition, we find that the stock acquirers of small targets are less overvalued than those of large targets, and that the announcement returns are less negative for stock acquirers of small targets than for those of large targets. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vijh, Anand M.; Yang, Ke</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing the term structure with linear regressions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adrian, Tobias; Crump, Richard K.; Moench, Emanuel
We show how to price the time series and cross section of the term structure of interest rate using a three-step linear regression approach. Our method allows computationally fast estimation of term structure models with a large number of pricing factors. We present specification tests favoring a model using five principal components of yields as factors. We demonstrate that this model outperforms the Cochrane and Piazzesi (2008) four-factor specification in out-of-sample exercises but generates similar in-sample term premium dynamics. Our regression approach can also incorporate unspanned factors and allows estimation of term structure models without observing a zero-coupon yield curve. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adrian, Tobias; Crump, Richard K.; Moench, Emanuel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictability of currency carry trades and asset pricing implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, Gurdip; Panayotov, George
This paper studies the time series predictability of currency carry trades, constructed by selecting currencies to be bought or sold against the US dollar, based on forward discounts. Changes in a commodity index, currency volatility and, to a lesser extent, a measure of liquidity predict in-sample the payoffs of dynamically re-balanced carry trades, as evidenced by individual and joint p-values in monthly predictive regressions at horizons up to six months. Predictability is further supported through out-of-sample metrics, and a predictability-based decision rule produces sizable improvements in the Sharpe ratios and skewness profile of carry trade payoffs. Our evidence also indicates that predictability can be traced to the long legs of the carry trades and their currency components. We test the theoretical restrictions that an asset pricing model, with average currency returns and the mimicking portfolio for the innovations in currency volatility as risk factors, imposes on the coefficients in predictive regressions. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bakshi, Gurdip; Panayotov, George</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment shocks and the commodity basis spread</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Fan
I identify a "slope" factor in the cross section of commodity futures returns: high-basis commodity futures have higher loadings on this factor than low-basis commodity futures. Combined with a level factor (an index of commodity futures), this slope factor explains most of the average excess returns of commodity futures portfolios sorted by basis. More importantly, I find that this factor is significantly correlated with investment shocks, which represent the technological progress in producing new capital. I investigate a competitive dynamic equilibrium model of commodity production to endogenize this correlation. The model reproduces the cross-sectional futures returns and many asset pricing tests. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yang, Fan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Supply uncertainty of the bond investor base and the leverage of the firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, Massimo; Yasuda, Ayako; Zhang, Lei
We examine the effect of the bond capital supply uncertainty of institutional investors (e.g., mutual bond funds and insurance companies) on the leverage of the firm using a novel data set. Our main finding is that the supply uncertainty of the firm's bond investor base - measured as (i) the average portfolio turnover, or (ii) the average flow volatility of investors holding the firm's bonds, or (iii) the prevalence of mutual funds among the firm's bondholders as opposed to insurance companies - has a negative and significant effect on the leverage of the firm. The supply uncertainty of the firm's bond investor base also has a negative and significant effect on the firm's probability of issuing bonds, and a positive and significant effect on the firm's probability of issuing equity and borrowing from banks. We take a multi-pronged approach to address potential endogeneity issues, including use of geography-based instruments and firm fixed effects, subsample analyses, and a placebo test. Our results highlight the fragility of access to the bond market for companies that depend on mutual funds with high turnover/ flow volatility as primary bond investors. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Massa, Massimo; Yasuda, Ayako; Zhang, Lei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset management and investment banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berzins, Janis; Liu, Crocker H.; Trzcinka, Charles
We find evidence that conflicts of interest are pervasive in the asset management business owned by investment banks. Using data from 1990 to 2008, we compare the alphas of mutual funds, hedge funds, and institutional funds operated by investment banks and non-bank conglomerates. We find that, while no difference exists in performance by fund type, being owned by an investment bank reduces alphas by 46 basis points per year in our baseline model. Making lead loans increases alphas, but the dispersion of fees across portfolios decreases alphas. The economic loss is $4.9 billion per year. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berzins, Janis; Liu, Crocker H.; Trzcinka, Charles</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Brand perception, cash flow stability, and financial policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Larkin, Yelena
This paper demonstrates that intangible assets play an important role in financial policy. Using a proprietary database of consumer brand evaluation, I show that positive consumer attitude toward a firm's products alleviates financial frictions and provides additional net debt capacity, as measured by higher leverage and lower cash holdings. Brand perception affects financial policy through reducing overall firm riskiness, as strong consumer evaluations translate into lower future cash flow volatility as well as higher credit ratings for potentially volatile firms. The impact of brand is stronger among small firms, contradicting a number of reverse causality and omitted variables explanations. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Larkin, Yelena</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Allocation of decision rights and the investment strategy of mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dass, Nishant; Nanda, Vikram; Wang, Qinghai
The literature suggests that while decentralized decision making can allow for greater specialization in an organization, it heightens the cost of coordinating decisions. The mutual fund industry in particular, sole- and team-managed balanced funds-provides an ideal setting to test the specialization versus coordination trade-off, as information on decision structures and fund actions is easily obtained. We show that sole-managed balanced funds, with centralized decision rights, exhibit significant market timing that requires reallocation across asset classes. However, consistent with coordination difficulties between managers specializing in particular asset classes, no market timing is evident in team-managed balanced funds. Team-managed funds exhibit greater returns from specialization, in the form of better security selection performance than sole-managed funds. These results hold cross-sectionally and for funds that switch management structures. The overall returns across different management structures are similar, indicating a market equilibrium. Investor flows reward market-timing performance for sole- but not team-managed funds. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dass, Nishant; Nanda, Vikram; Wang, Qinghai</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment cycles and startup innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nanda, Ramana; Rhodes-Kropf, Matthew
We find that venture capital-backed startups receiving their initial investment in hot markets are more likely to go bankrupt, but conditional on going public, are valued higher on the day of their initial public offering, have more patents, and have more citations to their patents. Our results suggest that VCs invest in riskier and more innovative startups in hot markets (rather than just worse firms). This is particularly true for the most experienced VCs. Furthermore, our results suggest that increased capital in hot times plays a causal role in shifting investments to more novel startups by lowering the cost of experimentation for early stage investors and allowing them to make riskier, more novel, investments. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nanda, Ramana; Rhodes-Kropf, Matthew</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting market returns using aggregate implied cost of capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Yan; Ng, David T.; Swaminathan, Bhaskaran
Theoretically, the implied cost of capital (ICC) is a good proxy for time-varying expected returns. We find that aggregate ICC strongly predicts future excess market returns at horizons ranging from one month to four years. This predictive power persists even in the presence of popular valuation ratios and business cycle variables, both in-sample and out-of-sample, and is robust to alternative implementations. We also find that ICCs of size and book-to-market portfolios predict corresponding portfolio returns. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Yan; Ng, David T.; Swaminathan, Bhaskaran</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund skill and the performance of corporate acquirers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nain, Amrita; Yao, Tong
We show that the commonly observed correlation between institutional investor ownership and the success of mergers is partly driven by active stock picking. Several mutual fund stock selection skill measures strongly predict the post-merger performance of corporate acquirers even after controlling for possible shareholder monitoring. These findings are stronger for funds with characteristics more indicative of active stock picking. Moreover, firms held by funds with higher stock selection skills are more likely to subsequently become acquirers, suggesting that the mutual fund skill set includes the ability to identify acquirers with value-enhancing acquisition opportunities. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nain, Amrita; Yao, Tong</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do jumps contribute to the dynamics of the equity premium?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maheu, John M.; McCurdy, Thomas H.; Zhao, Xiaofei
This paper investigates whether risks associated with time-varying arrival of jumps and their effect on the dynamics of higher moments of returns are priced in the conditional mean of daily market excess returns. We find that jumps and jump dynamics are significantly related to the market equity premium. The results from our time-series approach reinforce the importance of the skewness premium found in cross-sectional studies using lower-frequency data; and offer a potential resolution to sometimes conflicting results on the intertemporal risk-return relationship. We use a general utility specification, consistent with our pricing kernel, to evaluate the relative value of alternative risk premium models in an out-of-sample portfolio performance application. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maheu, John M.; McCurdy, Thomas H.; Zhao, Xiaofei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Human capital, capital structure, and employee pay: An empirical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Cheng, Yingmei; Zhang, Tianming
We test the predictions of Titman (1984) and Berk, Stanton, and Zechner (2010) by examining the effect of leverage on labor costs. Leverage has a significantly positive impact on cash, equity-based, and total compensation of chief executive officers (CEOs). Compensation of new CEOs hired from outside the firm is positively related to prior-year firm leverage. In addition, leverage has a positive and significant impact on average employee pay. The incremental total labor expenses associated with an increase in leverage are large enough to offset the incremental tax benefits of debt. The empirical evidence supports the theoretical prediction that labor costs limit the use of debt. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Cheng, Yingmei; Zhang, Tianming</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political uncertainty and risk premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pastor, L'ubos; Veronesi, Pietro
We develop a general equilibrium model of government policy choice in which stock prices respond to political news. The model implies that political uncertainty commands a risk premium whose magnitude is larger in weaker economic conditions. Political uncertainty reduces the value of the implicit put protection that the government provides to the market. It also makes stocks more volatile and more correlated, especially when the economy is weak. We find empirical evidence consistent with these predictions. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pastor, L'ubos; Veronesi, Pietro</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>