<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Journal of Finance4</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Ambiguity, information quality, and asset pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Epstein, Larry G.; Schneider, Martin
When ambiguity-averse investors process news of uncertain quality, they act as if they take a worst-case assessment of quality. As a result, they react more strongly to bad news than to good news. They also dislike assets for which information quality is poor, especially when the underlying fundamentals are volatile. These effects induce ambiguity premia that depend on idiosyncratic risk in fundamentals as well as skewness in returns. Moreover, shocks to information quality can have persistent negative effects on prices even if fundamentals do not change.</description><author>Epstein, Larry G.; Schneider, Martin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information asymmetry and asset prices: Evidence from the china foreign share discount</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Kalok; Menkveld, Albert J.; Yang, Zhishu
We examine the effect of information asymmetry on equity prices in the local A- and foreign B-share market in China. We construct measures of information asymmetry based on market microstructure models, and find that they explain a significant portion of cross-sectional variation in B-share discounts, even after controlling for other factors. On a univariate basis, the price impact measure and the adverse selection component of the bid-ask spread in the A- and B-share markets explains 44% and 46% of the variation in B-share discounts. On a multivariate basis, both measures are far more statistically significant than any of the control variables.</description><author>Chan, Kalok; Menkveld, Albert J.; Yang, Zhishu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition for order flow and smart order routing systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foucault, Thierry; Menkveld, Albert J.
We study the rivalry between Euronext and the London Stock Exchange (LSE) in the Dutch stock market to test hypotheses about the effect of market fragmentation. As predicted by our theory, the consolidated limit order book is deeper after entry of the LSE. Moreover, cross-sectionally, we find that a higher trade-through rate in the entrant market coincides with less liquidity supply in this market. These findings imply that (i) fragmentation of order flow can enhance liquidity supply and (ii) protecting limit orders against trade-throughs is important.</description><author>Foucault, Thierry; Menkveld, Albert J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which money is smart? Mutual fund buys and sells of individual and institutional investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keswani, Aneel; Stolin, David
Gruber (1996) and Zheng (1999) report that investors channel money toward mutual funds that subsequently perform well. Sapp and Tiwari (2004) find that this "smart money" effect no longer holds after controlling for stock return momentum. While prior work uses quarterly U.S. data, we employ a British data set of monthly fund inflows and outflows differentiated between individual and institutional investors. We document a robust smart money effect in the United Kingdom. The effect is caused by buying (but not selling) decisions of both individuals and institutions. Using monthly data available post-1991 we show that money is comparably smart in the United States.</description><author>Keswani, Aneel; Stolin, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heterogeneous beliefs, speculation, and the equity premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>David, Alexander
Agents with heterogeneous beliefs about fundamental growth do not share risks perfectly but instead speculate with each other on the relative accuracy of their models' predictions. They face the risk that market prices move more in line with the trading models of competing agents than with their own. Less risk-averse agents speculate more aggressively and demand higher risk premiums. My calibrated model generates countercyclical consumption volatility, earnings forecast dispersion, and cross-sectional consumption dispersion. With a risk aversion coefficient less than one, agents' speculation causes half the observed equity premium and lowers the riskless rate by about 1%.</description><author>David, Alexander</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Morgan Stanley - American Finance Association Award for Excellence in Finance 2008</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anonymous
nan</description><author>Anonymous</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency conflicts, investment, and asset pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albuquerque, Rui; Wang, Neng
The separation of ownership and control allows controlling shareholders to pursue private benefits. We develop an analytically tractable dynamic stochastic general equilibrium model to study asset pricing and welfare implications of imperfect investor protection. Consistent with empirical evidence, the model predicts that countries with weaker investor protection have more incentives to overinvest, lower Tobin's q, higher return volatility, larger risk premia, and higher interest rate. Calibrating the model to the Korean economy reveals that perfecting investor protection increases the stock market's value by 22%, a gain for which outside shareholders are willing to pay 11% of their capital stock.</description><author>Albuquerque, Rui; Wang, Neng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price volatility and investor behavior in an overlapping generations model with information asymmetry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Watanabe, Masahiro
This paper studies an overlapping generations model with multiple securities and heterogeneously informed agents. The model produces multiple equilibria, including highly volatile equilibria that can exhibit strong or weak correlations between asset returns-even when asset supplies and future dividends are uncorrelated across assets. Less informed agents rationally behave like trend-followers, while better informed agents follow contrarian strategies. Trading volume has a hump-shaped relation with information precision and is positively correlated with absolute price changes. Finally, accurate information increases the volatility and correlation of stock returns in the highly volatile, strongly correlated equilibrium.</description><author>Watanabe, Masahiro</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Individual investor trading and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaniel, Ron; Saar, Gideon; Titman, Sheridan
This paper investigates the dynamic relation between net individual investor trading and short-horizon returns for a large cross-section of NYSE stocks. The evidence indicates that individuals tend to buy stocks following declines in the previous month and sell following price increases. We document positive excess returns in the month following intense buying by individuals and negative excess returns after individuals sell, which we show is distinct from the previously shown past return or volume effects. The patterns we document are consistent with the notion that risk-averse individuals provide liquidity to meet institutional demand for immediacy.</description><author>Kaniel, Ron; Saar, Gideon; Titman, Sheridan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The demise of investment banking partnerships: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morrison, Alan D.; Wilhelm, William J.
In 1970 the New York Stock Exchange relaxed rules that prohibited the public incorporation of member firms. Investment banking concerns went public in waves, with Goldman Sachs the last of the bulge bracket banks to float. We explain the pattern of investment bank flotations. We argue that partnerships foster the formation of human capital and we use technological advances that undermine the role of human capital to explain the partnership's going-public decision. We support our theory using a new data set of investment bank partnership statistics.</description><author>Morrison, Alan D.; Wilhelm, William J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Downward-sloping demand curves, the supply of shares, and the collapse of internet stock prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schultz, Paul
Over March and April 2000, Internet stocks lost 56%, or $700 billion. This sudden collapse has been attributed to an increasing supply of shares from lockup expirations and equity offerings. I show that Internet stocks collapsed in this period regardless of whether their lockups expired. Furthermore, daily Internet stock portfolio returns were almost unaffected by the number or dollar amount of lockup expirations that day, or by the amount of stock offered in IPOs or SEOs. Most of the Internet stock decline is explained by poor marketwide returns, particularly for growth stocks.</description><author>Schultz, Paul</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO pricing and share allocation: The importance of being ignorant</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gondat-Larralde, Celine; James, Kevin R.
Since an underwriter sets an IPO's offer price without knowing its market value, investors can acquire information about its value and avoid overpriced deals ("lemon-dodge"). To mitigate this well-known risk, the bank enters into a repeat game with a coalition of investors who do not lemon-dodge in exchange for on-average underpriced shares. We (i) derive and test a quantitative IPO pricing rule (showing that tech IPOs were not excessively underpriced during the boom of the 1990s); and (ii) analyzing a unique multibank data set, find strong support for the conjecture that a bank preferentially allocates shares to its coalition.</description><author>Gondat-Larralde, Celine; James, Kevin R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The long-lasting momentum in weekly returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gutierrez, Roberto C.; Kelley, Eric K.
Reversal is the current stylized fact of weekly returns. However, we find that an opposing and long-lasting continuation in returns follows the well-documented brief reversal. These subsequent momentum profits are strong enough to offset the initial reversal and to produce a significant momentum effect over the full year following portfolio formation. Thus, ex post, extreme weekly returns are not too extreme. Our findings extend to weekly price movements with and without public news. In addition, there is no relation between news uncertainty and the momentum in 1-week returns.</description><author>Gutierrez, Roberto C.; Kelley, Eric K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information, trading, and product market interactions: Cross-sectional implications of informed trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tookes, Heather E.
I present a simple model of informed trading in which asset values are derived from imperfectly competitive product markets and private information events occur at individual firms. The model predicts that informed traders may have incentives to make information-based trades in the stocks of competitors, especially when events occur at firms with large market shares. In the context of 759 earnings announcements, I use intraday transactions data to test the hypothesis that net order flow and returns in the stocks of nonannouncing competitors have information content for announcing firms.</description><author>Tookes, Heather E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Neighbors matter: Causal community effects and stock market participation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Jeffrey R.; Ivkovic, Zoran; Smith, Paul A.; Weisbenner, Scott
This paper establishes a causal relation between an individual's decision whether to own stocks and average stock market participation of the individual's community. We instrument for the average ownership of an individual's community with lagged average ownership of the states in which one's nonnative neighbors were born. Combining this instrumental variables approach with controls for individual and community fixed effects, a broad set of time-varying individual and community controls, and state-year effects rules out alternative explanations. To further establish that word-of-mouth communication drives this causal effect, we show that the results are stronger in more sociable communities.</description><author>Brown, Jeffrey R.; Ivkovic, Zoran; Smith, Paul A.; Weisbenner, Scott</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The politics of financial development: Evidence from trade liberalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Braun, Matias; Raddatz, Claudio
Incumbents in various industries have different incentives to promote or oppose financial development. Changes in the relative strength of promoter and opponent industries thus result in changes in the political equilibrium level of financial development. We conduct an event study using a sample of 41 countries that liberalized trade during 1970 to 2000, and show that the strengthening of promoter relative to opponent industries resulting from liberalization is a good predictor of subsequent financial development. The benefits of developing the financial system are insufficient for financial development, and rents in particular hands appear to be necessary to achieve it.</description><author>Braun, Matias; Raddatz, Claudio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>More than words: Quantifying language to measure firms' fundamentals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tetlock, Paul C.; Saar-Tsechansky, Maytal; Macskassy, Sofus
We examine whether a simple quantitative measure of language can be used to predict individual firms' accounting earnings and stock returns. Our three main findings are: (1) the fraction of negative words in firm-specific news stories forecasts low firm earnings; (2) firms' stock prices briefly underreact to the information embedded in negative words; and (3) the earnings and return predictability from negative words is largest for the stories that focus on fundamentals. Together these findings suggest that linguistic media content captures otherwise hard-to-quantify aspects of firms' fundamentals, which investors quickly incorporate into stock prices.</description><author>Tetlock, Paul C.; Saar-Tsechansky, Maytal; Macskassy, Sofus</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Attracting Attention: Cheap Managerial Talk and Costly Market Monitoring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almazan, Andres; Banerji, Sanjay; De Motta, Adolfo
We provide a theory of informal communication-cheap talk-between firms and capital markets that incorporates the role of agency conflicts between managers and shareholders. The analysis suggests that a policy of discretionary disclosure that encourages managers to attract the market's attention when the firm is substantially undervalued can create shareholder value. The theory also relates the credibility of managerial announcements to the use of stock-based compensation, the presence of informed trading, and the liquidity of the stock. Our results are consistent with the existence of positive announcement effects produced by apparently innocuous corporate events (e.g., stock dividends, name changes).</description><author>Almazan, Andres; Banerji, Sanjay; De Motta, Adolfo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A search-based theory of the on-the-run phenomenon</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vayanos, Dimitri; Weill, Pierre-Olivier
We propose a model in which assets with identical cash flows can trade at different prices. Infinitely lived agents can establish long positions in a search spot market, or short positions by first borrowing an asset in a search repo market. We show that short-sellers can endogenously concentrate in one asset because of search externalities and the constraint that they must deliver the asset they borrowed. That asset enjoys greater liquidity, a higher lending fee ("specialness"), and trades at a premium consistent with no-arbitrage. We derive closed-form solutions for small frictions, and provide a calibration generating realistic on-the-run premia.</description><author>Vayanos, Dimitri; Weill, Pierre-Olivier</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank loans, bonds, and information monopolies across the business cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Santos, Joao A. C.; Winton, Andrew
Theory suggests that banks' private information about borrowers lets them hold up borrowers for higher interest rates. Since hold-up power increases with borrower risk, banks with exploitable information should be able to raise their rates in recessions by more than is justified by borrower risk alone. We test this hypothesis by comparing the pricing of loans for bank-dependent borrowers with the pricing of loans for borrowers with access to public debt markets, controlling for risk factors. Loan spreads rise in recessions, but firms with public debt market access pay lower spreads and their spreads rise significantly less in recessions.</description><author>Santos, Joao A. C.; Winton, Andrew</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loan sales and relationship banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parlour, Christine A.; Plantin, Guillaume
Firms raise money from banks and the bond market. Banks sell loans in a secondary market to recycle their funds or to trade on private information. Liquidity in the loan market depends on the relative likelihood of each motive for trade and affects firms' optimal financial structure. The endogenous degree of liquidity is not always socially optimal: There is excessive trade in highly rated names, and insufficient liquidity in riskier bonds. We provide testable implications for prices and quantities in primary and secondary loan markets, and bond markets. Further, we posit that risk-based capital requirements may be socially desirable.</description><author>Parlour, Christine A.; Plantin, Guillaume</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The price of immediacy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chacko, George C.; Jurek, Jakub W.; Stafford, Erik
This paper models transaction costs as the rents that a monopolistic market maker extracts from impatient investors who trade via limit orders. We show that limit orders are American options. The limit prices inducing immediate execution of the order are functionally equivalent to bid and ask prices and can be solved for various transaction sizes to characterize the market maker's entire supply curve. We find considerable empirical support for the model's predictions in the cross-section of NYSE firms. The model produces unbiased, out-of-sample forecasts of abnormal returns for firms added to the S&amp;P 500 index.</description><author>Chacko, George C.; Jurek, Jakub W.; Stafford, Erik</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock returns in mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hackbarth, Dirk; Morellec, Erwan
This paper develops a real options framework to analyze the behavior of stock returns in mergers and acquisitions. In this framework, the timing and terms of takeovers are endogenous and result from value-maximizing decisions. The implications of the model for abnormal announcement returns are consistent with the available empirical evidence. In addition, the model generates new predictions regarding the dynamics of firm-level betas for the period surrounding control transactions. Using a sample of 1,086 takeovers of publicly traded U.S. firms between 1985 and 2002, we present new evidence on the dynamics of firm-level betas, which is strongly supportive of the model's predictions.</description><author>Hackbarth, Dirk; Morellec, Erwan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market for mergers and the boundaries of the firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rhodes-Kropf, Matthew; Robinson, David T.
We relate the property rights theory of the firm to empirical regularities in the market for mergers and acquisitions. We first show that high market-to-book acquirers typically do not purchase low market-to-book targets. Instead, mergers pair together firms with similar ratios. We then build a continuous-time model of investment and merger activity combining search, scarcity, and asset complementarity to explain this like buys like result. We test the model by relating like-buys-like to search frictions. Search frictions and assortative matching vary inversely, supporting the model over standard explanations.</description><author>Rhodes-Kropf, Matthew; Robinson, David T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Blurring firm boundaries: The role of venture capital in strategic alliances</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lindsey, Laura
This study documents a new value-added role of venture capitalists and addresses important questions about how resources are combined to create firms. As part of the nexus of contracts surrounding a firm, strategic alliances can be viewed as relational contracts that blur firm boundaries. This paper provides evidence that alliances are more frequent among companies sharing a common venture capitalist. The effect is concentrated in alliances in which contracting problems are more pronounced, consistent with venture capitalists utilizing informational and other advantages in providing resources to firms. Further, these alliances improve the probability of exit for venture-backed firms.</description><author>Lindsey, Laura</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The corporate governance role of the media: Evidence from Russia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dyck, Alexander; Volchkova, Natalya; Zingales, Luigi
We study the effect of media coverage on corporate governance by focusing on Russia in the period 1999 to 2002. We find that an investment fund's lobbying increases coverage of corporate governance violations in the Anglo-American press. We also find that coverage in the Anglo-American press increases the probability that a corporate governance violation is reversed. This effect is present even when we instrument coverage with an exogenous determinant, the fund's portfolio composition at the beginning of the period. The fund's strategy seems to work in part by impacting Russian companies' reputation abroad and in part by forcing regulators into action.</description><author>Dyck, Alexander; Volchkova, Natalya; Zingales, Luigi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility information trading in the option market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ni, Sophie X.; Pan, Jun; Poteshman, Allen M.
This paper investigates informed trading on stock volatility in the option market. We construct non-market maker net demand for volatility from the trading volume of individual equity options and find that this demand is informative about the future realized volatility of underlying stocks. We also find that the impact of volatility demand on option prices is positive. More importantly, the price impact increases by 40% as informational asymmetry about stock volatility intensifies in the days leading up to earnings announcements and diminishes to its normal level soon after the volatility uncertainty is resolved.</description><author>Ni, Sophie X.; Pan, Jun; Poteshman, Allen M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Growth versus margins: Destabilizing consequences of giving the stock market what it wants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aghion, Philippe; Stein, Jeremy C.
We develop a model in which a firm can devote effort either to increasing sales growth, or to improving per-unit profit margins. If the firm's manager cares about the current stock price, she will favor the growth strategy when the market pays more attention to growth numbers. Conversely, it can be rational for the market to weight growth measures more heavily when it is known that the firm is following a growth strategy. This two-way feedback between firms' strategies and the market's pricing rule can lead to excess volatility in real variables, even absent any external shocks.</description><author>Aghion, Philippe; Stein, Jeremy C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Underreaction to dividend reductions and omissions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Yi; Szewczyk, Samuel H.; Zantout, Zaher
Using a sample of 2,337 cash dividend reduction or omission announcements over the 1927 to 1999 period, this study reports significant negative post-announcement long-term abnormal returns, which last 1 year only. However, this long-term abnormal performance is driven by the post-earnings-announcement drift. After controlling for the earnings performance and the skewness of buy-and-hold abnormal returns, there is no compelling evidence of a post-dividend-reduction or post-dividend-omission price drift.</description><author>Liu, Yi; Szewczyk, Samuel H.; Zantout, Zaher</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings management and firm performance following open-market repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gong, Guojin; Louis, Henock; Sun, Amy X.
Both post-repurchase abnormal returns and reported improvement in operating performance are driven, at least in part, by pre-repurchase downward earnings management rather than genuine growth in profitability. The downward earnings management increases with both the percentage of the company that managers repurchase and CEO ownership. Pre-repurchase abnormal accruals are also negatively associated with future performance, with the association driven mainly by those firms that report the largest income-decreasing abnormal accruals. The study suggests that one reason firms experience post-repurchase abnormal returns is that post-repurchase realized earnings growth exceeds expectations formed on the basis of pre-repurchase deflated earnings numbers.</description><author>Gong, Guojin; Louis, Henock; Sun, Amy X.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Share issuance and cross-sectional returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pontiff, Jeffrey; Woodgate, Artemiza
Post-1970, share issuance exhibits a strong cross-sectional ability to predict stock returns. This predictive ability is more statistically significant than the individual predictive ability of size, book-to-market, or momentum. Our finding is related to research that finds that long-run returns are associated with share repurchase announcements, seasoned equity offerings, and stock mergers, although our results remain strong even after exclusion of the data used in these studies. We estimate the issuance relation pre-1970 and find no statistically significant predictive ability for most holding periods.</description><author>Pontiff, Jeffrey; Woodgate, Artemiza</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition from specialized firms and the diversification-performance linkage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Santalo, Juan; Becerra, Manuel
In this study, we show that the effect of diversification on performance is not homogeneous across industries and explore analytically and empirically the implications of this finding for the diversification literature. Diversified firms perform better in industries with a small number of nondiversified competitors or, equivalently, when specialized firms have a small combined market share, but worse as the presence of specialized firms increases in the industries in which they compete. The results are robust to the use of methods that alleviate the self-selection problem and call for a reassessment of the diversification-performance relationship.</description><author>Santalo, Juan; Becerra, Manuel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Correlated trading and returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dorn, Daniel; Huberman, Gur; Sengmueller, Paul
A German broker's clients place similar speculative trades and therefore tend to be on the same side of the market in a given stock during a given day, week, month, and quarter. Aggregate liquidity effects, short sale constraints, the systematic execution of limit orders (coordinated through price movements) or the correlated trading of other investors who pick off retail limit orders do not fully explain why retail investors trade similarly. Correlated market orders lead returns, presumably due to persistent speculative price pressure. Correlated limit orders also predict subsequent returns, consistent with executed limit orders being compensated for accommodating liquidity demands.</description><author>Dorn, Daniel; Huberman, Gur; Sengmueller, Paul</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The term structure of real rates and expected inflation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Andrew; Bekaert, Geert; Wei, Min
Changes in nominal interest rates must be due to either movements in real interest rates, expected inflation, or the inflation risk premium. We develop a term structure model with regime switches, time-varying prices of risk, and inflation to identify these components of the nominal yield curve. We find that the unconditional real rate curve in the United States is fairly flat around 1.3%. In one real rate regime, the real term structure is steeply downward sloping. An inflation risk premium that increases with maturity fully accounts for the generally upward sloping nominal term structure.</description><author>Ang, Andrew; Bekaert, Geert; Wei, Min</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identification of maximal affine term structure models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.; Jones, Christopher S.
Building on Duffie and Kan (1996), we propose a new representation of affine models in which the state vector comprises infinitesimal maturity yields and their quadratic covariations. Because these variables possess unambiguous economic interpretations, they generate a representation that is globally identifiable. Further, this representation has more identifiable parameters than the "maximal" model of Dai and Singleton (2000). We implement this new representation for select three-factor models and find that model-independent estimates for the state vector can be estimated directly from yield curve data, which present advantages for the estimation and interpretation of multifactor models.</description><author>Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.; Jones, Christopher S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information sales and insider trading with long-lived information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cespa, Giovanni
Fundamental information resembles in many respects a durable good. Hence, the effects of its incorporation into stock prices depend on who is the agent controlling its flow. Like a durable goods monopolist, a monopolistic analyst selling information intertemporally competes against herself. This forces her to partially relinquish control over the information flow to traders. Conversely, an insider solves the intertemporal competition problem through vertical integration, thus exerting tighter control over the information flow. Comparing market patterns I show that a dynamic market where information is provided by an analyst is thicker and more informative than one where an insider trades.</description><author>Cespa, Giovanni</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical evidence of risk shifting in financially distressed firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eisdorfer, Assaf
This paper provides evidence of risk-shifting behavior in the investment decisions of financially distressed firms. Using a real options framework, I show that shareholders' risk-shifting incentives can reverse the expected negative relation between volatility and investment. I test two hypotheses that are consistent with risk-shifting behavior: (i) volatility has a positive effect on distressed firms' investment; (ii) investments of distressed firms generate less value during times of high uncertainty. Empirical evidence using 40 years of data supports both hypotheses. I further evaluate the effect of various firm characteristics on risk shifting, and estimate the costs of the investment distortion.</description><author>Eisdorfer, Assaf</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do bankruptcy codes matter? A study of defaults in France, Germany, and the UK</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davydenko, Sergei A.; Franks, Julian R.
Using a sample of small firms that defaulted on their bank debt in France, Germany, and the United Kingdom, we find that large differences in creditors' rights across countries lead banks to adjust their lending and reorganization practices to mitigate costly aspects of bankruptcy law. In particular, French banks respond to a creditor-unfriendly code by requiring more collateral than lenders elsewhere, and by relying on collateral forms that minimize the statutory dilution of their claims in bankruptcy. Despite such adjustments, bank recovery rates in default remain sharply different across the three countries, reflecting very different levels of creditor protection.</description><author>Davydenko, Sergei A.; Franks, Julian R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical analysis of the pricing of collateralized debt obligations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longstaff, Francis A.; Rajan, Arvind
We use the information in collateralized debt obligations (CDO) prices to study market expectations about how corporate defaults cluster. A three-factor portfolio credit model explains virtually all of the time-series and cross-sectional variation in an extensive data set of CDX index tranche prices. Tranches are priced as if losses of 0.4%, 6%, and 35% of the portfolio occur with expected frequencies of 1.2, 41.5, and 763 years, respectively. On average, 65% of the CDX spread is due to firm-specific default risk, 27% to clustered industry or sector default risk, and 8% to catastrophic or systemic default risk.</description><author>Longstaff, Francis A.; Rajan, Arvind</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which shorts are informed ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Jones, Charles M.; Zhang, Xiaoyan
We construct a long daily panel of short sales using proprietary NYSE order data. From 2000 to 2004, shorting accounts for more than 12.9% of NYSE volume, suggesting that shorting constraints are not widespread. As a group, these short sellers are well informed. Heavily shorted stocks underperform lightly shorted stocks by a risk-adjusted average of 1.16% over the following 20 trading days (15.6% annualized). Institutional nonprogram short sales are the most informative; stocks heavily shorted by institutions underperform by 1.43% the next month (19.6% annualized). The results indicate that, on average, short sellers are important contributors to efficient stock prices.</description><author>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Jones, Charles M.; Zhang, Xiaoyan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The industry life cycle, acquisitions and investment: Does firm organization matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maksimovic, Vojislav; Phillips, Gordon
We examine the effect of industry life-cycle stages on within-industry acquisitions and capital expenditures by conglomerates and single-segment firms controlling for endogeneity of organizational form. We find greater differences in acquisitions than in capital expenditures, which are similar across organizational types. In particular, 36% of the growth recorded by conglomerate segments in growth industries comes from acquisitions, versus 9% for single-segment firms. In growth industries, the effect of financial dependence on acquisitions and plant openings is mitigated for conglomerate firms. Plants acquired by conglomerate firms increase in productivity. The results suggest that organizational forms' comparative advantages differ across industry conditions.</description><author>Maksimovic, Vojislav; Phillips, Gordon</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital gains taxes and asset prices: Capitalization or lock-in?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dai, Zhonglan; Maydew, Edward; Shackelford, Douglas A.; Zhang, Harold H.
This paper demonstrates that the equilibrium impact of capital gains taxes reflects both the capitalization effect (i.e., capital gains taxes decrease demand) and the lock-in effect (i.e., capital gains taxes decrease supply). Depending on time periods and stock characteristics, either effect may dominate. Using the Taxpayer Relief Act of 1997 as our event, we find evidence supporting a dominant capitalization effect in the week following news that sharply increased the probability of a reduction in the capital gains tax rate and a dominant lock-in effect in the week after the rate reduction became effective.</description><author>Dai, Zhonglan; Maydew, Edward; Shackelford, Douglas A.; Zhang, Harold H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of corporate risk management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>MacKay, Peter; Moeller, Sara B.
We model and estimate the value of corporate risk management. We show how risk management can add value when revenues and costs are nonlinearly related to prices and estimate the model by regressing quarterly firm sales and costs on the second and higher moments of output and input prices. For a sample of 34 oil refiners, we find that hedging concave revenues and leaving concave costs exposed each represent between 2% and 3% of firm value. We validate our approach by regressing Tobin's q on the estimated value and level of risk management and find results consistent with the model.</description><author>MacKay, Peter; Moeller, Sara B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal debt and equity values in the presence of chapter 7 and chapter 11</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Broadie, Mark; Chernov, Mikhail; Sundaresan, Suresh
Explicit presence of reorganization in addition to liquidation leads to conflicts of interest between borrowers and lenders. In the first-best outcome, reorganization adds value to both parties via higher debt capacity, lower credit spreads, and improved overall firm value. If control of the ex ante reorganization timing and the ex post decision to liquidate is given to borrowers, most of the benefits are appropriated by borrowers ex post. Lenders can restore the first-best outcome by seizing this control or by the ex post transfer of control rights. Reorganization is more likely and liquidation is less likely relative to the benchmark case with liquidation only.</description><author>Broadie, Mark; Chernov, Mikhail; Sundaresan, Suresh</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial speculators' underperformance: Learning, self-selection, and endogenous liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mahani, Reza; Bernhardt, Dan
We develop an equilibrium model of learning by rational traders to reconcile several empirical regularities: Cross sectionally, most individual speculators lose money; large speculators outperform small speculators; past performance positively affects subsequent trade intensity; most new traders lose money and cease speculation; and performance shows persistence. Learning from trading generates substantial endogenous liquidity, reducing bid-ask spreads and the impact of exogenous liquidity shocks on asset prices, but amplifying the effects of real shocks. Introducing slightly overconfident traders increases bid-ask spreads, hurting all traders. Finally, behavioral theories cannot reconcile all of these empirical regularities.</description><author>Mahani, Reza; Bernhardt, Dan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Participation costs and the sensitivity of fund flows to past performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Jennifer; Wei, Kelsey D.; Yan, Hong
We present a simple rational model to highlight the effect of investors' participation costs on the response of mutual fund flows to past fund performance. By incorporating participation costs into a model in which investors learn about managers' ability from past returns, we show that mutual funds with lower participation costs have a higher flow sensitivity to medium performance and a lower flow sensitivity to high performance than their higher-cost peers. Using various fund characteristics as proxies for the reduction in participation costs, we provide empirical evidence supporting the model's implications for the asymmetric flow-performance relationship.</description><author>Huang, Jennifer; Wei, Kelsey D.; Yan, Hong</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reputation effects in trading on the New York Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Battalio, Robert; Ellul, Andrew; Jennings, Robert
Theory suggests that reputations allow nonanonymous markets to attenuate adverse selection in trading. We identify instances in which New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) stocks experience trading floor relocations. Although specialists follow the stocks to their new locations, most brokers do not. We find a discernable increase in liquidity costs around a stock's relocation that is larger for stocks with higher adverse selection and greater broker turnover. We also find that floor brokers relocating with the stock obtain lower trading costs than brokers not moving and brokers beginning trading post-move. Our results suggest that reputation plays an important role in the NYSE's liquidity provision process.</description><author>Battalio, Robert; Ellul, Andrew; Jennings, Robert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Simple forecasts and paradigm shifts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Harrison; Stein, Jeremy C.; Yu, Jialin
We study the asset pricing implications of learning in an environment in which the true model of the world is a multivariate one, but agents update only over the class of simple univariate models. Thus, if a particular simple model does a poor job of forecasting over a period of time, it is discarded in favor of an alternative simple model. The theory yields a number of distinctive predictions for stock returns, generating forecastable variation in the magnitude of the value-glamour return differential, in volatility, and in the skewness of returns. We validate several of these predictions empirically.</description><author>Hong, Harrison; Stein, Jeremy C.; Yu, Jialin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The underwriter persistence phenomenon</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoberg, Gerard
This study presents new evidence that initial IPO returns have persistent underwriter-specific components. These components cannot be explained by existing measures of underwriter quality, underwriter service, or controls for several known predictors of initial IPO returns. Tests that trace the roots of persistence most broadly support theories of asymmetric information among underwriters. I present such a model, and consistent with its predictions, I find that high underpricing underwriters (1) are responsible for a majority of the partial adjustment phenomenon, (2) make more informed analyst revisions, (3) experience superior market share growth, and (4) are more likely to serve an institutional clientele.</description><author>Hoberg, Gerard</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Giving content to investor sentiment: The role of media in the stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tetlock, Paul C.
I quantitatively measure the interactions between the media and the stock market using daily content from a popular Wall Street Journal column. I find that high media pessimism predicts downward pressure on market prices followed by a reversion to fundamentals, and unusually high or low pessimism predicts high market trading volume. These and similar results are consistent with theoretical models of noise and liquidity traders, and are inconsistent with theories of media content as a proxy for new information about fundamental asset values, as a proxy for market volatility, or as a sideshow with no relationship to asset markets.</description><author>Tetlock, Paul C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global growth opportunities and market integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekaert, Geert; Harvey, Campbell R.; Lundblad, Christian; Siegel, Stephan
We propose an exogenous measure of a country's growth opportunities by interacting the country's local industry mix with global price to earnings (PE) ratios. We find that these exogenous growth opportunities predict future changes in real GDP and investment in a large panel of countries. This relation is strongest in countries that have liberalized their capital accounts, equity markets, and banking systems. We also find that financial development, external finance dependence, and investor protection measures are much less important in aligning growth opportunities with growth than is capital market openness. Finally, we formulate new tests of market integration and segmentation by linking local and global PE ratios to relative economic growth.</description><author>Bekaert, Geert; Harvey, Campbell R.; Lundblad, Christian; Siegel, Stephan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficiency and the bear: Short sales and markets around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bris, Arturo; Goetzmann, William N.; Zhu, Ning
We analyze cross-sectional and time-series information from 46 equity markets around the world to consider whether short sales restrictions affect the efficiency of the market and the distributional characteristics of returns to individual stocks and market indices. We find some evidence that prices incorporate negative information faster in countries where short sales are allowed and practiced. A common conjecture by regulators is that short sales restrictions can reduce the relative severity of a market panic. We find strong evidence that in markets where short selling is either prohibited or not practiced, market returns display significantly less negative skewness.</description><author>Bris, Arturo; Goetzmann, William N.; Zhu, Ning</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do firms become widely held? An analysis of the dynamics of corporate ownership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Helwege, Jean; Pirinsky, Christo; Stulz, Rene M.
We examine the evolution of insider ownership of IPO firms from 1970 to 2001 to understand how U.S. firms become widely held. A majority of these firms has insider ownership below 20% after 10 years. Stock market performance and liquidity play an extremely important role in ownership dynamics. Firms with stocks that are highly valued, are liquid, and have performed well experience large decreases in insider ownership and become widely held. Ownership also falls for low cash flow and high capital expenditures firms. Surprisingly, variables proxying for agency costs have limited success in explaining the evolution of insider ownership.</description><author>Helwege, Jean; Pirinsky, Christo; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sports sentiment and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex; Garcia, Diego; Norli, Oyvind
This paper investigates the stock market reaction to sudden changes in investor mood. Motivated by psychological evidence of a strong link between soccer outcomes and mood, we use international soccer results as our primary mood variable. We find a significant market decline after soccer losses. For example, a loss in the World Cup elimination stage leads to a next-day abnormal stock return of -49 basis points. This loss effect is stronger in small stocks and in more important games, and is robust to methodological changes. We also document a loss effect after international cricket, rugby, and basketball games.</description><author>Edmans, Alex; Garcia, Diego; Norli, Oyvind</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive financial incentives and payout policy: Firm responses to the 2003 dividend tax cut</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Jeffrey R.; Liang, Nellie; Weisbenner, Scott
We test whether executive stock ownership affects firm payouts using the 2003 dividend tax cut to identify an exogenous change in the after-tax value of dividends. We find that executives with higher ownership were more likely to increase dividends after the tax cut in 2003, whereas no relation is found in periods when the dividend tax rate was higher. Relative to previous years, Firms that initiated dividends in 2003 were more likely to reduce repurchases. The stock price reaction to the tax cut suggests that the substitution of dividends for repurchases may have been anticipated, consistent with agency conflicts.</description><author>Brown, Jeffrey R.; Liang, Nellie; Weisbenner, Scott</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentive effects of stock and option holdings of target and acquirer CEOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cai, Jie; Vijh, Anand M.
Acquisitions enable target chief executive officers (CEOs) to remove liquidity restrictions on stock and option holdings and diminish the illiquidity discount. Acquisitions also enable acquirer CEOs to improve the long-term value of overvalued holdings. Examining all firms during 1993 to 2001, we show that CEOs with higher holdings (illiquidity discount) are more likely to make acquisitions (get acquired). Further, in 250 completed acquisitions, target CEOs with a higher illiquidity discount accept a lower premium, offer less resistance, and more often leave after acquisition. Similarly, acquirer CEOs with higher holdings pay a higher premium, expedite the process, and make diversifying acquisitions using stock payment.</description><author>Cai, Jie; Vijh, Anand M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance and acquirer returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Masulis, Ronald W.; Wang, Cong; Xie, Fei
We examine whether corporate governance mechanisms, especially the market for corporate control, affect the profitability of firm acquisitions. We find that acquirers with more antitakeover provisions experience significantly lower announcement-period abnormal stock returns. This supports the hypothesis that managers at firms protected by more antitakeover provisions are less subject to the disciplinary power of the market for corporate control and thus are more likely to indulge in empire-building acquisitions that destroy shareholder value. We also find that acquirers operating in more competitive industries or separating the positions of CEO and chairman of the board experience higher abnormal announcement returns.</description><author>Masulis, Ronald W.; Wang, Cong; Xie, Fei</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The takeover deterrent effect of open market share repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Billett, Matthew T.; Xue, Hui
This paper examines whether open market share repurchases deter takeovers. We model pre-repurchase takeover probability as a latent variable and examine its impact on the firm's decision to repurchase shares. Given specification tests reject the Tobit model, we turn to the censored quantile regression method of Powell (1986, Journal of Econometrics 32, 143-155). We find a significantly positive relation between open market share repurchases and takeover probability, and we reconcile empirical findings in previous studies that contradict predictions. Repurchase activity is inversely related to firm size, consistent with smaller firms having greater information asymmetry, and is related to temporary, but not permanent, cash flows.</description><author>Billett, Matthew T.; Xue, Hui</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance and firm value: The impact of the 2002 governance rules</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chhaochharia, Vidhi; Grinstein, Yaniv
The 2001 to 2002 corporate scandals led to the Sarbanes-Oxley Act and to various amendments to the US. stock exchanges'regulations. We find that the announcement of these rules has a significant effect on firm value. Firms that are less compliant with the provisions of the rules earn positive abnormal returns compared to firms that are more compliant. We also find variation in the response across firm size. Large firms that are less compliant earn positive abnormal returns but small firms that are less compliant earn negative abnormal returns, suggesting that some provisions are detrimental to small firms.</description><author>Chhaochharia, Vidhi; Grinstein, Yaniv</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do tests of capital structure theory mean what they say?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Strebulaev, Ilya A.
In the presence of frictions, firms adjust their capital structure infrequently. As a consequence, in a dynamic economy the leverage of most firms is likely to differ from the "optimum" leverage at the time of readjustment. This paper explores the empirical implications of this observation. I use a calibrated dynamic trade-off model to simulate firms' capital structure paths. The results of standard cross-sectional tests on these data are consistent with those reported in the empirical literature. In particular, the standard interpretation of some test results leads to the rejection of the underlying model. Taken together, the results suggest a rethinking of the way capital structure tests are conducted.</description><author>Strebulaev, Ilya A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How costly is external financing? Evidence from a structural estimation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hennessy, Christopher A.; Whited, Toni M.
We apply simulated method of moments to a dynamic model to infer the magnitude of financing costs. The model features endogenous investment, distributions, leverage, and default. The corporation faces taxation, costly bankruptcy, and linear-quadratic equity flotation costs. For large (small) firms, estimated marginal equity flotation costs start at 5.0% (10.7%) and bankruptcy costs equal to 8.4% (15.1%) of capital. Estimated financing frictions are higher for low-dividend firms and those identified as constrained by the Cleary and Whited-Wu indexes. In simulated data, many common proxies for financing constraints actually decrease when we increase financing cost parameters.</description><author>Hennessy, Christopher A.; Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium exhaustible resource price dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlson, Murray; Khokher, Zeigham; Titman, Sheridan
\We develop equilibrium models of exhaustible resource markets with endogenous extraction choices and prices. Our analysis demonstrates how adjustment costs can generate oil and gas forward price dynamics with two factors, consistent with the behavior these commodities exhibit in the Schwartz and Smith (2000) calibration. Our two-factor model predicts that stochastic volatility will arise in these markets as a natural consequence of production adjustments, however, and we provide supporting empirical evidence. Differences between endogenous price processes from our general equilibrium model and exogenous processes in earlier papers can generate significant differences in both financial and real option values.</description><author>Carlson, Murray; Khokher, Zeigham; Titman, Sheridan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lazy investors, discretionary consumption, and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jagannathan, Ravi; Wang, Yong
When consumption betas of stocks are computed using year-over-year consumption growth based upon the fourth quarter, the consumption-based asset pricing model (CCAPM) explains the cross-section of stock returns as well as the Fama and French (1993) three-factor model. The CCAPM's performance deteriorates substantially when consumption growth is measured based upon other quarters. For the CCAPM to hold at any given point in time, investors must make their consumption and investment decisions simultaneously at that point in time. We suspect that this is more likely to happen during the fourth quarter, given investors' tax year ends in December.</description><author>Jagannathan, Ravi; Wang, Yong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Working orders in limit order markets and floor exchanges</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Back, Kerry; Baruch, Shmuel
We analyze limit order markets and floor exchanges, assuming an informed trader and discretionary liquidity traders use market orders and can either submit block orders or work their demands as a series of small orders. By working their demands, large market order traders pool with small traders. We show that every equilibrium on a floor exchange must involve at least partial pooling. Moreover, there is always a fully pooling (worked order) equilibrium on a floor exchange that is equivalent to a block order equilibrium in a limit order market.</description><author>Back, Kerry; Baruch, Shmuel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pay me later: Inside debt and its role in managerial compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sundaram, Pangarajan K.; Yermack, David L.
Though widely used in executive compensation, inside debt has been almost entirely overlooked by prior work. We initiate this research by studying CEO pension arrangements in 237 large capitalization firms. Among our findings are that CEO compensation exhibits a balance between debt and equity incentives; the balance shifts systematically away from equity and toward debt as CEOs grow older; annual increases in pension entitlements represent about 10% of overall CEO compensation, and about 13% for CEOs aged 61-65; CEOs with high debt incentives manage their firms conservatively; and pension compensation influences patterns of CEO turnover and cash compensation.</description><author>Sundaram, Pangarajan K.; Yermack, David L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Presidential address: Issuers, underwriter syndicates, and aftermarket transparency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, Richard C.
I model strategic interaction among issuers, underwriters, retail investors, and institutional investors when the secondary market has limited price transparency. Search costs for retail investors lead to price dispersion in the secondary market, while the price for institutional investors is infinitely elastic. Because retail distribution capacity is assumed to be limited for each underwriter-dealer, Bertrand competition breaks down in the primary market and new issues are underpriced in equilibrium. Syndicates emerge in which underwriters bid symmetrically, with quantities allocated internally to efficiently utilize retail distribution capacity.</description><author>Green, Richard C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational inattention and portfolio selection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Lixin; Liu, Hong
Costly information acquisition makes it rational for investors to obtain important economic news with only limited frequency or limited accuracy. We show that this rational inattention to important news may make investors over- or underinvest. In addition, the optimal trading strategy is "myopic" with respect to future news frequency and accuracy. We find that the optimal news frequency is nonmonotonic in news accuracy and investment horizon. Furthermore, when both news frequency and news accuracy are endogenized, an investor with a higher risk aversion or a longer investment horizon chooses less frequent but more accurate periodic news updates.</description><author>Huang, Lixin; Liu, Hong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate bond market transaction costs and transparency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edwards, Amy K.; Harris, Lawrence E.; Piwowar, Michael S.
Using a complete record of U.S. over-the-counter (OTC) secondary trades in corporate bonds, we estimate average transaction costs as a function of trade size for each bond that traded more than nine times between January 2003 and January 2005. We find that transaction costs decrease significantly with trade size. Highly rated bonds, recently issued bonds, and bonds close to maturity have lower transaction costs than do other bonds. Costs are lower for bonds with transparent trade prices, and they drop when the TRACE system starts to publicly disseminate their prices. The results suggest that public traders benefit significantly from price transparency.</description><author>Edwards, Amy K.; Harris, Lawrence E.; Piwowar, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Model specification and risk premia: Evidence from futures options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Broadie, Mark; Chernov, Mikhail; Johannes, Michael
This paper examines model specification issues and estimates diffusive and jump risk premia using S&amp;P futures option prices from 1987 to 2003. We first develop a time series test to detect the presence of jumps in volatility, and find strong evidence in support of their presence. Next, using the cross section of option prices, we find strong evidence for jumps in prices and modest evidence for jumps in volatility based on model fit. The evidence points toward economically and statistically significant jump risk premia, which are important for understanding option returns.</description><author>Broadie, Mark; Chernov, Mikhail; Johannes, Michael</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stochastic volatilities and correlations of bond yields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Bing
I develop an interest rate model with separate factors driving innovations in bond yields and their covariances. It features a flexible and tractable affine structure for bond covariances. Maximum likelihood estimation of the model with panel data on swaptions and discount bonds implies pricing errors for swaptions that are almost always lower than half of the bid-ask spread. Furthermore, market prices of interest rate caps do not deviate significantly from their no-arbitrage values implied by the swaptions under the model. These findings support the conjectures of Collin-Dufresne and Goldstein (2003), Dai and Singleton (2003), and Jagnnathan, Kaplin, and Sun (2003).</description><author>Han, Bing</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Growth opportunities and the choice of leverage, debt maturity, and covenants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Billett, Matthew T.; King, Tao-Hsien Dolly; Mauer, David C.
We investigate the effect of growth opportunities in a firm's investment opportunity set on its joint choice of leverage, debt maturity, and covenants. Using a database that contains detailed debt covenant information, we provide large-sample evidence of the incidence of covenants in public debt and construct firm-level indices of bondholder covenant protection. We find that covenant protection is increasing in growth opportunities, debt maturity, and leverage. We also document that the negative relation between leverage and growth opportunities is significantly attenuated by covenant protection, suggesting that covenants can mitigate the agency costs of debt for high growth firms.</description><author>Billett, Matthew T.; King, Tao-Hsien Dolly; Mauer, David C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance, idiosyncratic risk, and information flow</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Laux, Paul A.
We study the relationship of corporate governance policy and idiosyncratic risk. Firms with fewer antitakeover provisions display higher levels of idiosyncratic risk, trading activity, private information flow, and information about future earnings in stock prices. Trading interest by institutions, especially those active in merger arbitrage, strengthens the relationship of governance to idiosyncratic risk. Our results indicate that openness to the market for corporate control leads to more informative stock prices by encouraging collection of and trading on private information. Consistent with an information-flow interpretation, the component of volatility unrelated to governance is associated with the efficiency of corporate investment.</description><author>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Laux, Paul A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decoupling CEO wealth and firm performance: The case of acquiring CEOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harford, Jarrad; Li, Kai
We explore how compensation policies following mergers affect a CEO's incentives to pursue a merger. We find that even in mergers where bidding shareholders are worse off, bidding CEOs are better off three quarters of the time. Following a merger, a CEO's pay and overall wealth become insensitive to negative stock performance, but a CEO's wealth rises in step with positive stock performance. Corporate governance matters; bidding firms with stronger boards retain the sensitivity of their CEOs' compensation to poor performance following the merger. In comparison, we find that CEOs are not rewarded for undertaking major capital expenditures.</description><author>Harford, Jarrad; Li, Kai</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the importance of measuring payout yield: Implications for empirical asset pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boudoukh, Jacob; Michaely, Roni; Richardson, Matthew; Roberts, Michael R.
We investigate the empirical implications of using various measures of payout yield rather than dividend yield for asset pricing models. We find statistically and economically significant predictability in the time series when payout (dividends plus repurchases) and net payout (dividends plus repurchases minus issuances) yields are used instead of the dividend yield. Similarly, we find that payout (net payout) yields contains information about the cross section of expected stock returns exceeding that of dividend yields, and that the high minus low payout yield portfolio is a priced factor.</description><author>Boudoukh, Jacob; Michaely, Roni; Richardson, Matthew; Roberts, Michael R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How are firms sold ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boone, Audra L.; Mulherin, J. Harold
As measured by the number of bidders that publicly attempt to acquire a target, the takeover arena in the 1990s appears noncompetitive. However, we provide novel data on the pre-public, private takeover process that indicates that public takeover activity is only the tip of the iceberg of actual takeover competition during the 1990s. We show a highly competitive market where half of the targets are auctioned among multiple bidders, while the remainder negotiate with a single bidder. In event study analysis, we find that the wealth effects for target shareholders are comparable in auctions and negotiations.</description><author>Boone, Audra L.; Mulherin, J. Harold</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of takeovers and disinvestment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lambrecht, Bart M.; Myers, Stewart C.
We present a real-options model of takeovers and disinvestment in declining industries. As product demand declines, a first-best closure level is reached, where overall value is maximized by closing the firm and releasing its capital to investors. Absent takeovers, managers of underleveraged firms always close too late, although golden parachutes may accelerate closure. We analyze the effects of takeovers of under-leveraged firms. Takeovers by raiders enforce first-best closure. Hostile takeovers by other firms occur either at the first-best closure point or too early. Closure in management buyouts and mergers of equals happens inefficiently late.</description><author>Lambrecht, Bart M.; Myers, Stewart C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial synergies and the optimal scope of the firm: Implications for mergers, spinoffs, and structured finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leland, Hayne E.
Multiple activities may be separated financially, allowing each to optimize its financial structure, or combined in a firm with a single optimal financial structure. We consider activities with nonsynergistic operational cash flows, and examine the purely financial benefits of separation versus merger. The magnitude of financial synergies depends upon tax rates, default costs, relative size, and the riskiness and correlation of cash flows. Contrary to accepted wisdom, financial synergies from mergers can be negative if firms have quite different risks or default costs. The results provide a rationale for structured finance techniques such as asset securitization and project finance.</description><author>Leland, Hayne E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Smart institutions, foolish choices: The limited partner performance puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lerner, Josh; Schoar, Antoinette; Wongsunwai, Wan
The returns that institutional investors realize from private equity differ dramatically across institutions. Using detailed, hitherto unexplored records, we document large heterogeneity in the performance of investor classes: endowments' annual returns are nearly 21% greater than average. Analysis of reinvestment decisions suggests that endowments (and to a lesser extent, public pensions) are better than other investors at predicting whether follow-on funds will have high returns. The results are not primarily due to endowments' greater access to established funds, since they also hold for young or undersubscribed funds. Our results suggest that investors vary in their sophistication and potentially their investment objectives.</description><author>Lerner, Josh; Schoar, Antoinette; Wongsunwai, Wan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Winners or losers? The effects of banking consolidation on corporate borrowers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>di Patti, Emilia Bonaccorsi; Gobbi, Giorgio
We estimate the impact of bank mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;As) on outstanding credit, credit lines, and the sensitivity of investment to cash flow using a large sample of Italian corporate borrowers. We distinguish between firms that experienced relationship termination as a consequence of bank M&amp;As and those that did not. Our findings are consistent with bank M&amp;As having an adverse effect on credit, particularly when the M&amp;A is followed by relationship termination. The effect persists 3 years and then is absorbed, suggesting that firms are able to compensate for the negative shock.</description><author>di Patti, Emilia Bonaccorsi; Gobbi, Giorgio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information asymmetry and financing arrangements: Evidence from syndicated loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sufi, Amir
I empirically explore the syndicated loan market, with an emphasis on how information asymmetry between lenders and borrowers influences syndicate structure and on which lenders become syndicate members. Consistent with moral hazard in monitoring, the lead bank retains a larger share of the loan and forms a more concentrated syndicate when the borrower requires more intense monitoring and due diligence. When information asymmetry between the borrower and lenders is potentially severe, participant lenders are closer to the borrower, both geographically and in terms of previous lending relationships. Lead bank and borrower reputation mitigates, but does not eliminate information asymmetry problems.</description><author>Sufi, Amir</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banking deregulation and industry structure: Evidence from the French banking reforms of 1985</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertrand, Marianne; Schoar, Antoinette; Thesmar, David
We investigate how the deregulation of the French banking industry in the 1980s affected the real behavior of firms and the structure and dynamics of product markets. Following deregulation, banks are less willing to bail out poorly performing firms and firms in the more bank-dependent sectors are more likely to undertake restructuring activities. At the industry level, we observe an increase in asset and job reallocation, an improvement in allocative efficiency across firms, and a decline in concentration. Overall, these findings support the view that a more efficient banking sector helps foster a Schumpeterian process of "creative destruction."</description><author>Bertrand, Marianne; Schoar, Antoinette; Thesmar, David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limits of arbitrage: Theory and evidence from the mortgage-backed securities market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gabaix, Xavier; Krishnamurthy, Arvind; Vigneron, Olivier
"Limits of Arbitrage" theories hypothesize that the marginal investor in a particular asset market is a specialized arbitrageur rather than a diversified representative investor. We examine the mortgage-backed securities (MBS) market in this light. We show that the risk of homeowner prepayment, which is a wash in the aggregate, is priced in the MBS market. The covariance of prepayment risk with aggregate wealth implies the wrong sign to match the observed prices of prepayment risk. The price of risk is better explained by a kernel based on MBS market-wide specific risk, consistent with the specialized arbitrageur hypothesis.</description><author>Gabaix, Xavier; Krishnamurthy, Arvind; Vigneron, Olivier</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial ability, compensation, and the closed-end fund discount</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berk, Jonathan B.; Stanton, Richard
This paper shows that the existence of managerial ability, combined with the labor contract prevalent in the industry, implies that the closed-end fund discount should exhibit many of the primary features documented in the literature. We evaluate the model's ability to match the quantitative features of the data, and find that it does well, although there is some observed behavior that remains to be explained.</description><author>Berk, Jonathan B.; Stanton, Richard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fund manager use of public information: New evidence on managerial skills</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kacperczyk, Marcin; Seru, Amit
We show theoretically that the responsiveness of a fund manager's portfolio allocations to changes in public information decreases in the manager's skill. We go on to estimate this sensitivity (RPI) as the R-2 of the regression of changes in a manager's portfolio holdings on changes in public information using a panel of U.S. equity funds. Consistent with RPI containing information related to managerial skills, we find a strong inverse relationship between RPI and various existing measures of performance, and between RPI and fund flows. We also document that both fund- and manager-specific attributes affect RPI.</description><author>Kacperczyk, Marcin; Seru, Amit</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lars Peter Hansen</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hansen, Lars Peter
nan</description><author>Hansen, Lars Peter</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Habit formation and macroeconomic models of the term structure of interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buraschi, Andrea; Jiltsov, Alexei
This paper introduces a new class of nonaffine models of the term structure of interest rates that is supported by an economy with habit formation. Distinguishing features of the model are that the interest rate dynamics are nonlinear, interest rates depend on lagged monetary and consumption shocks, and the price of risk is not a constant multiple of interest rate volatility. We find that habit persistence can help reproduce the nonlinearity of the spot rate process, the documented deviations from the expectations hypothesis, the persistence of the conditional volatility of interest rates, and the lead-lag relationship between interest rates and monetary aggregates.</description><author>Buraschi, Andrea; Jiltsov, Alexei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the corporate loan market globally integrated? A pricing puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carey, Mark; Nini, Greg
We offer evidence that interest rate spreads on syndicated loans to corporate borrowers are economically significantly smaller in Europe than in the United States, other things equal. Differences in borrower, loan, and lender characteristics do not appear to explain this phenomenon. Borrowers overwhelmingly issue in their natural home market and bank portfolios display home bias. This may explain why pricing discrepancies are not competed away, though their causes remain a puzzle. Thus, important determinants of loan origination market outcomes remain to be identified, home bias appears to be material for pricing, and corporate financing costs differ across Europe and the United States.</description><author>Carey, Mark; Nini, Greg</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring distress risk: The effect of R&amp;D intensity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Franzen, Laurel A.; Rodgers, Kimberly J.; Simin, Timothy T.
Because of upward trends in research and development activity, accounting measures of financial distress have become less accurate. We document that (1) higher research and development spending increases the likelihood of misclassifying solvent firms, (2) adjusting for conservative accounting of research and development increases the number of correctly identified distressed firms, and (3) adjusted measures of distress alleviate previously documented anomalously low returns of large, high distress risk, low book-to-market firms. The results hold after updating stale parameters and under various tax assumptions. Our evidence raises concerns about interpretation of extant literature that relies on accounting measures of distress.</description><author>Franzen, Laurel A.; Rodgers, Kimberly J.; Simin, Timothy T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Vote trading and information aggregation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Susan E. K.; Geczy, Christopher C.; Musto, David K.; Reed, Adam V.
The standard analysis of corporate governance assumes that shareholders vote in ratios that firms choose, such as one share-one vote. However, if the cost of unbundling and trading votes is sufficiently low, then shareholders choose the ratios. We document an active market for votes within the U.S. equity loan market, where the average vote sells for zero. We hypothesize that asymmetric information motivates the vote trade and find support in the cross section. More trading occurs for higher-spread and worse-performing firms, especially when voting is close. Vote trading corresponds to support for shareholder proposals and opposition to management proposals.</description><author>Christoffersen, Susan E. K.; Geczy, Christopher C.; Musto, David K.; Reed, Adam V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-term return reversals: Overreaction or taxes?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>George, Thomas J.; Hwang, Chuan-Yang
Long-term reversals in U.S. stock returns are better explained as the rational reactions of investors to locked-in capital gains than an irrational overreaction to news. Predictors of returns based on the overreaction hypothesis have no power, while those that measure locked-in capital gains do, completely subsuming past returns measures that are traditionally used to predict long-term returns. In data from Hong Kong, where investment income is not taxed, reversals are nonexistent, and returns are not forecastable either by traditional measures or by measures based on the capital gains lock-in hypothesis that successfully predict U.S. returns.</description><author>George, Thomas J.; Hwang, Chuan-Yang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Adaptive traders and the design of financial markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pouget, Sebastien
This paper studies a financial market populated by adaptive traders. Learning is modeled following Camerer and Ho (1999). A call market and a Walrasian tatonnement are compared in an environment in which both institutions have the same Nash and competitive equilibrium outcomes. When traders learn via a belief-based model, equilibrium is discovered in both types of markets. In contrast, when traders learn via a reinforcement-based model, convergence to equilibrium is achieved in the Walrasian tatonnement but not in the call market. This paper suggests that market mechanisms can be designed to foster traders' learning of equilibrium strategies.</description><author>Pouget, Sebastien</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How laws and institutions shape financial contracts: The case of bank loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qian, Jun; Strahan, Philip E.
Legal and institutional differences shape the ownership and terms of bank loans across the world. We show that under strong creditor protection, loans have more concentrated ownership, longer maturities, and lower interest rates. Moreover, the impact of creditor rights on loans depends on borrower characteristics such as the size and tangibility of assets. Foreign banks appear especially sensitive to the legal and institutional environment, with their ownership declining relative to domestic banks as creditor protection falls. Our multidimensional empirical model paints a more complete picture of how financial contracts respond to the legal and institutional environment than existing studies.</description><author>Qian, Jun; Strahan, Philip E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>US banking deregulation, small businesses, and interstate insurance of personal income</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demyanyk, Yuliya; Ostergaard, Charlotte; Sorensen, Bent E.
We estimate the effects of deregulation of U.S. banking restrictions on interstate personal income insurance for the period 1970 to 2001. Interstate income insurance occurs when personal income reacts less than one-to-one to state-specific output shocks. We find that insurance improved after banking deregulation, with a larger effect in states where small businesses are more important and on proprietors' income than on other components of personal income. Our explanation centers on the role of banks as a prime source of small business finance and on the close intertwining of the personal and business finances of small business owners.</description><author>Demyanyk, Yuliya; Ostergaard, Charlotte; Sorensen, Bent E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How smart is smart money? A two-sided matching model of venture capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sorensen, Morten
I find that companies funded by more experienced VCs are more likely to go public. This follows both from the direct influence of more experienced VCs and from sorting in the market, which leads experienced VCs to invest in better companies. Sorting creates an endogeneity problem, but a structural model based on a two-sided matching model is able to exploit the characteristics of the other agents in the market to separately identify and estimate influence and sorting. Both effects are found to be significant, with sorting almost twice as important as influence for the difference in IPO rates.</description><author>Sorensen, Morten</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bidding into the red: A model of post-auction bankruptcy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Board, Simon
This paper investigates auctions where bidders have limited liability. First, we analyze bidding behavior under different auction formats, showing that the second-price auction induces higher prices, higher bankruptcy rates, and lower utilities than the first-price auction. Second, we show that the cost of bankruptcy critically affects the seller's preference over the choice of auction. If bankruptcy is very costly, the seller prefers the first-price auction over the second-price auction. Alternatively, if the bankrupt assets are resold among the losers of the initial auction, the seller prefers the second-price auction.</description><author>Board, Simon</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The US Treasury buyback auctions: The cost of retiring illiquid bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Bing; Longstaff, Francis A.; Merrill, Craig
We study an important recent series of buyback auctions conducted by the U.S. Treasury in retiring $67.5 billion of its illiquid off-the-run debt. The Treasury was successful in buying back large amounts of illiquid debt while suffering only a small market-impact cost. The Treasury included the most-illiquid bonds more frequently in the auctions, but tended to buy back the least-illiquid of these bonds. Although the Treasury had the option to cherry pick from among the bonds offered, we find that the Treasury was actually penalized for being spread too thinly in the buybacks.</description><author>Han, Bing; Longstaff, Francis A.; Merrill, Craig</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic actions and credit spreads: An empirical investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davydenko, Sergei A.; Strebulaev, Ilya A.
Do strategic actions of borrowers and lenders affect corporate debt values ? We find higher bond spreads for firms that can renegotiate debt contracts relatively easily. Consistent with theories of strategic debt service, the threat of strategic default depresses bond values ex ante, even though there may be efficiency gains from renegotiation ex post. However, the economic significance of the net effect is small, suggesting that bondholders have considerable bargaining power. The effect of strategic actions is higher when creditors are particularly vulnerable to strategic threats, including risky firms with high managerial shareholding, simple debt structures, and high liquidation costs.</description><author>Davydenko, Sergei A.; Strebulaev, Ilya A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Security design with investor private information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Axelson, Ulf
I study the security design problem of a firm when investors rather than managers have private information about the firm. I find that it is often optimal to issue information-sensitive securities such as equity. The "folklore proposition of debt" from traditional signaling models only goes through if the firm can vary the face value of debt with investor demand. When the firm has several assets, debt backed by a pool of assets is optimal when the degree of competition among investors is low, while equity backed by individual assets is optimal when competition is high.</description><author>Axelson, Ulf</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The risk-adjusted cost of financial distress</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, Heitor; Philippon, Thomas
Financial distress is more likely to happen in bad times. The present value of distress costs therefore depends on risk premia. We estimate this value using risk-adjusted default probabilities derived from corporate bond spreads. For a BBB-rated firm, our benchmark calculations show that the NPV of distress is 4.5% of predistress value. In contrast, a valuation that ignores risk premia generates an NPV of 1.4%. We show that marginal distress costs can be as large as the marginal tax benefits of debt derived by Graham (2000). Thus, distress risk premia can help explain why firms appear to use debt conservatively.</description><author>Almeida, Heitor; Philippon, Thomas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Supply and demand shifts in the shorting market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Lauren; Diether, Karl B.; Malloy, Christopher J.
nan</description><author>Cohen, Lauren; Diether, Karl B.; Malloy, Christopher J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-sales constraints and price discovery: Evidence from the Hong Kong market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Eric C.; Cheng, Joseph W.; Yu, Yinghui
nan</description><author>Chang, Eric C.; Cheng, Joseph W.; Yu, Yinghui</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price convexity and skewness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xu, Jianguo
nan</description><author>Xu, Jianguo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum and credit rating</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avramov, Doron; Chordia, Tarun; Jostova, Gergana; Philipov, Alexander
nan</description><author>Avramov, Doron; Chordia, Tarun; Jostova, Gergana; Philipov, Alexander</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange rates and cash flows in differentiated product industries: A simulation approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Friberg, Richard; Ganslandt, Mattias
nan</description><author>Friberg, Richard; Ganslandt, Mattias</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial constraints, competition, and hedging in industry equilibrium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adam, Tim; Dasgupta, Sudipto; Titman, Sheridan
nan</description><author>Adam, Tim; Dasgupta, Sudipto; Titman, Sheridan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taking a view: Corporate speculation, governance, and compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Geczy, Christopher C.; Minton, Bernadette A.; Schrand, Catherine M.
nan</description><author>Geczy, Christopher C.; Minton, Bernadette A.; Schrand, Catherine M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyst disagreement, mispricing, and liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sadka, Ronnie; Scherbina, Anna
nan</description><author>Sadka, Ronnie; Scherbina, Anna</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity premia and transaction costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jang, Bong-Gyu; Koo, Hyeng Keun; Liu, Hong; Loewenstein, Mark
nan</description><author>Jang, Bong-Gyu; Koo, Hyeng Keun; Liu, Hong; Loewenstein, Mark</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity or credit risk? The determinants of very short-term corporate yield spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Covitz, Dan; Downing, Chris
nan</description><author>Covitz, Dan; Downing, Chris</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity Coinsurance, Moral Hazard, and Financial Contagion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brusco, Sandro; Castiglionesi, Fabio
nan</description><author>Brusco, Sandro; Castiglionesi, Fabio</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Episodic liquidity crises: Cooperative and predatory trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlin, Bruce Ian; Lobo, Miguel Sousa; Viswanathan, S.
nan</description><author>Carlin, Bruce Ian; Lobo, Miguel Sousa; Viswanathan, S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and the law of one price: The case of the futures-cash basis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roll, Richard; Schwartz, Eduardo; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
nan</description><author>Roll, Richard; Schwartz, Eduardo; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multimarket trading and liquidity: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baruch, Shmuel; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Lemmon, Michael L.
nan</description><author>Baruch, Shmuel; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Lemmon, Michael L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio choice over the life-cycle when the stock and labor markets are cointegrated</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benzoni, Luca; Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.
nan</description><author>Benzoni, Luca; Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning by observing: Information spillovers in the execution and valuation of commercial bank M&amp;As</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delong, Gayle; Deyoung, Robert
We offer a new explanation for why academic studies typically fail to find value creation in bank mergers. Our conjectures are predicated on the idea that, until recently, large bank acquisitions were a new phenomenon, with no best practices history to inform bank managers or market investors. We hypothesize that merging banks, and investors pricing bank mergers, learn by observing information that spills over from previous bank mergers. We find evidence consistent with these conjectures for 216 M&amp;As of large, publicly traded U.S. commercial banks between 1987 and 1999. Our findings are consistent with semistrong stock market efficiency.</description><author>Delong, Gayle; Deyoung, Robert</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do firms issue equity ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dittmar, Amy; Thakor, Anjan
We develop and test a new theory of security issuance that is consistent with the puzzling stylized fact that firms issue equity when their stock prices are high. The theory also generates new predictions. Our theory predicts that managers use equity to finance projects when they believe that investors' views about project payoffs are likely to be aligned with theirs, thus maximizing the likelihood of agreement with investors. Otherwise, they use debt. We find strong empirical support for our theory and document its incremental explanatory power over other security-issuance theories such as market timing and time-varying adverse selection.</description><author>Dittmar, Amy; Thakor, Anjan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why is long-horizon equity less risky? A duration-based explanation of the value premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lettau, Martin; Wachter, Jessica A.
We propose a dynamic risk-based model that captures the value premium. Firms are modeled as long-lived assets distinguished by the timing of cash flows. The stochastic discount factor is specified so that shocks to aggregate dividends are priced, but shocks to the discount rate are not. The model implies that growth firms covary more with the discount rate than do value firms, which covary more with cash flows. When calibrated to explain aggregate stock market behavior, the model accounts for the observed value premium, the high Sharpe ratios on value firms, and the poor performance of the CAPM.</description><author>Lettau, Martin; Wachter, Jessica A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Common failings: How corporate defaults are correlated</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Das, Sanjiv R.; Duffie, Darrell; Kapadia, Nikunj; Saita, Leandro
We test the doubly stochastic assumption under which firms' default times are correlated only as implied by the correlation of factors determining their default intensities. Using data on U.S. corporations from 1979 to 2004, this assumption is violated in the presence of contagion or "frailty" (unobservable explanatory variables that are correlated across firms). Our tests do not depend on the time-series properties of default intensities. The data do not support the joint hypothesis of well-specified default intensities and the doubly stochastic assumption. We find some evidence of default clustering exceeding that implied by the doubly stochastic model with the given intensities.</description><author>Das, Sanjiv R.; Duffie, Darrell; Kapadia, Nikunj; Saita, Leandro</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate yield spreads and bond liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Long; Lesmond, David A.; Wei, Jason
We find that liquidity is priced in corporate yield spreads. Using a battery of liquidity measures covering over 4,000 corporate bonds and spanning both investment grade and speculative categories, we find that more illiquid bonds earn higher yield spreads, and an improvement in liquidity causes a significant reduction in yield spreads. These results hold after controlling for common bond-specific, firm-specific, and macroeconomic variables, and are robust to issuers' fixed effect and potential endogeneity bias. Our findings justify the concern in the default risk literature that neither the level nor the dynamic of yield spreads can be fully explained by default risk determinants.</description><author>Chen, Long; Lesmond, David A.; Wei, Jason</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information cascades: Evidence from a field experiment with financial market professionals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alevy, Jonathan E.; Haigh, Michael S.; List, John A.
Previous empirical studies of information cascades use either naturally occurring data or laboratory experiments. We combine attractive elements from each of these lines of research by observing market professionals from the Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT) in a controlled environment. Analysis of over 1,500 individual decisions suggests that CBOT professionals behave differently from our student control group. For instance, professionals are better able to discern the quality of public signals and their decisions are not affected by the domain of earnings. These results have implications for market efficiency and are important in both a positive and normative sense.</description><author>Alevy, Jonathan E.; Haigh, Michael S.; List, John A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of friendly boards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, Renee B.; Ferreira, Daniel
We analyze the consequences of the board's dual role as advisor as well as monitor of management. Given this dual role, the CEO faces a trade-off in disclosing information to the board: If he reveals his information, he receives better advice; however, an informed board will also monitor him more intensively. Since an independent board is a tougher monitor, the CEO may be reluctant to share information with it. Thus, management-friendly boards can be optimal. Using the insights from the model, we analyze the differences between sole and dual board systems. We highlight several policy implications of our analysis.</description><author>Adams, Renee B.; Ferreira, Daniel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Whom you know matters: Venture capital networks and investment performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hochberg, Yael V.; Ljungqvist, Alexander; Lu, Yang
Many financial markets are characterized by strong relationships and networks, rather than arm's-length, spot market transactions. We examine the performance consequences of this organizational structure in the context of relationships established when VCs syndicate portfolio company investments. We find that better-networked VC firms experience significantly better fund performance, as measured by the proportion of investments that are successfully exited through an IPO or a sale to another company. Similarly, the portfolio companies of better-networked VCs are significantly more likely to survive to subsequent financing and eventual exit. We also provide initial evidence on the evolution of VC networks.</description><author>Hochberg, Yael V.; Ljungqvist, Alexander; Lu, Yang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lower salaries and no options? On the optimal structure of executive pay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dittmann, Ingolf; Maug, Ernst
We calibrate the standard principal-agent model with constant relative risk aversion and lognormal stock prices to a sample of 598 U.S. CEOs. We show that this model predicts that most CEOs should not hold any stock options. Instead, CEOs should have lower base salaries and receive additional shares in their companies; many would be required to purchase additional stock in their companies. These contracts would reduce average compensation costs by 20% while providing the same incentives and the same utility to CEOs. We conclude that the standard principal-agent model typically used in the literature cannot rationalize observed contracts.</description><author>Dittmann, Ingolf; Maug, Ernst</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate caps "smile" too! But can the LIBOR market models capture the smile?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jarrow, Robert; Li, Haitao; Zhao, Feng
Using 3 years of interest rate caps price data, we provide a comprehensive documentation of volatility smiles in the caps market. To capture the volatility smiles, we develop a multifactor term structure model with stochastic volatility and jumps that yields a closed-form formula for cap prices. We show that although a three-factor stochastic volatility model can price at-the-money caps well, significant negative jumps in interest rates are needed to capture the smile. The volatility smile contains information that is not available using only at-the-money caps, and this information is important for understanding term structure models.</description><author>Jarrow, Robert; Li, Haitao; Zhao, Feng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of collateralization on swap rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johannes, Michael; Sundaresan, Suresh
Interest rate swap pricing theory traditionally views swaps as a portfolio of forward contracts with net swap payments discounted at LIBOR rates. In practice, the use of marking-to-market and collateralization questions this view as they introduce intermediate cash flows and alter credit characteristics. We provide a swap valuation theory under marking-to-market and costly collateral and examine the theory's empirical implications. We find evidence consistent with costly collateral using two different approaches; the first uses single-factor models and Eurodollar futures prices, and the second uses a formal term structure model and Treasury/swap data.</description><author>Johannes, Michael; Sundaresan, Suresh</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of embedded real options: Evidence from consumer automobile lease contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giaccotto, Carmelo; Goldberg, Gerson M.; Hegde, Shantaram P.
Under the common assumption of constant interest rates, we show that penalties for early termination of a lease are often structured in such a way that the cancellation option embedded in consumer automotive leases has little value. Furthermore, our estimates drawn from a sample of three popular car models over 1990 to 2000 indicate that the stand-alone value of the lease-end purchase option is, on average, about 16% of the market value of underlying used vehicles, or about $1,462 per contract. Finally, we examine the sensitivity of our option value estimates to model parameters and default risk.</description><author>Giaccotto, Carmelo; Goldberg, Gerson M.; Hegde, Shantaram P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The initial public offerings of listed firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Derrien, Francois; Kecskes, Ambrus
A number of firms in the United Kingdom list without issuing equity and then issue equity shortly thereafter. We argue that this two-stage offering strategy is less costly than an initial public offering (IPO) because trading reduces the valuation uncertainty of these firms before they issue equity. We find that initial returns are 10% to 30% lower for these firms than for comparable IPOs, and we provide evidence that the market in the firm's shares lowers financing costs. We also show that these firms time the market both when they list and when they issue equity.</description><author>Derrien, Francois; Kecskes, Ambrus</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical evidence on capital investment, growth options, and security returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, C. W.; Garcia-Feijoo, L.
Growth in capital expenditures conditions subsequent classification of firms to portfolios based on size and book-to-market ratios, as in the widely used Fama and French (1992, 1993) methods. Growth in capital expenditures also explains returns to portfolios and the cross section of future stock returns. These findings are consistent with recent theoretical models (e.g., Berk, Green, and Naik (1999)) in which the exercise of investment-growth options results in changes in both valuation and expected stock returns.</description><author>Anderson, C. W.; Garcia-Feijoo, L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wealth and executive compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, B.
Using new data on the wealth of Swedish CEOs, I show that higher wealth CEOs receive stronger incentives. Since high wealth (excluding own-firm holdings) implies low absolute risk aversion, this is consistent with a risk aversion explanation. To examine whether wealth is likely to proxy for power, I use lagged wealth (typically measured before the CEO was hired), and the results remain for one of two incentive measures. Also, the wealth-incentive result is not stronger for CEOs likely to face limited owner oversight. Finally, wealth is unrelated to pay levels, and is hence unlikely to proxy for skill.</description><author>Becker, B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unspanned stochastic volatility: Evidence from hedging interest rate derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, H. T.; Zhao, F.
Most existing dynamic term structure models assume that interest rate derivatives are redundant securities and can be perfectly hedged using solely bonds. We find that the quadratic term structure models have serious difficulties in hedging caps and cap straddles, even though they capture bond yields well. Furthermore, at-the-money straddle hedging errors are highly correlated with cap-implied volatilities and can explain a large fraction of hedging errors of all caps and straddles across moneyness and maturities. Our results strongly suggest the existence of systematic unspanned factors related to stochastic volatility in interest rate derivatives markets.</description><author>Li, H. T.; Zhao, F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competing for securities underwriting mandates: Banking relationships and analyst recommendations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ljungqvist, A.; Marston, F.; Wilhelm, W. J.
We investigate whether analyst behavior influenced banks' likelihood of winning underwriting mandates for a sample of 16,625 U.S. debt and equity offerings in 1993-2002. We control for the strength of the issuer's investment banking relationships with potential competitors for the mandate, prior lending relationships, and the endogeneity of analyst behavior and the bank's decision to provide analyst coverage. Although analyst behavior was influenced by economic incentives, we find no evidence that aggressive analyst behavior increased their bank's probability of winning an underwriting mandate. The main determinant of the lead-bank choice is the strength of prior underwriting and lending relationships.</description><author>Ljungqvist, A.; Marston, F.; Wilhelm, W. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cross-section of volatility and expected returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, A.; Hodrick, R. J.; Xing, Y. H.; Zhang, X. Y.
We examine the pricing of aggregate volatility risk in the cross-section of stock returns. Consistent with theory, we find that stocks with high sensitivities to innovations in aggregate volatility have low average returns. Stocks with high idiosyncratic volatility relative to the Fama and French (1993, Journal of Financial Economics 25, 2349) model have abysmally low average returns. This phenomenon cannot be explained by exposure to aggregate volatility risk. Size, book-to-market, momentum, and liquidity effects cannot account for either the low average returns earned by stocks with high exposure to systematic volatility risk or for the low average returns of stocks with high idiosyncratic volatility.</description><author>Ang, A.; Hodrick, R. J.; Xing, Y. H.; Zhang, X. Y.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The limits of investor behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loewenstein, M.; Willard, G. A.
Many models use noise trader risk and corresponding violations of the Law of One Price to explain pricing anomalies, but include a storage technology in perfectly elastic supply or unlimited asset liability. Storage allows aggregate consumption risk to differ from exogenous fundamental risk, but using aggregate consumption as a factor for asset returns can make noise trader risk superfluous. Using (i) limited asset liability and limited storage withdrawals, or (ii) an endogenous locally riskless interest rate eliminates violations of the Law of One Price. Our main results use only budget equations and market clearing, and require virtually no assumptions about behavior.</description><author>Loewenstein, M.; Willard, G. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The price impact and survival of irrational traders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kogan, L.; Ross, S. A.; Wang, J.; Westerfield, M. M.
Milton Friedman argued that irrational traders will consistently lose money, will not survive, and, therefore, cannot influence long-run asset prices. Since his work, survival and price impact have been assumed to be the same. In this paper, we demonstrate that survival and price impact are two independent concepts. The price impact of irrational traders does not rely on their long-run survival, and they can have a significant impact on asset prices even when their wealth becomes negligible. We also show that irrational traders' portfolio policies can deviate from their limits long after the price process approaches its long-run limit.</description><author>Kogan, L.; Ross, S. A.; Wang, J.; Westerfield, M. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing implications of nonconvex adjustment costs and irreversibility of investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, I.
This paper derives a real options model that accounts for the value premium. If real investment is largely irreversible, the book value of assets of a distressed firm is high relative to its market value because it has idle physical capital. The firm's excess installed capital capacity enables it to fully benefit from positive aggregate shocks without undertaking costly investment. Thus, returns to equity holders of a high book-to-market firm are sensitive to aggregate conditions and its systematic risk is high. Simulations indicate that the model goes a long way toward accounting for the observed value premium.</description><author>Cooper, I.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance as a barrier to entry: Bank competition and industry structure in local US Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cetorelli, N.; Strahan, P. E.
This paper tests how competition in local U.S. banking markets affects the market structure of nonfinancial sectors. Theory offers competing hypotheses about how competition ought to influence firm entry and access to bank credit by mature firms. The empirical evidence, however, strongly supports the idea that in markets with concentrated banking, potential entrants face greater difficulty gaining access to credit than in markets in which banking is more competitive.</description><author>Cetorelli, N.; Strahan, P. E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Uncertainty and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, X. F.
There is substantial evidence of short-term stock price continuation, which the prior literature often attributes to investor behavioral biases such as underreaction to new information. This paper investigates the role of information uncertainty in price continuation anomalies and cross-sectional variations in stock returns. If short-term price continuation is due to investor behavioral biases, we should observe greater price drift when there is greater information uncertainty. As a result, greater information uncertainty should produce relatively higher expected returns following good news and relatively lower expected returns following bad news. My evidence supports this hypothesis.</description><author>Zhang, X. F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Favoritism in mutual fund families? Evidence on strategic cross-fund subsidization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gaspar, J. M.; Massa, M.; Matos, P.
We investigate whether mutual fund families strategically transfer performance across member funds to favor those more likely to increase overall family profits. We find that "high family value" funds (i.e., high fees or high past performers) overperform at the expense of "low value" funds. Such a performance gap is above the one existing between similar funds not affiliated with the same family. Better allocations of underpriced initial public offering deals and opposite trades across member funds partly explain why high value funds overperform. Our findings highlight how the family organization prevalent in the mutual fund industry generates distortions in delegated asset management.</description><author>Gaspar, J. M.; Massa, M.; Matos, P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment and financing constraints: Evidence from the funding of corporate pension plans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rauh, J. D.
I exploit sharply nonlinear funding rules for defined benefit pension plans in order to identify the dependence of corporate investment on internal financial resources in a large sample. Capital expenditures decline with mandatory contributions to DB pension plans, even when controlling for correlations between the pension funding status itself and the firm's unobserved investment opportunities. The effect is particularly evident among firms that face financing constraints based on observable variables such as credit ratings. Investment also displays strong negative correlations with the part of mandatory contributions resulting solely from unexpected asset market movements.</description><author>Rauh, J. D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What works in securities laws?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>La Porta, R.; Lopez-De-Silanes, F.; Shleifer, A.
We examine the effect of securities laws on stock market development in 49 countries. We find little evidence that public enforcement benefits stock markets, but strong evidence that laws mandating disclosure and facilitating private enforcement through liability rules benefit stock markets.</description><author>La Porta, R.; Lopez-De-Silanes, F.; Shleifer, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Initial public offerings: An analysis of theory and practice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brau, J. C.; Fawcett, S. E.
We survey 336 chief financial officers (CFOs) to compare practice to theory in the areas of initial public offering (IPO) motivation, timing, underwriter selection, underpricing, signaling, and the decision to remain private. We find the primary motivation for going public is to facilitate acquisitions. CFOs base IPO timing on overall market conditions, are well informed regarding expected underpricing, and feel underpricing compensates investors for taking risk. The most important positive signal is past historical earnings, followed by underwriter certification. CFOs have divergent opinions about the IPO process depending on firm-specific characteristics. Finally, we find the main reason for remaining private is to preserve decision-making control and ownership.</description><author>Brau, J. C.; Fawcett, S. E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor tax heterogeneity and ex-dividend day trading volume</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dhaliwal, D.; Li, O. Z.
We propose that ex-dividend day excess volume is motivated by tax heterogeneity among investors, and thus is increasing in investor tax heterogeneity. Institutional ownership is our measure of heterogeneity. Since investor heterogeneity is a concave function of institutional ownership, we hypothesize that ex-day volume is a concave function of institutional ownership. Cross-sectional tests support the tax-motivated trading hypothesis. Additional tests, using trade size and pension ownership as proxies for institutional trades, yield similar results. We contribute to the literature by considering the interaction between payout policy and ownership structure in explaining the cross-sectional variation in ex-day volume.</description><author>Dhaliwal, D.; Li, O. Z.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of short selling on bubbles and crashes in experimental spot asset markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haruvy, E.; Noussair, C. N.
A series of experiments illustrate that relaxing short-selling constraints lowers prices in experimental asset markets, but does not induce prices to track fundamentals. We argue that prices in experimental asset markets are influenced by restrictions on short-selling capacity and limits on the cash available for purchases. Restrictions on short sales in the form of cash reserve requirements and quantity limits on short positions behave in a similar manner. A simulation model, based on DeLong et al. (1990), generates average price patterns that are similar to the observed data.</description><author>Haruvy, E.; Noussair, C. N.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does a parent-subsidiary structure enhance financing flexibility?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vjh, Anand M.
I examine whether firms exploit a publicly traded parent-subsidiary structure to issue equity of the overvalued firm regardless of which firm needs funds, and whether this conveys opposite information about firm values. Using 90 subsidiary and 37 parent seasoned equity offering (SEO) announcements during 1981-2002, I document negative returns to issuers but insignificant returns to nonissuers in both samples, and insignificant changes in combined firm value and parent's nonsubsidiary equity value in subsidiary SEOs. Firms issue equity to meet their own financing needs. My evidence contrasts with previous studies and suggests that parent-subsidiary structures do not enhance financing flexibility.</description><author>Vjh, Anand M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do dividend clienteles exist? Evidence on dividend preferences of retail investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, J. R.; Kumar, A.
We study stock holdings and trading behavior of more than 60,000 households and find evidence consistent with dividend clienteles. Retail investor stock holdings indicate a preference for dividend yield that increases with age and decreases with income, consistent with age and tax clienteles, respectively. Trading patterns reinforce this evidence: Older, low-income investors disproportionally purchase stocks before the exdividend day. Furthermore, among small stocks, the ex-day price drop decreases with age and increases with income, consistent with clientele effects. Finally, consistent with the behavioral "attention" hypothesis, we document that older and low-income investors purchase stocks following dividend announcements.</description><author>Graham, J. R.; Kumar, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The costs of bankruptcy: Chapter 7 liquidation versus Chapter 11 reorganization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bris, A.; Welch, I.; Zhu, N.
Our paper explores a comprehensive sample of small and large corporate bankruptcies in Arizona and New York from 1995 to 2001. Bankruptcy costs are very heterogeneous and sensitive to the measurement method used. We find that Chapter 7 liquidations appear to be no faster or cheaper (in terms of direct expense) than Chapter 11 reorganizations. However, Chapter 11 seems to preserve assets better, thereby allowing creditors to recover relatively more. Our paper also provides a large number of further empirical regularities.</description><author>Bris, A.; Welch, I.; Zhu, N.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate equity ownership and the governance of product market relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fee, C. E.; Hadlock, C. J.; Thomas, S.
We assemble a sample of over 10,000 customer-supplier relationships and determine whether the customer owns equity in the supplier. We find that factors related to both contractual incompleteness and financial market frictions are important in the decision of a customer firm to take an equity stake in their supplier. Evidence on the variation in the size of observed equity positions suggests that there are limits to the size of optimal ownership stakes in many relationships. Finally, we find that relationships accompanied by equity ownership last significantly longer than other relationships, suggesting that ownership aids in bonding trading parties together.</description><author>Fee, C. E.; Hadlock, C. J.; Thomas, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor sentiment and pre-IPO markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornelli, Francesca; Goldreich, David; Ljungqvist, Alexander
We examine whether irrational behavior among small (retail) investors drives post-IPO prices. We use prices from the grey market (the when-issued market that precedes European IPOs) to proxy for small investors' valuations. High grey market prices (indicating overoptimism) are a very good predictor of first-day aftermarket prices, while low grey market prices (indicating excessive pessimism) are not. Moreover, we find long-run price reversal only following high grey market prices. This asymmetry occurs because larger (institutional) investors can choose between keeping the shares they are allocated in the IPO, and reselling them when small investors are overoptimistic.</description><author>Cornelli, Francesca; Goldreich, David; Ljungqvist, Alexander</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analysts' selective coverage and subsequent performance of newly public firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Das, S.; Guo, R. J.; Zhang, H.
This study examines the ability of analysts to forecast future firm performance, based on the selective coverage of newly public firms. We hypothesize that the decision to provide coverage contains information about an analyst's underlying expectation of a firm's future prospects. We extract this expectation by obtaining residual analyst coverage from a model of initial analyst following. We document that in the three subsequent years, initial public offerings with high residual coverage have significantly better returns and operating performance than those with low residual coverage. This evidence indicates analysts have superior predictive abilities and selectively provide coverage for firms about which their true expectations are favorable.</description><author>Das, S.; Guo, R. J.; Zhang, H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset float and speculative bubbles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, H.; Scheinkman, J.; Xiong, W.
We model the relationship between asset float (tradeable shares) and speculative bubbles. Investors with heterogeneous beliefs and short-sales constraints trade a stock with limited float because of insider lockups. A bubble arises as price overweighs optimists' beliefs and investors anticipate the option to resell to those with even higher valuations. The bubble's size depends on float as investors anticipate an increase in float with lockup expirations and speculate over the degree of insider selling. Consistent with the internet experience, the bubble, turnover, and volatility decrease with float and prices drop on the lockup expiration date.</description><author>Hong, H.; Scheinkman, J.; Xiong, W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital gains tax overhang and price pressure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jin, L.
I study whether the capital gains tax is an impediment to selling by some investors and if so, to what degree associated delayed selling affects stock prices. I find that selling decisions by institutions serving tax-sensitive clients are sensitive to cumulative capital gains, a pattern not observed for institutions with predominantly tax-exempt clients. Moreover, tax-related underselling impacts stock prices during large-earnings surprises for stocks held primarily by tax-sensitive investors. The corresponding price reactions are less negative (more positive) with higher cumulative capital gains. This. price pressure pattern is more severe when arbitrage is more costly.</description><author>Jin, L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit ratings and capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kisgen, Darren J.
This paper examines to what extent credit ratings directly affect capital structure decisions. The paper outlines discrete costs (benefits) associated with firm credit rating level differences and tests whether concerns for these costs (benefits) directly affect debt and equity financing decisions. Firms near a credit rating upgrade or downgrade issue less debt relative to equity than firms not near a change in rating. This behavior is consistent with discrete costs (benefits) of rating changes but is not explained by traditional capital structure theories. The results persist within previous empirical tests of the pecking order and tradeoff capital structure theories.</description><author>Kisgen, Darren J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate investment and asset price dynamics: Implications for SEO event studies and long-run performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlson, M.; Fisher, A.; Giammarino, R.
We present a rational theory of SEOs that explains a pre-issuance price run-up, a negative announcement effect, and long-run post-issuance underperformance. When SEOs finance investment in a real options framework, expected returns decrease endogenously because growth options are converted into assets in place. Regardless of their risk, the new assets are less risky than the options they replace. Although both size and book-to-market effects are present, standard matching procedures fail to fully capture the dynamics of risk and expected return. We calibrate the model and show that it closely matches the primary features of SEO return dynamics.</description><author>Carlson, M.; Fisher, A.; Giammarino, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robert J. Shiller</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anonymous
nan</description><author>Anonymous</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Secondary trading costs in the municipal bond market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harris, L. E.; Piwowar, M. S.
Using new econometric methods, we separately estimate average transaction costs for over 167,000 bonds from a 1-year sample of all U.S. municipal bond trades. Municipal bond transaction costs decrease with trade size and do not depend significantly on trade frequency. Also, municipal bond trades are substantially more expensive than similar-sized equity trades. We attribute these results to the lack of bond market price transparency. Additional cross-sectional analyses show that bond trading costs increase with credit risk, instrument complexity, time to maturity, and time since issuance. Investors, and perhaps ultimately issuers, might benefit if issuers issued simpler bonds.</description><author>Harris, L. E.; Piwowar, M. S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uncovering the risk-return relation in the stock market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, H.; Whitelaw, R. F.
There is ongoing debate about the apparent weak or negative relation between risk (conditional variance) and expected returns in the aggregate stock market. We develop and estimate an empirical model based on the intertemporal capital asset pricing model (ICAPM) that separately identifies the two components of expected returns, namely, the risk component and the component due to the desire to hedge changes in investment opportunities. The estimated coefficient of relative risk aversion is positive, statistically significant, and reasonable in magnitude. However, expected returns are driven primarily by the hedge component. The omission of this component is partly responsible for the existing contradictory results.</description><author>Guo, H.; Whitelaw, R. F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distance constraints: The limits of foreign lending in poor economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mian, Atif
How far does mobility of multinational banks solve problems of financial development? Using a panel of 80,000 loans over 7 years, I show that greater cultural and geographical distance between a foreign bank's headquarters and local branches leads it to further avoid lending to "informationally difficult" yet fundamentally sound firms requiring relational contracting. Greater distance also makes them less likely to bilaterally renegotiate, and less successful at recovering defaults. Differences in bank size, legal institutions, risk preferences, or unobserved borrower heterogeneity cannot explain these results. These distance constraints can be large enough to permanently exclude certain sectors of the economy from financing by foreign ganks.</description><author>Mian, Atif</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which investors fear expropriation? Evidence from investors' portfolio choices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giannetti, M.; Simonov, A.
Using a data set that provides unprecedented detail on investors' stockholdings, we analyze whether investors take the quality of corporate governance into account when selecting stocks. We find that all categories of investors (domestic and foreign, institutional and small individual) who generally enjoy only security benefits are reluctant to invest in companies with weak corporate governance. In contrast, individuals connected with company insiders are more likely to invest in weak corporate governance companies. These findings suggest that it is important to distinguish between investors who enjoy private benefits or access private information, and investors who enjoy only security benefits.</description><author>Giannetti, M.; Simonov, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm value and hedging: Evidence from US oil and gas producers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jin, Y. B.; Jorion, P.
This paper studies the hedging activities of 119 U.S. oil and gas producers from 1998 to 2001 and evaluates their effect on firm value. Theories of hedging based on market imperfections imply that hedging should increase the firm's market value (MV). To test this hypothesis, we collect detailed information on the extent of hedging and on the valuation of oil and gas reserves. We verify that hedging reduces the firm's stock price sensitivity to oil and gas prices. Contrary to previous studies, however, we find that hedging does not seem to affect MVs for this industry.</description><author>Jin, Y. B.; Jorion, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do crises spread? Evidence from accessible and inaccessible stock indices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyer, B. H.; Kumagai, T.; Yuan, K.
We provide empirical evidence that stock market crises are spread globally through asset holdings of international investors. By separating emerging market stocks into two categories, namely, those that are eligible for purchase by foreigners (accessible) and those that are not (inaccessible), we estimate and compare the degree to which accessible and inaccessible stock index returns co-move with crisis country index returns. Our results show greater co-movement during high volatility periods, especially for accessible stock index returns, suggesting that crises spread through the asset holdings of international investors rather than through changes in fundamentals.</description><author>Boyer, B. H.; Kumagai, T.; Yuan, K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pension plan funding and stock market efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Franzoni, F.; Marin, J. M.
The paper argues that the market significantly overvalues firms with severely underfunded pension plans. These companies earn lower stock returns than firms with healthier pension plans for at least 5 years after the first emergence of the underfunding. The low returns are not explained by risk, price momentum, earnings momentum, or accruals. Further, the evidence suggests that investors do not anticipate the impact of the pension liability on future earnings, and they are surprised when the negative implications of underfunding ultimately materialize. Finally, underfunded firms have poor operating performance, and they earn low returns, although they are value companies.</description><author>Franzoni, F.; Marin, J. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks' advantage in hedging liquidity risk: Theory and evidence from the commercial paper market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gatev, E.; Strahan, P. E.
Banks have a unique ability to hedge against market-wide liquidity shocks. Deposit inflows provide funding for loan demand shocks that follow declines in market liquidity. Consequently, banks can insure firms against systematic declines in liquidity at lower cost than other institutions. We provide evidence that when liquidity dries up and commercial paper spreads widen, banks experience funding inflows. These flows allow banks to meet loan demand from borrowers drawing funds from commercial paper backup lines without running down their holdings of liquid assets. We also provide evidence that implicit government support for banks during crises explains these funding flows.</description><author>Gatev, E.; Strahan, P. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market valuation of tax-timing options: Evidence from capital gains distributions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chay, J. B.; Choi, D. S.; Pontiff, J.
We examine a distribution that is taxed as a capital gain rather than as a dividend. Since the distribution induces a realized capital gain while the price change is an unrealized gain, ex-day return behavior provides evidence of the value of tax-timing capital gains. We show that investors are compensated 7 cent in unrealized gains for each dollar of realized capital gains, that is, $1 of realized capital gains is equivalent to 93 cent of unrealized gains. An investor with a tax rate on realized gains of 15% has an effective tax rate on unrealized capital gains of 8.6%.</description><author>Chay, J. B.; Choi, D. S.; Pontiff, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The entrepreneur's choice between private and public ownership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boot, A. W. A.; Gopalan, R.; Thakor, A. V.
We analyze an entrepreneur/manager's choice between private and public ownership. The manager needs decision-making autonomy to optimally manage the firm and thus trades off an endogenized control preference against the higher cost of capital accompanying greater managerial autonomy. Investors need liquid ownership stakes. Public capital markets provide liquidity, but stipulate corporate governance that imposes generic exogenous controls, so the manager may not attain the desired trade-off between autonomy and the cost of capital. In contrast, private ownership provides the desired trade-off through precisely calibrated contracting, but creates illiquid ownership. Exploring this tension generates new predictions.</description><author>Boot, A. W. A.; Gopalan, R.; Thakor, A. V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Offering versus choice in 401(k) plans: Equity exposure and number of funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huberman, G.; Jiang, W.
Records of over half a million participants in more than 600 401(k) plans indicate that participants tend to allocate their contributions evenly across the funds they use, with the tendency weakening with the number of funds used. The number of funds used, typically between three and four, is not sensitive to the number of funds offered by the plans, which ranges from 4 to 59. A participant's propensity to allocate contributions to equity funds is not very sensitive to the fraction of equity funds among offered funds. The paper also comments on limitations on inferences from experiments and aggregate-level data analysis.</description><author>Huberman, G.; Jiang, W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does investor misvaluation drive the takeover market?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dong, M.; Hirshleifer, D.; Richardson, S.; Teoh, S. H.
This paper uses pre-offer market valuations to evaluate the misvaluation and Q theories of takeovers. Bidder and target valuations (price-to-book, or price-to-residual-income-model-value) are related to means of payment, mode of acquisition, premia, target hostility, offer success, and bidder and target announcement-period returns. The evidence is broadly consistent with both hypotheses. The evidence for the Q hypothesis is stronger in the pre-1990 period than in the 1990-2000 period, whereas the evidence for the misvaluation hypothesis is stronger in the 1990-2000 period than in the pre-1990 period.</description><author>Dong, M.; Hirshleifer, D.; Richardson, S.; Teoh, S. H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are busy boards effective monitors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fich, E. M.; Shivdasani, A.
Firms with busy boards, those in which a majority of outside directors hold three or more directorships, are associated with weak corporate governance. These firms exhibit lower market-to-book ratios, weaker profitability, and lower sensitivity of CEO turnover to firm performance. Independent but busy boards display CEO turnover-performance sensitivities indistinguishable from those of inside-dominated boards. Departures of busy outside directors generate positive abnormal returns (ARs). When directors become busy as a result of acquiring an additional directorship, other companies in which they hold board seats experience negative ARs. Busy outside directors are more likely to depart boards following poor performance.</description><author>Fich, E. M.; Shivdasani, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does weak governance cause weak stock returns? An examination of firm operating performance and investors' expectations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Core, J. E.; Guay, W. R.; Rusticus, T. O.
We investigate Gompers, Ishii, and Metrick's (2003) finding that firms with weak shareholder rights exhibit significant stock market underperformance. If the relation between poor governance and poor returns is causal, we expect that the market is negatively surprised by the poor operating performance of weak governance firms. We find that firms with weak shareholder rights exhibit significant operating underperformance. However, analysts' forecast errors and earnings announcement returns show no evidence that this underperformance surprises the market. Our results are robust to controls for takeover activity. Overall, our results do not support the hypothesis that weak governance causes poor stock returns.</description><author>Core, J. E.; Guay, W. R.; Rusticus, T. O.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk, reputation, and IPO price support</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lewellen, K.
Immediately following an initial public offering, underwriters often repurchase shares of poorly performing offerings in an apparent attempt to stabilize the price. Using proprietary Nasdaq data, I study the price effects and determinants of price support. Some of the key findings are (1) Stabilization is substantial, inducing price rigidity at and below the offer price; (2) I find no evidence that stocks with larger information asymmetries are stabilized more strongly; (3) Larger underwriters stabilize more, perhaps to protect their reputations with investors; and (4) Investment banks with retail brokerage operations stabilize much more than other banks, inconsistent with the view that stabilization benefits primarily institutional investors.</description><author>Lewellen, K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do the Fama-French factors proxy for innovations in predictive variables?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Petkova, R.
The Fama-French factors HML and SMB are correlated with innovations in variables that describe investment opportunities. A model that includes shocks to the aggregate dividend yield and term spread, default spread, and one-month Treasury-bill yield explains the cross section of average returns better than the Fama-French model. When loadings on the innovations in the predictive variables are present in the model, loadings on HML and SMB lose their explanatory power for the cross section of returns. The results are consistent with an ICAPM explanation for the empirical success of the Fama-French portfolios.</description><author>Petkova, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A consumption-based explanation of expected stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yogo, M.
When utility is nonseparable in nondurable and durable consumption and the elasticity of substitution between the two consumption goods is sufficiently high, marginal utility rises when durable consumption falls. The model explains both the cross-sectional variation in expected stock returns and the time variation in the equity premium. Small stocks and value stocks deliver relatively low returns during recessions, when durable consumption falls, which explains their high average returns relative to big stocks and growth stocks. Stock returns are unexpectedly low at business cycle troughs, when durable consumption falls sharply, which explains the countercyclical variation in the equity premium.</description><author>Yogo, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank mergers and crime: The real and social effects of credit market competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garmaise, M. J.; Moskowitz, T. J.
Using a unique sample of commercial loans and mergers between large banks, we provide micro-level (within-county) evidence linking credit conditions to economic development and find a spillover effect on crime. Neighborhoods that experience more bank mergers are subject to higher interest rates, diminished local construction, lower prices, an influx of poorer households, and higher property crime in subsequent years. The elasticity of property crime with respect to merger-induced banking concentration is 0.18. We show that these results are not likely due to reverse causation, and confirm the central findings using state branching deregulation to instrument for bank competition.</description><author>Garmaise, M. J.; Moskowitz, T. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Report of the editor of The Journal of Finance for the year 2005</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stambaugh, Robert F.
nan</description><author>Stambaugh, Robert F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The disposition effect and underreaction to news</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frazzini, Andrea
This paper tests whether the "disposition effect," that is the tendency of investors to ride losses and realize gains, induces "underreaction" to news, leading to return predictability. I use data on mutual fund holdings to construct a new measure of reference purchasing prices for individual stocks, and I show that post-announcement price drift is most severe whenever capital gains and the news event have the same sign. The magnitude of the drift depends on the capital gains (losses) experienced by the stock holders on the event date. An event-driven strategy based on this effect yields monthly alphas of over 200 basis points.</description><author>Frazzini, Andrea</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting returns with managerial decision variables: Is there a small-sample bias ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, Malcolm; Taliaferro, Ryan; Wurgler, Jeffrey
Many studies find that aggregate managerial decision variables, such as aggregate equity issuance, predict stock or bond market returns. Recent research argues that these findings may be driven by an aggregate time-series version of Schultz's (2003, Journal of Finance 58, 483-517) pseudo market-timing bias. Using standard simulation techniques, we find that the bias is much too small to account for the observed predictive power of the equity share in new issues, corporate investment plans, insider trading, dividend initiations, or the maturity of corporate debt issues.</description><author>Baker, Malcolm; Taliaferro, Ryan; Wurgler, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Household finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, John Y.
The study of household finance is challenging because household behavior is difficult to measure, and households face constraints not captured by textbook models. Evidence on participation, diversification, and mortgage refinancing suggests that many households invest effectively, but a minority make significant mistakes. This minority appears to be poorer and less well educated than the majority of more successful investors. There is some evidence that households understand their own limitations and avoid financial strategies for which they feel unqualified. Some financial products involve a cross-subsidy from naive to sophisticated households, and this can inhibit welfare-improving financial innovation.</description><author>Campbell, John Y.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market reactions to tangible and intangible information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Daniel, Kent; Titman, Sheridan
The book-to-market effect is often interpreted as evidence of high expected returns on stocks of "distressed" firms with poor past performance. We dispute this interpretation. We find that while a stock's future return is unrelated to the firm's past accounting-based performance, it is strongly negatively related to the "intangible" return, the component of its past return that is orthogonal to the firm's past performance. Indeed, the book-to-market ratio forecasts returns because it is a good proxy for the intangible return. Also, a composite equity issuance measure, which is related to intangible returns, independently forecasts returns.</description><author>Daniel, Kent; Titman, Sheridan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor sentiment and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, Malcolm; Wurgler, Jeffrey
We study how investor sentiment affects the cross-section of stock returns. We predict that a wave of investor sentiment has larger effects on securities whose valuations are highly subjective and difficult to arbitrage. Consistent with this prediction, we find that when beginning-of-period proxies for sentiment are low, subsequent returns are relatively high for small stocks, young stocks, high volatility stocks, unprofitable stocks, non-dividend-paying stocks, extreme growth stocks, and distressed stocks. When sentiment is high, on the other hand, these categories of stock earn relatively low subsequent returns.</description><author>Baker, Malcolm; Wurgler, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How persistent is the impact of market timing on capital structure ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alti, Aydogan
This paper examines the capital structure implications of market timing. I isolate timing attempts in a single major financing event, the initial public offering, by identifying market timers as firms that go public in hot issue markets. I find that hot-market IPO firms issue substantially more equity, and lower their leverage ratios by more, than cold-market firms do. However, immediately after going public, hot-market firms increase their leverage ratios by issuing more debt and less equity relative to cold-market firms. At the end of the second year following the IPO, the impact of market timing on leverage completely vanishes.</description><author>Alti, Aydogan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can managers successfully time the maturity structure of their debt issues ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Butler, Alexander W.; Grullon, Gustavo; Weston, James P.
This paper provides a rational explanation for the apparent ability of managers to successfully time the maturity of their debt issues. We show that a structural break in excess bond returns during the early 1980s generates a spurious correlation between the fraction of long-term debt in total debt issues and future excess bond returns. Contrary to Baker, Taliaferro, and Wurgler (2006), we show that the presence of structural breaks can lead to nonsense regressions, whether or not there is any small sample bias. Tests using firm-level data further confirm that managers are unable to time the debt market successfully.</description><author>Butler, Alexander W.; Grullon, Gustavo; Weston, James P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does corporate headquarters location matter for stock returns ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pirinsky, Christo; Wang, Qinghai
We document strong comovement in the stock returns of firms headquartered in the same geographic area. Moreover, stocks of companies that change their headquarters location experience a decrease in their comovement with stocks from the old location and an increase in their comovement with stocks from the new location. The local comovement of stock returns is not explained by economic fundamentals and is stronger for smaller firms with more individual investors and in regions with less financially sophisticated residents. We argue that price formation in equity markets has a significant geographic component linked to the trading patterns of local residents.</description><author>Pirinsky, Christo; Wang, Qinghai</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO turnover after acquisitions: Are bad bidders fired ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lehn, Kenneth M.; Zhao, Mengxin
We examine the relation between bidder returns and the probability of chief executive officer (CEO) turnover in acquiring firms. Using a sample of 714 acquisitions during 1990 to 1998, we find that 47% of CEOs of acquiring firms are replaced within 5 years, including 27% by internal governance, 16% by takeovers, and 4% by bankruptcy. A significant inverse relation exists between bidder returns and the likelihood of CEO turnover. This relation is not associated with governance structure. It also is not significantly different in stock versus cash acquisitions, which appears to be inconsistent with Shleifer and Vishny's theory of "stock market driven" acquisitions.</description><author>Lehn, Kenneth M.; Zhao, Mengxin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEOs' outside employment opportunities and the lack of relative performance evaluation in compensation contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rajgopal, Shivaram; Shevlin, Terry; Zamora, Valentina
Although agency theory suggests that firms should index executive compensation to remove market-wide effects (i.e., RPE), there is little evidence to support this theory. Oyer (2004, Journal of Finance 59, 1619-1649) posits that an absence of RPE is optimal if the CEO's reservation wages from outside employment opportunities vary with the economy's fortunes. We directly test and find support for Oyer's (2004) theory. We argue that the CEO's outside opportunities depend on his talent, as proxied by the CEO's financial press visibility and his firm's industry-adjusted ROA. Our results are robust to alternate explanations such as managerial skimming, oligopoly, and asymmetric benchmarking.</description><author>Rajgopal, Shivaram; Shevlin, Terry; Zamora, Valentina</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information control, career concerns, and corporate governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Song, Fenghua; Thakor, Anjan V.
We examine corporate governance effectiveness when the CEO generates project ideas and the board of directors screens these ideas for approval. However, the precision of the board's screening information is controlled by the CEO. Moreover, both the CEO and the board have career concerns that interact. The board's career concerns cause it to distort its investment recommendation procyclically, whereas the CEO's career concerns cause her to sometimes reduce the precision of the board's information. Moreover, the CEO sometimes prefers a less able board, and this happens only during economic upturns, suggesting that corporate governance will be weaker during economic upturns.</description><author>Song, Fenghua; Thakor, Anjan V.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do banks affect the level and composition of industrial volatility ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Larrain, Borja
In theory, better access to bank credit can reduce or increase output volatility depending on whether firms are more financially constrained during contractions or expansions. This paper finds that the volatility of industrial output is lower in countries with more bank credit. Most of the reduction in volatility is idiosyncratic, which follows from the ability of banks to pool and diversify shocks. Systematic volatility is reduced less strongly. Volatility dampening is achieved via countercyclical borrowing: At the firm level, short-term borrowing is less (or more negatively) correlated with sales and inventories in countries with high levels of bank credit.</description><author>Larrain, Borja</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry concentration and average stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hou, Kewei; Robinson, David T.
Firms in more concentrated industries earn lower returns, even after controlling for size, book-to-market, momentum, and other return determinants. Explanations based on chance, measurement error, capital structure, and persistent in-sample cash flow shocks do not explain this finding. Drawing on work in industrial organization, we posit that either barriers to entry in highly concentrated industries insulate firms from undiversifiable distress risk, or firms in highly concentrated industries are less risky because they engage in less innovation, and thereby command lower expected returns. Additional time-series tests support these risk-based interpretations.</description><author>Hou, Kewei; Robinson, David T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate financial policy and the value of cash</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faulkender, Michael; Wang, Rong
We examine the cross-sectional variation in the marginal value of corporate cash holdings that arises from differences in corporate financial policy. We begin by providing semi-quantitative predictions for the value of an extra dollar of cash depending upon the likely use of that dollar, and derive a set of intuitive hypotheses to test empirically. By examining the variation in excess stock returns over the fiscal year, we find that the marginal value of cash declines with larger cash holdings, higher leverage, better access to capital markets, and as firms choose greater cash distribution via dividends rather than repurchases.</description><author>Faulkender, Michael; Wang, Rong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Model uncertainty and option markets with heterogeneous beliefs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buraschi, Andrea; Jiltsov, Alexei
This paper provides option pricing and volume implications for an economy with heterogeneous agents who face model uncertainty and have different beliefs on expected returns. Market incompleteness makes options nonredundant, while heterogeneity creates a link between differences in beliefs and option volumes. We solve for both option prices and volumes and test the joint empirical implications using S&amp;P500 index option data. Specifically, we use survey data to build an Index of Dispersion in Beliefs and find that a model that takes information heterogeneity into account can explain the dynamics of option volume and the smile better than can reduced-form models with stochastic volatility.</description><author>Buraschi, Andrea; Jiltsov, Alexei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Derivative pricing 60 years before black-scholes: Evidence from the Johannesburg Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moore, Lyndon; Juh, Steve
We obtain daily data for warrants traded on the Johannesburg Stock Exchange between 1909 and 1922, and for a broker's call option quotes on stocks from 1908 to 1911. We use this new data set to test how close derivative prices are to Black-Scholes (1973) prices and to compute profits for investors using a simple trading rule for call options. We examine whether investors exercised warrants optimally and how they reacted to extensions of the warrants' durations. We show that long before the development of the formal theory, investors had an intuitive grasp of the determinants of derivative pricing.</description><author>Moore, Lyndon; Juh, Steve</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tax-loss selling and the January effect: Evidence from municipal bond closed-end funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Starks, Laura T.; Yong, Li; Zheng, Lu
This paper provides direct evidence supporting the tax-loss selling hypothesis as an explanation of the January effect. Examining turn-of-the-year return and volume patterns for municipal bond closed-end funds, which are held mostly by tax-sensitive individual investors, we document a January effect for these funds, but not for their underlying assets. We provide evidence that this effect can be largely explained by tax-loss selling activities at the previous year-end. Moreover, we find that funds associated with brokerage firms display more tax-loss selling behavior, suggesting that tax counseling plays a role.</description><author>Starks, Laura T.; Yong, Li; Zheng, Lu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyst coverage and financing decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Xin; Dasgupta, Sudipto; Hilary, Gilles
We provide evidence that analyst coverage affects security issuance. First, firms covered by fewer analysts are less likely to issue equity as opposed to debt. They issue equity less frequently, but when they do so, it is in larger amounts. Moreover, these firms depend more on favorable market conditions for their equity issuance decisions. Finally, debt ratios of less covered firms are more affected by Baker and Wurgler's (2002) "external finance-weighted" average market-to-book ratio. These results are consistent with market timing behavior associated with information asymmetry, as well as behavior implied by dynamic adverse selection models of equity issuance.</description><author>Chang, Xin; Dasgupta, Sudipto; Hilary, Gilles</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When financial institutions are large shareholders: The role of macro corporate governance environments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Donghui; Moshirian, Fariborz; Pham, Peter Kien; Zein, Jason
While financial institutions' aggregate investments have grown substantially worldwide, the size of their individual shareholdings, and ultimately their incentive to monitor, may be limited by the free-rider problem, regulations, and a preference for diversification and liquidity. We compare institutions' shareholding patterns across countries and find vast differences in the extent to which they are large shareholders. These variations are largely determined by macro corporate governance factors such as shareholder protection, law enforcement, and corporate disclosure requirements. This suggests that strong governance environments act to strengthen monitoring ability such that more institutions are encouraged to hold concentrated equity positions.</description><author>Li, Donghui; Moshirian, Fariborz; Pham, Peter Kien; Zein, Jason</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insider trading, news releases, and ownership concentration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fidrmuc, Jana P.; Goergen, Marc; Renneboog, Luc
This paper investigates the market's reaction to U.K. insider transactions and analyzes whether the reaction depends on the firm's ownership. We present three major findings. First, differences in regulation between the U.K. and United States, in particular the speedier reporting of trades in the U.K., may explain the observed larger abnormal returns in the U.K. Second, ownership by directors and outside shareholders has an impact on the abnormal returns. Third, it is important to adjust for news released before directors' trades. In particular, trades preceded by news on mergers and acquisitions and CEO replacements contain significantly less information.</description><author>Fidrmuc, Jana P.; Goergen, Marc; Renneboog, Luc</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information, trading, and volatility: Evidence from weather-sensitive markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fleming, Jeff; Kirby, Chris; Ostdiek, Barbara
We find that trading-versus nontrading-period variance ratios in weather-sensitive markets are lower than those in the equity market and higher than those in the currency market. The variance ratios are also substantially lower during periods of the year when prices are most sensitive to the weather. Moreover, the comovement of returns and volatilities for related commodities is stronger during the weather-sensitive season, largely due to stronger comovement during nontrading periods. These results are consistent with a strong link between prices and public information flow and cannot be explained by pricing errors or changes in trading activity.</description><author>Fleming, Jeff; Kirby, Chris; Ostdiek, Barbara</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading volume: Implications of an intertemporal capital asset pricing model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lo, Andrew W.; Wang, Jiang
We derive an intertemporal asset pricing model and explore its implications for trading volume and asset returns. We show that investors trade in only two portfolios: the market portfolio, and a hedging portfolio that is used to hedge the risk of changing market conditions. We empirically identify the hedging portfolio using weekly volume and returns data for U.S. stocks, and then test two of its properties implied by the theory: Its return should be an additional risk factor in explaining the cross section of asset returns, and should also be the best predictor of future market returns.</description><author>Lo, Andrew W.; Wang, Jiang</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the gains from trade in limit-order markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hollifield, Burton; Miller, Robert A.; Sandas, Patrik; Slive, Joshua
We present a method to estimate the gains from trade in limit-order markets and provide empirical evidence that the limit-order market is a good market design. Using observations on order submissions and execution and cancellation histories, we estimate both the distribution of traders' unobserved valuations for the stock and latent trader arrival rates. We use the resulting estimates to compute the current gains from trade, the gains from trade in a perfectly liquid market, and the gains from trade with a monopoly liquidity supplier. The current gains are 90% of the maximum gains and 150% of the monopolist gains.</description><author>Hollifield, Burton; Miller, Robert A.; Sandas, Patrik; Slive, Joshua</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the contribution of corporate cash holdings and dividends to firm value depend on governance? A cross-country analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pinkowitz, Lee; Stulz, Rene; Williamson, Rohan
Agency theories predict that the value of corporate cash holdings is less in countries with poor investor protection because of the greater ability of controlling shareholders to extract private benefits from cash holdings in such countries. Using various specifications of the valuation regressions of Farna and French (1998), we find that the relation between cash holdings and firm value is much weaker in countries with poor investor protection than in other countries. In further support of the importance of agency theories, the relation between dividends and firm value is weaker in countries with stronger investor protection.</description><author>Pinkowitz, Lee; Stulz, Rene; Williamson, Rohan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal security design and dynamic capital structure in a continuous-time agency model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeMarzo, Peter M.; Sannikov, Yuliy
We derive the optimal dynamic contract in a continuous-time principal-agent setting, and implement it with a capital structure (credit line, long-term debt, and equity) over which the agent controls the payout policy. While the project's volatility and liquidation cost have little impact on the firm's total debt capacity, they increase the use of credit versus debt. Leverage is nonstationary, and declines with past profitability. The firm may hold a compensating cash balance while borrowing (at a higher rate) through the credit line. Surprisingly, the usual conflicts between debt and equity (asset substitution, strategic default) need not arise.</description><author>DeMarzo, Peter M.; Sannikov, Yuliy</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of pyramidal ownership and family business groups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, Heitor V.; Wolfenzon, Daniel
We provide a new rationale for pyramidal ownership in family business groups. A pyramid allows a family to access all retained earnings of a firm it already controls to set up a new firm, and to share the new firm's nondiverted payoff with shareholders of the original firm. Our model is consistent with recent evidence of a small separation between ownership and control in some pyramids, and can differentiate between pyramids and dual-class shares, even when either method can achieve the same deviation from one share-one vote. Other predictions of the model are consistent with both systematic and anecdotal evidence.</description><author>Almeida, Heitor V.; Wolfenzon, Daniel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political connections and corporate bailouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faccio, Mara; Masulis, Ronald W.; McConnell, John J.
We analyze the likelihood of government bailouts of 450 politically connected firms from 35 countries during 1997-2002. Politically connected firms are significantly more likely to be bailed out than similar nonconnected firms. Additionally, politically connected firms are disproportionately more likely to be bailed out when the International Monetary Fund or the World Bank provides financial assistance to the firm's home government. Further, among bailed-out firms, those that are politically connected exhibit significantly worse financial performance than their nonconnected peers at the time of and following the bailout. This evidence suggests that, at least in some countries, political connections influence the allocation of capital through the mechanism of financial assistance when connected companies confront economic distress.</description><author>Faccio, Mara; Masulis, Ronald W.; McConnell, John J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>