<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Journal of Banking &amp; Finance14</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Information acquisition, coordination, and fundamentals in a financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nikitin, Maxim; Smith, R. Todd
This paper reconciles the two explanations of a financial crisis, the self-fulfilling prophecy and the fundamental causes, in an empirically-relevant framework, by explicitly modeling the costly voluntary acquisition of information about fundamentals in a variant of Diamond and Dybvig [Diamond, D., Dybvig, P., 1983. Bank runs, deposit insurance, and liquidity. Journal of Political Economy 91, 401-419]. The model exhibits strategic complementarity in information acquisition. In the "partial run" equilibrium investors engage in costly evaluation of projects, so that banks with lower-return projects fail. There also exist the classic "full-run" and "no-run" equilibria in which there is no project evaluation. Investors' coordination on a specific equilibrium is triggered by a self-fulfilling prophecy. So, financial crises are seen as both fundamentals based and self-fulfilling prophecies-based phenomena. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nikitin, Maxim; Smith, R. Todd</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Backtesting trading risk of commercial banks using expected shortfall</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wong, Woon K.
This paper uses saddlepoint technique to backtest the trading risk of commercial banks using expected shortfall. It is found that four out of six US commercial banks have excessive trading risks. Monte Carlo simulation studies show that the proposed backtest is very accurate and powerful even for small test samples. More importantly, risk managers can carry out the proposed backtest based on any number of exceptions, so that incorrect risk models can be promptly detected before any further huge losses are realized. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wong, Woon K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Legal insider trading and market efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aktas, Nihat; de Bodt, Eric; Van Oppens, Herve
Does legal insider trading contribute to market efficiency? Using refinements proposed in the recent microstructure literature, we analyzed the information content of legal insider trading. We used data on 2110 companies subject to 59,244 aggregated daily insider trades between January 1995 and the end of September 1999. Our main finding is that, even though financial markets do not respond strongly in terms of abnormal returns to insider trading activities, the significant change in price sensitivity to relative order imbalance due to abnormal insider trades reveals that price discovery is hastened on insider trading days. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aktas, Nihat; de Bodt, Eric; Van Oppens, Herve</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial market models with Levy processes and time-varying volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Young Shin; Rachev, Svetlozar T.; Bianchi, Michele Leonardo; Fabozzi, Frank J.
Asset management and pricing models require the proper modeling of the return distribution of financial assets. While the return distribution used in the traditional theories of asset pricing and portfolio selection is the normal distribution, numerous studies that have investigated the empirical behavior of asset returns in financial markets throughout the world reject the hypothesis that asset return distributions are normally distribution. Alternative models for describing return distributions have been proposed since the 1960s, with the strongest empirical and theoretical support being provided for the family of stable distributions (with the normal distribution being a special case of this distribution). Since the turn of the century, specific forms of the stable distribution have been proposed and tested that better fit the observed behavior of historical return distributions. More specifically, subclasses of the tempered stable distribution have been proposed. In this paper, we propose one such subclass of the tempered stable distribution which we refer to as the "KR distribution". We empirically test this distribution as well as two other recently proposed subclasses of the tempered stable distribution: the Carr-Geman-Madan-Yor (CGMY) distribution and the modified tempered stable (MTS) distribution. The advantage of the KR distribution over the other two distributions is that it has more flexible tail parameters. For these three subclasses of the tempered stable distribution, which are infinitely divisible and have exponential moments for some neighborhood of zero, we generate the exponential Levy market models induced from them. We then construct a new GARCH model with the infinitely divisible distributed innovation and three subclasses of that GARCH model that incorporates three observed properties of asset returns: volatility clustering, fat tails, and skewness. We formulate the algorithm to find the risk-neutral return processes for those GARCH models using the "change of measure" for the tempered stable distributions. To compare the performance of those exponential Levy models and the GARCH models, we report the results of the parameters estimated for the S&amp;P 500 index and investigate the out-of-sample forecasting performance for those GARCH models for the S&amp;P 500 option prices. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Young Shin; Rachev, Svetlozar T.; Bianchi, Michele Leonardo; Fabozzi, Frank J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Emerging market exchange rate exposure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chue, Timothy K.; Cook, David
We estimate the exposure of emerging market companies to fluctuations in their domestic exchange rates. We use an instrumental-variable approach that identifies the total exposure of a company to exchange rate movements, yet abstracts from the influence of confounding macroeconomic shocks. In the sub-period of 1999-2002, we find that depreciations tend to have a negative impact on emerging market stock returns. In the sub-period of 2002-2006, this tendency has largely disappeared. Since we estimate the exchange rate exposure of firms from different countries with a common set of instruments, we can make coherent, cross-country comparisons of their determinants. We find that the impact of various measures of debt on exchange rate exposure, which is negative and significant in the early sub-period, becomes insignificant and even reverses sign in the recent sub-period. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chue, Timothy K.; Cook, David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor protection and the value effects of bank merger announcements in Europe and the US</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hagendorff, Jens; Collins, Michael; Keasey, Kevin
Investor protection regimes have been shown to partly explain why the same type of corporate event may attract different investor reactions across countries. We compare the value effects of large bank merger announcements in Europe and the US and find an inverse relationship between the level of investor protection prevalent in the target country and abnormal returns that bidders realize during the announcement period. Accordingly, bidding banks realize higher returns when targeting low protection economies (most European economies) than bidders targeting institutions which operate under a high investor protection regime (the US). We argue that bidding bank shareholders need to be compensated for an increased risk of expropriation by insiders which they face in a low protection environment where takeover markets are illiquid and there are high private benefits of control. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hagendorff, Jens; Collins, Michael; Keasey, Kevin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting foreign exchange rates using idiosyncratic volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, Hui; Savickas, Robert
Average idiosyncratic stock volatility forecasts the bilateral exchange rates of the US dollar against major foreign currencies in and out of sample. The US dollar tends to appreciate after an increase in US idiosyncratic volatility. Similarly, ceteris paribus, German and Japanese idiosyncratic volatilities positively and significantly correlate with future US dollar prices of the Deutsche mark and the Japanese yen, respectively. Our results suggest that exchange rates are predictable. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guo, Hui; Savickas, Robert</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can tax convexity be ignored in corporate financing decisions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarkar, Sudipto
The standard modeling practice in corporate finance has been to assume a linear tax schedule. This paper extends the structural contingent-claim model of corporate finance to incorporate a more realistic convex tax schedule. It is shown that tax convexity raises the optimal default boundary and thus increases the likelihood of default, and also reduces the optimal leverage ratio. While the former effect seems insignificant in general, the effect of tax convexity on the optimal leverage ratio can be quantitatively significant. We conclude that tax convexity should not be ignored in corporate financing decisions, and theoretical models should use a convex tax schedule instead of a linear one. Thus, the short answer to the question in the title is "No". (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sarkar, Sudipto</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is there cyclical bias in bank holding company risk ratings?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Curry, Timothy J.; Fissel, Gary S.; Hanweck, Gerald A.
This paper examines whether bank holding company (BHC) risk ratings are asymmetrically assigned or biased over business cycles from 1986 to 2003. In a model of ratings determination which accounts for bank characteristics, financial market conditions, past supervisory information, and aggregate macro-economic factors, we find that bank exam ratings exhibit inter-temporal characteristics. First, exam ratings exhibit some evidence of examiner bias for several periods analyzed. When the business cycle turns, examiners sometime depart from standards that they set during the previous phases of the cycle. However, this bias is not widespread or systematic. Second, exam ratings exhibit some inertia. Our results suggest that examiners rate on the side of not changing (rather than upgrading or downgrading) an institution's exam rating. Third, we find robust evidence of a secular trend towards more stringent examination BHC ratings standards over time. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Curry, Timothy J.; Fissel, Gary S.; Hanweck, Gerald A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commodity betas with mean reverting output prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Gwangheon; Sarkar, Sudipto
This paper provides a theoretical derivation of commodity beta (stock price sensitivity to commodity price) using a contingent-claim model. The model incorporates operating leverage, financial leverage, costly financial distress, and mean reverting commodity prices; and highlights the important role played by the speed of reversion of the commodity price. It is used to identify theoretically the main determinants of commodity beta. Commodity beta is predicted to be an increasing function of the operating and financial leverage of the firm, and a decreasing function of the company's tax rate and the level, volatility and speed of reversion of the commodity price. Empirical tests with a sample of gold mining firms provide support for these predictions, particularly the new implications of the model (the effect of the commodity price's speed of reversion and the company's tax rate). (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hong, Gwangheon; Sarkar, Sudipto</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The delivery option in credit default swaps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jankowitsch, Rainer; Pullirsch, Rainer; Veza, Tanja
Under standard assumptions the reduced-form credit risk model is not capable of accurately pricing the two fundamental credit risk instruments - bonds and credit default swaps (CDS) - simultaneously. Using a data set of euro-denominated corporate bonds and CDS our paper quantifies this mispricing by calibrating such a model to bond data, and subsequently using it to price CDS, resulting in model CDS spreads up to 50% lower on average than observed in the market. An extended model is presented which includes the delivery option implicit in CDS contracts emerging since a basket of bonds is deliverable in default. By using a constant recovery rate standard models assume equal recoveries for all bonds and hence zero value for the delivery option. Contradicting this common assumption, case studies of Chapter 11 filings presented in the paper show that corporate bonds do not necessarily trade at equal levels following default. Our extension models the implied expected recovery rate of the cheapest-to-deliver bond and, applied to data, largely eliminates the mispricing. Calibrated recovery values lie between 8% and 47% for different obligors, exhibiting strong variation among rating classes and industries. A cross-sectional analysis reveals that the implied recovery parameter depends on proxies for the delivery option, primarily the number of available bonds and bond pricing errors. No evidence is found for a direct influence of the bid-ask spread, notional amount, coupon, or rating used as proxies for bond market liquidity. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jankowitsch, Rainer; Pullirsch, Rainer; Veza, Tanja</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volume and skewness in international equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hutson, Elaine; Kearney, Colm; Lynch, Margaret
We examine the relation between trading volume and skewness in 11 international stock markets using daily and monthly data from January 1980 to August 2004. We construct single equation and VAR models of the relation between the first three moments of market returns and trading volumes. Our results show hitherto unrecognised channels of influence, and support the investor heterogeneity approach to explaining return asymmetries. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hutson, Elaine; Kearney, Colm; Lynch, Margaret</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Flexible inflation targeting and financial stability: Is it enough to stabilize inflation and output?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akram, Q. Farooq; Eitrheim, Oyvind
We investigate empirically whether a central bank can promote financial stability by stabilizing inflation and output, and whether additional stabilization of asset prices and credit growth would enhance financial stability in particular. We employ an econometric model of the Norwegian economy to investigate the performance of simple interest rate rules that allow a response to asset prices and credit growth, in addition to inflation and output. We find that output stabilization tends to improve financial stability. Additional stabilization of house prices, equity prices and/or credit growth enhances stability in both inflation and output, but has mixed effects on financial stability. In general, financial stability as measured by e.g., asset price volatility improves, while financial stability measured by indicators that depend directly on interest rates deteriorates, mainly because of higher interest rate volatility owing to a more active monetary policy. (C) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Akram, Q. Farooq; Eitrheim, Oyvind</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Opacity of young businesses: Evidence from rating disagreements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hyytinen, Ari; Pajarinen, Mika
A conventional wisdom in the contemporary corporate finance literature argues that small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) are informationally opaque. We use data from two credit information companies and in particular their disagreements over the creditworthiness of SMEs to study the empirical relevance of this often invoked assumption. Our panel data analysis shows that once unobserved firm-effects are controlled for, the disagreements (i.e., rating splits) are inversely related to the age of firms. We are not able to document such a robust relationship between the disagreements and the size of firms. This finding holds a lesson for empirical corporate finance researchers who need firm-level proxies for informational imperfections and asymmetries: of the two often-used proxies, firm size is not as closely related to informational opacity as firm age is. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hyytinen, Ari; Pajarinen, Mika</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information shares in the US treasury market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mizrach, Bruce; Neely, Christopher J.
This paper highlights the previously neglected role of the futures markets in US Treasury price discovery. The estimates of 5- and 10-year GovPX spot market information shares typically fail to reach 50% from 1999 on. The GovPX information shares for the 2-year contract are higher than those of the 5- and 10-year maturities but also decline after 1998. Relative bid-ask spreads, number of trades, and realized volatility are statistically significant and explain up to 21% of daily information shares. In roughly 1/4 of cases when public information is released, the futures market gains information share, but macroeconomic announcements rarely explain information shares independently of liquidity. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mizrach, Bruce; Neely, Christopher J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of corporate cash holdings: Evidence from spin-offs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>D'Mello, Ranjan; Krishnaswami, Sudha; Larkin, Patrick J.
We study the factors that influence the cash allocation decision around a spin-off, using variables suggested by the trade-off theory, and controlling for the possible endogeneity of leverage and cash ratios. Spin-offs provide an opportunity to examine the determinants of cash allocation at the margin at the time of creation of a new entity. Our results indicate that managers allocate higher cash ratios to smaller firms, and firms with high research and development expense ratio, low net working capital ratio, and low leverage. Thus, higher cash ratios are correlated with difficulty of raising external capital and reduced availability of cash from internal sources. In addition, managers also base the cash allocation on observable immediate growth opportunities instead of on long-term possible growth. An analysis of excess cash ratios, defined as the difference between the actual and predicted cash ratios, indicate that firms are, on average, allocated less cash than suggested by trade-off models, and this deviation in allocated cash from predicted levels is explained only by concurrent profitability of the firms (a pecking order theory implication). (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>D'Mello, Ranjan; Krishnaswami, Sudha; Larkin, Patrick J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Implicit recourse and credit card securitizations: What do fraud losses reveal?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vermilyea, Todd A.; Webb, Elizabeth R.; Kish, Andrew A.
In this paper, we develop and test a model of implicit recourse in asset-backed securitizations. Fraud losses on securitized assets are generally incurred by the bank and do not affect the performance of securitization trusts, while credit losses do affect the trust's performance and are potentially borne by the owner of the securitized assets. Thus, the classification of losses as either fraud or credit losses provides a potential avenue of implicit recourse to manipulate the performance of securitization trusts. Using annual data from 2001 to 2006, we find that the performance of the credit card securitization portfolio is negatively related to fraud losses reported by the bank. We examine these results in light of the proposed Basel II capital rules and argue that a bank's incentive to provide implicit recourse will increase under the anticipated regime. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vermilyea, Todd A.; Webb, Elizabeth R.; Kish, Andrew A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A comparison of MAD and CVaR models with real features</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Angelelli, Enrico; Mansini, Renata; Speranza, M. Grazia
In this paper we consider two different mixed integer linear programming models for solving the single period portfolio selection problem when integer stock units, transaction costs and a cardinality constraint are taken into account. The first model has been formulated by using the maximization of the worst conditional expectation as objective function. The second model is based on the maximization of the safety measure corresponding to the mean absolute deviation. Extensive computational results are provided to compare the financial characteristics of the optimal portfolios selected by the two models on real data from European stock exchange markets. Some simple heuristics are also introduced that provide efficient and effective solutions when an optimal integer solution cannot be found in a reasonable amount of time. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Angelelli, Enrico; Mansini, Renata; Speranza, M. Grazia</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk aversion and skewness preference</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Post, Thierry; van Vliet, Pim; Levy, Haim
Empirically, co-skewness of asset returns seems to explain a substantial part of the cross-sectional variation of mean return not explained by beta. This finding is typically interpreted in terms of a risk averse representative investor with a cubic utility function. This paper questions this interpretation. We show that the empirical tests fail to impose risk aversion and the implied utility function takes an inverse S-shape. Unfortunately, the first-order conditions are not sufficient to guarantee that the market portfolio is the global maximum for this utility function, and our results suggest that the market portfolio is more likely to represent the global minimum. In addition, if we do impose risk aversion, then co-skewness has minimal explanatory power. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Post, Thierry; van Vliet, Pim; Levy, Haim</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Francesco Paris, the power of the will</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Szego, Giorgio
nan</description><author>Szego, Giorgio</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reference point formation by market investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kliger, Doron; Kudryavtsev, Andrey
The disposition effect [Shefrin, H., Statman M., 1985, The disposition to sell winners too early and ride losers too long. Journal of Finance. 40. 777-790], investors' tendency to sell gaining assets and hold on to loosing assets, relies on the notion of a reference point distinguishing between losses and gains. While literature using aggregated market data documented the existence of such a reference point affecting investors' decisions. it had not pinpointed it. The main goal Of our work is to shed light on the mechanism of reference point formation. We hypothesize that salient events taking place during a stock's holding period influence investors' perceptions and make them Update the stock's reference point. Using analysts' earnings forecasts, stock price data, and firms' quarterly earnings announcements, we document that company-specific events indeed affect the reference points. We discover that the earnings announcements played a role in reference point formation when they were not anticipated, i.e.. when (i) analysts' earnings forecasts failed to provide accurate predictions; and (ii) the earnings announcements were followed by market price reactions. Moreover, the reference points were affected more profoundly for low market capitalization, high beta firms. pointing that the reference point updating process is more reactive to events when information flow is low and prices are sensitive to market fluctuations. Our results also corroborate the attention hypothesis, i.e., the observation that agents facing numerous alternatives may consider primarily those that have caught their attention. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kliger, Doron; Kudryavtsev, Andrey</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Weather and intraday patterns in stock returns and trading activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Shao-Chi; Chen, Sheng-Syan; Chou, Robin K.; Lin, Yueh-Hsiang
We examine the relation between weather in New York City and intraday returns and trading patterns of NYSE stocks. While stock returns arc found to be generally lower on cloudier days, cloud cover has a significant influence on stock returns only M the market open. There arc significantly more seller-initiated trades when there is more cloud cover at the market open. which is consistent with the return results. Cloudy skies arc associated with higher volatility and less market depth over the entire trading day. Finally. Cloud cover is not significantly correlated with spread measures and turnover ratios. The findings overall suggest that weather has a significant influence oil investors' intraday trading behavior. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Shao-Chi; Chen, Sheng-Syan; Chou, Robin K.; Lin, Yueh-Hsiang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can subordinated debt constrain banks' risk taking?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Niu, Jijun
This paper presents a model in which requiring banks to issue a proper amount of subordinated debt can constrain their risk taking both before and after debt issuance. The main idea is that the prospect of issuing debt motivates banks to invest in safe assets before debt issuance; holding such assets then constrains their risk taking after debt issuance. The model helps understand the existing empirical findings, and offers a new testable prediction. It also suggests that: (1) regulators should set the amount of subordinated debt within a range; and (2) subordinated debt cannot entirely substitute for equity capital. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Niu, Jijun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversification and ownership concentration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parigi, Bruno M.; Pelizzon, Loriana
If controlling shareholders can divert profits, equity ownership is more concentrated the higher the stock returns correlation. A higher returns correlation reduces the benefits of diversification, giving rise to both a higher investment by the controlling shareholder in the asset that he controls and a lower investment by the non-controlling shareholders. The empirical analysis supports the predictions of the model: equity ownership is more concentrated in countries where the stock returns correlation is higher; moreover the intensity of the relationship between the stock returns correlation and ownership concentration is amplified by poor investor protection. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Parigi, Bruno M.; Pelizzon, Loriana</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effective fair pricing of international mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chua, Choong Tze; Lai, Sandy; Wu, Yangru
We propose a new methodology to provide fair prices of international mutual funds by adjusting prices at the individual security level using a comprehensive and economically relevant information set. Stepwise regressions are used to endogenously determine the stock-specific optimal set of factors. Using 16 synthetic funds whose characteristics are extracted from 16 corresponding actual US-based Japanese mutual funds, we demonstrate that our method estimates fund prices significantly more accurately than existing methods. Although existing fair-pricing methods provide an improvement over the current practice of simply using Japanese market closing prices. they are still highly vulnerable to exploitation by market-timers. By contrast, our method is the most successful in preventing such strategic exploitation since no competing method can profit from our stated prices. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chua, Choong Tze; Lai, Sandy; Wu, Yangru</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inflation-indexed swaps and swaptions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hinnerich, Mia
This article considers the pricing and hedging of inflation-indexed swaps, and the pricing of inflation-indexed swaptions, and options on inflation-indexed bonds. To price the inflation-indexed swaps, we suggest an extended HJM model. The model allows both the forward rates and the consumer price index to be driven, not only by a standard Multidimensional Wiener process but also by I general marked point process. Our model is an extension of the HJM approach proposed by Jarrow and Yildirim [Jarrow, R., Yildirim Y., 2003. Pricing treasury inflation protected securities and related derivatives using an HJM model. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 38. 409-430] and later also used by Mercurio [Mercurio. F., 2005. Pricing inflation-indexed derivatives. Quantitative Finance 5 (3), 289-302] to price inflation-indexed swaps. Furthermore we price options on so called TIPS-bonds assuming the model is purely Wiener driven. We then introduce all inflation swap market model to price inflation-indexed swaptions. All prices derived have explicit closed-form solutions. Furthermore. we formally prove the validity of the so called foreign-currency analogy (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hinnerich, Mia</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial services in an increasingly integrated global financial market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
This paper discusses aspects of global financial services. As part of financial globalisation, financial institutions have evolved both nationally and internationally. FDI is becoming an important vehicle for multinational banks to enter developing countries. This in turn is changing the composition of trade in financial services. The experience of regional integration in Europe and the emergence of large multinational European banks signal a new era of global competition and consolidation of financial institutions. Home bias in international financial services is much less where financial integration is taking place. With financial globalisation, one should expect more diversification of ownership of multinational banks around the world, particularly when China and India are now able to have strategic investment in some of the key investment banks around the world. Financial globalisation requires stronger and more effective international institutions as a way of monitoring the activities of multinational financial institutions at both the national and international levels. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Financial Services, Capital Markets and Financial Globalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
nan</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Two-sided coherent risk measures and their application in realistic portfolio optimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Zhiping; Wang, Yi
By using a different derivation scheme, a new class of two-sided coherent risk measures is constructed in this paper. Different from existing coherent risk measures, both positive and negative deviations from the expected return are considered in the new measure Simultaneously but differently. This innovation makes it easy to reasonably describe and control the asymmetry and fat-tail characteristics of the loss distribution and to properly reflect the investor's risk attitude. With its easy Computation of the new Fisk measure, a realistic portfolio selection model is established by taking into account typical market frictions such as taxes, transaction costs, and value constraints. Empirical results demonstrate that our new portfolio selection model can not only Suitably reflect the impact of different trading constraints, but find more robust optimal portfolios, which are better than the optimal portfolio obtained under the conditional value-at-risk measure in terms of diversification and typical performance ratios. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Zhiping; Wang, Yi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The stocks at stake: Return and risk in socially responsible investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Galema, Rients; Plantinga, Auke; Scholtens, Bert
We relate US portfolio returns, book-to-market values and excess stock returns to different dimensions of socially responsible performance. We find that socially responsible investing (SRI) impacts on stock returns by lowering the book-to-market ratio and not by generating positive alphas. Our result is consistent with the theoretical work suggesting that SRI is reflected in demand differences between SRI and non-SRI stock. It also explains why so few studies are able to establish a link between alpha's and SRI. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Galema, Rients; Plantinga, Auke; Scholtens, Bert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Controlling-minority shareholder incentive conflicts and directors' and officers' liability insurance: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zou, Hong; Wong, Sonia; Shum, Clement; Xiong, Jun; Yan, Jun
This paper examines the demand for directors' and officers' liability insurance (D&amp;O insurance) by Chinese listed companies where controlling-minority shareholder incentive conflicts are acute due to the concentrated and split ownership structure. We hypothesize and find evidence that the incidence of seeking D&amp;O insurance is positively related to the extent of controlling-minority shareholder incentive conflicts - a finding not previously documented in the literature. Using an event study, we find that the announcements of D&amp;O insurance decisions in firms that engage in earnings management, and/or are controlled by a local government (such firms tend to have stronger incentives to tunnel), seem to have a negative wealth effect. In addition, the incidence of the D&amp;O insurance decision is positively related to the proportion of independent directors and several litigation risk proxies. Therefore, the breakthrough in corporate governance and judicial reforms has created non-negligible perceived securities litigation risks in China. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Zou, Hong; Wong, Sonia; Shum, Clement; Xiong, Jun; Yan, Jun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate restructuring in Japan: Who monitors the monitor?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Inoue, Kotaro; Kato, Hideaki Kiyoshi; Bremer, Marc
Peek and Rosengren [Peek, J., Rosengren, E., 2005. Unnatural selection: Perverse incentives and the misallocation of credit in Japan. American Economic Review 95, 1144-1166] showed that, when the bubble economy era ended, regulatory forbearance and perverse incentives allowed Japanese banks to engage extensively in evergreening. This is the first comprehensive study to empirically analyze the economics of private debt restructurings of financially distressed companies in Japan, where the corporate monitoring mechanism is not market based but large-stakeholder based - typically, banks and affiliated companies. These stakeholders are expected to efficiently resolve potential bankruptcy or collapse with better information resulting from long-term relationships with the distressed firms. Our study, however, finds that private restructurings led by them failed because of delays in implementing fundamental solutions. Forbearance in addressing the needs of distressed firms demonstrates the weakness of such stakeholders in instituting discipline, hence the need for a system to "monitor the monitor". (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Inoue, Kotaro; Kato, Hideaki Kiyoshi; Bremer, Marc</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A first-passage-time model under regime-switching market environment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Mi Ae; Jang, Bong-Gyu; Lee, Ho-Seok
In this paper, we Suggest a first-passage-time model which can explain default probability and default correlation dynamics under stochastic market environment. We add a Markov regime-switching market condition to the first-passage-time model of Zhou [Zhou, C., 2001. An analysis of default correlations and Multiple defaults. Review of Financial Studies 14, 555-576]. Using this model, we try to explain various relationship between default probability, default correlation, and market condition. We also suggest a valuation method for credit default swap (CDS) with (or without) counterparty default Fisk (CDR) and basket default swap under this model. Our numerical results provide us with several meaningful implications. First, default swap spread is higher in economic recession than in economic expansion across default swap maturity. Second, as the difference of asset return volatility between under bear market and under bull market increases, CDS spread increases regardless of maturity. Third, the bigger the intensity shifting from bull market to bear market, the higher the spread for both CDS without CDR and basket default swap. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Mi Ae; Jang, Bong-Gyu; Lee, Ho-Seok</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic cycles and the stock market's reaction to monetary policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basistha, Arabinda; Kurov, Alexander
This paper examines cyclical variation in the effect of Fed policy on the stock market. We find a much stronger response of stock returns to unexpected changes in the federal funds target rate in recession and in tight credit market conditions. Using firm-level data, we also show that firms that face financial constraints are more affected by monetary shocks in tight credit conditions than the relatively unconstrained firms. Overall, the results are consistent with the credit channel of monetary policy transmission. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Basistha, Arabinda; Kurov, Alexander</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of yield spread dynamics: Euro versus US dollar corporate bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Van Landschoot, Astrid
This paper presents a systematic comparison between the determinants of euro and US dollar yield spread dynamics. The results show that US dollar yield spreads are significantly more affected by changes in the level and the slope of the default-free term structure and the stock market return and volatility. Surprisingly, euro yield spreads are strongly affected by the US (and not the euro) level and slope. This confirms the dominance of US interest rates in the corporate bond markets. Interestingly, I find that liquidity risk is higher for US dollar corporate bonds than euro corporate bonds. For both regions, the effect of changes in the bid-ask spread is mainly significant during periods of high liquidity risk. Finally, the results indicate that the credit cycle as measured by the region-specific default probability significantly increases US yield spreads. This is not the case for euro yield spreads. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Van Landschoot, Astrid</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Combining fair pricing and capital requirements for non-life insurance companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gatzert, Nadine; Schmeiser, Hato
The aim of this article is to identify fair equity-premium combinations for non-life insurers that satisfy solvency capital requirements imposed by regulatory authorities. In particular, we compare target capital derived using the value at risk concept as planned for Solvency II in the European Union with the tail value at risk concept as required by the Swiss Solvency Test. The model framework uses Merton's Jump-diffusion process for the market value of liabilities and a geometric Brownian motion for the asset process: fair valuation is conducted using option pricing theory. We show that even if regulatory requirements are satisfied under different risk measures and parameterizations, the associated costs of insolvency - measured with the insurer's default put option value - can differ substantially. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gatzert, Nadine; Schmeiser, Hato</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity in auction and specialist market structures: Evidence from the Italian bourse</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frino, Alex; Gerace, Dionigi; Lepone, Andrew
Several studies find that bid-ask spreads for stocks listed on the NYSE are lower than for stocks listed on NASDAQ. While this suggests that specialist market structures provide greater liquidity than competing dealer markets, the nature of trading on the NYSE, which comprises a specialist competing with limit order flow, obfuscates the comparison. In 2001, a structural change was implemented on the Italian Bourse. Many stocks that traded in an auction market switched to a specialist market, where the specialist controls order flow. Results confirm that liquidity is significantly improved when stocks commence trading in the specialist market. Analysis of the components of the bid-ask spread reveal that the adverse selection component of the spread is significantly reduced. This evidence Suggests that specialist market structures provide greater liquidity to market participants. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Frino, Alex; Gerace, Dionigi; Lepone, Andrew</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance in banking: The role of the board of directors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Andres, Pablo; Vallelado, Eleuterio
We use a sample of large international commercial banks to test hypotheses on the dual role of boards of directors. We use a suitable econometric model (two step system estimator) to solve the well-known endogeneity problem in corporate governance literature, and demonstrate the empirical and theoretical superiority of system estimator over OLS and within estimators. We find an inverted U-shaped relation between bank performance and board size, and between the proportion of non-executive directors and performance. Our results show that bank board composition and size are related to directors' ability to monitor and advise management, and that larger and not excessively independent boards might prove more efficient in monitoring and advising functions, and create more value. All of these relations hold after we control for the measure of performance, the weight of the banking industry in each country, bank ownership, and regulatory and institutional differences. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>de Andres, Pablo; Vallelado, Eleuterio</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit derivatives and loan pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Norden, Lars; Wagner, Wolf
This paper examines the relation between the new markets for credit default swaps (CIDS) and banks' pricing of syndicated loans to US corporates. We find that changes in CDS spreads have a significantly positive coefficient and explain about 25% of subsequent monthly changes in aggregate loan spreads during 2000-2005. Moreover, when compared to traditional explanatory factors, they turn out to be the dominant determinant of loan spreads. In particular, they explain loan rates much better than same rated bonds. This suggests that CDS prices contain, beyond general credit risk. to a substantial extent information relevant for bank lending. We also find that, over time, new information from CDs markets is faster incorporated into loans, but information from other markets is not. Overall, our results indicate that the markets for CDS have gained an important role for banks. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Norden, Lars; Wagner, Wolf</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>WTI crude oil Futures in portfolio diversification: The time-to-maturity effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Geman, Helyette; Kharoubi, Cecile
The aim of the paper is to analyze the diversification effect brought by crude oil Futures contracts, the most liquid commodity Futures, into a portfolio of stocks. The studies that have documented the very low- and essentially negative-correlations between commodities and equities typically rely on normally distributed returns, which is not the case for crude oil Futures and stocks indexes. Moreover, the particular time-to-maturity chosen for the Future Contract used as an investment vehicle is an important matter that needs to be addressed, in presence of forward curves switching between backwardation and contango shapes. Our goal in this paper is twofold: (a) we introduce Copula functions to have a better representation of the dependence structure of oil Futures with equity indexes: (b) using this copula representation, we are able to analyze in a precise manner the "maturity effect" in the choice of crude oil Future contract with respect to its diversification benefits. Our finding is that, in the case of distant maturities Futures, e.g., 18 months, the negative correlation effect is more pronounced whether stock prices increase or decrease. This property has the merit to avoid the hurdles of a frequent roll over while being quite desirable in the current trendless equity markets. Empirical evidence is exhibited on a database comprising the NYMEX WTI crude oil Futures and S&amp;P 500 index over a 15 year-time period. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Geman, Helyette; Kharoubi, Cecile</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Computing the market price of volatility risk in the energy commodity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doran, James S.; Ronn, Ehud I.
In this paper, we demonstrate the need for a negative market price of volatility risk to recover the difference between Black-Scholes [Black, F., Scholes, M., 1973. The pricing of options and corporate liabilities. journal of Political Economy 81, 637-654]/Black [Black, F., 1976. Studies of stock price volatility changes. In: Proceedings of the 1976 Meetings of the Business and Economics Statistics Section, American Statistical Association, pp. 177-181] implied volatility and realized-term volatility. Initially, using quasi-Monte Carlo simulation, we demonstrate numerically that a negative market price of volatility risk is the key risk premium in explaining the disparity between risk-neutral and statistical volatility in both equity and commodity-energy markets. This is robust to multiple specifications that also incorporate jumps. Next, using futures and options data from natural gas, heating oil and crude oil contracts over a 10 year period, we estimate the volatility risk premium and demonstrate that the premium is negative and significant for all three commodities. Additionally, there appear distinct seasonality patterns for natural gas and heating oil, where winter/withdrawal months have higher volatility risk premiums. Computing such a negative market price of volatility risk highlights the importance of volatility risk in understanding priced volatility in these financial markets. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Doran, James S.; Ronn, Ehud I.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long term spread option valuation and hedging</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dempster, M. A. H.; Medova, Elena; Tang, Ke
This paper investigates the valuation and hedging of spread options on two commodity prices which in the long run are in dynamic equilibrium (i.e., cointegrated). The spread exhibits properties different from its two underlying commodity prices and should therefore be modelled directly. This approach offers significant advantages relative to the traditional two price methods since the correlation between two asset returns is notoriously hard to model. In this paper, we propose a two factor model for the spot spread and develop pricing and hedging formulae for options on spot and futures spreads. Two examples of spreads in energy markets - the crack spread between heating oil and WTI crude oil and the location spread between Brent blend and WTI crude oil - are analyzed to illustrate the results. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dempster, M. A. H.; Medova, Elena; Tang, Ke</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The price of power: The valuation of power and weather derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pirrong, Craig; Jermakyan, Martin
Pricing contingent claims on power presents numerous challenges due to (1) the unique behavior of power prices, and (2) time-dependent variations in prices. We propose and implement a model in which the spot price of power is a function of two state variables: demand (load) and fuel price. in this model, any power derivative price must satisfy a PDE with boundary conditions that reflect capacity limits and the non-linear relation between load and the spot price of power. Moreover, since power is non-storable and demand is not a traded asset, the power derivative price embeds a market price of risk. Using inverse problem techniques and power forward prices from the PJM market, we solve for this market price of risk function. During 1999-2001, the upward bias in the forward price was as large as $50/MWh for some days in July. By 2005, the largest estimated upward bias had fallen to $19/MWh. These large biases are plausibly due to the extreme right skewness of power prices: this induces left skewness in the payoff to short forward positions, and a large risk premium is required to induce traders to sell power forwards. This risk premium suggests that the power market is not fully integrated with the broader financial markets. (C) 2008 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Pirrong, Craig; Jermakyan, Martin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spot price modeling and the valuation of electricity forward contracts: The role of demand and capacity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cartea, Alvaro; Villaplana, Pablo
We propose a model where wholesale electricity prices are explained by two state variables: demand and capacity. We derive analytical expressions to price forward contracts and to calculate the forward premium. We apply our model to the PJM, England and Wales, and Nord Pool markets. Our empirical findings indicate that volatility of demand is seasonal and that the market price of demand risk is also seasonal and positive, both of which exert an upward (seasonal) pressure on the price of forward contracts. We assume that both volatility of capacity and the market price of capacity risk are constant and find that, depending on the market and period under study, it could either exert an upward or downward pressure on forward prices. In all markets we find that the forward premium exhibits a seasonal pattern. During the months of high volatility of demand, forward contracts trade at a premium. During months of low volatility of demand, forwards can either trade at a relatively small premium or, even in some cases, at a discount, i.e. they exhibit a negative forward premium. (C) 2008 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Cartea, Alvaro; Villaplana, Pablo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Special Section: Commodities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Geman, Helyette
nan</description><author>Geman, Helyette</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dynamics of operational loss clustering</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernobai, Anna; Yildirim, Yidiray
This paper investigates the characteristics of the operational loss data formation mechanism that takes place between the date of discovery of a new operational risk event and the final settlement date on which all losses are materialized. The first loss that characterizes the initial impact of a new operational risk event frequently triggers a sequence of related losses. Then, losses generated by the same event are not independent and follow a predictable scheme and the frequency of secondary losses is not homogeneous: both are functions of the initial loss amount and time. We model the arrival intensity and loss severities with a shot-noise stochastic process and derive its key properties. We then discuss implications Of Our model for the estimation of the regulatory capital charge for operational risk. In an empirical analysis, we find strong evidence of a shot-noise behavior in operational losses using the data of a major US commercial bank. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chernobai, Anna; Yildirim, Yidiray</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exploring the nexus between banking sector reform and performance: Evidence from newly acceded EU countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brissimis, Sophocles N.; Delis, Manthos D.; Papanikolaou, Nikolaos I.
The aim of this study is to examine the relationship between banking sector reform and bank performance - measured in terms of efficiency, total factor productivity growth and net interest margin accounting for the effects through competition and bank risk-taking. To this end, we develop an empirical model of bank performance, which is consistently estimated using recent econometric techniques. The model is applied to bank panel data from ten newly acceded EU countries. The results indicate that both banking sector reform and competition exert a positive impact on bank efficiency, while the effect of reform on total factor productivity growth is significant only toward the end of the reform process. Finally, the effect of capital and credit risk on bank performance is in most cases negative, while it seems that higher liquid assets reduce the efficiency and productivity of banks. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brissimis, Sophocles N.; Delis, Manthos D.; Papanikolaou, Nikolaos I.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank concentration and financial constraints on firm-level investment in Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ratti, Ronald A.; Lee, Sunglyong; Seol, Youn
This study examines the effect of bank concentration on financing constraints of non-financial firms in 14 European countries between 1992 and 2005. Using firm-level data we analyze financial constraints with the Euler equation derived from the dynamic investment model. We find that with a highly concentrated banking sector firms are less financially constrained. This result is robust to consideration of firm opacity, firm size, and business cycle. Relaxation of financial constraint while greater for firms in less opaque industries also accrues for firms in more opaque industries. Greater bank concentration is associated with less tight financial constraint during both expansions and recessions. Results overall are consistent with an information-based hypothesis that more market power increases banks' incentives to produce information on potential borrowers. Findings are robust to consideration of country specific institutional factors. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ratti, Ronald A.; Lee, Sunglyong; Seol, Youn</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loan pricing under Basel II in an imperfectly competitive banking market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ruthenberg, David; Landskroner, Yoram
The new Basel II Accord (2006), established new and revised capital requirements for banks. In this paper we analyze and estimate the possible effects of the new rules on the pricing of bank loans. We relate to the two approaches for capital requirements (internal and standardized) and distinguish between retail and corporate customers. Our loan-equation is based on a model of a banking firm facing uncertainty operating in an imperfectly competitive loan market. We use Israeli economic data and data of a leading Israeli bank. The main results indicate that high quality corporate and retail customers will enjoy a reduction in loan interest rates in (big) banks which, most probably, will adopt the IRB approach. On the other hand high risk Customers will benefit by shifting to (small) banks that adopt the standardized approach. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ruthenberg, David; Landskroner, Yoram</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does corporate international diversification destroy value? Evidence from cross-border mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dos Santos, Marcelo B.; Errunza, Vihang R.; Miller, Darius P.
This paper investigates the valuation effects of corporate international diversification by examining cross-border mergers and acquisitions of US acquirers over the period 1990-2000. We find that, on average, acquisitions of "fairly valued" foreign business units do not lead to value discounts. In contrast, unrelated cross-border acquisitions result in a significant diversification discount of about 24% after accounting for the valuation of foreign targets. Furthermore, significant wealth gains accrue to foreign target shareholders regardless of the type of acquisition. Overall, our results suggest that international diversification does not destroy value while industrial diversification leads to discounts even after controlling for the pre-acquisition value of the target. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dos Santos, Marcelo B.; Errunza, Vihang R.; Miller, Darius P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Individual stock-option prices and credit spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, Martijn; Driessen, Joost; Maenhout, Pascal; Weinbaum, David
This paper introduces measures of volatility and jump risk that are based on individual stock options to explain credit spreads on corporate bonds. Implied volatilities of individual options are shown to contain useful information for credit spreads and improve on historical volatilities when explaining the cross-sectional and time-series variation in a panel of corporate bond spreads. Both the level of individual implied volatilities and (to a lesser extent) the implied-volatility skew matter for credit spreads. Detailed principal component analysis shows that a large part of the time-series variation in credit spreads can be explained, in this way. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cremers, Martijn; Driessen, Joost; Maenhout, Pascal; Weinbaum, David</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of no-arbitrage on forecasting: Lessons from a parametric term structure model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, Caio; Vicente, Jose
Parametric term structure models have been successfully applied to numerous problems in fixed income markets, including pricing, hedging, managing risk, as well as to the study of monetary policy implications. In turn, dynamic term structure models, equipped with stronger economic structure, have been mainly adopted to price derivatives and explain empirical stylized facts. In this paper, we combine flavors of those two classes of models to test whether no-arbitrage affects forecasting. We construct cross-sectional (allowing arbitrages) and arbitrage-free versions of a parametric polynomial model to analyze how well they predict out-of-sample interest rates. Based oil US Treasury yield data, we find that no-arbitrage restrictions significantly improve forecasts. Arbitrage-free versions achieve overall smaller biases and root mean square errors for most maturities and forecasting horizons. Furthermore, a decomposition of forecasts into forward-rates and holding return premia indicates that the superior performance of no-arbitrage versions is due to a better identification of bond risk premium. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Almeida, Caio; Vicente, Jose</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The expansion of services in European banking: Implications for loan pricing and interest margins</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lepetit, Laetitia; Nys, Emmanuelle; Rous, Philippe; Tarazi, Amine
Our study of 602 European banks over 1996-2002 investigates how the banks' expansion into fee-based services has affected their interest margins and loan pricing. We find that higher income share from commissions and fees is associated with lower margins and loan spreads. The higher the commission and fee income share, moreover, the weaker the link between bank loan spreads and loan risk. The latter result is consistent with the conjecture that banks price (or misprice) loans to increase sales of other services. That loss leader (or cross selling) hypothesis has implications for bank regulation and competition with (non-bank) lenders. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lepetit, Laetitia; Nys, Emmanuelle; Rous, Philippe; Tarazi, Amine</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The contribution of product mix versus efficiency and technical change in US banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asaftei, Gabriel
Similar to a Du Pont analysis, this paper divides the changes in returns on assets of US commercial banks for the period from 2000 to 2005 into conventional measures of bank performance. The contribution of product mix is significant and offsets losses from technical change and operating efficiency. Banks respond to changes in the business environment by switching towards more luerative traditional and nontraditional products. Large banks are found to benefit more than community banks from the switch to an optimal output portfolio mix including new products spawned by recent financial innovations and deregulation. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Asaftei, Gabriel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Characteristics determining the efficiency of foreign banks in Australia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Strum, Jan-Egbert; Williams, Barry
The factors determining foreign bank efficiency are investigated using a three stage research method. It is found that host market incumbency reduces efficiency of foreign banks in Australia, resulting in over use of inputs. Factors underlying the limited global advantage hypothesis of Berger et al. [Berger, Allen N., DeYoung, Robert, Genay, Hesna, Udell, Gregory F., 2000. Globalisation of financial institutions: Evidence from cross-border banking performance. Brookings-Wharton Papers on Financial Service 3, 23-120] are identified, in that nationality specific factors represented by dummy variables are not significant once other relevant effects are controlled for. Parent profitability is not found to result in increased host nation efficiency, while parent credit rating effects are mixed. Some evidence is presented that banks from more financially sophisticated nations are more efficient. The implications of these results are explored from the perspectives of bank management and bank regulators. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Strum, Jan-Egbert; Williams, Barry</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The optimal structure of PD buckets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krink, Thierno; Paterlini, Sandra; Resti, Andrea
In designing credit rating systems under the new Basel Accord, considerable effort has been devoted to rating assignment and quantification, while the choice of the optimal bucket structure has received less attention. To fill this gap, we propose two "bucketing" strategies based on constrained optimisation, paying attention to the implications of rating buckets for loan-pricing and adverse selection phenomena. We compare them with some more naive approaches, based on a sample of about 100,000 European companies. We also analyse the persistence of our performance measures over time, as well as the effect of large exposures being associated with low-PD obligors. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Krink, Thierno; Paterlini, Sandra; Resti, Andrea</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bayesian inference for issuer heterogeneity in credit ratings migration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kadam, Ashay; Lenk, Peter
Rating transition matrices for corporate bond issuers are often based on fitting a discrete time Markov chain model to homogeneous cohorts. Literature has documented that rating migration matrices can differ considerably depending on the characteristics of the issuers in the pool used for estimation. However, it is also well known in the literature that a continuous time Markov chain gives statistically superior estimates of the rating migration process. It remains to verify and quantify the issuer heterogeneity in rating migration behavior using a continuous time Markov chain. We fill this gap in the literature. We provide Bayesian estimates to mitigate the problem of data sparsity. Default data, especially when narrowing down to issuers with specific characteristics, can be highly sparse. Using classical estimation tools in such a situation can result in large estimation errors. Hence we adopt Bayesian estimation techniques. We apply them to the Moodys corporate bond default database. Our results indicate strong country and industry effects on the determination of rating migration behavior. Using the CreditRisk+ framework, and a sample credit portfolio, we show that ignoring issuer heterogeneity can give erroneous estimates of Value-at-Risk and a misleading picture of the risk capital. This insight is consistent with some recent findings in the literature. Therefore, given the upcoming Basel II implementation, understanding issuer heterogeneity has important policy implications. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kadam, Ashay; Lenk, Peter</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A behavioral explanation for the negative asymmetric return-volatility relation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hibbert, Ann Marie; Daigler, Robert T.; Dupoyet, Brice
We examine the short-term dynamic relation between the S&amp;P 500 (Nasdaq 100) index return and changes in implied volatility at both the daily and intraday level. Neither the leverage hypothesis nor the volatility feedback hypothesis adequately explains the results. Alternatively, we propose that the behavior of traders (from the representativeness, affect, and extrapolation bias concepts of behavioral finance) is consistent with our empirical results of a strong daily and intraday negative return-implied volatility relation. Moreover, both the presence and magnitude of the negative relation and the asymmetry between return and implied volatility are most closely associated with extreme changes in the index returns. We also show that the strength of the relation is consistent with the implied volatility skew. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hibbert, Ann Marie; Daigler, Robert T.; Dupoyet, Brice</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market quality changes in the London Stock Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chelley-Steeley, Patricia L.
This paper examines the impact that the introduction of a closing call auction had on market quality at the London Stock Exchange. Using estimates from the partial adjustment with noise model of Amihud and Mendelson [Amihud, Y., Mendelson, H., 1987. Trading mechanisms and stock returns: An empirical investigation. Journal of Finance 42, 533-553] we show that opening and closing market quality improved for participating stocks. When we stratify our sample securities into five groups based on trading activity we find that the least active securities experience the greatest improvements to market quality. A control sample of stocks are not characterized by discernable changes to market quality. (C) 2008 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Chelley-Steeley, Patricia L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank shareholding and lending: Complementarity or substitution? Some evidence from a panel of large Italian firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barucci, Emilio; Mattesini, Fabrizio
The paper studies the motivations behind banks' shareholding of non-financial firms using a panel of large Italian companies in the period 1994-2000. Empirical evidence shows that banks are shareholders of companies that are less profitable, have experienced slower growth, are more indebted, are endowed with collateral and have hard time to repay their debt out of current income. Banks arc more likely to hold shares in companies they lend to. Overall the evidence suggests that there is complementarity between bank equity holding and lending. A plausible explanation is the shareholder-debtholder conflict, the evidence is weakly compatible with governance and information hypotheses. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barucci, Emilio; Mattesini, Fabrizio</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Developing a stress testing framework based on market risk models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, Carol; Sheedy, Elizabeth
The Basel 2 Accord requires regulatory capital to cover stress tests, yet no coherent and objective framework for stress testing portfolios exists. We propose a new methodology for stress testing in the context of market risk models that can incorporate both volatility clustering and heavy tails. Empirical results compare the performance of eight risk models with four possible conditional and unconditional return distributions over different rolling estimation periods. When applied to major currency pairs using daily data spanning more than 20 years we find that stress test results should have little impact on current levels of foreign exchange regulatory capital. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alexander, Carol; Sheedy, Elizabeth</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does the call market method affect price efficiency? Evidence from the Singapore Stock Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Rosita P.; Rhee, S. Ghon; Stone, Gregory R.; Tang, Ning
On August 21, 2000, the Singapore Exchange (SGX) adopted the call market method to open and close the market while the remainder of the day's trading continued to rely on the continuous auction method. The call method significantly improved the price discovery process and market quality. A positive spillover effect is observed from the opening and closing calls. Day-end price manipulation also declined after the introduction of the call market method. However, the beneficial impact from the call market method is asymmetric, benefiting liquid stocks more than illiquid stocks. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Rosita P.; Rhee, S. Ghon; Stone, Gregory R.; Tang, Ning</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial distress, corporate control, and management turnover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jostarridt, Philipp; Sautner, Zacharias
We empirically investigate the effect of financial distress oil corporate ownership and control. Our analysis is based on a panel of 267 German firms that suffered from repeated interest coverage shortfalls between 1996 and 2004. We track each firm's development over the distress cycle With particular attention to corporate ownership, restructuring, and management turnover. We find a significant decrease in ownership concentration. Private investors gradually give up their dominating role and thereby cease to be ail effective source of managerial control. By contrast, ownership representation by banks and outside investors almost doubles. Shareholdings by executive and non-executive directors also substantially increase but have no effect on managerial tenure. Forced management turnover is mostly initiated by outside investors and banks and often occurs subsequent to debt restructurings, block investments, and takeovers. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jostarridt, Philipp; Sautner, Zacharias</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A century of corporate takeovers: What have we learned and where do we stand?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martynova, Marina; Renneboog, Luc
This paper reviews the vast academic literature on the market for corporate control. Our main focus is the cyclical wave pattern that this market exhibits. We address the following questions: Why do we observe recurring surges and downfalls in M&amp;A activity? Why do managers herd in their takeover decisions? Is takeover activity fuelled by capital market developments? Does a transfer of control generate shareholder gains and do such gains differ across takeover waves? What caused the formation of conglomerate firms in the wave of the 1960s and their de-conglomeration in the 1980s and 1990s? And, why do we observe time- and country-clustering of hostile takeover activity? We find that the patterns of takeover activity and their profitability vary significantly across takeover waves. Despite such diversity, all waves still have some common factors: they are preceded by technological or industrial shocks, and occur in a positive economic and political environment, amidst rapid credit expansion and stock market booms. Takeovers towards the end of each wave are usually driven by non-rational, frequently self-interested managerial decision-making. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Martynova, Marina; Renneboog, Luc</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Socially responsible investments: Institutional aspects, performance, and investor behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Renneboog, Luc; Ter Horst, Jenke; Zhang, Chendi
This paper provides a critical review of the literature On Socially responsible investments (SRI). Particular to SRI is that both financial goals and social objectives are pursued. Over the past decade. SRI has experienced an explosive growth around the world reflecting the increasing awareness of investors to social. environmental, ethical and corporate governance issues. We argue that there are significant opportunities for future research on the increasingly important area of SRI. A number of questions are reviewed in this paper on the causes and the shareholder-value impact of corporate social responsibility (CSR). the risk exposure and performance of SRI funds and firms. as well as fund Subscription and redemption behavior of SRI investors. We conclude that the existing studies hint but do not unequivocally demonstrate that SRI investors are willing to accept suboptimal financial performance to Pursue social or ethical objectives. Furthermore. the emergence of SRI raises interesting questions for research on corporate finance, asset pricing, and financial intermediation. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Renneboog, Luc; Ter Horst, Jenke; Zhang, Chendi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Improving VWAP strategies: A dynamic volume approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bialkowski, Jedrzej; Darolles, Serge; Le Fol, Gaelle
Ill this paper. we present a new methodology for modelling intraday volume, which allows for a reduction of the execution risk in VWAP (Volume Weighted Average Price) orders. The results are obtained for all the stocks included in the CAC40 index ill the beginning of September 2004. The idea of considered models is based on the decomposition of traded volume into two parts: one reflects volume changes due to market evolution: the second describes the stock specific volume pattern. The dynamic of the specific volume part is depicted by ARMA and SETAR models. The implementation of VWAP strategies allows some dynamic adjustments during the day in order to improve tracking of the end-of-day VWAP. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bialkowski, Jedrzej; Darolles, Serge; Le Fol, Gaelle</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tunneling and propping: A justification for pyramidal ownership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Riyanto, Yohanes E.; Toolsema, Linda A.
This paper links existence of the pyramidal ownership structure to tunneling and propping. Tunneling refers to a transfer of resources from a lower-level firm to a higher-level firm in the pyramidal chain, whereas propping concerns a transfer in the opposite direction intended to bail out the receiving firm from bankruptcy. We show that tunneling alone cannot justify the pyramidal structure unless outside investors are myopic, since rational outside investors anticipate tunneling and adjust their willingness-to-pay for the firm's shares accordingly. With propping, however, they may be willing to be expropriated in exchange for implicit insurance against bankruptcy. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Riyanto, Yohanes E.; Toolsema, Linda A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information acquisition and financial contagion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasman, Augusto; Samartin, Margarita
This paper incorporates costly voluntary acquisition of information a la Nikitin and Smith (2007) [Nikitin, M., Smith, R.T., 2007. Information acquisition. coordination, and fundamentals in a financial crisis. Journal of Banking and Finance, in press, doi: 10.1016/j.jbankfin.2007.04.031], in a framework similar to Allen and Gale (2000) [Allen, F., Gale, D., 2000. Financial contagion. Journal of Political Economy 108, 1-33], without relying on any unexpected shock to model contagion. In this framework, contagion and financial crises are the result of information gathering by depositors, weak fundamentals and an incomplete market structure of banks. It also shows how financial systems entering a recession can affect others with apparently stronger economic conditions (contagion). Finally, this is the first paper to investigate the effectiveness of the Contingent Credit Line procedures, introduced by the IMF at the end of the nineties, as a mechanism to prevent the propagation of crises. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hasman, Augusto; Samartin, Margarita</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pre-IPO ownership structure and its impact on the IPO process</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alavi, Arash; Pham, Peter Kien; Pham, Toan My
We investigate the impact of pre-issue ownership structure on the key decisions surrounding an IPO. We find that managerial ownership. is significantly related to (1) the proportion of shares offered. (2) share allocation, and (3) direct issue-related expenses. This suggests that pre-IPO ownership by managers influences their incentive to maintain control and to lower the cost of going public. In comparison, large pre-IPO non-managerial shareholders are more concerned about exiting, and their presence tends to increase issue size and costs. Our findings indicate that differences in pre-IPO owners' incentives and bargaining, power as implied by their pre-IPO shareholdings can significantly influence the IPO process. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alavi, Arash; Pham, Peter Kien; Pham, Toan My</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-country variation in household access to financial services</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Honohan, Patrick
This paper presents estimates, for more than 160 Countries, of the fraction of the adult population using formal financial intermediaries. The estimates are constructed by combining information on account numbers at banks and microfinance institutions (together with banking depth and GDP data) with estimates from household surveys for a smaller set of countries. All illustrative application of the data compares them with information on poverty: there is a correlation, but it is not clearly causal. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Honohan, Patrick</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accurate minimum capital risk requirements: A comparison of several approaches</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grane, A.; Veiga, H.
In this paper we estimate, for several investment horizons, minimum capital risk requirements for short and long positions, using the unconditional distribution of three daily indexes futures returns and a set of short and long memory stochastic volatility and GARCH-type models. We consider the possibility that errors follow a t-Student distribution in order to capture the kurtosis of the returns' series. The results suggest that accurate modelling of extreme observations obtained for long and short trading investment positions is possible with air autoregressive stochastic volatility model. Moreover, modelling futures returns with a long memory stochastic volatility model produces, in general, excessive volatility persistence, and consequently, leads to large minimum capital risk requirement estimates. Finally, the models' predictive ability is assessed with the help of out-of-sample conditional tests. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grane, A.; Veiga, H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Detecting structural breaks and identifying risk factors in hedge fund returns: A Bayesian approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Meligkotsidou, Loukia; Vrontos, Ioarinis D.
Extending previous work on asset-based style factor models, this paper proposes a model that allows for the presence of structural breaks in hedge fund return series. We consider a Bayesian approach to detecting structural breaks occurring at unknown times and identifying relevant risk factors to explain the monthly return variation. Exact and efficient Bayesian inference for the unknown number and positions of the breaks is performed by using filtering recursions similar to those of the forward-backward algorithm. Existing methods of testing for Structural breaks are also Used for comparison. We investigate the presence of structural breaks in several hedge fund indices: our results are consistent with market events and episodes that Caused Substantial volatility in hedge fund returns during the last decade. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Meligkotsidou, Loukia; Vrontos, Ioarinis D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deviations from optimal CEO ownership and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tong, Zhenxu
The transaction cost theory of managerial ownership and firm value predicts that deviations from optimal managerial ownership reduce firm value. This paper empirically tests the transaction cost theory by studying the relation between deviations on either side of optimal CEO ownership and firm value. We find that both above-optimal and below-optimal deviations reduce firm value. We find that a change in CEO ownership is associated with a higher (lower) abnormal return if it moves the ownership towards (away from) the optimal level. These findings are consistent with the transaction cost theory of managerial ownership and firm value. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tong, Zhenxu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ex-dividend returns: The Mexican puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kadapakkam, Palani-Rajan; Martinez, Valeria
We study ex-dividend returns in Mexico, where an imputation system entitles individual investors to a net dividend tax credit. Based on taxation, we expect ex-day abnormal returns to he negative or at most zero in Mexico. However, they are significantly positive. Because ex-day returns are positive even for stocks restricted to Mexican nationals, they are not attributable to foreign stockholders' tax considerations. None of the market microstructure-based hypothesis in the literature can explain these positive ex-day returns. Ex-day returns in Mexico are a puzzle. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kadapakkam, Palani-Rajan; Martinez, Valeria</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio choice and mortality-contingent claims: The general HARA case</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Huaxiong; Milevsky, Moshe A.
We solve a portfolio choice problem that includes mortality-contingent claims and labor income under general HARA preferences. Our contribution beyond existing literature is to (i) focus on the covariance between shocks to human capital and financial capital, to (ii) model the utility of a family with basic needs and (iii) include life insurance and pension annuity claims in one unified life-cycle model. Our solution employs a "similarity reduction" mapping which reduces the two-dimensional HJB equation into one dimension. This allows for the implementation of a quick numerical scheme. And, when shocks to human capital and financial capital are perfectly correlated, a closed-form expression is obtained as a special case. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Huaxiong; Milevsky, Moshe A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of the voting premium in Italy: The evidence from 1974 to 2003</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caprio, Lorenzo; Croci, Ettore
We examine the voting premium in Italy in the period 1974 to 2003, when it ranged from 1% to 100%. At firm level, the measure of the price differential between voting and non-voting stocks cannot be fully explained without taking into account the effect of the largest shareholder's identity. Family-controlled firms have higher voting premiums, especially when the family owns a large stake in the company's voting equity and the founder is the firm's CEO and/or Chairman. We explain this result by showing that families attach greater importance to control and are more prone than other types of controlling shareholders to expropriate the non-voting class of shareholders. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Caprio, Lorenzo; Croci, Ettore</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Family values: Ownership structure, performance and capital structure of Canadian firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>King, Michael R.; Santor, Eric
This study examines how family ownership affects the performance and capital structure of 613 Canadian firms from 1998 to 2005. In particular, we distinguish the effect of family ownership from the use of control-enhancing mechanisms. We find that freestanding family owned firms with a single share class have similar market performance than other firms based on Tobin's q ratios, superior accounting performance based on ROA, and higher financial leverage based on debt-to-total assets. By contrast, family owned firms that use dual-class shares have valuations that are lower by 17% on average relative to widely held firms, despite having similar ROA and financial leverage. Crown Copyright (C) 2008 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>King, Michael R.; Santor, Eric</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rating agencies and the role of rating publication rights</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maehlmann, Thomas
While credit rating agencies disclose all public ratings as a matter of policy, a firm call choose whether to make a so called private rating public or to keep it confidential. This paper analyzes the economic role of Such rating publication rights. In particular, the paper tries to answer the following two questions: (1) If firms have scope to disclose agency ratings at their own discretion, can they use this discretion strategically and conceal low-quality ratings?, and (2), if this is the case, what are the economic implications for rated firms, unrated firms and the rating agency, resulting from strategically motivated selective rating disclosures? Using a theoretical model, it is shown that ail equilibrium with partial nondisclosure of low-quality ratings can emerge whenever investors cannot be sure whether rating nondisclosure is due to the firm being not rated, or due to the rating's adverse content. Moreover, since from an investors' perspective, strategically acting rated firms and unrated firms are pooled, unrated firms' debt is always under-valued (compared to a Situation in which investors know that the firm is not rated), and the debt of firms concealing their rating is always over-valued. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maehlmann, Thomas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can the evolution of implied volatility be forecasted? Evidence from European and US implied volatility indices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Konstantinidi, Eirini; Skiadopoulos, George; Tzakaraki, Emmilia
We address the question whether the evolution of implied volatility can be forecasted by Studying a number of European and US implied volatility indices. Both point and interval forecasts are formed by alternative model specifications. The statistical and economic significance of these forecasts is examined. The latter is assessed by trading strategies in the recently inaugurated CBOE volatility futures markets. Predictable patterns are detected from a statistical point of view. However, these are not economically significant since no abnormal profits can be attained. Hence, the hypothesis that the volatility futures markets are efficient cannot be rejected. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Konstantinidi, Eirini; Skiadopoulos, George; Tzakaraki, Emmilia</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dynamics of quote adjustments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Kee H.; Chuwonganant, Chairat; Jiang, Jing
Liquidity providers oil the NYSE make faster quote adjustments towards equilibrium spreads and depths than they do oil NASDAQ. Liquidity providers in both markets make faster spread and depth adjustments for stocks with more frequent trading, greater return volatility, higher prices, smaller market capitalizations, and smaller trade sizes. We find that stocks with greater information-based trading and in more competitive trading environments exhibit faster quote adjustments. The speed of quote adjustment is faster after decimalization in both markets. These results are robust and not driven by differences in stock attributes between the two markets or time periods. Overall, our results indicate that stock attributes, market structure, and tick size exert a significant impact on the speed of quote adjustment. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, Kee H.; Chuwonganant, Chairat; Jiang, Jing</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign versus local investors: Who knows more? Who makes more?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalev, Petko S.; Nguyen, Ann H.; Oh, Natalie Y.
This paper examines the nature of information asymmetry between foreign and local investors on the Helsinki stock exchange (HEX) for the period 1999-2004. We take into account the differences in information characteristics by partitioning stocks into single-listed, cross-listed and internationally well-known stock categories, after which we compare foreign and local investors' performance and trading for Nokia, the only internationally well-known stock on HEX. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All right reserved.</description><author>Kalev, Petko S.; Nguyen, Ann H.; Oh, Natalie Y.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Influence of disclosure and governance on risk of US financial services firms following Sarbanes-Oxley</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akhlgbe, Aigbe; Martin, Anna D.
This study finds significant changes in capital market measures of risk following the passage of Sarbanes-Oxley for US financial services firms. Shorter-term measures of risk shifts are positive, on average, and consistent with the mandatory nature of the disclosure and governance provisions. Longer-term total and unsystematic risk shifts are negative, on average, and consistent with reductions in investor uncertainty as transparency improved. We find that the changes in shorter-term and longer-term risk measures vary inversely with the strength of disclosure and governance characteristics. The financial market rewarded (punished) firms with stronger (weaker) disclosure and stronger (weaker) governance. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Akhlgbe, Aigbe; Martin, Anna D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical analysis of the dynamic relationship between mutual fund flow and market return volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Charles; Chang, Eric C.; Wang, Ying
We study the dynamic relation between aggregate mutual fund flow and market-wide volatility. Using daily flow data and a VAR approach, we find that market volatility is negatively related to concurrent and lagged flow. A structural VAR impulse response analysis suggests that shock in flow has a negative impact on market volatility: An inflow (outflow) shock predicts a decline (an increase) in volatility. From the perspective of volatility-flow relation, we find evidence of volatility timing for recent period of 1998-2003. Finally, we document a differential impact of daily inflow versus outflow on intraday volatility. The relation between intraday volatility and inflow (outflow) becomes weaker (stronger) from morning to afternoon. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cao, Charles; Chang, Eric C.; Wang, Ying</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The performance effect of managerial ownership: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Yifan; Zhou, Xianming
By examining a sample of non-listed Chinese firms, we provide the first evidence from China for the effect of managerial ownership on firm performance. In matching-sample comparisons, we find that firms of significant managerial ownership outperform firms whose managers do not own equity shares. Our further results indicate the relation between firm performance and managerial ownership is nonlinear, and the inflection point at which the relation turns negative occurs at ownership above 50%. Compared with previous studies, our results are less likely to suffer from an endogeneity problem due to the non-list nature of our sample and the unique institutional environment in China. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hu, Yifan; Zhou, Xianming</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On real interest rate dynamics and regime switching</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kanas, Angelos
We find evidence of regime switching dynamics in the USA and the UK real interest rates over the period 1881-2003. For the UK, there is a regime in which the real interest rate displays a relatively stronger mean-reversion and a regime in which it displays a relatively weaker mean-reversion. The former regime is characterized by a relatively larger error in the estimation of the reversion parameter, and higher volatility. For the USA, the two regimes differ in volatility. The probability of transition from one regime to another is found to be significantly related to the inflation rate regime, and to the political regime. The results highlight the importance of regime switching in the dynamics of the real interest rate, as well as the role of inflation and political regimes in explaining this switching. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kanas, Angelos</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing discretely monitored Asian options under Levy processes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fusai, Gianluca; Meucci, Attilic
We present methodologies to price discretely monitored Asian options when the underlying evolves according to a generic Levy process. For geometric Asian options we provide closed-form solutions in terms of the Fourier transform and we study in particular these formulas in the Levy-stable case. For arithmetic Asian options we solve the valuation problem by recursive integration and derive a recursive theoretical formula for the moments to check the accuracy of the results. We compare the implementation of our method to Monte Carlo simulation implemented with control variates and using different parametric Levy processes. We also discuss model risk issues. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fusai, Gianluca; Meucci, Attilic</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A revisited and stable Fourier transform method for affine jump diffusion models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Minenna, Marcello; Verzella, Paolo
In the last decade, fast Fourier transform methods (i.e. FFT) have become the standard tool for pricing and hedging with affine jump diffusion models (i.e. AJD), despite the FFT theoretical framework is still in development and it is known that the early solutions have serious problems in terms of stability and accuracy. This fact depends from the relevant computational gain that the FFT approach offers with respect to the standard Fourier transform methods that make use of a canonical inverse Levy formula. In this work we revisit a classic FT method and find that changing the quadrature algorithm and using alternative, less flawed, representation for the pricing formulas can improve the computational performance up to levels that are only three time slower than FFT can achieve. This allows to have at the same time a reasonable computational speed and the well known stability and accuracy of canonical FT methods. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Minenna, Marcello; Verzella, Paolo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beyond Sharpe ratio: Optimal asset allocation using different performance ratios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Farinelli, Simone; Ferreira, Manuel; Rossello, Damiano; Thoeny, Markus; Tibiletti, Luisa
As the assumption of normality in return distributions is relaxed, classic Sharpe ratio and its descendants become questionable tools for constructing optimal portfolios. In order to overcome the problem, asymmetrical parameter-dependent performance ratios have been recently proposed in the literature. The aim of this note is to develop an integrated decision aid system for asset allocation based on a toolkit of eleven performance ratios. A multi-period portfolio optimization up covering a fixed horizon is set up: at first, bootstrapping of asset return distributions is assessed to recover all ratios calculations; at second, optimal rebalanced-weights are achieved; at third, optimal final wealth is simulated for each ratios. Eventually, we make a robustness test on best performance ratios. Empirical simulations confirm the weakness in forecasting of Sharpe ratio, whereas asymmetrical parameter-dependent ratios, such as the Generalized Rachev, Sortino-Satchell and Farinelli-Tibiletti ratios show satisfactorily robustness. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Farinelli, Simone; Ferreira, Manuel; Rossello, Damiano; Thoeny, Markus; Tibiletti, Luisa</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust optimization of conditional value at risk and portfolio selection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Quaranta, Anna Grazia; Zaffaroni, Alberto
This paper deals with a portfolio selection model in which the methodologies of robust optimization are used for the minimization of the conditional value at risk of a portfolio of shares. Conditional value at risk, being in essence the mean shortfall at a specified confidence level, is a coherent risk measure which can hold account of the so called "tail risk" and is therefore an efficient and synthetic risk measure, which can overcome the drawbacks of the most famous and largely used VaR. An important feature of our approach consists in the use of techniques of robust optimization to deal with uncertainty, in place of stochastic programming as proposed by Rockafellar and Uryasev. Moreover we succeeded in obtaining a linear robust copy of the bicriteria minimization model proposed by Rockafellar and Uryasev. We suggest different approaches for the generation of input data, with special attention to the estimation of expected returns. The relevance of our methodology is illustrated by a portfolio selection experiment on the Italian market. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Quaranta, Anna Grazia; Zaffaroni, Alberto</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analytical pricing of discretely monitored Asian-style options: Theory and application to commodity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fusai, Gianluca; Marena, Marina; Roncoroni, Andrea
We compute an analytical expression for the moment generating function of the joint random vector consisting of a spot price and its discretely monitored average for a large class of square-root price dynamics. This result, combined with the Fourier transform pricing method proposed by Carr and Madan [Carr, P., Madan D., 1999. Option valuation using the fast Fourier transform. Journal of Computational Finance 2(4), Summer, 61-73] allows us to derive a closed-form formula for the fair value of discretely monitored Asian-style options. Our analysis encompasses the case of commodity price dynamics displaying mean reversion and jointly fitting a quoted futures curve and the seasonal structure of spot price volatility. Four tests are conducted to assess the relative performance of the pricing procedure stemming from our formulae. Empirical results based on natural gas data from NYMEX and corn data from CBOT show a remarkable improvement over the main alternative techniques developed for pricing Asian-style options within the market standard framework of geometric Brownian motion. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fusai, Gianluca; Marena, Marina; Roncoroni, Andrea</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An econometric analysis of emission allowance prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Paolella, Marc S.; Taschini, Luca
Knowledge of the statistical distribution of the prices of emission allowances, and their forecastability, are crucial in constructing, among other things, purchasing and risk management strategies in the emissions-constrained markets. This paper analyzes the two emission permits markets, CO2 in Europe, and SO2 in the US, and investigates a model for dealing with the unique stylized facts of this type of data. Its effectiveness in terms of model fit and out-of-sample value-at-risk-forecasting, as compared to models commonly used in risk-forecasting contexts, is demonstrated. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Paolella, Marc S.; Taschini, Luca</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing forward contracts in power markets by the certainty equivalence principle: Explaining the sign of the market risk premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benth, Fred Espen; Cartea, Alvaro; Kiesel, Ruediger
In this paper we provide a framework that explains how the market risk premium, defined as the difference between forward prices and spot forecasts, depends on the risk preferences of market players and the interaction between buyers and sellers. In commodities markets this premium is an important indicator of the behavior of buyers and sellers and their views on the market spanning between short-term and long-term horizons. We show that under certain assumptions it is possible to derive explicit solutions that link levels of risk aversion and market power with market prices of risk and the market risk premium. We apply our model to the German electricity market and show that the market risk premium exhibits a term structure which can be explained by the combination of two factors. Firstly, the levels of risk aversion of buyers and sellers, and secondly, how the market power of producers, relative to that of buyers, affects forward prices with different delivery periods. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Benth, Fred Espen; Cartea, Alvaro; Kiesel, Ruediger</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-consistency in managing a commodity portfolio: A dynamic risk measure approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Geman, Helyette; Ohana, Steve
We address the problem of managing a storable commodity portfolio, that includes physical assets and positions in spot and forward markets. The vast amount of capital involved in the acquisition of a power plant or storage facility implies that the financing period stretches over a period of several quarters or years. Hence, an intertemporally consistent way of optimizing the portfolio over the planning horizon is required. We demonstrate the temporal inconsistency of static risk objectives based on final wealth and advocate the validity in our setting of a new class of recursive risk measures introduced by Epstein and Zin [Epstein, G., Zin, S., 1989. Substitution, risk aversion, and the temporal behavior of consumption and asset returns: A theoretical framework. Econometrica, 57 (4) 937-969] and Wang [Wang, T., 2000. A class of dynamic risk measures University of British Columbia]. These risk measures provide important insights on the trade-offs between date-specific risks (i.e., losses occurring at a point in time) and time-duration risks represented by the pair (return, risk) over a planning horizon; in a number of situations, they dramatically improve the efficiency of static risk objectives, as exhibited in numerical examples. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Geman, Helyette; Ohana, Steve</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk management in commodity and financial markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>D'Ecclesia, Rita L.
nan</description><author>D'Ecclesia, Rita L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The causal effect of board size in the performance of small and medium-sized firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bennedsen, Morten; Kongsted, Hans Christian; Nielsen, Kasper Meisner
Empirical studies of large publicly traded firms have shown a robust negative relationship between board size and firm performance. The evidence on small and medium-sized firms is less clear; we show that existing work has been incomplete in analyzing the causal relationship due to weak identification strategies. Using a rich data set of almost 7000 closely held corporations we provide a causal analysis of board size effects on firm performance: We use a novel instrument given by the number of children of the chief executive officer (CEO) of the firms. First, we find a strong positive correlation between family size and board size and show this correlation to be driven by firms where the CEO's relatives serve on the board. Second, we find empirical evidence of a small adverse board size effect driven by the minority of small and medium-sized firms that are characterized by having comparatively large boards of six or more members. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bennedsen, Morten; Kongsted, Hans Christian; Nielsen, Kasper Meisner</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What lies beneath: Foreign exchange rate exposure, hedging and cash flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartram, Soehnke M.
This paper presents results from an in-depth analysis of the foreign exchange rate exposure of a large nonfinancial firm based on proprietary internal data including cash flows, derivatives and foreign currency debt, as well as external capital market data. While the operations of the multinational firm have significant exposure to foreign exchange rate risk due to foreign currency-based activities and international competition, corporate hedging mitigates this gross exposure. The analysis illustrates that the insignificance of foreign exchange rate exposures of comprehensive performance measures such as total cash flow can be explained by hedging at the firm level. Thus, the residual net exposure is economically and statistically small, even if the operating cash flows of the firm are significantly exposed to exchange rate risk. The results of the paper suggest that managers of nonfinancial firms with operations exposed to foreign exchange rate risk take savvy actions to reduce exposure to a level too low to allow its detection empirically. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bartram, Soehnke M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are there long-run implications of analyst coverage for IPOs?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bradley, Daniel; Chan, Konan; Kim, Joonghyuk; Singh, Ajai
Analyst coverage has been cited increasingly as an important attribute in the selection of, an underwriter for a firm about to go public. However, it has also been alleged that affiliated analysts provide biased research. In this study, we examine these interrelated issues by examining the long-run performance of IPOs with coverage from their managing underwriters in a 1993-2003 sample. We find that (1) analysts' research coverage from their managing syndicate is not related to long-run performance; (2) long-run performance is not different for firms that receive all-star analyst coverage; and (3) investors are not systematically worse off for following lead underwriter recommendations. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bradley, Daniel; Chan, Konan; Kim, Joonghyuk; Singh, Ajai</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging index exchange traded funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, C.; Barbosa, A.
This paper presents an empirical comparison of the out of sample hedging performance from naive and minimum variance hedge ratios for the four largest US index exchange traded funds (ETFs). Efficient hedging is important to offset long and short positions on market maker's accounts, particularly imbalances in net creation or redemption demands around the time of dividend payments. Our evaluation of out of sample hedging performance includes aversion to negative skewness and excess kurtosis. The results should be of interest to hedge funds employing tax arbitrage or leveraged long-short equity strategies as well as to ETF market makers. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alexander, C.; Barbosa, A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on foreign bank ownership and monitoring: An international comparison</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertus, Mark; Jahera, John S.; Yost, Keven
This paper empirically analyzes the relation between foreign bank ownership and the three pillars of the New Basel Capital Accord (i.e., capital regulatory oversight, supervisory oversight, and market discipline). Using a new database covering 153 countries, we find that countries with greater market discipline have a lower presence of foreign banks operating in their economy. Furthermore, our evidence indicates that capital regulatory oversight and supervisory oversight are not significantly related to foreign bank ownership. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bertus, Mark; Jahera, John S.; Yost, Keven</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Factorization of European and American option prices under complete and incomplete markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ibanez, Alfredo
In a standard option-pricing model, with continuous-trading and diffusion processes, this paper shows that the price of one European-style option can be factorized into two intuitive components: One robust, X-0, which is priced by arbitrage, and a second, no, which depends on a risk orthogonal to the traded securities. This result implies the following: (1) In an incomplete market, these parts represent the price of a hedging portfolio, which is unique, and a premium, which depends only on the risk premiums associated with the residual risk, respectively. (2) In a complete market, it allows factoring the contribution of the different sources of risk to the final option price. For example, in a stochastic volatility model, we can quantify the impact on the option price of volatility risk relative to market risk, Pi(0) and X-0, respectively. Hence, certain misspricings in option markets can be directly related to the premium, Pi(0). (3) Moreover, these results extend to American securities, which have a third component - an additional early-exercise premium. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ibanez, Alfredo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank failures and bank fundamentals: A comparative analysis of Latin America and East Asia during the nineties using bank-level data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arena, Marco
This paper uses bank-level data from recent banking crises in East Asia and Latin America to address the following two questions: (1) To what extent did individual bank conditions explain the failures? (2) In terms of their fundamentals, was it mainly the weak banks ex ante that failed in the crisis countries? The results show that for the two regions, bank-level fundamentals significantly affect the likelihood of collapse for these banks. Systemic shocks (both macroeconomic and liquidity) that triggered the crises mainly destabilized the weak banks ex ante, particularly in East Asia, which raises questions about the role that regional differences play for the degree of banking sector resilience to systemic shocks in the financial and macroeconomic environment. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Arena, Marco</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing options on scenario trees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Topaloglou, Nikolas; Vladimirou, Hercules; Zenios, Stavros A.
We examine valuation procedures that can be applied to incorporate options in scenario-based portfolio optimization models. Stochastic programming models use discrete scenarios to represent the stochastic evolution of asset prices. At issue is the adoption Of Suitable procedures to price options on the basis of the postulated discrete distributions of asset prices so as to ensure internally consistent portfolio optimization models. We adapt and implement two methods to price European options in accordance with discrete distributions represented by scenario trees and assess their performance with numerical tests. We consider features of option prices that are observed in practice. We find that asymmetries and/or leptokurtic features in the distribution of the underlying materially affect option prices; we quantify the impact of higher moments (skewness and excess kurtosis) on option prices. We demonstrate through empirical tests using market prices of the S&amp;P500 stock index and options on the index that the proposed procedures consistently approximate the observed prices of options under different market regimes, especially for deep out-of-the-money options. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Topaloglou, Nikolas; Vladimirou, Hercules; Zenios, Stavros A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of autoregressive conditional skewness and kurtosis in the estimation of conditional VaR</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Mo, Hengyong; Tang, Yi
This paper investigates the role of high-order moments in the estimation of conditional value at risk (VaR). We use the skewed generalized t distribution (SGT) with time-varying parameters to provide an accurate characterization of the tails of the standardized return distribution. We allow the high-order moments of the SGT density to depend on the past information set, and hence relax the conventional assumption in conditional VaR calculation that the distribution of standardized returns is iid. The maximum likelihood estimates show that the time-varying conditional volatility, skewness, tail-thickness, and peakedness parameters of the SGT density are statistically significant. The in-sample and out-of-sample performance results indicate that the conditional SGT-GARCH approach with autoregressive conditional skewness and kurtosis provides very accurate and robust estimates of the actual VaR thresholds. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Mo, Hengyong; Tang, Yi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overnight information and stochastic volatility: A study of European and</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tsiakas, Ilias
This paper provides a comprehensive evaluation of the predictive ability of information accumulated during nontrading hours for a set of European and US stock indexes. We introduce a stochastic volatility model, which conditions on lagged overnight information, distinguishes between the nontrading periods of weeknights, weekends, holidays and long weekends, and allows for an asymmetric leverage effect on the impact of overnight news. We implement Bayesian methods for estimation and ranking of the empirical models, and find two key results: (i) there is substantial predictive ability in financial information accumulated during nontrading hours; and (ii) the performance of stochastic volatility models improves considerably by separating the asymmetric impact of positive and negative news made available over weeknights, weekends, holidays and long weekends. (c) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Tsiakas, Ilias</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Preferred habitat for liquidity in international short-term interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kotomin, Vladimir; Smith, Stanley D.; Winters, Drew B.
Risk-shifting window dressing and a preferred habitat for liquidity have been offered as possible explanations as to why US money market rates are higher before the year-end than afterwards. The two hypotheses differ in the timing of the rate decline at the year-end and the evidence on the timing of the decline supports the preferred habitat hypothesis in US money markets. This paper extends this line of research to the behavior of international short-term interest rates at year-ends and quarter-ends using London interbank offer rates (LIBOR) for 11 different currencies. The results suggest that the behavior of LIBOR for five currencies: the US Dollar, Euro, Japanese Yen, Swiss Franc, and German Mark is consistent with year-end or quarter-end preferred habitats for liquidity. Other currencies do not demonstrate consistently distinct patterns in turn-of-the-year and turn-of-the-quarter yields. None of the results provides any support for risk-shifting window dressing. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kotomin, Vladimir; Smith, Stanley D.; Winters, Drew B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal strike prices of stock options for effort-averse executives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Palmon, Oded; Bar-Yosef, Sasson; Chen, Ren-Raw; Venezia, Itzhak
This paper evaluates the common practice of setting the strike prices of executive option plans at-the-money. Hall and Murphy [Hall, Brian, Murphy, Kevin J., 2000. Optimal exercise prices for executive stock options. American Economic Review 90 (2), 209-214] claim this practice to be optimal since it maximizes the sensitivity of compensation to firm performance. However, they do not incorporate effort and the possibility that managers are effort-averse into their model. We revisit this question while explicitly introducing these factors and allowing the reward package to include fixed wages, options, and stock grants. We simulate the manager's effort choice and compensation as well as the value of shareholders' equity under alternative compensation schemes, and identify schemes that are optimal. Our simulations indicate that, when abstracting from tax considerations, it is optimal to award managers with options that will most likely be highly valuable (i.e., substantially in-the-money) on their expiration date. Prior to 2006, the tax code and financial reporting standards provided incentives to award options that are closer to the money when issued than the options that were optimal in the absence of these considerations. Recent tax and reporting changes voided these incentives and thus we predict that these changes will induce firms to issue options with lower strike prices than those that were issued prior to 2006. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Palmon, Oded; Bar-Yosef, Sasson; Chen, Ren-Raw; Venezia, Itzhak</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-country determinants of bank income smoothing by managing loan-loss provisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fonseca, Ana Rosa; Gonzalez, Francisco
This paper studies the determinants of income smoothing by management of loan-loss provisions in banks around the world. Using a panel database of 3221 bank-year observations from 40 countries and controlling for unobservable bank effects and for the endogeneity of explanatory variables, we find that bank income smoothing depends on investor protection, disclosure, regulation and supervision, financial structure, and financial development. Results suggest there is less bank income smoothing not only with the strength of investor protection, but also with the extent of accounting disclosure, restrictions on bank activities, and official and private supervision, while there is more income smoothing with market orientation and development of a country's financial system. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fonseca, Ana Rosa; Gonzalez, Francisco</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of capital market imperfections on investment-cash flow sensitivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agca, Senay; Mozumdar, Abon
We examine the investment-cash flow sensitivity of US manufacturing firms in relation to five factors associated with capital market imperfections - fund flows, institutional ownership, analyst following, bond ratings, and an index of antitakeover amendments. We find a steady decline in the estimated sensitivity over time. Furthermore, we find that investment-cash flow sensitivity decreases with increasing fund flows, institutional ownership, analyst following, antitakeover amendments and with the existence of a bond rating. The overall evidence suggests that investment-cash flow sensitivity decreases with factors that reduce capital market imperfections. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Agca, Senay; Mozumdar, Abon</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relative deviation metrics and the problem of strategy replication</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stoyanov, Stoyan V.; Rachev, Svetlozar T.; Ortobelli, Sergio; Fabozzi, Frank J.
In the paper, we generalize the classical benchmark tracking problem by introducing the class of relative deviation metrics. We introduce an axiomatic description of the benchmark tracking problem and a classification inspired by the theory of probability metrics. Two examples of such metrics are provided and their in-sample behaviour is compared to the classical tracking error in a numerical example. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stoyanov, Stoyan V.; Rachev, Svetlozar T.; Ortobelli, Sergio; Fabozzi, Frank J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric effect of basis on dynamic futures hedging: Empirical evidence from commodity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lien, Donald; Yang, Li
The dynamic minimum variance hedge ratios (MVHRs) have been commonly estimated using the Bivariate GARCH model that overlooks the basis effect on the time-varying variance-covariance of spot and futures returns. This paper proposes an alternative specification of the BGARCH model in which the effect is incorporated for estimating MVHRs. Empirical investigation in commodity markets suggests that the basis effect is asymmetric, i.e., the positive basis has greater impact than the negative basis on the variance and covariance structure. Both in-sample and out-of-sample comparisons of the MVHR performance reveal that the model with the asymmetric effect provides greater risk reduction than the conventional models, illustrating importance of the asymmetric effect when modeling the joint dynamics of spot and futures returns and hence estimating hedging strategies. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lien, Donald; Yang, Li</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity, default, taxes, and yields on municipal bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Junbo; Wu, Chunchi; Zhang, Frank X.
We examine the effects of liquidity, default and personal taxes on the relative yields of Treasuries and municipals using a generalized model with liquidity risk. The municipal yield model includes liquidity as a state factor. Using a unique transaction dataset, we estimate the liquidity risk of municipals and its effect on bond yields. Empirical evidence shows that municipal bond yields are strongly affected by all three factors. The effects of default and liquidity risk on municipal yields increase with maturity and credit risk. Liquidity premium accounts for about 9-13% of municipal yields for AAA bonds, 9-15% for AA/A bonds and 8-19% for BBB bonds. A substantial portion of the maturity spread between long- and short-maturity municipal bonds is attributed to the liquidity premium. Ignoring the liquidity risk effect thus results in a severe underestimation of municipal bond yields. Conditional on the effects of default and liquidity risk, we obtain implicit tax rates very close to the statutory tax rates of high-income individuals and institutional investors. Furthermore, these implicit income tax rates are quite stable across bonds of different maturities. Results show that including liquidity risk in the municipal bond pricing model helps explain the muni puzzle. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Wang, Junbo; Wu, Chunchi; Zhang, Frank X.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamics of insurance markets: Structure, conduct, and performance in the 21st century</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cummins, J. David; Dionne, Georges
nan</description><author>Cummins, J. David; Dionne, Georges</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Providers' affiliation, insurance and collusion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bourgeon, Jean-Marc; Picard, Pierre; Pouyet, Jerome
This paper provides a theoretical analysis of the benefits for an insurance company to develop its own network of service providers when insurance fraud is characterized by collusion between policyholders and providers. In a static framework without collusion, exclusive affiliation of providers allows insurance companies to recover some market power and to lessen competition on the insurance market. This entails a decrease in the insured's welfare. However, exclusive affiliation of providers may entail a positive effect on customers' surplus when insurers and providers are engaged in a repeated relationship. In particular, while insurers must cooperate to retaliate against a fraudulent provider under non-exclusive affiliation, no cooperation is needed under exclusive affiliation. In that case, an insurer is indeed able to reduce the profit of a malevolent provider by moving to collusion-proof contracts when collusion is detected, and this threat may act as a deterrent for fraudulent activities. This possibility may supplement an inefficient judicial system: it is thus a second-best optimal anti-fraud policy. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bourgeon, Jean-Marc; Picard, Pierre; Pouyet, Jerome</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"Crises" in medical malpractice insurance: Evidence of excessive price-cutting in the preceding soft market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harrington, Scott E.; Danzon, Patricia M.; Epstein, Andrew J.
Prior work suggests that heterogeneous information or weak incentives for solvency could have caused some general liability insurers to charge low ex ante prices during the early 1980s and mid-to-late 1990s, putting downward pressure on other firms' prices and plausibly aggravating subsequent periods of rapid premium growth. We analyse whether the 1994-1999 "soft" market in medical malpractice insurance led some firms to underprice, grow rapidly, and subsequently experience upward revisions in loss forecasts ("loss development"), which could have aggravated subsequent market "crises". Consistent with the underpricing hypothesis, the results indicate a positive relation between loss development and premium growth among growing firms. Underpricing was likely more prevalent among non-specialist malpractice insurers. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harrington, Scott E.; Danzon, Patricia M.; Epstein, Andrew J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>State regulation and the structure, conduct, efficiency and performance of US auto insurers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weiss, Mary A.; Choi, Byeongyong Paul
This research investigates the impact of regulation on state automobile insurance markets while controlling for other state insurance market characteristics that may be related to performance. Data for a large sample of insurers are analyzed. The results suggest that insurers in competitive and non-stringently regulated states may benefit from market power by charging higher unit prices, however insurers in these states are on average more cost X-efficient and cost X-efficient insurers charge lower prices and earn smaller profits. The empirical results also suggest that insurers in some rate regulated states are less revenue and cost-scale efficient than in competitive states. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Weiss, Mary A.; Choi, Byeongyong Paul</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulator performance, regulatory environment and outcomes: An examination of insurance regulator career incentives on state insurance markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grace, Martin F.; Phillips, Richard D.
In this paper we test whether the past or future labor market choices of insurance commissioners provide incentives for regulators in states with price regulation to either favor or oppose the industry by allowing prices that differ significantly from what would otherwise be the competitive market outcome. Using biographical data on insurance regulators, economic and state specific market structure and regulatory variables, and state premium and loss data on the personal automobile insurance market, we find no evidence consumers in prior approval states paid significantly different "unit prices" for insurance than consumers in states that allow competitive market forces to determine equilibrium prices during the time period 1985-2002. We do, however, find evidence regulators who obtained the position of insurance commissioner by popular election and those who seek higher elective office following their tenure as insurance commissioner allow higher overall "unit prices" relative to competitive market states. The "unit price" of insurance in regulated states is not statistically different from the competitive market outcome for regulators that make lateral moves back into state government and it is mildly higher for regulators who enter the insurance industry following their tenure. Finally, we find some evidence regulators who describe themselves as consumer advocates are successful reducing the price of insurance in favor of consumers in regulated markets. Overall the results are consistent with the existence of asymmetric information in the regulatory process that agents use to enhance their career aspirations. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Grace, Martin F.; Phillips, Richard D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reinsurance and corporate taxation in the United Kingdom life insurance industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, Mike; Hardwick, Philip; Zou, Hong
There are two main tax-related arguments regarding the use of reinsurance - the income volatility reduction and the income level enhancement arguments. The income volatility reduction argument contends that firms facing convex tax schedules have incentives to hedge in order to reduce the volatility of their annual taxable income and thereby lower expected tax liabilities [Smith, C.W., Stulz, R.M., 1985. Optimal hedging policies. Journal of Financial and Quantitative Analysis 19, 127-140]. The income level enhancement argument, advanced by Adiel [Adiel, R., 1996. Reinsurance and the management of regulatory ratios and taxes in the property-casualty insurance industry. Journal of Accounting and Economics 22, 207-240], is more specific to hedging via reinsurance. This perspective holds that reinsurance enhances current reported earnings via the receipt of reinsurance commissions and so increases tax liabilities. Consequently, insurance firms with high marginal tax rates should use less reinsurance than those with low marginal tax rates if tax matters. Prior studies using data on financial derivatives have produced mixed results on the validity of the first argument, while Adiel (1996) finds the second argument insignificant in his study of the use of reinsurance by a sample of United States (US) property-liability insurance firms. This study tests the two tax-related arguments using 1992-2001 data for a sample of United Kingdom (UK) life insurance firms. We find that UK life insurers with low before-planning marginal tax rates tend to use more reinsurance; in contrast, tax convexity is found to have no significant impact on the purchase of reinsurance and so the volatility-reduction argument is not supported. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adams, Mike; Hardwick, Philip; Zou, Hong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market structure and the efficiency of European insurance companies: A stochastic frontier analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fenn, Paul; Vencappa, Dev; Diacon, Stephen; Klumpes, Paul; O'Brien, Chris
This paper is motivated by the progressive liberalisation of the European insurance market in recent years. It uses stochastic frontier analysis to estimate Flexible Fourier cost functions for European insurance companies. Separate frontiers are estimated for life, non-life and composite companies. We adopt a maximum likelihood approach to estimation in which the variance of both one-sided and two-sided error terms is modelled jointly with the frontiers. This approach allows us to simultaneously control for the impact of heteroskedasticity on the estimation of scale economies as well as estimating the effect of firm size and market structure on X-inefficiency. The study draws on Standard &amp; Poor's Eurothesys data set of financial reports for the period 1995 to 2001. This provides technical and non-technical accounts at year-end for life, non-life and composite insurance businesses in 14 major European countries. Our estimates suggest that over this period most European insurers were operating under conditions of decreasing costs (increasing returns to scale), and that company size and domestic market share were significant factors determining X-inefficiency. Larger firms, and those with high market shares, tend to have higher levels of cost inefficiency. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fenn, Paul; Vencappa, Dev; Diacon, Stephen; Klumpes, Paul; O'Brien, Chris</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the pricing of intermediated risks: Theory and application to catastrophe reinsurance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Froot, Kenneth A.; O'Connell, Paul G. J.
We model the equilibrium price and quantity of risk transfer between firms and financial intermediaries. Value-maximizing firms have downward sloping demands to cede risk, while intermediaries, who assume risk, provide less-than-fully-elastic supply. We show that equilibrium required returns will be "high" in the presence of financing imperfections that make intermediary capital costly. Moreover, financing imperfections can give rise to intermediary market power, so that small changes in financial imperfections can give rise to large changes in price. We develop tests of this alternative against the null that the supply of intermediary capital is perfectly elastic. We take the US catastrophe reinsurance market as an example, using detailed data from Guy Carpenter &amp; Co., covering a large fraction of the catastrophe risks exchanged during 1970-94. Our results suggest that the price of reinsurance generally exceeds "fair" values, particularly in the aftermath of large events, that market power of reinsurers is not a complete explanation for such pricing, and that reinsurers' high costs of capital appear to play an important role. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Froot, Kenneth A.; O'Connell, Paul G. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consolidation and value creation in the insurance industry: The role of governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boubakri, Narjess; Dionne, Georges; Triki, Thouraya
We examine the long run performance of M&amp;A transactions in the property-liability insurance industry. We specifically investigate whether such transactions create value for the bidders' shareholders, and assess how corporate governance mechanisms, internal and external, affect such performance. Our results show that M&amp;A create value in the long run as buy and hold abnormal returns are positive and significant after 3 years. While tender offers appear to be more profitable than mergers, our multivariate evidence does not support the conjecture that domestic transactions create more value than cross-border transactions. Furthermore, positive returns are significantly higher for frequent acquirers and in countries where investor protection is weaker. Internal corporate governance mechanisms, such as board independence, and CEO share ownership, are also significant determinants of the long run positive performance of bidders. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boubakri, Narjess; Dionne, Georges; Triki, Thouraya</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mergers and acquisitions in the US property-liability insurance industry: Productivity and efficiency effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cummins, J. David; Xie, Xiaoying
This paper analyzes the productivity and efficiency effects of mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;As) in the US property-liability insurance industry during the period 1994-2003 using data envelopment analysis (DEA) and Malmquist productivity indices. We seek to determine whether M&amp;As are value-enhancing, value-neutral, or value-reducing. The analysis examines efficiency and productivity change for acquirers, acquisition targets, and non-M&amp;A firms. We also examine the firm characteristics associated with becoming an acquirer or target through probit analysis. The results provide evidence that M&amp;As in property-liability insurance were value-enhancing. Acquiring firms achieved more revenue efficiency gains than non-acquiring firms, and target firms experienced greater cost and allocative efficiency growth than non-targets. Factors other than efficiency enhancement are important factors in property-liability insurer M&amp;As. Financially vulnerable insurers are significantly more likely to become acquisition targets, consistent with corporate control theory, and we also find evidence that M&amp;As are motivated to achieve diversification. However, there is no evidence that scale economies played an important role in the insurance M&amp;A wave. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cummins, J. David; Xie, Xiaoying</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-border M&amp;As in the financial sector: Is banking different from insurance?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Focarelli, Dario; Pozzolo, Alberto Franco
This paper investigates what factors might help explain the internationalization strategy of banks and insurance companies, by comparing the determinants of cross-border M&amp;As in the two sectors in a unified framework. The empirical analysis shows that between 1990 and 2003 the internationalization of banks and insurance companies followed similar patterns. Distance and economic and cultural integration are important determinants for both the banks' and the insurance companies' expansion abroad. Comparative advantage also has a prominent role, the more so for banks. The evidence is less supportive of the view that cross-border M&amp;As are more frequent between similar countries, as predicted by the new trade theory. Finally, and most interestingly, we find indirect evidence consistent with the hypothesis that implicit barriers to foreign entry are more important in explaining the behavior of banks than that of insurance companies. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Focarelli, Dario; Pozzolo, Alberto Franco</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insurance market mechanisms and government interventions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kessler, Denis
The expansion of the State-as-insurer has played a major role in the long-term growth of the public sector, but we are probably reaching the turning point. Because of its manifold failures, the State-as-insurer is facing crisis all around the world, with exploding expenditures. This will probably induce a shift in the private-public frontier, which makes it much more important than in the past to regulate the insurance industry efficiently. Coming back to the failures of the State-as-insurer, we should underline the role played by this flawed hypothesis that sets market logic and private interest against public interest. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kessler, Denis</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bounds and prices of currency cross-rate options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, San-Lin; Wang, Yaw-Huei
This paper derives the pricing bounds of a currency cross-rate option using the option prices of two related dollar rates via a copula theory and presents the analytical properties of the bounds under the Gaussian framework. Our option pricing bounds are useful, because (1) they are general in the sense that they do not rely on the distribution assumptions of the state variables or on the selection of the copula function; (2) they are portfolios of the dollar-rate options and hence are potential hedging instruments for cross-rate options; and (3) they can be applied to generate bounds on deltas. The empirical tests suggest that there are persistent and stable relationships between the market prices and the estimated bounds of the cross-rate options and that our option pricing bounds (obtained from the market prices of options on two dollar rates) and the historical correlation of two dollar rates are highly informative for explaining the prices of the cross-rate options. Moreover, the empirical results are consistent with the predictions of the analytical properties under the Gaussian framework and are robust in various aspects. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chung, San-Lin; Wang, Yaw-Huei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Surprise vs anticipated information announcements: Are prices affected differently? An investigation in the context of stock splits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hwang, Soosung; Keswani, Aneel; Shackleton, Mark B.
We compare the long run reaction to anticipated and surprise information announcements using stock splits. Although there is underreaction in both cases, anticipated splits are treated differently to those that are unforeseen. After anticipated splits, cumulative abnormal returns peak at one-and-a-half times the level observed after unanticipated splits although the time taken for the announcement to be absorbed into prices is the same. We explain the difference in underreaction by the degree to which split announcements are believed and hence invested in. The favorable signal conveyed in forecast splits is more credible owing to their better pre-split performance, resulting in a far more pronounced underreaction effect. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hwang, Soosung; Keswani, Aneel; Shackleton, Mark B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Minimum variance hedging when spot price changes are partially predictable</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ederington, Louis H.; Saias, Jesus M.
In many markets, changes in the spot price are partially predictable. We show that when this is the case: (1) although unbiased, traditional regression estimates of the minimum variance hedge ratio are inefficient, (2) estimates of the riskiness of both hedged and unhedged positions are biased upward, and (3) estimates of the percentage risk reduction achievable through hedging are biased downward. For natural gas cross hedges, we find that both the inefficiency and bias are substantial. We further find that incorporating the expected change in the spot price, as measured by the futures-spot price spread at the beginning of the hedge, into the regression results in a substantial increase in efficiency and reduction in the bias. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ederington, Louis H.; Saias, Jesus M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The behaviour of the real exchange rate: Evidence from regression quantiles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nikolaou, Kleopatra
We test for mean reversion in real exchange rates using a recently developed unit root test for non-normal processes based on quantile autoregression inference in semi-parametric and non-parametric settings. The quantile regression approach allows us to directly capture the impact of different magnitudes of shocks that hit the real exchange rate, conditional on its past history, and can detect asymmetric, dynamic adjustment of the real exchange rate towards its long run equilibrium. It, therefore provides a detailed mapping of the real exchange rate behaviour, while being a robust alternative to previous unit root tests. The latter is confirmed by a simulation analysis comparing the power of the alternative tests. As concerns the real exchange rate, our results suggest that large shocks tend to induce strong mean reverting tendencies in the exchange rate, with half lives less than one year in the extreme quantiles. Mean reversion is faster when large shocks originate at points of large real exchange rate deviations from the long run equilibrium. However, in the absence of shocks no mean reversion is observed. Finally, we report asymmetries in the dynamic adjustment of the RER. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nikolaou, Kleopatra</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Federal Home Loan Bank membership and advances increase bank risk-taking?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stojanovic, Dusan; Vaughan, Mark D.; Yeager, Timothy J.
Since the early 1990s, commercial banks have turned to Federal Home Loan Bank (FHLBank) advances to plug the gap between loan and deposit growth. Is this trend worrisome? On the one hand, advances implicitly encourage risk by insulating borrowers from market discipline. On the other, advances give borrowers greater flexibility to managing interest rate and liquidity risk. And access to FHLBank funding encourages members to reshape their balance sheets in ways that could lower credit risk. Using quarterly financial and supervisory data for banks from 1992 to 2065, we assess the effect of FHLBank membership and advances on risk. The evidence suggests liquidity and leverage risks rose modestly, but interest-rate risk declined somewhat. Credit risk and overall failure risk were largely unaffected. Although the evidence suggest FHLBank membership and advances have had, at best, only a modest impact on bank risk, we caution that our sample period constitutes one observation and that moral hazard could be pronounced if leverage ratios revert to historical norms. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Stojanovic, Dusan; Vaughan, Mark D.; Yeager, Timothy J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of the implications of uncertainty and agency problems on the wealth effects to acquirers of private firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mantecon, Tomas
Extensive empirical work shows that bidders do not gain from the acquisition of publicly traded targets but experience positive excess returns in the acquisition of privately held firms. This study investigates how two important differences between private and public firms, namely, informational uncertainty and ownership characteristics, impact the returns to acquirers. A sample of targets that were acquired shortly after filing for an IPO was collected to circumvent the lack of information on private firms. In spite of the special characteristics of these targets, the listing effect is still prevalent in this sample. The results of the analysis are consistent with the hypothesis that acquirers gain in the acquisition of private firms because these targets have a relatively weaker bargaining position due to informational and agency problems and costly access to external capital markets to finance growth opportunities. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mantecon, Tomas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of shorting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nilsson, Roland
This paper assesses the effects of short-sale constraints on asset prices. The analysis focuses on a particular period in Sweden during which shorting stocks was impossible but stock options were traded. Firstly, the effect on both stock options and the underlying stock was investigated jointly by considering deviations from put-call-parity. Secondly, the effects on only the derivatives were investigated by considering their implied volatilites. The main findings are: (i) the impact on pricing are consistent with a short-sale constraint, (ii) these effects are much more pronounced when shorting is not possible, (iii) these effects are not solely attributable to the mispricing of the stock, as previous research indicates, and (iv) access to international shorting markets can alleviate local short-sale constraints. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Nilsson, Roland</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Operational risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jarrow, Robert A.
This paper provides an economic and mathematical characterization of operational risk useful for clarifying the issues related to estimation and the determination of economic capital. The insights for this characterization originate in the corporate finance literature. Operational risk is subdivided into two types, either: (i) the risk of a loss due to the firm's operating technology, or (ii) the risk of a loss due to agency costs. These two types of operational risks generate loss processes with different economic characteristics. We argue that the current methodology for the determination of economic capital for operational risk is overstated. It is biased high because the computation omits the bank's net present value (NPV) generating process. We also show that although it is conceptually possible to estimate the operational risk processes' parameters using only market prices, the non-observability of the firm's value makes this an unlikely possibility, except in rare cases. Instead, we argue that data internal to the firm, in conjunction with standard hazard rate estimation procedures, provides a more fruitful alternative. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jarrow, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What drives credit dollarization in transition economies?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Luca, Alina; Petrova, Iva
This paper provides an in-depth analysis of the use of foreign currencies in the lending activities of banks in transition economies. The impact of bank and firm variables on credit dollarization is studied in an optimal portfolio allocation model and estimated using new aggregate data for 21 transition economies for the period 1990-2003. Empirical results provide evidence that credit dollarization is the combined outcome of domestic deposit dollarization and banks' desire for currency-matched portfolios beyond regulatory requirements. The effects of international financial factors and natural hedges are less robust across alternative specifications. The paper further discusses the role of regulations in affecting the impact of these factors on credit dollarization and calls for more developed domestic forward foreign exchange markets. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Luca, Alina; Petrova, Iva</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive option exercises and financial misreporting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burns, Natasha; Kedia, Simi
Several recent papers document that the magnitude of potential gains from stock-based compensation is positively related to the likelihood of misreporting. In a sample of firms that announce restatements of their financial statements from 1997 to 2002, we examine whether managers realize these potential gains occurring from their accounting choices. After controlling for diversification needs and stock price impact, we find no significant evidence of higher option exercises by executives in the misreported years. However, for firms that are more likely to have made deliberate aggressive accounting choices, we find significant evidence of higher option exercises. For these firms, option exercises are higher by 20-60% in comparison to industry and size matched nonrestating firms. Options exercises by executives are also increasing in the magnitude of the restatement as captured by the effect of the restatement on net income. These higher option exercises tend to be more pervasive and are not just confined to the CEO and CFO of the firm. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Burns, Natasha; Kedia, Simi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank efficiency and foreign ownership: Do good institutions matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lensink, Robert; Meesters, Aljar; Naaborg, Ilko
This paper contributes to the literature on foreign ownership and bank efficiency by examining whether the efficiency of foreign banks depends on the institutional quality of the host country and on institutional differences between the home and host country. Using stochastic frontier analysis for a sample of 2095 commercial banks in 105 countries for the years 1998-2003, we find that foreign ownership negatively affects bank efficiency. However, in countries with good governance this negative effect is less pronounced. We also find that higher quality of the institutions in the home country and higher similarity between home and host country institutional quality reduce foreign bank inefficiency. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lensink, Robert; Meesters, Aljar; Naaborg, Ilko</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An examination of Value Line's long-term projections</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Szakmary, Andrew C.; Conover, C. Mitchell; Lancaster, Carol
Unlike previous papers, which have focused on the timeliness ranks, we examine Value Line's 3-5 year projections for stock returns, earnings, sales and related measures. We find that Value Line's stock return and earnings forecasts exhibit large positive bias, although their sales predictions do not. For stock returns, Value Line's projections lack predictive power; for other variables predictive power may exist to some degree. Our findings suggest the spectacular past performance of the timeliness indicator reflects either close alignment with other known anomalies or data mining, and that investors and researchers should use Value Line's long-term projections with caution. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Szakmary, Andrew C.; Conover, C. Mitchell; Lancaster, Carol</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity market information, bank holding company risk, and market discipline</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Curry, Timothy J.; Fissel, Gary S.; Hanweek, Gerald A.
For market discipline to be effective, market factors such as changes in firm equity and debt values and returns, must influence firm decision making. In banking, this can occur directly via bank management or indirectly though supervisory examinations and oversight influencing bank management. In this study, we investigate whether equity market variables can provide timely information and add value to accounting models that predict changes in bank holding company (BOPEC) risk ratings over the 1988-2000 period. Using a variety of equity market indicators, the findings suggest that one-quarter lagged market data adds forecast value to lagged financial statement data and prior supervisory information in the logistic regressions. Furthermore, using extensive out-of-sample testing for the years 2001-2003, we find: (1) that multiple models estimated over different phases of the business and banking cycles are superior to a single model for forecasting BOPEC rating changes; (2) that equity data adds economically significant power in forecasting BOPEC rating upgrades and performs well for identifying no changes; (3) that for downgrades, the accounting model forecasts the best; (4) that modeling the three possible risk ratings categories simultaneously (downgrade, no change and upgrade) minimizes both Type I and Type II classification errors; and (5) that using multiple models to forecast risk ratings enhances the overall percentage of correct classifications. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Curry, Timothy J.; Fissel, Gary S.; Hanweek, Gerald A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Share reacquisitions, surplus cash, and agency problems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oswald, Dennis; Young, Steven
Share repurchases help alleviate agency costs of surplus cash by restricting management's scope to waste corporate resources. But why do self-interested managers agree to disgorge surplus cash in the first place? This study examines the intervening effect of managerial monitoring and incentive alignment mechanisms on the decision to distribute excess cash through a share repurchase. Findings indicate that repurchases substitute for cash retention decisions that would otherwise prove costly for shareholders, and that better managerial incentive alignment and closer monitoring by external shareholders are important factors stimulating such payouts. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Oswald, Dennis; Young, Steven</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do banks overstate their Value-at-Risk?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perignon, Christophe; Deng, Zi Yin; Wang, Zhi Jun
This paper is the first empirical study of banks' risk management systems based on non-anonymous daily Value-at-Risk (VaR) and profit-and-loss data. Using actual data from the six largest Canadian commercial banks, we uncover evidence that banks exhibit a systematic excess of conservatism in their VaR estimates. The data used in this paper have been extracted from the banks' annual reports using an innovative Matlab-based data extraction method. Out of the 7354 trading days analyzed in this study, there are only two exceptions, i.e. days when the actual loss exceeds the disclosed VaR, whereas the expected number of exceptions with a 99% VaR is 74. For each sample bank, we extract from historical VaRs a risk-overstatement coefficient, ranging between 19 and 79%. We attribute VaR overstatement to several factors, including extreme cautiousness and underestimation of diversification effects when aggregating VaRs across business lines and/or risk categories. We also discuss the economic and social cost of reporting inflated VaRs. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Perignon, Christophe; Deng, Zi Yin; Wang, Zhi Jun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonlinear mean reversion in stock prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Demirtas, K. Ozgur; Levy, Haim
This paper provides new evidence on the time-series predictability of stock market returns by introducing a test of nonlinear mean reversion. The performance of extreme daily returns is evaluated in terms of their power to predict short- and long-horizon returns on various stock market indices and size portfolios. The paper shows that the speed of mean reversion is significantly higher during the large falls of the market. The parameter estimates indicate a negative and significant relation between the monthly portfolio returns and the extreme daily returns observed over the past one to eight months. Specifically, in a quarter in which the minimum daily return is -2% the expected excess return is 37 basis points higher than in a month in which the minimum return is only -1%. This result holds for the value-weighted and equal-weighted stock market indices and for each of the size decile portfolios. The findings are also robust to different sample periods, different indices, and investment horizons. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Demirtas, K. Ozgur; Levy, Haim</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity market timing and capital structure: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mahajan, Arvind; Tartaroglu, Semih
We investigate the equity market timing hypothesis of capital structure in major industrialized (G-7) countries. As claimed by its proponents, we find that leverage of firms is negatively related to the historical market-to-book ratio in all G-7 countries. However, this negative relationship cannot be attributed to equity market timing. We find no association between equity issues and market-to-book ratios at the time of equity financing decisions by Japanese firms. Firms in all G-7 countries, except Japan, undo the effect of equity issuance and the impact of equity market timing attempts on leverage is short lived. This is inconsistent with the prediction of the equity market timing hypothesis and more in line with dynamic trade-off model. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mahajan, Arvind; Tartaroglu, Semih</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge fund pricing and model uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vrontos, Spyridon D.; Vrontos, Loannis D.; Giamouridis, Daniel
This article uses Bayesian model averaging to study model uncertainty in hedge fund pricing. We show how to incorporate heteroscedasticity, thus, we develop a framework that jointly accounts for model uncertainty and heteroscedasticity. Relevant risk factors are identified and compared with those selected through standard model selection techniques. The analysis reveals that a model selection strategy that accounts for model uncertainty in hedge fund pricing regressions can be superior in estimation/inference. We explore potential impacts of our approach by analysing individual funds and show that they can be economically important. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vrontos, Spyridon D.; Vrontos, Loannis D.; Giamouridis, Daniel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Euro exchange rates follow a martingale? Some out-of-sample evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Jian; Su, Xiaojing; Kolari, James W.
Traditional autocorrelation and variance ratio tests are based on serial uncorrelatedness rather than martingale difference. As such, they do not capture potential nonlinearity-in-mean, which could lead to misleading inferences in favor of the martingale hypothesis. This paper employs various parametric and nonparametric nonlinear models as well as several model comparison criteria to examine the potential martingale behavior of Euro exchange rates in the context of out-of-sample forecasts. The overall evidence indicates that, while martingale behavior cannot be rejected for Euro exchange rates with major currencies such as the Japanese yen, British pound, and US dollar, there is nonlinear predictability in terms of economic criteria with respect to several smaller currencies. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yang, Jian; Su, Xiaojing; Kolari, James W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The economic determinants of interest rate option smiles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deuskar, Prachi; Gupta, Anurag; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.
We address three questions relating to the interest rate options market: What is the shape of the smile? What are the economic determinants of the shape of the smile? Do these determinants have predictive power for the future shape of the smile and vice versa? We investigate these issues using daily bid and ask prices of euro (sic) interest rate caps/floors. We find a clear smile pattern in interest rate options. The shape of the smile varies over time and is affected in a dynamic manner by yield curve variables and the future uncertainty in the interest rate markets; it also has information about future aggregate default risk. Our findings are useful for the pricing, hedging and risk management of these derivatives. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Deuskar, Prachi; Gupta, Anurag; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset restructuring strategies in bank acquisitions: Does distance between dealing partners matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alessandrini, Pietro; Calcagnini, Giorgio; Zazzaro, Alberto
One of the most lively-debated effects of banking acquisitions is the change in lending and asset allocation of the target bank in favour of transaction-based products, at the expense of small and informationally opaque borrowers. These changes may be the result of two distinct restructuring strategies pursued by the acquirer with respect to the asset portfolio of the acquired bank: a cleaning strategy (CS), in which the acquirer makes a clean sweep of all the negative net present value activities in the portfolio of the acquired bank, and a portfolio strategy (PS), in which the acquiring bank permanently changes the portfolio allocation of the acquired bank. In this paper we focus on Italian bank acquisitions and test which asset restructuring strategy was predominantly pursued over the period 1997-2003. Moreover, we distinguish acquisitions according to their geographic diversifying character and to the physical and cultural distances that separate acquiring from acquired banks. When we look at the mean value, we do not find clear evidence of a primacy either of CSs or PSs. When we separate in-market from out-of-market bank acquisitions, however, results show that the CSs prevail only in the former type of deals, while in the latter the portfolio of acquired banks is subject to PSs. Finally, we find that differences in asset restructuring strategies can be explained by differences in corporate culture and the workplace environment of the dealing partners. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alessandrini, Pietro; Calcagnini, Giorgio; Zazzaro, Alberto</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance and development: Is Schumpeter's analysis still relevant?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertocco, Giancarlo
In recent years, numerous studies have been published highlighting the role of financial structures in the development process of contemporary economies. In these recent studies, there is always a reference to the pioneering work of Schumpeter; in particular in the writings of Rajan and Zingales [Rajan, R., Zingales, L. 2003a. Banks and markets: The changing character of european finance, NBER Working Paper Series, No. 9595, March; Rajan, R., Zingales, L. 2003b. The great reversal: The politics of financial development in the twentieth century, Journal of Financial Economics 69, 5-50; Rajan, R., Zingales, L. 2003c. Saving Capitalism from Capitalist, Crown Business Division of Random House, New York], important elements of Schumpeter's theoretical framework are used. These works afford us an interesting opportunity to re-evaluate the importance of Schumpeter's contribution. The thesis put forward in this paper is that while they do indeed highlight important elements of Schumpeter's theory, Rajan and Zingales do not take the implications thereof into account and, furthermore, they neglect certain fundamental aspects of the Schumpeterian analysis that are closely connected with the parts that they consider. This renders their work incomplete, and prevents their analysis from achieving the coherence of Schumpeter's theory. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bertocco, Giancarlo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unraveling the complex interrelationships between exchange rates and fundamentals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Murphy, Austin; Zhu, Yun
This research investigates the intrinsic characteristics of currency values by fundamentally decomposing investor expectations on 16 currencies. The results on 195 exchange rates over several decades indicate investors perceive countries to be more likely to choose devaluation solutions to BOP problems when inflation is lower and when an alternative drop in real income growth is more "painful". In addition, empirical support is provided for the hypothesis that forward rates often appear biased because the distributional expectations incorporated into them include, for a country with a current account deficit, a small probability of a large spot decline that does not actually occur in most finite samples. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Murphy, Austin; Zhu, Yun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit booms, monetary integration and the new neoclassical synthesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Backe, Peter; Wojcik, Cezary
Credit to the private sector has risen rapidly in many new Central and Eastern European EU Member States (nMS) in recent years. The lending boom has recently been particularly strong in the segment of loans to households, primarily mortgage-based housing loans, and in those countries that operate currency boards or other forms of hard pegs. The main aim of this paper is to propose a conceptual framework to analyze the observed developments with a view to exploring some policy implications at a stage in which these countries are preparing for their prospective integration with the euro area. To achieve this, we first use a stylized new neoclassical synthesis (NNS) framework, which has recently been advanced by Goodfriend [Goodfriend, M., 2002. Monetary policy in the new neoclassical synthesis: A primer, Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond, July.] and Goodfriend and King [Goodfriend, M., King, R., 2001. The case for price stability. NBER Working Paper 8423]. We then discuss the implications of the NNS model for credit dynamics and ensuing monetary policy challenges. Specifically, we emphasize consumption smoothing as an important channel of the observed credit expansion and we show how it is related to and how it affects the monetary policy making in MS. In doing so, we place our discussion in the context of the monetary integration process in general and the nominal convergence process in particular. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Backe, Peter; Wojcik, Cezary</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The evolution of the January effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moller, Nicholas; Zilca, Shlomo
This paper extends recent studies of the January effect by investigating the evolution of the daily pattern of the effect across size deciles. Our evidence documents a sizable mean reverting component beginning in the latter part of January and a shorter duration of the seasonal effect. Despite lower abnormal returns in the second part of January, higher abnormal returns in the first part of January keeps the magnitude of the January effect unchanged. Further analysis of daily trading volumes suggests a stable trading volume intensity in the first part of January and a substantial decline in trading volume intensity in the second part of January. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moller, Nicholas; Zilca, Shlomo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Improving performance of corporate rating prediction models by reducing financial ratio heterogeneity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Niemann, Martin; Schmidt, Jan Hendrik; Neukirchen, Max
We introduce a new approach to improve the performance of rating prediction models for multinational corporations. In this segment, the low number of defaults poses a challenge, as it prevents rating models to be constructed for individual industry sectors or regions. We show that reducing group-level heterogeneity in financial ratios results in a rating prediction model with better performance than both unadjusted models and models adjusted by including industry dummies or other simpler procedures. Our approach fills a gap in cases where a limited dataset does not permit the construction of separate models for individual industries or regions. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Niemann, Martin; Schmidt, Jan Hendrik; Neukirchen, Max</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-listing and liquidity in emerging market stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Silva, Ana Cristina; Chavez, Gonzalo A.
In this study, we analyze liquidity costs for stocks and ADRs from the four main Latin American markets. The results indicate that international investors are exposed to different trading costs in Latin America, with market location and firm size as important determinants. In the local market, stocks that cross-list internationally do not always present a liquidity cost advantage relative to non-cross-listed stocks. When the ADR and the local stock markets are compared, large firms present lower trading costs in the home market. The opposite occurs for small firms. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Silva, Ana Cristina; Chavez, Gonzalo A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does liberalization reduce agency costs? Evidence from the Indian banking sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghosh, Chinmoy; Harding, John; Phani, B. V.
On February 16, 2002, the Reserve Bank of India issued a circular that signaled a policy liberalization facilitating acquisition of private sector banks in India by foreign entities. Portfolios of private sector and nationalized banks posted significant value gains in the days surrounding the announcement. The gains by private sector banks were almost double those of nationalized banks. We further analyze the firm specific abnormal returns using cross-sectional regressions and find a significant relation between firm-specific abnormal returns and factors typically associated with a bank's potential for takeover. These results provide the first empirical support for Stulz's hypothesis that one cause of the valuation gains associated with liberalization is the expected gain from a reduction of agency costs. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ghosh, Chinmoy; Harding, John; Phani, B. V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment principles for individual retirement accounts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malliaris, A. G.; Malliaris, Mary E.
The phenomenal growth of individual retirement accounts in the US, and globally, challenges both individuals and their advisors to rationally manage these investments. The two essential differences between an individual retirement account and an institutional portfolio are the length of the investment horizon and the regularity of monthly contributions. The purpose of this paper is to contrast principles of institutional investing with the management of individual retirement accounts. Using monthly historical data from 1926 to 2005 we evaluate the suitability for managing individual retirement portfolios of seven principles employed in institutional investing. We discover that some of these guidelines can be beneficially applied to the investment management of individual retirement accounts while others need to be reconsidered. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Malliaris, A. G.; Malliaris, Mary E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal pension insurance design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doskeland, Trond M.; Nordahl, Helge A.
In this paper we analyze how the traditional life and pension contracts with a guaranteed rate of return can be optimized to increase customers' welfare. Given that the contracts have to be priced correctly, we use individuals' preferences to find the preferred design. Assuming CRRA utility, we cannot explain the existence of any form of guarantees. Through numerical solutions we quantify the difference (measured in certainty equivalents) to the preferred Merton solution of direct investments in a fixed proportion of risky and risk free assets. The largest welfare loss seems to come from the fact that guarantees are effective by the end of each year, not only by the expiry of the contract. However, the demand for products with guarantees may be explained through behavioral models. We use cumulative prospect theory as an example, showing that the optimal design is a simple contract with a life-time guarantee and no default option. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Doskeland, Trond M.; Nordahl, Helge A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the empirics of international smoothing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asdrubali, Pierfederico; Kim, Soyoung
By fully exploiting the statistical properties of panel data, this paper improves upon existing methodologies to estimate consumption smoothing at least in three respects. First, we model explicitly incomplete risksharing as well as incomplete intertemporal smoothing, and couch the two mechanisms in a unified framework. Second, we fully exploit simple panel data analysis in order to measure degrees of both risksharing and intertemporal smoothing taking place in a given set of economic regions. In particular, we are able to measure not only the smoothing of idiosyncratic shocks, but also the dependence on aggregate (non-diversitiable) shocks. Third, we distinguish neatly between the effects of temporary vs. permanent shocks. This can be done by taking advantage of the complementarity between the within" estimator and the "between" estimator in a panel regression. We apply the above methodology to a panel of 23 OECD countries in the period from 1955 to 2005. The main finding is consistent with the puzzle of negligible international risksharing, as domestic consumption growth - once properly analyzed - does not depend on aggregate income growth. Our analysis shows that industrial countries have tended to absorb output shocks mostly through intertemporal smoothing. About 25% of all temporary shocks are smoothed this way, while a comparable fraction of permanent shocks determine consumption growth. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Asdrubali, Pierfederico; Kim, Soyoung</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do improvements in government quality necessarily reduce the incidence of costly sudden stops?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Honig, Adam
Sudden stops have been linked to a number of financial crises in emerging market countries. While a large literature has developed emphasizing the importance of institutions and governance in reducing economic volatility, this paper finds that the effect of government quality on the incidence of sudden stops is non-linear. Initial improvements in governance actually increase the incidence of costly sudden stops. A possible explanation is that improved governance encourages capital inflows that can overwhelm banking systems in countries with weak institutions. What is striking is that this result holds for a large number of countries including those with average levels of institutional quality that already receive considerable inflows. Eventually, however, improving institutions does reduce the frequency of sudden stops, allowing countries to enjoy the benefits of financial globalization with fewer risks. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Honig, Adam</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do policy and information shocks impact co-movements of China's T-bond and stock markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Xiao-Ming; Zou, Li-Ping
We investigate the impacts of policy and information shocks on the correlation of China's T-bond and stock returns, using originally the asymmetric dynamic conditional correlation (DCC) model that allows for the coexistence of opposite-signed asymmetries. The co-movements of China's capital markets react to large macroeconomic policy shocks as evidenced by structural breaks in the correlation following the drastic 2004 macroeconomic austerity. We show that the T-bond market and the bond-stock correlations bear more of the brunt of the macroeconomic contractions. We also find that the bond-stock correlations respond more strongly to joint negative than joint positive shocks, implying that investors tend to move both the T-bond and stock prices in the same direction when the two asset classes have been hit concurrently by bad news, but tend to shift funds from one asset class to the other when hit concurrently by good news. However, the stock-stock correlation is found to increase for joint positive shocks, indicating that investors tend to herd more for joint bullish than joint bearish stock markets in Shanghai and Shenzhen. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Xiao-Ming; Zou, Li-Ping</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accounting and capital market measures of risk: Evidence from Asian banks during 1998-2003</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agusman, Agusman; Monroe, Gary S.; Gasbarro, Dominic; Zumwalt, J. K.
This study examines the relation between accounting and capital market risk measures for a sample of 46 listed Asian banks during the period 1998-2003. By applying a panel data analysis that includes a control for country-specific factors, the results show that the standard deviation of the return-on-assets and loan-loss-reserves-to-gross-loans are significantly related to total risk. Also gross-loans-to-total-assets and loan-loss-reserves-to-gross-loans are significantly related to non-systematic risk. These results indicate that in these Asian countries, firm-specific risk is more important than systematic risk and the results are robust even though significant differences exist across Asian countries in banking activities, capital adequacy requirements, and deposit insurance protection. (C) 2008 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Agusman, Agusman; Monroe, Gary S.; Gasbarro, Dominic; Zumwalt, J. K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial globalization and growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
nan</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Globalisation, growth and institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
We are currently in the second wave of globalisation. Despite the fact that over the past two decades a number of national financial and other barriers have been removed, there are still a number of national, regional and global factors that are slowing down the process of financial globalisation from trickling down to all parts of the world. This paper briefly discusses the process of globalisation and considers the human development index including education as a way of measuring economic growth and financial wealth in different parts of the world. The paper analyses the process of financial globalisation and the way some nations have become the recipients of more foreign capital than others. As a way of seeing the importance of both national and international economic and financial integration as important ingredients for sustained economic growth, the process of financial integration in Europe is analysed as a model for acceleration of the process of globalisation and sustained economic growth in this century. The 21st century is referred to as the Pacific century and hence financial integration in the Asia Pacific region (APEC) could create a new impetus for the EU to increase its internal integration including its fiscal policies as a way of remaining competitive in the global economy. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Samuelson hypothesis in futures markets: An analysis using intraday data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duong, Huu Nhan; Kalev, Petko S.
This paper considers the Samuelson hypothesis, which argues that the futures price volatility increases as the futures contract approaches its expiration. Utilizing intraday data from 20 futures markets in six futures exchanges, we find strong support for the Samuelson hypothesis in agricultural futures, However, the Samuelson hypothesis does not hold for other futures contracts, We also provide supporting evidence that the 'negative covariance' hypothesis is the key factor for the empirical support of the Samuelson hypothesis. In addition, our findings remain largely unaltered even after we control for seasonality and liquidity effects. (C) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Duong, Huu Nhan; Kalev, Petko S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Further analysis of the expectations hypothesis using very short-term rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Craig R.; Cyree, Ken B.; Griffiths, Mark D.; Winters, Drew B.
Longstaff (Longstaff, F., 2000. The term structure of very short-term rates: new evidence for the expectations hypothesis. Journal of Financial Economics 58, 397-415] finds support for the expectations hypothesis at the very short end of the repurchase agreement (repo) term structure while other studies find calendar-time-based regularities cause rejection of the expectations hypothesis. Using Longstaffs methods on a sample of repo rates that pre-dates Longstaffs sample, we reject the expectations hypothesis for every maturity. The pre-Longstaff-sample repo data comes from a time period where the behavior of short-term interest rates is similar to the long-run average behavior of short-term interest rates. Our results imply that expectations hold when rates are less volatile and/or that we may be entering a period of lower volatility. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, Craig R.; Cyree, Ken B.; Griffiths, Mark D.; Winters, Drew B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note on Chui, Gai and Haldane's "Sovereign liquidity crisis: Analytics and implications for public policy"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dreisbach, Dina; Kindermann, Fabian
This note corrects the welfare calculations in Chui, Gai and Haldane's paper on sovereign liquidity crisis [Chui, M., Gai, P., Haldane, A.G., 2002. Sovereign liquidity crisis: Analytics and implications for public policy. Journal of Banking and Finance 26, 519-544]. We show that the exact formula not only dramatically reduces the computed welfare consequences from 66% of ex-ante expected output to roughly 13%, but also changes the direction of some reported comparative static results. In addition, we clarify the difference between fundamentals-driven and belief-driven welfare costs and extend some of the sensitivity calculations. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dreisbach, Dina; Kindermann, Fabian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modelling the term structure of interest rates: An efficient nonparametric approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gomez-Valle, Lourdes; Martinez-Rodriguez, Julia
We propose a new approach for estimating the coefficients of the term structure equation by means of the volatility of the interest rates and the slope of the yield curve. One advantage of this approach consists in the fact that the drift and the market price of risk are jointly estimated and need not be individually specified. We then generate trajectories in a test problem to investigate the finite properties of this approach. Our simulation results show that this new approach outperforms the classic nonparametric models in the literature. Finally, an application to USA Treasury Bill data is also illustrated. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gomez-Valle, Lourdes; Martinez-Rodriguez, Julia</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The informational content of unsolicited ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Behr, Patrick; Guettler, Andre
This paper investigates whether the stock market reacts to unsolicited ratings for a sample of firms rated by S&amp;P between January 1996 and December 2005. We first analyze the stock market reaction to the assignment of an initial unsolicited rating. We find evidence that this reaction is negative and particularly accentuated for small Japanese firms. We then analyze the stock market reaction to changes in unsolicited ratings for a Japanese sub-sample and find that here too the stock market reacts negatively. Our results imply that unsolicited ratings convey new information to the stock market and that investors react to this information. Although unsolicited ratings are based on publicly available information only, the stock market seems to be inefficient in processing this information for Japanese companies. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Behr, Patrick; Guettler, Andre</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Detecting abnormal credit union performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bauer, Keldon
Credit unions are an important financial intermediary, but little credit union research is done. A primary reason for the lack of research is the cooperative nature of the industry, making traditional methods of detecting abnormal performance inappropriate. This paper proposes two methods of detecting abnormal performance, one parametric, the other non-parametric. Instead of testing the efficiency of the institution, this paper proposes testing the return vector, as indicated in the theoretical objective function of the member. Simulations demonstrate that both methods are correctly specified and powerful. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bauer, Keldon</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"Hot Hands" in bond funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huij, Joop; Derwall, Jeroen
We investigate persistence in the relative performance of 3549 bond mutual funds from 1990 to 2003. We show that bond funds that display strong (weak) performance over a past period continue to do so in future periods. The out-of-sample difference in risk-adjusted return between the top and bottom decile of funds ranked on past alpha exceeds 3.5 percent per year. We demonstrate that a strategy based on past fund returns earns an economically and statistically significant abnormal return, suggesting that bond fund investors can exploit the observed persistence. Our results are robust to a wide range of model specifications and bootstrapped test statistics. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huij, Joop; Derwall, Jeroen</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum profits and time-varying unsystematic risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Xiafei; Miffre, Joelle; Brooks, Chris; O'Sullivan, Niall
This study assesses whether the widely documented momentum profits can be attributed to time-varying risk as described by a GJR-GARCH(1,1)-M model. We reveal that momentum profits are a compensation for time-varying unsystematic risks, which are common to the winner and loser stocks but affect the former more than the latter. In addition, we find that, perhaps because losers have a higher propensity than winners to disclose bad news, negative return shocks increase their volatility more than they increase those of the winners. The volatility of the losers is also found to respond to news more slowly, but eventually to a greater extent, than that of the winners. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Li, Xiafei; Miffre, Joelle; Brooks, Chris; O'Sullivan, Niall</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is it the weather?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobsen, Ben; Marquering, Wessel
We show that results in the recent strand of the literature, which tries to explain stock returns by weather induced mood shifts of investors, might be data-driven inference. More specifically, we consider two recent studies [Kamstra, Mark J., Kramer, Lisa A., Levi, Maurice D., 2003a. Winter blues: A SAD stock market cycle. American Economic Review 93(l), 324-343; Cao, Melanie, Wei, Jason, 2005. Stock market returns: A note on temperature anomaly. Journal of Banking and Finance 29(6), 1559-1573] that claim that a seasonal anomaly in stock returns is caused by mood changes of investors due to lack of daylight and temperature variations, respectively. While we confirm earlier results in the literature that there is indeed a strong seasonal effect in stock returns in many countries: stock market returns tend to be significantly lower during summer and fall months than during winter and spring months as documented by Bouman and Jacobsen [Bouman, Sven, Jacobsen, Ben, 2002. The Halloween indicator, Sell in May and go away: Another puzzle. American Economic Review, 92(5), 1618-1635], there is little evidence in favor of a SAD or temperature explanation. In fact, we find that a simple winter/summer dummy best describes this seasonality. Our results suggest that without any further evidence the correlation between weather-related variables and stock returns might be spurious and the conclusion that weather affects stock returns through mood changes of investors is premature. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jacobsen, Ben; Marquering, Wessel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock exchange demutualization, self-listing and performance: The case of the Australian Stock Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Otchere, Isaac; Abou-Zied, Khaled
This paper examines the effects of the recent spate of financial exchange mutual-to-stock conversion phenomenon on the performance of listed exchanges and the quality of the stock market using the Australian Stock Exchange (ASX) as a case study. We find that the ASX stock significantly outperformed the stock index and the control group on a market-adjusted return basis. The stock market performance is driven by strong operating performance. The profitability ratios of the ASX have significantly improved in the five years following the demutualization and self-listing. The performance improvements remain significant even after controlling for growth in the Australian economy. From a market quality perspective, we document evidence of increased trading activity by foreign investors after ASX's demutualization and self-listing. Interestingly, we also find that bid-ask spreads of the stock market have narrowed in the post-conversion period. In particular, small-cap firms have become more liquid. The results show that stock exchange conversion from mutual to publicly traded exchange is not only value enhancing for the exchange and its shareholders, but it is also beneficial for the stock market as a whole. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Otchere, Isaac; Abou-Zied, Khaled</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary policy transparency and pass-through of retail interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Ming-Hua; Margaritis, Dimitri; Tourani-Rad, Alireza
This paper examines the degree of pass-through and adjustment speed of retail interest rates in response to changes in benchmark market rates in New Zealand during the period 1994-2004. We consider the effects of policy transparency and financial structure of the monetary transmission mechanism. New Zealand is the first OECD country to adopt a full-fledged inflation targeting regime with specific accountability and transparency provisions. Policy transparency was further enhanced by a shift from quantity (settlement cash) to price (interest rate) operating targets in 1999. Using Phillips-Loretan estimates of cointegrating regressions we find complete long-term pass-through for some but not all retail rates. Our results also show that the introduction of the Official Cash Rate (OCR) increased the pass-through of floating and deposit rates but not fixed mortgage rates. In line with previous studies we find the immediate pass-through of market interest rates to bank retail rates to be incomplete. Although we find no statistical evidence for asymmetric response of retail rates to changes in market rates other than for business lending rates in the pre OCR period, differences in the magnitude of mean adjustment lags indicate that banks appear to pass on decreases to fixed mortgage rates faster. Overall, our results confirm that monetary policy rate has more influence on short-term interest rates and that increased transparency has lowered instrument volatility and enhanced the efficacy of policy. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Ming-Hua; Margaritis, Dimitri; Tourani-Rad, Alireza</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Globalization and financial services in emerging economies - Editorial</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
nan</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric information and the mode of entry in foreign credit markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Van Tassel, Eric; Vishwasrao, Sharmila
in a newly liberalized credit market, foreign banks with cost advantages are likely to be less informed than domestic banks that hold information on credit risks. These relative advantages may generate incentives for a foreign bank to negotiate acquisition of a domestic bank in order to capture information endowments. However, if it is difficult to assess the value of information held by banks, the foreign bank will face important choices about the optimal Diode of entry and what acquisition price to pay. These choices have implications for the survival of domestic banks and how capital is allocated after liberalization. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Van Tassel, Eric; Vishwasrao, Sharmila</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does IT investment improve bank performance? Evidence from Europe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beccalli, Elena
This paper investigates whether investment in information technology (IT) - hardware, software and other IT services - influences the performance of banks. Using a sample of 737 European banks over the period 1995-2000 we analyse whether IT investment is reflected in improved performance (measured using both standard accounting ratios and cost and alternative profit efficiency measures). Despite banks being major investors in IT we find little relationship between total IT investment and improved bank profitability or efficiency indicating the existence of a profitability paradox. However, the impact of different types of IT investment (hardware, software and services) on banks' performance is heterogeneous. Investment in IT services from external providers (consulting services, implementation services, training and education, support services) appears to have a positive influence on accounting profits and profit efficiency, while the acquisition of hardware and software seems to reduce banks' performance. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beccalli, Elena</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analysing the determinants of performance of best and worst European banks: A mixed logit approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barros, Carlos Pestana; Ferreira, Candida; Williams, Jonathan
Using a dataset of 7635 observations on 1384 commercial banks operating in the EU between 1993 and 2001, we utilise a mixed logit model to identify factors that explain the probability of a bank being a best [worst] performer. The empirical evidence confirms the importance of country-level characteristics (location and legal tradition), and firm-level features (bank ownership, balance sheet structure and size). Specifically, smaller sized banks with higher loan-intensity, and foreign banks from countries upholding common law traditions have a higher probability of best performance. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barros, Carlos Pestana; Ferreira, Candida; Williams, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do cross-country differences in bank efficiency support a policy of "national champions"?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carbo Valverde, Santiago; Humphrey, David B.; Lopez del Paso, Rafael
As banking consolidation proceeds and Europe moves toward a single market, cross-country differences in banking efficiency can affect the future competitive position of a country's financial market, helping to determine which European money centers may expand or contract. Looking at large banks across 10 countries, we find they are roughly equally efficient after controlling for differences in business environment, banking costs, and bank productivity. As no country seems to have a strong efficiency advantage, it seems likely that state efforts to promote "national champions" through favorable mergers which expand scale and market share may determine the outcome. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carbo Valverde, Santiago; Humphrey, David B.; Lopez del Paso, Rafael</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder value efficiency in European banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fiordelisi, Franco
This paper advances the studies of [Hughes, J.P., Lang W.W., Mester L.J., Moon C.G., Pagano M.S., 2003. Do bankers sacrifice value to build empires? Managerial incentives, industry consolidation, and financial performance. Journal of Banking and Finance 27, 417-447] by developing a new measure of bank performance which we refer to as "shareholder value efficiency" - a bank producing the maximum possible Economic Value Added (EVA), given particular inputs and outputs, is defined as "shareholder value efficient". This new efficiency measure is estimated using the stochastic frontier method focussing on the French, German, Italian and UK banking systems over the period 1997-2002 and includes both listed and non-listed banks. We find that European banks are, on average, 36% shareholder value inefficient. Shareholder value efficiency is found to be the most important factor explaining value creation in European banking, whereas cost and profit efficiency only have a marginal influence. (c) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Fiordelisi, Franco</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership structure, risk and performance in the European banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iannotta, Giuliano; Nocera, Giacomo; Sironi, Andrea
We compare the performance and risk of a sample of 181 large banks from 15 European countries over the 1999-2004 period and evaluate the impact of alternative ownership models, together with the degree of ownership concentration, on their profitability, cost efficiency and risk. Three main results emerge. First, after controlling for bank characteristics, country and time effects, mutual banks and government-owned banks exhibit a lower profitability than privately owned banks, in spite of their lower costs. Second, public sector banks have poorer loan quality and higher insolvency risk than other types of banks while mutual banks have better loan quality and lower asset risk than both private and public sector banks. Finally, while ownership concentration does not significantly affect a bank's profitability, a higher ownership concentration is associated with better loan quality, lower asset risk and lower insolvency risk. These differences, along with differences in asset composition and funding mix, indicate a different financial intermediation model for the different ownership forms. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Iannotta, Giuliano; Nocera, Giacomo; Sironi, Andrea</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cost of market power in banking: Social welfare loss vs. cost inefficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maudos, Joaquin; Fernandez de Guevara, Juan
This paper analyses the relationship between market power in the loan and deposit markets and efficiency in the EU-15 countries over 1993-2002. Results show the existence of a positive relationship between market power and cost X-efficiency, allowing rejection of the so-called quiet life hypothesis [Berger, A.N, Hannan, T.H., 1998. The efficiency cost of market power in the banking industry: A test of the 'quiet life' and related hypotheses. Review of Economics and Statistics 8 (3), 454-465]. The social welfare loss attributable to market power in 2002 represented 0.54% of the GDP of the EU-15. Results show that the welfare gains associated with a reduction of market power are greater than the loss of bank cost efficiency, showing the importance of economic policy measures aimed at removing the barriers to outside competition. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Maudos, Joaquin; Fernandez de Guevara, Juan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Globalisation and the role of effective international institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moshirian, Fariborz
Since empirical research has demonstrated that a sound financial system drives economic growth and the reverse causality alone is not causing this relationship, one can well extend this causal relationship to a global financial system and also argue that those factors that are limiting stronger economic growth and financial globalisation are partly related to deficiencies of the current global financial system. In the same way that some studies have argued for the significance of high quality national institutions as a way of addressing some of the national social and economic bottlenecks and also as a way of creating the right environment for sustained economic growth and integration into the global markets, high quality international institutions with adequate mandates and effective executive power can also influence the process of regional and global financial integration. These international institutions can accelerate the process of national institutional reforms. The paper argues that a number of financial barriers limiting financial globalisation have in essence international, regional and national components and hence without a globally coordinated strategy and framework to have parallel reforms at three levels, the limits to financial globalisation may remain for the foreseeable future. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moshirian, Fariborz</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mean-variance portfolio selection with 'at-risk' constraints and discrete distributions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, Gordon J.; Baptista, Alexandre M.; Yan, Shu
We examine the impact of adding either a VaR or a CVaR constraint to the mean-variance model when security returns are assumed to have a discrete distribution with finitely many jump points. Three main results are obtained. First, portfolios on the VaR-constrained boundary exhibit (K + 2)-fund separation, where K is the number of states for which the portfolios suffer losses equal to the VaR bound. Second, portfolios on the CVaR-constrained boundary exhibit (K + 3)-fund separation, where K is the number of states for which the portfolios suffer losses equal to their VaRs. Third, an example illustrates that while the VaR of the CVaR-constrained optimal portfolio is close to that of the VaR-constrained optimal portfolio, the CVaR of the former is notably smaller than that of the latter. This result suggests that a CVaR constraint is more effective than a VaR constraint to curtail large losses in the mean-variance model. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alexander, Gordon J.; Baptista, Alexandre M.; Yan, Shu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Migration, spillovers, and trade diversion: The impact of internationalization on domestic stock market activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levine, Ross; Schmukler, Sergio L.
This paper studies the relation between internationalization (firms cross-listing, issuing depositary receipts, or raising capital in international stock markets) and the trading activity of the remaining firms in domestic markets. Using a panel of 3000 firms from 55 emerging economies during 19892000, we find that internationalization is negatively related to the trading activity of domestic firms. We identify two channels. First, the trading of international firms migrates from domestic to international markets and this migration along with the reduction in domestic trading of international firms has negative spillover effects on domestic firm trading activity. Second, there is trade diversion within domestic markets as trading activity shifts out of domestic firms and into international firms. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Levine, Ross; Schmukler, Sergio L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Basel's value-at-risk capital requirement regulation: An efficiency analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaplanski, Guy; Levy, Haim
We analyze the optimal portfolio policies of expected utility maximizing agents under VaR Capital Requirement (VaR-CR) regulation in comparison to the optimal policy under exogenouslyimposed VaR Limit (VaR-L) and Limited-Expected-Loss (LEL) regulations. With VaR-CR regulation the agent strategy consists of simultaneous decisions on both the portfolio VaR and on the implied amount of required eligible capital. As a result, the performance of VaR-CR regulation depends on its design (the parameter n) and the agent preferences. We show that an optimal VaR-CR regulation allows the regulator on the one hand, to completely eliminate the exposure to the largest losses, which may jeopardize the existence of the institution, and on the other hand, to restrain the portfolio exposure to all other losses. These results rationalize the current Basel regulations. However, the analysis shows also that there is an optimal level of required eligible capital from the regulator standpoint. Counter-intuitively, any requirement above this optimal level is inefficient as it leads to a smaller amount of actually maintained eligible capital and thereby to a larger exposure to the most adverse states of the world. Unfortunately, the current Basel's range of required levels (n = 3-4) is within this inefficient range. Moreover, with an inefficient regulation the agent might employ an inefficient reporting and disclosure procedure. (c) 2007 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Kaplanski, Guy; Levy, Haim</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum strategies in commodity futures markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Miffre, Joelle; Rallis, Georgios
The article tests for the presence of short-term continuation and long-term reversal in commodity futures prices. While contrarian strategies do not work, the article identifies 13 profitable momentum strategies that generate 9.38% average return a year. A closer analysis of the constituents of the long-(s)hort portfolios reveals that the momentum strategies buy backwardated contracts and sell contangoed contracts. The correlation between the momentum returns and the returns of traditional asset classes is also found to be low, making the commodity-based relative-strength portfolios excellent candidates for inclusion in well-diversified portfolios. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Miffre, Joelle; Rallis, Georgios</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Model-free hedge ratios and scale-invariant models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, Carol; Nogueira, Leonardo M.
A price process is scale-invariant if and only if the returns distribution is independent of the price measurement scale. We show that most stochastic processes used for pricing options on financial assets have this property and that many models not previously recognised as scale-invariant are indeed so. We also prove that price hedge ratios for a wide class of contingent claims under a wide class of pricing models are model-free. In particular, previous results on model-free price hedge ratios of vanilla options based on scale-invariant models are extended to any contingent claim with homogeneous pay-off, including complex, path-dependent options. However, model-free hedge ratios only have the minimum variance property in scale-invariant stochastic volatility models when price volatility correlation is zero. In other stochastic volatility models and in scale-invariant local volatility models, model-free hedge ratios are not minimum variance ratios and our empirical results demonstrate that they are less efficient than minimum variance hedge ratios. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alexander, Carol; Nogueira, Leonardo M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using self-organizing maps to adjust for intra-day seasonality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben Omrane, Walid; de Bodt, Eric
The existence of an intra-day seasonality component in financial market variables (volatility, volume, activity, etc.) has been highlighted in many previous studies. To remove this cyclical component from raw data, many researchers use the intra-day average observations model (IAOM) and/or some smoothing techniques (e.g. the kernel method). When the seasonality is related to the first moment (the conditional expectation) and involves only a deterministic component, the IAOM method succeeds in estimating the periodicity almost perfectly. However, when seasonality affects the first or the second moment (the conditional variance) of the data and contains both deterministic and stochastic components, both IAOM and the kernel method fail to capture it. We introduce self-organizing maps (SOM) as a solution. SOM are based on neural network learning and nonlinear projections. Their flexibility allows seasonality to be captured even in the presence of stochastic cycles. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ben Omrane, Walid; de Bodt, Eric</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The incentive to give incentives: On the relative seniority of debt claims and managerial compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calcagno, Riccardo; Renneboog, Luc
We show that the relative seniority of debt and managerial compensation has important implications for the design of remuneration contracts. Whereas the traditional literature assumes that debt is senior to remuneration, there are in reality many cases in which remuneration contracts are de facto senior to debt claims in financially distressed firms and in workouts. We theoretically show that risky debt changes the incentive to provide the manager with performance-related incentives (a "contract substitution" effect). In other words, the relative degree of seniority of managers' claims and creditors' claims in case a bankruptcy procedure starts is crucial to determine the optimal incentive contract ex-ante. If managerial compensation is more senior than debt, higher leverage leads to lower power incentive schemes (lower bonuses and option grants) and a higher base salary. In contrast, when compensation is junior, we expect more emphasis on pay-for-performance incentives in highly-levered firms. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Calcagno, Riccardo; Renneboog, Luc</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of institutional ownership on corporate operating performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornett, Marcia Millon; Marcus, Alan J.; Saunders, Anthony; Tehranian, Hassan
This paper examines the relation between institutional investor involvement in and the operating performance of large firms. We find a significant relation between a firm's operating cash flow returns and both the percent of institutional stock ownership and the number of institutional stockholders. However, this relation is found only for a subset of institutional investors: those less likely to have a business relationship with the firm. These results suggest that institutional investors with potential business relations with the firms in which they invest are compromised as monitors of the firm. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cornett, Marcia Millon; Marcus, Alan J.; Saunders, Anthony; Tehranian, Hassan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing for negative expected market return premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eleswarapu, Venkat R.; Thompson, Rex
This paper tests the hypothesis that the expected return premium on the market portfolio is always non-negative. A violation of this lower bound restriction provides evidence against a broad class of risk-based equilibrium models in favor of bubble behavior. Our tests utilize information variables, identified in prior literature, that predict time variation in market return premia. We employ out-of-sample forecasts and bootstraps generated with parameters that are consistent with non-negativity but closest to the estimated parameters. We find statistically reliable evidence against non-negativity for the excess return on the value-weighted market index. The most negative outof-sample prediction was -2.01% in September 1973. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eleswarapu, Venkat R.; Thompson, Rex</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market development under globalization: Whither the gains from reforms?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de la Torre, Augusto; Gozzi, Juan Carlos; Schmukler, Sergio L.
Over the past decades, many countries have implemented significant reforms (including financial liberalization, privatization, and regulatory and supervisory improvements) to foster domestic capital market development. Despite these policies, the performance of capital markets in several countries has been disappointing. To understand the effects of reforms, we study the impact of six capital market reforms on domestic stock market development and internationalization. We find that reforms tend to be followed by increases in domestic market capitalization and trading. But reforms are also followed by an increase in the share of activity in international equity markets, with potential negative spillover effects. (c) 2006 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>de la Torre, Augusto; Gozzi, Juan Carlos; Schmukler, Sergio L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Soft related lending: A tale of two Korean banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bonin, John P.; Imai, Masami
In this paper, we present indirect evidence that the IMFs insistence on foreign control of two large nationwide Korean banks in exchange for short-term support during the 1997 financial crisis helped restrain soft related lending practices. News signaling the likely sale of a bank to a foreign financial institution yields an average daily decrease of about 2% in the stock price of related borrowers. News indicating difficulty in finding an interested foreign investor generates an increase in the stock price of related borrowers of about the same magnitude. These signals have larger impacts on less-profitable, less-liquid, and more bank-dependent firms. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bonin, John P.; Imai, Masami</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International portfolio diversification benefits: Cross-country evidence from a local perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Driessen, Joost; Laeven, Luc
We investigate how the benefits of international portfolio diversification differ across countries from the perspective of a local investor. We find that the benefits of investing abroad are largest for investors in developing countries, including when controlling for currency effects. Most of the benefits are obtained from investing outside the region of the home country. These global diversification benefits remain large when controlling for short-sales constraints in developing stock markets. The gains from international portfolio diversification appear to be largest for countries with high country risk. In addition to this cross-sectional evidence, we also provide evidence that diversification benefits vary over time as country risk changes. We find that diversification benefits have decreased for most countries in our sample over the past two decades. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Driessen, Joost; Laeven, Luc</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How banks go abroad: Branches or subsidiaries?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cerutti, Eugenio; Dell'Ariccia, Giovanni; Peria, Maria Soledad Martinez
We examine the factors influencing international banks' organizational form, using an original database on the operations in Latin America and Eastern Europe of the world's top 100 banks. We find that banks are more likely to operate as branches in countries that have higher taxes and lower regulatory restrictions on bank entry and on foreign branches. Subsidiary operations are preferred by banks seeking to penetrate host markets by establishing large retail operations. Finally, economic and political risks have opposite effects, suggesting that legal differences in parent banks' responsibilities associated with branches and subsidiaries are important determinants of banks' organizational form. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cerutti, Eugenio; Dell'Ariccia, Giovanni; Peria, Maria Soledad Martinez</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>ADR holdings of US-based emerging market funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, Reena; Dahiya, Sandeep; Klapper, Leora
What motivates investors to hold American Depositary Receipts (ADRs) rather than the underlying stock of US listed foreign firms? We analyze the investment allocation decision of actively-managed emerging market mutual fund managers. Although legal provisions are typically assumed to affect ADR and its underlying domestic shares equally, investors holding ADRs may have a higher level of legal protection as these securities are issued and traded in the US. We find that ADRs are the preferred mode of holdings if the local market of the issuer has weak investor protection, low liquidity and high transaction costs. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aggarwal, Reena; Dahiya, Sandeep; Klapper, Leora</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Concentration and foreign penetration in Latin American banking sectors: Impact on competition and risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yeyati, Eduardo Levy; Micco, Alejandro
in the 1990s, Latin American banking sectors experienced an accelerated process of concentration and foreign penetration that prompted diverse views regarding its implications for the competitive behavior of banks and the financial stability of the system. In this paper, we examine these issues exploiting a rich bank-level database for eight Latin American countries. We find that, while increased concentration did not weaken banking competition within the region, foreign penetration appears to have led to a less competitive industry. Moreover, we find that bank risk has been negatively associated with competition which, coupled with the previous finding, explains the positive link between banking sector stability and foreign penetration revealed by the data. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yeyati, Eduardo Levy; Micco, Alejandro</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The mix of international banks' foreign claims: Determinants and implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Herrero, Alicia Garcia; Peria, Maria Soledad Martinez
We analyze the cross-country determinants and financial stability implications of the mix of international banks' foreign claims. We distinguish between local claims - extended by host country affiliates - and cross-border claims - booked outside the receiving country. Using data on Italian, Spanish, and US banks' foreign claims, we find that the share of local claims is driven by restrictions on banking sector openness and by local scale economies/business opportunities. The impact of limits on property rights, entry requirements, start-up and informational costs is less robust. Finally, foreign claim volatility is lower in countries with a larger share of local claims. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Herrero, Alicia Garcia; Peria, Maria Soledad Martinez</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is there a single frontier in a single European banking market?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bos, J. W. B.; Schmiedel, H.
This paper attempts to estimate comparable efficiency scores for European banks operating in the Single Market in the EU. Using a data set of more than 5000 large commercial banks from all major European banking markets over the period 1993-2004, the application of meta-frontiers enables us to assess the existence of a single and integrated European banking market. We find evidence in favor of a single European banking market characterized by cost and profit meta-frontiers. However, compared to the meta-frontier estimations, pooled frontier estimations tend to underestimate efficiency levels and correlate poorly with country-specific frontier efficiency ranks. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bos, J. W. B.; Schmiedel, H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonparametric efficiency estimation in stochastic environments: Noise-to-signal estimation, finite sample performance and hypothesis testing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Post, Thierry
This study considers the issues of noise-to-signal estimation, finite sample performance and hypothesis testing for a new nonparametric and stochastic efficiency estimation technique. We apply the technique for analyzing the efficiency of European banks from various regions and with various specializations. The technique seems well suited for this application area because banking inputs and outputs generally are measured with error, the banking production technology is not well-defined and large banking data sets such as BankScope allow for a nonparametric approach. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Post, Thierry</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of bank margins in European banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carbo Valverde, Santiago; Rodriguez Fernandez, Francisco
Most of the theoretical and empirical literature on bank margins has dealt solely with interest margins. Applying the seminal Ho-Saunders model (JFQA, 1981) to a multi-output framework, we show that the relationship between bank margins and market power varies significantly across bank specializations. In this context, European banks are a better laboratory than US banks, since they have generally enjoyed a more flexible regulatory environment in which to provide a wider range of services. Using accounting margins and New Empirical Industrial Organization margins, we find that market power increases as output becomes more diversified towards non-traditional activities in European banking. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Carbo Valverde, Santiago; Rodriguez Fernandez, Francisco</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competitive conditions among the major British banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Matthews, Kent; Murinde, Victor; Zhao, Tianshu
This paper reports an empirical assessment of competitive conditions among the major British banks, during a period of major structural change. Specifically, estimates of the Rosse-Panzar H-statistic are reported for a panel of 12 banks for the period 1980-2004. The sample banks correspond closely to the major British banking groups specified by the British Banking Association. The robustness of the results of the Rosse-Panzar methodology is tested by estimating the ratio of Lerner indices obtained from interest rate setting equations. The results confirm the consensus finding that competition in British banking is most accurately characterised by the theoretical model of monopolistic competition. There is evidence that the intensity of competition in the core market for bank lending remained approximately unchanged throughout the 1980s and 1990s. However, competition appears to have become less intense in the non-core (off-balance sheet) business of British banks. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Matthews, Kent; Murinde, Victor; Zhao, Tianshu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The limits of diversification when losses may be large</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ibragimov, Rustam; Walden, Johan
Recent results in value at risk analysis show that, for extremely heavy-tailed risks with unbounded distribution support, diversification may increase value at risk, and that generally it is difficult to construct an appropriate risk measure for such distributions. We further analyze the limitations of diversification for heavy-tailed risks. We provide additional insight in two ways. First, we show that similar non-diversification results are valid for a large class of risks with bounded support, as long as the risks are concentrated on a sufficiently large interval. The required length of the support depends on the number of risks available and on the degree of heavy-tailedness. Second, we relate the value at risk approach to more general risk frameworks. We argue that in markets for risky assets where the number of assets is limited compared with the (bounded) distribution support of the risks, unbounded heavy-tailed risks may provide a reasonable approximation. We suggest that this type of analysis may have a role in explaining various types of market failures in markets for assets with possibly large negative outcomes. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ibragimov, Rustam; Walden, Johan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>