<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Journal of Financial Economics2</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Disagreement, speculation, and aggregate investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, Steven D.; Hollifield, Burton; Osambela, Emilio
When investors disagree, speculation between them alters equilibrium prices in financial markets. Because managers maximize firm value given financial market prices, disagreement alters firms' value-maximizing investment policies. Disagreement therefore impacts aggregate investment, consumption, and output. In a production economy with recursive preferences and disasters, we demonstrate that static disagreement among investors generates dynamic aggregate investment that is positively correlated with capital shocks, leading to stochastic volatility in aggregate consumption, investment, and equity returns. The direction of these effects is consistent with business cycle facts, and with several features of the 2008 financial crisis. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Baker, Steven D.; Hollifield, Burton; Osambela, Emilio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of takeover defenses: Evidence from closed-end funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Souther, Matthew E.
I use a sample of closed-end funds to examine how takeover defenses impact shareholder value and promote managerial entrenchment. These funds use the same defenses as general corporations but provide an ideal, homogeneous environment for testing their effects. Defenses are associated with lower fund market values, weaker reactions to activist 13D filings, and higher compensation levels for both fund managers and directors. This study provides greater clarity on the unresolved impact of takeover defenses on firm value, while showing for the first time that directors, who are responsible for adopting takeover defenses, financially benefit from their use. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Souther, Matthew E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bridging the gap: the design of bank loan contracts and distance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hollander, Stephan; Verriest, Arnt
How do the distance constraints faced by lenders in acquiring borrower information affect the design of bank loan contracts? Theoretical studies posit that greater information asymmetry leads to the allocation of stronger ex ante decision rights to the lender (the uninformed party). Consistent with this hypothesis, we find that, upon inception, contracts tend to be more restrictive when firms seek loans from remote lenders. This finding is robust to potential endogeneity bias and simultaneity of various loan terms. Overall, we establish a strong informational link between distance and loan contract design. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hollander, Stephan; Verriest, Arnt</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can analysts pick stocks for the long-run?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altinkilic, Oya; Hansen, Robert S.; Ye, Liyu
This paper examines post-revision return drift, or PRD, following analysts' revisions of their stock recommendations. PRD refers to the finding that the analysts' recommendation changes predict future long-term returns in the same direction as the change (i.e., upgrades are followed by positive returns, and downgrades are followed by negative returns). During the high-frequency algorithmic trading period of 2003-2010, average PRD is no longer significantly different from zero. The new findings agree with improved market efficiency after declines in real trading cost inefficiencies. They are consistent with a reduced information production role for analysts in the supercomputer.era. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Altinkilic, Oya; Hansen, Robert S.; Ye, Liyu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal inside debt compensation and the value of equity and debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, T. Colin; Galpin, Neal; Johnson, Shane A.
We use firm and chief executive officer (CEO) characteristics motivated by optimal contracting theory to estimate optimal CEO relative debt-equity incentive ratios. Equity values rise as firms adjust CEO incentive ratios toward their predicted optimums, whether that increases or decreases the relative incentive ratio. Debt values rise as firms adjust ratios upward and do not fall as they adjust them downward. Our predicted optimums explain changes in equity and debt values better than a model in which firms simply match CEO inside debt-equity ratios to firm debt-equity ratios. The results suggest important cross-sectional differences in firms' optimal inside debt policies. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Campbell, T. Colin; Galpin, Neal; Johnson, Shane A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance governance and risk management at unprotected banks: National banks in the 1890s</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calomiris, Charles W.; Carlson, Mark
We examine bank governance and risk choices from the 1890s, a period without distortions from deposit insurance or other government assistance to banks. We link differences in managerial ownership to different corporate governance policies, risk, and methods of risk management. Formal corporate governance and high manager ownership are negatively correlated. Managerial salaries and self-lending are greater when managerial ownership is higher and lower when formal governance is employed. Banks with high managerial ownership (low formal governance) target lower default risk. High managerial ownership, not formal governance, is associated with greater reliance on cash instead of equity to limit risk. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Calomiris, Charles W.; Carlson, Mark</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>State variables, macroeconomic activity, and the cross section of individual stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boons, Martijn
I study whether risk premiums for exposure to state variables in the cross-section of individual stocks are consistent with how these variables forecast macroeconomic activity in the time series. I find such time series and cross-sectional consistency. This finding suggests that investors are ultimately concerned about business cycle risk and therefore require a premium for exposure to variables that contain systematic economic news. This finding challenges recent portfolio-level evidence showing that state variable risk premiums are inconsistent with hedging incentives in the Intertemporal CAPM. Moreover, state variable risk premiums are not fully captured by the factors and characteristics of Fama and French (1992, 1993). (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boons, Martijn</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive overconfidence and compensation structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Humphery-Jenner, Mark; Lisic, Ling Lei; Nanda, Vikram; Silveri, Sabatino Dino
We examine the impact of overconfidence on compensation structure. Our findings support the exploitation hypothesis: firms offer incentive-heavy compensation contracts to overconfident Chief Executive Officers (CEOs) to exploit their positively biased views of firm prospects. Overconfident CEOs receive more option-intensive compensation and this relation increases with CEO bargaining power. Exogenous shocks (Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 (SOX) and Financial Accounting Standard (FAS) 123R) provide additional support for the findings. Overconfident non-CEO executives also receive more incentive-based pay, independent of CEO overconfidence, buttressing the notion that firms tailor compensation contracts to individual behavioral traits such as overconfidence. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Humphery-Jenner, Mark; Lisic, Ling Lei; Nanda, Vikram; Silveri, Sabatino Dino</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ambiguity aversion and household portfolio choice puzzles: Empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dimmock, Stephen G.; Kouwenberg, Roy; Mitchell, Olivia S.; Peijnenburg, Kim
We test the relation between ambiguity aversion and five household portfolio choice puzzles: nonparticipation in equities, low allocations to equity, home-bias, own-company stock ownership, and portfolio under-diversification. In a representative US household survey, we measure ambiguity preferences using custom-designed questions based on Ellsberg urns. As theory predicts, ambiguity aversion is negatively associated with stock market participation, the fraction of financial assets in stocks, and foreign stock ownership, but it is positively related to own-company stock ownership. Conditional on stock ownership, ambiguity aversion is related to portfolio under-diversification, and during the financial crisis, ambiguity-averse respondents were more likely to sell stocks. (C) 2016 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Dimmock, Stephen G.; Kouwenberg, Roy; Mitchell, Olivia S.; Peijnenburg, Kim</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nominal price illusion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Birru, Justin; Wang, Baolian
We explore the psychology of stock price levels and provide evidence that investors suffer from a nominal price illusion in which they overestimate the room to grow for low-priced stocks relative to high-priced stocks. While it has become increasingly clear that nominal price levels influence investor behavior, why prices matter to investors is a question that as of yet has gone unanswered. We find widespread evidence that investors systematically overestimate the skewness of low-priced stocks. In the broad cross-section of stocks, we find that investors substantially overweight the importance of price when forming skewness expectations. Asset pricing implications of our findings are borne out in the options market. A zero-cost option portfolio strategy that exploits investor overestimation of skewness for low-priced stocks generates significant abnormal returns. Finally, investor expectations of future skewness increase drastically on days that a stock undergoes a split to a lower nominal price. Empirically, however, future physical skewness decreases following splits. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Birru, Justin; Wang, Baolian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heuristic portfolio trading rules with capital gain taxes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fischer, Marcel; Gallmeyer, Michael F.
We study the out-of-sample performance of portfolio trading strategies used when an investor faces capital gain taxation and proportional transaction costs. Overlaying simple tax trading heuristics on trading strategies improves out-of-sample performance. For medium to large transaction costs, no trading strategy can outperform a 1/N trading strategy augmented with a tax heuristic, not even the most tax and transaction cost-efficient buy-and hold strategy. Overall, the best strategy is 1/N augmented with a heuristic that allows for a fixed deviation in absolute portfolio weights. Our results thus show that the best trading strategies balance diversification considerations and tax considerations. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fischer, Marcel; Gallmeyer, Michael F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Dodd-Frank affect OTC transaction costs and liquidity? Evidence from real-time CDS trade reports</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loon, Yee Cheng; Zhong, Zhaodong
This paper examines transaction costs and liquidity in the index CDS market by matching intraday quotes to real-time trade reports made available through the Dodd-Frank reforms. We find that the average relative effective spread is 0.27% of price level or 2.73% of CDS spread. Dodd-Frank does affect transaction costs and liquidity. Liquidity improves after the commencement of public dissemination of OTC derivatives trades. Moreover, cleared trades, trades executed on exchange-like venues, end-user trades, and bespoke trades exhibit lower trading costs, price impact, and price dispersion. These findings improve our understanding of the OTC derivatives market that is undergoing fundamental changes. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Loon, Yee Cheng; Zhong, Zhaodong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The common factor in idiosyncratic volatility: Quantitative asset pricing implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Herskovic, Bernard; Kelly, Bryan; Lustig, Hanno; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn
We show that firms' idiosyncratic volatility obeys a strong factor structure and that shocks to the common idiosyncratic volatility (CIV) factor are priced. Stocks in the lowest CIV-beta quintile earn average returns 5.4% per year higher than those in the highest quintile. The CIV factor helps to explain a number of asset pricing anomalies. We provide new evidence linking the CIV factor to income risk faced by households. Our findings are consistent with an incomplete markets heterogeneous agent model. In the model, CIV is a priced state variable because an increase in idiosyncratic firm volatility raises the average household's marginal utility. The calibrated model matches the high degree of co-movement in idiosyncratic volatilities, the CIV-beta return spread, and several other asset price moments. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Herskovic, Bernard; Kelly, Bryan; Lustig, Hanno; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment and the weighted average cost of capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frank, Murray Z.; Shen, Tao
In a standard q-theory model, corporate investment is negatively related to the cost of capital. Empirically, we find that the weighted average cost of capital matters for corporate investment. The form of the impact depends on how the cost of equity is measured. When the capital asset pricing model (CAPM) is used, firms with a high cost of equity invest more. When the implied cost of capital is used, firms with a high cost of equity invest less. The implied cost of capital can better reflect the time-varying required return on capital. The CAPM measure reflects forces that are outside the standard model. (C) 2015 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Frank, Murray Z.; Shen, Tao</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The ownership and trading of debt claims in Chapter 11 restructurings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ivashina, Victoria; Iverson, Benjamin; Smith, David C.
Using a novel data set that covers individual debt claims against 136 bankrupt US companies and includes information on a subset of claims transfers, we provide new empirical insight regarding how a firm's debt ownership relates to bankruptcy outcomes. Firms with higher debt concentration at the start of the case are more likely to file prearranged bankruptcy plans, to move quickly through the restructuring process, and to emerge successfully as independent going concerns. Moreover, higher ownership concentration within a debt class is associated with higher recovery rates to that class. Trading of claims during bankruptcy concentrates ownership further, but this trading is not associated with subsequent improvements in bankruptcy outcomes and could, at the margin, increase the likelihood of liquidation. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ivashina, Victoria; Iverson, Benjamin; Smith, David C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic risk and the macroeconomy: An empirical evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giglio, Stefano; Kelly, Bryan; Pruitt, Seth
This article studies how systemic risk and financial market distress affect the distribution of shocks to real economic activity. We analyze how changes in 19 different measures of systemic risk skew the distribution of subsequent shocks to industrial production and other macroeconomic variables in the US and Europe over several decades. We also propose dimension reduction estimators for constructing systemic risk indexes from the cross section of measures and demonstrate their success in predicting future macroeconomic shocks out of sample. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Giglio, Stefano; Kelly, Bryan; Pruitt, Seth</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional investors and stock return anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edelen, Roger M.; Ince, Ozgur S.; Kadlec, Gregory B.
We examine institutional demand prior to well-known stock return anomalies and find that institutions have a strong tendency to buy stocks classified as overvalued (short leg of anomaly), and that these stocks have particularly negative ex post abnormal returns. Our results differ from numerous studies documenting a positive relation between institutional demand and future returns. We trace the difference to measurement horizon. We too find a positive relation at a quarterly horizon. However, the relation turns strongly negative at the one-year horizon used in anomaly studies. We consider several explanations for institutions' tendency to trade contrary to anomaly prescriptions. Our evidence largely rules out explanations based on flow and limits-of-arbitrage, but is more consistent with agency-induced preferences for stock characteristics that relate to poor long-run performance. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Edelen, Roger M.; Ince, Ozgur S.; Kadlec, Gregory B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt-equity choices, R&amp;D investment and market timing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lewis, Craig M.; Tan, Yongxian
In this paper, we examine whether managers time their debt-equity choices to exploit market mispricing. Controlling for the level of external financing and corporate investment activities, we find evidence consistent with the market timing hypothesis. We find managers issue more equity relative to debt when analysts are relatively optimistic about firms' long-term growth prospects. Moreover, equity issuers earn lower returns than debt issuers at subsequent earnings announcements. Controlling for research and development (R&amp;D) investment, we find that, consistent with the market timing hypothesis and inconsistent with the extant empirical literature, the debt-equity composition of external financing predicts year-ahead stock return. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lewis, Craig M.; Tan, Yongxian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cost of friendship</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gompers, Paul A.; Mukharlyamov, Vladimir; Xuan, Yuhai
We investigate how personal characteristics affect people's desire to collaborate and whether this attraction enhances or detracts from performance in venture capital. We find that venture capitalists who share the same ethnic, educational, or career background are more likely to syndicate with each other. This homophily reduces the probability of investment success, and the detrimental effect is most prominent for early-stage investments. A variety of tests show that the cost of affinity is most likely attributable to poor decision making by high-affinity syndicates after the investment is made. These results suggest that "birds-of-a-feather-flock-together" effects in collaboration can be costly. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gompers, Paul A.; Mukharlyamov, Vladimir; Xuan, Yuhai</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum crashes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Daniel, Kent; Moskowitz, Tobias J.
Despite their strong positive average returns across numerous asset classes, momentum strategies can experience infrequent and persistent strings of negative returns. These momentum crashes are partly forecastable. They occur in panic states, following market declines and when market volatility is high, and are contemporaneous with market rebounds. The low ex ante expected returns in panic states are consistent with a conditionally high premium attached to the option like payoffs of past losers. An implementable dynamic momentum strategy based on forecasts of momentum's mean and variance approximately doubles the alpha and Sharpe ratio of a static momentum strategy and is not explained by other factors. These results are robust across multiple time periods, international equity markets, and other asset classes. (C) 2016 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Daniel, Kent; Moskowitz, Tobias J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Underwriter networks, investor attention, and initial public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bajo, Emanuele; Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Simonyan, Karen; Tehranian, Hassan
Using various centrality measures from social network analysis, we analyze how the location of a lead initial public offering (IPO) underwriter in its network of investment banks affects various IPO characteristics. We hypothesize that investment banking networks allow lead IPO underwriters to induce institutions to pay attention to the firms they take public and to perform two information-related roles during the IPO process: an information dissemination role, in which the lead underwriter uses its investment banking network to disseminate noisy information about various aspects of the IPO firm to institutional investors; and an information extraction role, in which the lead underwriter uses its investment banking network to extract information useful in pricing the IPO firm equity from institutional investors. Based on these two roles, we develop testable hypotheses relating lead IPO underwriter centrality to the IPO characteristics of firms they take public. We find that more central lead IPO underwriters are associated with larger absolute values of offer price revisions, greater IPO and after-market valuations, larger IPO initial returns, greater institutional investor equity holdings and analyst coverage immediately post-IPO, greater stock liquidity post-IPO, and better long-run stock returns. Using a hand-collected data set of pre-IPO media coverage as a proxy for investor attention, we show that an important channel through which more central lead IPO underwriters achieve favorable IPO characteristics is by attracting greater investor attention to the IPOs underwritten by them. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bajo, Emanuele; Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Simonyan, Karen; Tehranian, Hassan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of unconventional monetary policy on firm financing constraints: Evidence from the maturity extension program</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foley-Fisher, Nathan; Ramcharan, Rodney; Yu, Edison
This paper investigates the impact of unconventional monetary policy on firm financial constraints using the maturity extension program (MEP). Consistent with bond market segmentation and limits to arbitrage, around the MEP's announcement, stock prices rose for those firms more dependent on longer-term debt. These firms also issued more long-term debt during the MEP and expanded employment and investment. There is also evidence of "reach for yield" behavior, as the demand for riskier corporate debt also increased. Our results suggest that unconventional monetary policy might have relaxed financial constraints for some firms by inducing gap-filling behavior and affecting bond market risk premia. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Foley-Fisher, Nathan; Ramcharan, Rodney; Yu, Edison</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A trend factor: Any economic gains from using information over investment horizons?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Yufeng; Zhou, Guofu; Zhu, Yingzi
In this paper, we provide a trend factor that captures simultaneously all three stock price trends: the short-, intermediate-, and long-term, by exploiting information in moving average prices of various time lengths whose predictive power is justified by a proposed general equilibrium model. It outperforms substantially the well-known short-term reversal, momentum, and long-term reversal factors, which are based on the three price trends separately, by more than doubling their Sharpe ratios. During the recent financial crisis, the trend factor earns 0.75% per month, while the market loses -2.03% per month, the shortterm reversal factor loses -0.82%, the momentum factor loses -3.88%, and the long-term reversal factor barely gains 0.03%. The performance of the trend factor is robust to alternative formations and to a variety of control variables. From an asset pricing perspective, it also performs well in explaining cross-section stock returns. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Han, Yufeng; Zhou, Guofu; Zhu, Yingzi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who neglects risk? Investor experience and the credit boom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernenko, Sergey; Hanson, Samuel G.; Sunderam, Adi
Many have argued that overoptimistic thinking on the part of lenders helps fuel credit booms. We use new micro-data on mutual funds' holdings of securitizations to examine which investors are susceptible to such boom-time thinking. We show that firsthand experience plays a key role in shaping investors' beliefs. During the 2003-2007 mortgage boom, inexperienced fund managers loaded up on securitizations linked to nonprime mortgages, accumulating twice the holdings of more seasoned managers. Moreover, inexperienced managers who personally experienced severe or recent adverse investment outcomes behaved more like seasoned managers. Training and institutional memory can serve as partial substitutes for personal experience. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chernenko, Sergey; Hanson, Samuel G.; Sunderam, Adi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market maturity and mispricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobs, Heiko
Relying on the Stambaugh, Yu, and Yuan (2015) mispricing score and on 45 countries between 1994 and 2013, I document economically meaningful and statistically significant cross-sectional stock return predictability around the globe. In contrast to the widely held belief, mispricing associated with the 11 long/short anomalies underlying the composite ranking measure appears to be at least as prevalent in developed markets as in emerging markets. Additional support for this conjecture is obtained, among others, from tests for biased expectations based on the behavior of anomaly spreads surrounding earnings announcements as well as from within-country variation in development. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jacobs, Heiko</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Patient capital outperformance: The investment skill of high active share managers who trade infrequently</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, Martijn; Pareek, Ankur
Among high active share portfolios whose holdings differ substantially from their benchmark only those with patient investment strategies (with holding durations of over two years) on average outperform, over 2% per year. Funds trading frequently generally underperform, including those with high active share. Among patient funds, separating closet index from high active share funds matters, as low active share funds on average under perform even with patient strategies. Our results suggest that U.S. equity markets provide opportunities for longer-term active managers, perhaps because of the limited arbitrage capital devoted to patient and active investment strategies. The Online Appendix is available at http://ssrn.comiabstract=2810798. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cremers, Martijn; Pareek, Ankur</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corruption culture and corporate misconduct</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Xiaoding
Despite significant interest in corporate culture, there is little empirical research on its role in influencing corporate misconduct. Using cultural background information on key company insiders, I construct a measure of corporate corruption culture, capturing a firm's general attitude toward opportunistic behavior. Firms with high corruption culture are more likely to engage in earnings management, accounting fraud, option backdating, and opportunistic insider trading. I further explore the inner workings of corruption culture and find evidence that it operates both as a selection mechanism and by having a direct influence on individual behavior. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Liu, Xiaoding</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mortgage companies and regulatory arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demyanyk, Yuliya; Loutskina, Elena
Mortgage companies (MCs) do not fall under the strict regulatory regime of depository institutions. We empirically show that this gap resulted in regulatory arbitrage and allowed bank holding companies (BHCs) to circumvent consumer compliance regulations, mitigate capital requirements, and reduce exposure to loan-related losses. Compared to bank subsidiaries, MC subsidiaries of BHCs originated riskier mortgages to borrowers with lower credit scores, lower incomes, higher loan-to-income ratios, and higher default rates. Our results imply that precrisis regulations had the capacity to mitigate the deterioration of lending standards if consistently applied and enforced for all types of intermediaries. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Demyanyk, Yuliya; Loutskina, Elena</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxes and leverage at multinational corporations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faulkender, Michael; Smith, Jason M.
Empirical research has struggled to show that variation in corporate capital structure arises from variation in estimated corporate income tax rates. We argue that, in previdus studies, both the tax rates applied to multinational corporations and the taxable income earned have been mismeasured. Using the Bureau of Economic Analysis annual survey sample combined with each firm's income and country specific tax rate, we find that firms do have higher leverage ratios and lower interest coverage ratios when they operate in countries with higher tax rates, as theory would suggest. The trade-off theory of capital structure continues to have empirical support. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Faulkender, Michael; Smith, Jason M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reading the tea leaves: Model uncertainty, robust forecasts, and the autocorrelation of analysts' forecast errors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Linnainmaaa, Juhani T.; Torous, Walter; Yae, James
We put forward a model in which analysts are uncertain about a firm's earnings process. Faced with the possibility of using a misspecified model, analysts issue forecasts that are robust to model misspecification. We estimate that this mechanism explains approximately 60% of the autocorrelation in analysts' forecast errors. The remainder stems from the cross-sectional variation in mean forecast errors and in analysts' estimation errors of the persistence of earnings growth shocks. Consistent with our model, we find that analysts learn about some features of the earnings process but not others, and this learning reduces, but does not eliminate, the autocorrelation of forecast errors as firms age. Other potential explanations for the autocorrelation of analyst forecast errors are rejected. Our model of robust forecasting applies not only to analysts' forecasts but also to all model-based forecasts. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Linnainmaaa, Juhani T.; Torous, Walter; Yae, James</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign credit risk, liquidity, and European Central Bank intervention: Deus ex machina?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pelizzon, Loriana; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.; Tomio, Davide; Uno, Jun
We examine the dynamic relation between credit risk and liquidity in the Italian sovereign bond market during the eurozone crisis and the subsequent European Central Bank (ECB) interventions. Credit risk drives the liquidity of the market. A 10% change in the credit default swap (CDS) spread leads to a 13% change in the bid-ask spread, the relation being stronger when the CDS spread exceeds 500 basis points. The Long-Term Refinancing Operations of the ECB weakened the sensitivity of market makers' liquidity provision to credit risk, highlighting the importance of funding liquidity measures as determinants of market liquidity. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Pelizzon, Loriana; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.; Tomio, Davide; Uno, Jun</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disaster recovery and the term structure of dividend strips</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasler, Michael; Marfe, Roberto
Recent empirical findings document downward-sloping term structures of equity return volatility and risk premia. An equilibrium model with rare disasters followed by recoveries helps reconcile theory with empirical observations. Indeed, recoveries outweigh the upward-sloping effect of time-varying disaster intensity and expected growth, generating downward-sloping term structures of dividend growth risk, equity return volatility, and equity risk premia. In addition, the term structure of interest rates is upward-sloping when accounting for recoveries and downward-sloping otherwise. The model quantitatively reconciles high risk premia and a low risk-free rate with the shape of the term structures, which are at odds in other models. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hasler, Michael; Marfe, Roberto</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should we be afraid of the dark? Dark trading and market quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foley, Sean; Putnins, Tails J.
We exploit a unique natural experiment recent restrictions of dark trading in Canada and Australia and proprietary trade-level data to analyze the effects of dark trading. Disaggregating two types of dark trading, we find that dark limit order markets are beneficial to market quality, reducing quoted, effective, and realized spreads and increasing informational efficiency. In contrast, we do not find consistent evidence that dark midpoint crossing systems significantly affect market quality. Our results support recent theory that dark limit order markets encourage aggressive competition in liquidity provision. We discuss implications for the regulation of dark trading and tick sizes. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Foley, Sean; Putnins, Tails J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Failure to refinance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keys, Benjamin J.; Pope, Devin G.; Pope, Jaren C.
Households that fail to refinance their mortgage when interest rates decline lose out on substantial savings. Using a random sample of outstanding US mortgages in December 2010, we estimate that approximately 20% of unconstrained households for whom refinancing was optimal had not done so. The median household would save $160/month over the remaining life of the loan, for a total present-discounted value of forgone savings of $11,500, a particularly large consumer financial mistake. To shed light on possible mechanisms, we also provide results from a mail campaign targeted at a sample of homeowners who could benefit from refinancing. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Keys, Benjamin J.; Pope, Devin G.; Pope, Jaren C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cyclicality, performance measurement, and cash flow liquidity in private equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Robinson, David T.; Sensoy, Berk A.
We study the liquidity properties of private equity cash flows using data from 837 buyout and venture capital funds from 1984 to 2010. Most cash flow variation at a point in time is diversifiable either idiosyncratic to a given fund or explained by the fund's age. Both capital calls and distributions also have a procyclical systematic component. Distributions are more sensitive than calls, implying procyclical aggregate net cash flows. A consequence is that the well-known finding that funds raised in hot markets underperform in absolute terms is sharply attenuated when comparing to public equities. Consistent with a liquidity premium for calling capital in bad times, we find that funds with a relatively high propensity to do so perform better in both absolute and relative terms. Venture capital cash flows and performance are considerably more cyclical than buyout, and the links between cyclical cash flows and performance are likewise stronger. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Robinson, David T.; Sensoy, Berk A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information tradeoffs in dynamic financial markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avdis, Efstathios
In dynamic financial markets the stochastic supply of risky assets has a significant informational role. Contrary to static models, where it acts as "noise," in dynamic markets stochastic supply contains information about risk premiums. Acquiring private dividend information helps investors disentangle dividend information from discount-rate information contained in prices. For uninformed investors, however, as more informed investors enter the economy prices become more informative about dividends but less informative about discount rates. This tradeoff creates complementarities in information acquisition and multiple equilibria in the information market. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Avdis, Efstathios</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limited attention, marital events and hedge funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lu, Yan; Ray, Sugata; Teo, Melvyn
We explore the impact of limited attention by analyzing the performance of hedge fund managers who are distracted by marital events. We find that marriages and divorces are associated with significantly lower fund alpha, during the six-month period surrounding and the two-year period after the event. Busy managers who manage multiple funds and who are not part of a team are more affected by marital transitions. Inattentive managers place fewer active bets relative to their style peers, load more on index stocks, exhibit higher R-squareds with respect to systematic factors, and are more prone to the disposition effect. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lu, Yan; Ray, Sugata; Teo, Melvyn</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Have financial markets become more informative?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bai, Jennie; Philippon, Thomas; Savov, Alexi
The finance industry has grown, financial markets have become more liquid, information technology has been revolutionized. But have financial market prices become more informative? We derive a welfare-based measure of price informativeness: the predicted variation of future cash flows from current market prices. Since 1960, price informativeness has increased at longer horizons (three to five years). The increase is concentrated among firms with greater institutional ownership and share turnover, firms with options trading, and growth firms. Prices have also become a stronger predictor of investment, and investment a stronger predictor of cash flows. These findings suggest increased revelatory price efficiency. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bai, Jennie; Philippon, Thomas; Savov, Alexi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Playing it safe? Managerial preferences, risk, and agency conflicts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gormley, Todd A.; Matsa, David A.
This article examines managers' incentive to play it safe. We find that, after managers are insulated by the adoption of an antitakeover law, they take value-destroying actions that reduce their firms' stock volatility and risk of distress. To illustrate one such action, we show that managers undertake diversifying acquisitions that target firms likely to reduce risk, have negative announcement returns, and are concentrated among firms with managers who gain the most from reducing risk. Our findings suggest that instruments typically used to motivate managers, such as greater financial leverage and larger ownership stakes, exacerbate risk-related agency challenges. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gormley, Todd A.; Matsa, David A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Say on pay laws, executive compensation, pay slice, and firm valuation around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Correa, Ricardo; Lel, Ugur
Using a large sample of firms from 38 countries over the 2001-2012 period, this study finds evidence that, following the adoption of say on pay (SoP) laws, chief executive officer (CEO) pay growth rates decline and the sensitivity of CEO pay to firm performance improves. These changes are concentrated in firms with high excess pay and shareholder dissent, long CEO tenure, and less independent boards. Further, the portion of top management pay captured by CEOs is lower in the post-SoP period, which is associated with higher firm valuations. Overall, these results suggest that SoP laws are associated with significant changes in CEO pay policies. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Correa, Ricardo; Lel, Ugur</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short selling meets hedge fund 13F: An anatomy of informed demand</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiao, Yawen; Massa, Massimo; Zhang, Hong
The existing literature treats the short side (i.e., short selling) and the long side of hedge fund trading (i.e., fund holdings) independently. The two sides, however, complement each other: opposite changes in the two are likely to be driven by information, whereas simultaneous increases (decreases) of the two may be motivated by hedging (unwinding) considerations. We use this intuition to identify informed demand and document that it exhibits highly significant predictive power over returns (approximately 10% per year). We also find that informed demand forecasts future firm fundamentals, suggesting that hedge funds play an important role in information discovery. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jiao, Yawen; Massa, Massimo; Zhang, Hong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Socially responsible firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferrell, Allen; Liang, Hao; Renneboog, Luc
In the corporate finance tradition, starting with Berle and Means (1932), corporations should generally be run to maximize shareholder value. The agency view of corporate social responsibility (CSR) considers CSR an agency problem and a waste of corporate resources. Given our identification strategy by means of an instrumental variable approach, we find that well-governed firms that suffer less from agency concerns (less cash abundance, positive pay-for-performance, small control wedge, strong minority protection) engage more in CSR. We also find that a positive relation exists between CSR and value and that CSR attenuates the negative relation between managerial entrenchment and value. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Ferrell, Allen; Liang, Hao; Renneboog, Luc</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The volatility of a firm's assets and the leverage effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Jaewon; Richardson, Matthew
We investigate the volatility of firms' assets in contrast to existing studies that focus on equity volatility. We estimate asset volatility using a comprehensive data set on the market values of corporate security returns. We find significant differences between the properties of equity and asset volatilities with implications for several important areas of finance. First, financial leverage has a large influence on equity volatility. Second, leverage and asset volatility have permanent and transitory effects, respectively, on equity volatility, helping explain the short- and long-run dynamics of equity volatility. Third, we analyze and compare the cross-section of asset versus equity returns. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Choi, Jaewon; Richardson, Matthew</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of connections in turbulent times: Evidence from the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acemoglu, Daron; Johnson, Simon; Kermani, Amir; Kwak, James; Mitton, Todd
The announcement of Timothy Geithner as nominee for Treasury Secretary in November 2008 produced a cumulative abnormal return for financial firms with which he had a prior connection. This return was about 6% after the first full day of trading and about 12% after ten trading days. There were subsequently abnormal negative returns for connected firms when news broke that Geithner's confirmation might be derailed by tax issues. Personal connections to top executive branch officials can matter greatly even in a country with strong overall institutions, at least during a time of acute financial crisis and heightened policy discretion. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acemoglu, Daron; Johnson, Simon; Kermani, Amir; Kwak, James; Mitton, Todd</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure effects on the prices of equity call options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Geske, Robert; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Zhou, Yi
We examine whether values of equity options traded on individual firms are sensitive to the firm's capital structure. We estimate the compound option (CO) model, which views equity as an option on the firm. Compared with the Black-Scholes model, the CO model with a term structure of volatility (TSV) reduces pricing errors by 20% on average. The compound option effect is particularly strong for highly levered firms and long-term options, in which the pricing improvement is up to 70% of the Black-Scholes error. Without a TSV, the CO model reduces pricing errors of in-the-money options by 12.74% on average and for out-of-the-money by 9.22%. We show that the CO model implies a market value of firm leverage and allows imputation of the firm's implied volatility, both of which have potential applications in corporate finance. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Geske, Robert; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Zhou, Yi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Early option exercise: Never say never</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jensen, Mads Vestergaard; Pedersen, Lasse Heje
A classic result by Merton (1973) is that, except just before expiration or dividend payments, one should never exercise a call option and never convert a convertible bond. We show theoretically that this result is overturned when investors face frictions. Early option exercise can be optimal when it reduces short-sale costs, transaction costs, or funding costs. We provide consistent empirical evidence, documenting billions of dollars of early exercise for options and convertible bonds using unique data on actual exercise decisions and frictions. Our model can explain as much as 98% of early exercises by market makers and 67% by customers. (C) 2016 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. This is an open access article under the CC BY license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).</description><author>Jensen, Mads Vestergaard; Pedersen, Lasse Heje</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loans on sale: Credit market seasonality, borrower need, and lender rents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Murfin, Justin; Petersen, Mitchell
The market for corporate credit is characterized by significant seasonal variation, both in interest rates and the volume of new lending. Firms borrowing from banks during seasonal "sales" in late spring and fall issue at 19 basis points cheaper than winter and summer borrowers. Issuers during cheap seasons appear to have less immediate needs, but are enticed by low rates to engage in precautionary borrowing. High-interest-rate periods capture borrowers with unanticipated, non-deferrable investment needs. Consistent with models of intertemporal price discrimination, seasonality is strongly associated with market concentration among a few large banks with repeated interactions. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Murfin, Justin; Petersen, Mitchell</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market conditions, fragility, and the economics of market making</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anand, Amber; Venkataraman, Kumar
Using audit-trail data from the Toronto Stock Exchange, we find that market makers scale back in unison when market conditions are unfavorable, which contributes to covariation in liquidity supply, both within and across stocks. Market conditions lower aggregate participation via their impact on trading profits and risk. Contrary to regulatory view, higher stock volatility is associated with more participation and higher profits, even after controlling for other market conditions, including stock volume. Fragility concerns extend to larger stocks and to active participants. The designated market maker mitigates periodic illiquidity created by synchronous withdrawal of market makers in large and small stocks. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Anand, Amber; Venkataraman, Kumar</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>US political corruption and firm financial policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smith, Jared D.
Using US Department of Justice data on local political corruption, I find that firms in more corrupt areas hold less cash and have greater leverage than firms in less corrupt areas. The results are robust to including a range of controls and to using an instrumental variable approach, two alternative survey measures of corruption, and propensity score matching. Further, the association between corruption and leverage is largest among firms that operate primarily around their headquarters. Overall, the evidence is consistent with the hypothesis that firms manage liquidity downward and debt obligations upward to limit expropriation by corrupt local officials. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Smith, Jared D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Clouded judgment: The role of sentiment in credit origination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cortes, Kristle; Duchin, Ran; Sosyura, Denis
Using daily fluctuations in local sunshine as an instrument for sentiment, we study its effect on day-to-day decisions of lower-level financial officers. Positive sentiment is associated with higher credit approvals, and negative sentiment has the opposite effect of a larger magnitude. These effects are stronger when financial decisions require more discretion, when reviews are less automated, and when capital constraints are less binding. The variation in approval rates affects ex post financial performance and produces significant real effects. Our analysis of the economic channels suggests that sentiment influences managers' risk tolerance and subjective judgment. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cortes, Kristle; Duchin, Ran; Sosyura, Denis</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anxiety in the face of risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eisenbach, Thomas M.; Schmalz, Martin C.
We model an anxious agent as one who is more risk averse with respect to imminent risks than with respect to distant risks. Based on a utility function that captures individual subjects' behavior in experiments, we provide a tractable theory relaxing the restriction of constant risk aversion across horizons and show that it generates rich implications. We first apply the model to insurance markets and explain the high premia for short-horizon insurance. Then, we show that costly delegated portfolio management, investment advice, and withdrawal fees emerge as endogenous features and strategies to cope with dynamic inconsistency in intratemporal risk-return trade-offs. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eisenbach, Thomas M.; Schmalz, Martin C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time is money: Rational life cycle inertia and the delegation of investment management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Hugh Hoikwang; Maurer, Raimond; Mitchell, Olivia S.
Many households display inertia in investment management over their life cycles. Our calibrated dynamic life cycle portfolio choice model can account for such an apparently 'irrational' outcome, by incorporating the fact that investors must forgo acquiring job-specific skills when they spend time managing their money, and their efficiency in financial decision making varies with age. Resulting inertia patterns mesh well with findings from prior studies and our own empirical results from Panel Study of Income Dynamics (PSID) data. We also analyze how people optimally choose between actively managing their assets versus delegating the task to financial advisors. Delegation proves valuable to both the young and the old. Our calibrated model quantifies welfare gains from including investment time and money costs as well as delegation in a life cycle setting. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kim, Hugh Hoikwang; Maurer, Raimond; Mitchell, Olivia S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does variance risk have two prices? Evidence from the equity and option markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barras, Laurent; Malkhozov, Aytek
We formally compare two versions of the market variance risk premium (VRP) measured in the equity and option markets. Both VRPs follow common patterns and respond similarly to changes in volatility and economic conditions. However, we reject the null hypothesis that they are identical and find that their difference is strongly related to measures of the financial standing of intermediaries. These results shed new light on the information content of the VRP, suggest the presence of market frictions between the two markets, and are consistent with the key role played by intermediaries in setting option prices. (c) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barras, Laurent; Malkhozov, Aytek</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance measurement with selectivity, market and volatility timing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferson, Wayne; Mo, Haitao
The performance of portfolio managers depends on market timing, volatility timing, and security selection. We develop holdings-based performance measures that adjust for risk using stochastic discount factors, display all three components in a consistent framework, and avoid strong assumptions about managers' behavior. Previous models leave out some of the components of performance, and correcting for this we deliver better measures of selectivity. Sorting stocks held by funds on selectivity produces a quintile spread in four factor alphas greater than 2.5% per year before costs and more than 1.7% greater than found using the Daniel, Grinblatt, Titman, and Wermers (1997) measure. (c) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ferson, Wayne; Mo, Haitao</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Passive investors, not passive owners</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Appel, Ian R.; Gormley, Todd A.; Keim, Donald B.
Passive institutional investors are an increasingly important component of U.S. stock ownership. To examine whether and by which mechanisms passive investors influence firms' governance, we exploit variation in ownership by passive mutual funds associated with stock assignments to the Russell 1000 and 2000 indexes. Our findings suggest that passive mutual funds influence firms' governance choices, resulting in more independent directors, removal of takeover defenses, and more equal voting rights. Passive investors appear to exert influence through their large voting blocs, and consistent with the observed governance differences increasing firm value, passive ownership is associated with improvements in firms' longer-term performance. (c) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Appel, Ian R.; Gormley, Todd A.; Keim, Donald B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Borrower protection and the supply of credit: Evidence from foreclosure laws</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dagher, Jihad; Sun, Yangfan
Laws governing the foreclosure process can have direct consequences for the costs of foreclosure and, therefore could affect lending decisions. We exploit the heterogeneity in judicial requirements across US states to examine their impact on banks' lending decisions in a sample of urban areas straddling state borders. A key feature of our study is the way it exploits an exogenous cutoff in loan eligibility to government-sponsored enterprises (GSEs) guarantees, which shift the burden of foreclosure costs onto the GSEs. We find that judicial requirements reduce the supply of credit only for jumbo loans, which are ineligible for GSE guarantees, i.e., in the nonsubsidized segment of the market. Thus, while we find a significant effect on credit supply, the aggregate impact is muted by the indirect cross-subsidy by the GSEs to borrower-friendly states. (c) 2016 Dr. Jihad C. Dagher. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dagher, Jihad; Sun, Yangfan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leverage dynamics over the business cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Halling, Michael; Yu, Jin; Zechner, Josef
Surprisingly little is known about the business cycle dynamics of leverage. The existing evidence documents that target leverage evolves pro-cyclically either for all firms or financially constrained ones. In contrast, we show that, on average, target leverage ratios evolve counter-cyclically once cyclicality is measured comprehensively, accounting for variation in explanatory variables and model parameters. These counter-cyclical dynamics are robust to different subsamples of firms, data samples, empirical models of leverage, and definitions of leverage. There is a fraction of 10-25% of firms with pro-cyclical dynamics whose characteristics are consistent with counter-cyclical dynamics for loss-given-default and probability of default. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Halling, Michael; Yu, Jin; Zechner, Josef</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Friday announcements special? Overcoming selection bias</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Michaely, Roni; Rubin, Amir; Vedrashko, Alexander
We report reduced market response to Friday announcements of dividend changes, seasoned equity offerings, share repurchases, earnings, and mergers, which is seemingly consistent with the notion of investor inattention on Fridays. However, we show that these findings are an outcome of selection bias. Firms that make announcements on Fridays experience reduced market response on any weekday and have common unobserved characteristics across announcement types. After correcting for selection bias, there is no evidence that investors pay less attention to announcements made on Fridays. The method introduced here is applicable to other studies in which an exogenous factor influencing firm performance can actually be associated with firm characteristics. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Michaely, Roni; Rubin, Amir; Vedrashko, Alexander</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Double bank runs and liquidity risk management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ippolito, Filippo; Peydro, Jose-Luis; Polo, Andrea; Sette, Enrico
By providing liquidity to depositors and credit-line borrowers, banks can be exposed to double-runs on assets and liabilities. For identification, we exploit the 2007 freeze of the European interbank market and the Italian Credit Register. After the shock, there are sizeable, aggregate double-runs. In the cross-section, credit-line drawdowns are not larger for banks more exposed to the interbank market; however, they are larger when we condition on the same firms with multiple credit lines. We show that, ex-ante, more exposed banks actively manage their liquidity risk by granting fewer credit lines to firms that run more during crises. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ippolito, Filippo; Peydro, Jose-Luis; Polo, Andrea; Sette, Enrico</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gambling preference and individual equity option returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Byun, Suk-Joon; Kim, Da-Hea
We investigate the relation between the option returns and the underlying stock's lottery like characteristics. Call options written on the most lottery-like stocks underperform otherwise similar call options written on the least lottery-like stocks by 10-20% per month. Moreover, the more lottery-like the underlying stocks, the further and more frequently the options deviate from the put-call parity in the direction induced by overvalued calls. Furthermore, the lottery-like characteristic effect is stronger during periods of high investor sentiment. The results suggest that optimism-induced gambling preference causes lottery like options to be overvalued. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Byun, Suk-Joon; Kim, Da-Hea</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Golden hellos: Signing bonuses for new top executives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xu, Jin; Yang, Jun
We examine signing bonuses awarded to executives hired for or promoted to named executive officer (NEO) positions at Standard &amp; Poor's 1500 companies during the period 1992-2011. Executive signing bonuses are sizable and increasing in use, and they are labeled by the media as "golden hellos." We find that executive signing bonuses are mainly awarded at firms with greater information asymmetry and higher innate risks, especially to younger executives, to mitigate the executives' concerns about termination risk. When termination concerns are strong, signing bonus awards are associated with better performance and retention outcomes. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Xu, Jin; Yang, Jun</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relative peer quality and firm performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Francis, Bill; Hasan, Iftekhar; Mani, Sureshbabu; Ye, Pengfei
We examine the performance impact of the relative quality of a Chief Executive Officer (CEO)'s compensation peers (peers to determine a CEO's overall compensation) and bonus peers (peers to determine a CEO's relative-performance-based bonus). We use the fraction of peers with greater managerial ability scores (Demerjian, Lev, and McVay, 2012) than the reporting firm to measure this CEO's relative peer quality (RPQ). We find that firms with higher RPQ earn higher stock returns and experience higher profitability growth than firms with lower RPQ Learning among peers and the increased incentive to work harder induced by the peer-based tournament contribute to RPQs performance effect. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Francis, Bill; Hasan, Iftekhar; Mani, Sureshbabu; Ye, Pengfei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What do private equity firms say they do?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gompers, Paul; Kaplan, Steven N.; Mukharlyamov, Vladimir
We survey 79 private equity (PE) investors with combined assets under management of more than $750 billion about their practices in firm valuation, capital structure, governance, and value creation. Investors rely primarily on internal rates of return and multiples to evaluate investments. Their limited partners focus more on absolute performance as opposed to risk-adjusted returns. Capital structure choice is based equally on optimal trade-off and market timing considerations. PE investors anticipate adding value to portfolio companies, with a greater focus on increasing growth than on reducing costs. We also explore how the actions that PE managers say they take group into specific firm strategies and how those strategies are related to firm founder characteristics. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gompers, Paul; Kaplan, Steven N.; Mukharlyamov, Vladimir</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can analysts assess fundamental risk and valuation uncertainty? An empirical analysis of scenario-based value estimates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Joos, Peter; Piotroski, Joseph D.; Srinivasan, Suraj
We use a data set of sell-side analysts' scenario-based equity valuation estimates to examine whether analysts can assess the state-contingent risk surrounding a firm's fundamental value. We find that the spread in analysts' scenario-based valuations captures the riskiness of operations and predicts the absolute magnitude of long-run valuation errors and future changes in firm fundamentals. We also show that analysts' assessment of fundamental risk and its predictive ability systematically improved after the financial crisis, consistent with the macroeconomic shock raising analysts' awareness of firms' systematic risk exposures. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Joos, Peter; Piotroski, Joseph D.; Srinivasan, Suraj</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can information be locked up? Informed trading ahead of macro-news announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernile, Gennaro; Hu, Jianfeng; Tang, Yuehua
Government agencies routinely allow pre-release access to information to accredited news agencies under embargo agreements. Using high-frequency data, we find evidence consistent with informed trading during embargoes of Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) scheduled announcements. The E-mini Standard &amp; Poor's 500 futures' abnormal order imbalances are in the direction of subsequent policy surprises and contain information that predicts the market reaction to the policy announcements. The estimated informed trades' profits are arguably large. Notably, we find no evidence of informed trading prior to the start of FOMC news embargoes or during lockups ahead of nonfarm payroll, US Producer Price Index, and gross domestic product data releases. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bernile, Gennaro; Hu, Jianfeng; Tang, Yuehua</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capitalizing on Capitol Hill: Informed trading by hedge fund managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Meng; Huang, Jiekun
This paper examines the hypothesis that hedge fund managers gain an informational advantage in securities trading through their connections with lobbyists. Using data sets on the long-equity holdings and lobbyist connections of hedge funds from 1999 through 2012, we show that hedge funds outperform passive benchmarks by 56-93 basis points per month on their political holdings when they are connected to lobbyists. Furthermore, the political outperformance of connected funds decreased significantly after the Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge (STOCK) Act became effective. Our study provides evidence on the transmission of political information in financial markets and on the value of such information to financial market participants. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Gao, Meng; Huang, Jiekun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shorting at close range: A tale of two types</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Comerton-Forde, Carole; Jones, Charles M.; Putnins, Tails J.
We examine returns, order flow, and market conditions in the minutes before, during, and after NYSE and Nasdaq short sales. We find two distinct types of short sales: those that provide liquidity, and those that demand it. Liquidity-supplying shorts are strongly contrarian at intraday horizons. They trade when spreads are unusually wide, facing greater adverse selection. Liquidity-demanding shorts trade when spreads are narrow and tend to follow short-term price declines. These results support a competitive rational expectations model where both market-makers and informed traders short, indicating that these two shorting types are integral to both price discovery and liquidity provision. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Comerton-Forde, Carole; Jones, Charles M.; Putnins, Tails J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fragility in money market funds: Sponsor support and regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parlatore, Cecilia
Money market funds (MMFs), which are crucial to short-term funding markets, rely on voluntary support of fund sponsors to maintain stable share values. I develop a general equilibrium model of MMFs to study how sponsor support affects the industry's fragility and regulation. Adverse asset-quality shocks lead MMFs to liquidate assets. When liquidity in asset markets is limited, asset prices are lower if more funds liquidate. Lower asset prices, in turn, make sponsor support costlier and even more liquidations occur. This feedback leads to complementarities in sponsors' support decisions. Based on the model's insights, I derive implications for the regulation of MMFs. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Parlatore, Cecilia</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decision-making approaches and the propensity to default: Evidence and implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Jeffrey R.; Farrell, Anne M.; Weisbenner, Scott J.
This paper examines heterogeneity in the responsiveness to default options in a large state retirement plan, focusing on individuals' decision-making approaches as well as their economic and demographic characteristics. Analyses of a survey of plan participants show that procrastination and the need for cognitive closure are important determinants of the likelihood of default. This paper also explores an important implication of defaulting individuals who default are significantly more likely to subsequently express a desire to enroll in a different plan. The desire to change plans is also correlated with numerous economic and decision-making characteristics, including procrastination. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, Jeffrey R.; Farrell, Anne M.; Weisbenner, Scott J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securities trading by banks and credit supply: Micro-evidence from the crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abbassi, Puriya; Iyer, Rajkamal; Peydro, Jose-Luis; Tous, Francesc R.
We analyze securities trading by banks during the crisis and the associated spillovers to the supply of credit. We use a proprietary data set that has the investments of banks at the security level for 2005-2012 in conjunction with the credit register from Germany. We find that-during the crisis-banks with higher trading expertise (trading banks) increase their investments in securities, especially in those that had a larger price drop, with the strongest impact in low-rated and long-term securities. Moreover, trading banks reduce their credit supply, and the credit crunch is binding at the firm level. All of the effects are more pronounced for trading banks with higher capital levels. Finally, banks use central bank liquidity and government subsidies like public recapitalization and implicit guarantees mainly to support trading of securities. Overall, our results suggest an externality arising from fire sales in securities markets on credit supply via the trading behavior of banks. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Abbassi, Puriya; Iyer, Rajkamal; Peydro, Jose-Luis; Tous, Francesc R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comovement revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Honghui; Singal, Vijay; Whitelaw, Robert F.
Evidence of excessive comovement among stocks following index additions (Barberis, Shleifer, and Wurgler, 2005) and stock splits (Green and Hwang, 2009) challenges traditional finance theory. We show that the bivariate regressions in this literature provide little information about the economic magnitude of excess comovement, with coefficients that are sensitive to unrelated factors. Using robust univariate regressions and matched control samples, almost all evidence of excess comovement disappears. In both examples, the stocks exhibit strong returns prior to the event, akin to momentum winners. We document that winner stocks exhibit increases in betas, generating much of the apparent excess comovement. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Honghui; Singal, Vijay; Whitelaw, Robert F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank loans and troubled debt restructurings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demiroglu, Cem; James, Christopher
This paper examines the relation between the number and type of lenders that participate in corporate loan facilities and the nature of troubled debt restructurings. We find that loans from traditional bank lenders are significantly easier to restructure out of court than loans from institutional lenders. We also find that the existence of a past banking relationship between the borrower and the lead arranger of a syndicated loan adversely affects the ease of restructuring. Finally, we find that reliance on loans that are held in part by collateralized loan obligations (CLOs) is positively related to the likelihood of a prepackaged bankruptcy, consistent with greater holdout problems when loans are held by CLOs. Overall, our findings suggest that the role of banks in the restructuring process is quite different when bank loans are diffusely held or securitized. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Demiroglu, Cem; James, Christopher</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wealth transfers via equity transactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sloan, Richard G.; You, Haifeng
Previous research indicates that firms issue shares when their stock is overpriced and repurchase shares when their stock is underpriced. Such transactions transfer wealth from transacting stockholders to ongoing stockholders. We quantify the magnitude of these wealth transfers and analyze their implications. Strikingly, we find that for the average firm-year, these wealth transfers approximate 40% of net income. We also find that these wealth transfers can be predicted using a variety of firm characteristics and that future wealth transfers are an important determinant of current stock prices. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sloan, Richard G.; You, Haifeng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dark trading and price discovery</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Comerton-Forde, Carole; Putnins, Talis J.
Regulators globally are concerned that dark trading harms price discovery. We show that dark trades are less informed than lit trades. High levels of dark trading increase adverse selection risk on the lit exchange by increasing the concentration of informed traders. Using both high- and low-frequency measures of informational efficiency we find that low levels of non-block dark trading are benign or even beneficial for informational efficiency, but high levels are harmful. In contrast, we find no evidence that block trades in the dark impede price discovery. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Comerton-Forde, Carole; Putnins, Talis J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Employee rights and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>John, Kose; Knyazeva, Anzhela; Knyazeva, Diana
This paper examines the outcomes and characteristics of corporate acquisitions from the perspective of stakeholder-shareholder agency conflicts. Using state variation in labor protections, we find that acquirers with strong labor rights experience lower announcement returns. Combined acquirer and target announcement returns are also lower in the presence of strong labor rights. Our findings remain statistically and economically significant after we control for a range of deal, firm, industry and state characteristics and explore various channels for the labor rights effect. Overall, the evidence indicates that employee-shareholder conflicts of interest reduce shareholder gains from acquisitions. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>John, Kose; Knyazeva, Anzhela; Knyazeva, Diana</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Motivated monitors: The importance of institutional investors' portfolio weights</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fich, Eliezer M.; Harford, Jarrad; Tran, Anh L.
Studies of institutional monitoring focus on the fraction of the firm held by institutions. We focus on the fraction of the institution's portfolio represented by the firm. In the context of acquisitions, we hypothesize that institutional monitoring will be greatest when the target firm represents a significant allocation of funds in the institution's portfolio. We show that this measure is important in reconciling mixed findings for total institutional ownership in the prior literature. The results indicate that our measure of institutional holdings leads to greater bid completion rates, higher premiums, and lower acquirer returns. This empirical evidence provides support for theories predicting a beneficial effect of blockholders in monitoring the firm in general and in enhancing the gains to takeover targets in particular. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fich, Eliezer M.; Harford, Jarrad; Tran, Anh L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Maturity rationing and collective short-termism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milbradt, Konstantin; Oehmke, Martin
Financing terms and investment decisions are jointly determined. This interdependence, which links firms' asset and liability sides, can lead to short-termism in investment. In our model, financing frictions increase with the investment horizon, such that financing for long-term projects is relatively expensive and potentially rationed. In response, firms whose first-best investments are long-term may adopt second-best projects of shorter maturities. This worsens financing terms for firms with shorter-maturity projects, inducing them to change their investments as well. In equilibrium, investment is inefficiently short-term. Equilibrium asset-side adjustments by firms can amplify shocks and, while privately optimal, can be socially undesirable. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Milbradt, Konstantin; Oehmke, Martin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt, labor markets, and the creation and destruction of firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almazan, Andres; de Motta, Adolfo; Titman, Sheridan
We analyze the financing and liquidation decisions of firms that face a labor market with search frictions. By inducing bankruptcy, debt can facilitate the process of creative destruction (i.e., the elimination of inefficient firms and the creation of new firms) but can also lead to excessive liquidation and unemployment in particular, during economic downturns. Within this setting, we examine policy interventions that influence the firms' financing and liquidation choices. We consider the role of monetary policy, which can reduce debt burdens during economy-wide downturns, and tax policy, which can influence the incentives of firms to use debt financing. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Almazan, Andres; de Motta, Adolfo; Titman, Sheridan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of risk capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erel, Isil; Myers, Stewart C.; Read, James A.
We present a theory of risk capital and of how tax and other costs of risk capital should be allocated in a financial firm. Risk capital is equity investment that backs obligations to creditors and other liability holders and maintains the firm's credit quality. Credit quality is measured by the ratio of the value of the firm's option to default to the default-free value of its liabilities. Marginal default values provide a full and unique allocation of risk capital. Efficient capital allocations maintain credit quality and preclude risk shifting. Our theory leads to an adjusted present value (APV) criterion for making investment and contracting decisions. We set out implications for risk management and corporate finance. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Erel, Isil; Myers, Stewart C.; Read, James A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deposits and bank capital structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Franklin; Carletti, Elena; Marquez, Robert
In a model with bankruptcy costs and segmented deposit and equity markets, we endogenize the cost of equity and deposit finance for banks. Despite risk neutrality, equity capital earns a higher expected return than direct investment in risky assets. Banks hold positive capital to reduce bankruptcy costs, but there is a role for capital regulation when deposits are insured. Banks could no longer use capital when they lend to firms instead of investing directly in risky assets. This depends on whether the firms are public and compete with banks for equity capital or are private with exogenous amounts of capital. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Allen, Franklin; Carletti, Elena; Marquez, Robert</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of Treasury supply on financial sector lending and stability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krishnamurthy, Arvind; Vissing-Jorgensen, Annette
We present a theory in which the key driver of short-term debt issued by the financial sector is the portfolio demand for safe and liquid assets by the nonfinancial sector. This demand drives a premium on safe and liquid assets that the financial sector exploits by owning risky and illiquid assets and writing safe and liquid claims against them. The central prediction of the theory is that safe and liquid government debt should crowd out financial sector lending financed by short-term debt. We verify this prediction with US data from 1875 to 2014. We take a series of approaches to rule out standard crowding out via real interest rates and to address potential endogeneity concerns. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Krishnamurthy, Arvind; Vissing-Jorgensen, Annette</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Introduction: New perspectives on corporate capital structures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Almeida, Heitor; Baker, Malcolm
nan</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Almeida, Heitor; Baker, Malcolm</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric decrease in liquidity trading before earnings announcements and the announcement return premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levi, Shai; Zhang, Xiao-Jun
Investors are reluctant to trade in the high-information-asymmetry days before earnings announcements. We show that the decrease in liquidity trading before announcements is asymmetric. We analyze buy and sell orders of investors with passive investment strategies, and find they do not reduce their sales as much as their purchases in the days before announcements. Investors needing liquidity sell stocks at a discount relative to the post-announcement price, and these preannouncement liquidity sales are a significant driver of the average positive returns, or return premium, known to characterize announcement days. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Levi, Shai; Zhang, Xiao-Jun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The price of wine</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dimson, Elroy; Rousseau, Peter L.; Spaenjers, Christophe
Using historical price records for Bordeaux Premiers Crus, we examine the impact of aging on wine prices and the long-term investment performance of fine wine. In line with the predictions of an illustrative model, young maturing wines from high-quality vintages provide the highest financial returns. Past maturity, famous chateaus deliver growing non-pecuniary benefits to their owners. Using an arithmetic repeat-sales regression over 1900-2012, we estimate a real financial return to wine investment (net of storage costs) of 4.1%, which exceeds bonds, art, and stamps. Returns to wine and equities are positively correlated. Finally, we find evidence of in-sample return predictability. Crown Copyright (C) 2015 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dimson, Elroy; Rousseau, Peter L.; Spaenjers, Christophe</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stocking up: Executive optimism, option exercise, and share retention</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sen, Rik; Tumarkin, Robert
We show that an executive is optimistic about her company's prospects if and only if she retains some of the shares received whenever she exercises company stock options. Empirically, an indicator of optimism based on this idea matches the expected relations between optimism and corporate decision-making better than commonly used indicators based on the timing of option exercise. This makes sense, as our model of an executive's optimal option exercise and portfolio choice demonstrates that the timing of option exercise depends just as much on stock and other executive characteristics as it does on optimism. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sen, Rik; Tumarkin, Robert</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Smart money, dumb money, and capital market anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akbas, Ferhat; Armstrong, Will J.; Sorescu, Sorin; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
We investigate the dual notions that "dumb money" exacerbates well-known stock return anomalies and "smart money" attenuates these anomalies. We find that aggregate flows to mutual funds (dumb money) appear to exacerbate cross-sectional mispricing, particularly for growth, accrual, and momentum anomalies. In contrast, hedge fund flows (smart money) appear to attenuate aggregate mispricing. Our results suggest that aggregate flows to mutual funds can have real adverse allocation effects in the stock market and that aggregate flows to hedge funds contribute to the correction of cross-sectional mispricing. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Akbas, Ferhat; Armstrong, Will J.; Sorescu, Sorin; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A century of capital structure: The leveraging of corporate America</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, John R.; Leary, Mark T.; Roberts, Michael R.
Unregulated US corporations dramatically increased their debt usage over the past century. Aggregate leverage low and stable before 1945 more than tripled between 1945 and 1970 from 11% to 35%, eventually reaching 47% by the early 1990s. The median firm in 1946 had no debt, but by 1970 had a leverage ratio of 31%. This increase occurred in all unregulated industries and affected firms of all sizes. Changing firm characteristics are unable to account for this increase. Rather, changes in government borrowing, macroeconomic uncertainty, and financial sector development play a more prominent role. Despite this increase among unregulated firms, a combination of stable debt usage among regulated firms and a decrease in the fraction of aggregate assets held by regulated firms over this period resulted in a relatively stable economy-wide leverage ratio during the 20th century. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Graham, John R.; Leary, Mark T.; Roberts, Michael R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>As certain as debt and taxes: Estimating the tax sensitivity of leverage from state tax changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heider, Florian; Ljungqvist, Alexander
Using staggered corporate income tax changes across U.S. states, we show that taxes have a first-order effect on capital structure. Firms increase leverage by around 40 basis points for every percentage-point tax increase. Consistent with dynamic tradeoff theory, the effect is asymmetric: leverage does not respond to tax cuts. This is true even within-firm: tax increases that are later reversed nonetheless lead to permanent leverage increases. The treatment effects are heterogeneous and confirm the tax channel: tax sensitivity is greater among profitable and investment-grade firms which respectively have a greater marginal tax benefit and lower marginal cost of issuing debt. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Heider, Florian; Ljungqvist, Alexander</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity hoarding and interbank market rates: The role of counterparty risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heider, Florian; Hoerova, Marie; Holthausen, Cornelia
We develop a model of interbank lending and borrowing with counterparty risk. The model has two key ingredients. First, liquidity in the banking sector is endogenous, so there is an opportunity cost of holding liquid assets. Second, banks are privately informed about the risk of their long-term assets, which can lead to adverse selection and high interest rates in the interbank market. We identify a novel form of a market break-down, which can lead to liquidity hoarding. It arises because adverse selection in the interbank market changes the opportunity cost of holding liquidity. We use the model to shed light on developments in interbank markets prior to and during the 2007-09 financial crisis, as well as the effectiveness of policy interventions aimed at restoring interbank market activity. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Heider, Florian; Hoerova, Marie; Holthausen, Cornelia</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discount window stigma during the 2007-2008 financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Armantier, Olivier; Ghysels, Eric; Sarkar, Asani; Shrader, Jeffrey
We provide empirical evidence for the existence, magnitude, and economic cost of stigma associated with banks borrowing from the Federal Reserve's Discount Window (DW) during the 2007-2008 financial crisis. We find that banks were willing to pay a premium of around 44 basis points (bps) across funding sources (126 bps after the bankruptcy of Lehman Brothers) to avoid borrowing from the DW. DW stigma is economically relevant as it increased some banks' borrowing cost by 32 bps of their pre-tax return on assets (ROA) during the crisis. The implications of our results for the provision of liquidity by central banks are discussed. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Armantier, Olivier; Ghysels, Eric; Sarkar, Asani; Shrader, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Payout policy through the financial crisis: The growth of repurchases and the resilience of dividends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Floyd, Eric; Li, Nan; Skinner, Douglas J.
We compare the payout policies of US industrials and banks over the past 30 years to better understand dividends, especially for banks. For industrials, dividends grow strongly after 2002, when the declining propensity to pay reverses. Banks have a higher and more stable propensity to pay dividends and resist cutting dividends as the 2007-2008 financial crisis begins. Before the crisis, increases in repurchases push payouts to historic levels. These findings are broadly consistent with the idea that banks use dividends to signal financial strength while agency costs of free cash flow better explain industrial payouts. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Floyd, Eric; Li, Nan; Skinner, Douglas J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility and mutual fund manager skill</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jordan, Bradford D.; Riley, Timothy B.
In a standard four-factor framework, mutual fund return volatility is a reliable, persistent, and powerful predictor of future abnormal returns. However, the abnormal returns are eliminated by the addition of a "vol" anomaly factor contrasting returns on portfolios of low and high volatility stocks. Consistent with Novy-Marx (2014) and Fama and French (2014), the Fama and French (2015) profitability and investment factors are equally effective at eliminating the abnormal returns. Failure to account for the vol anomaly, either directly or indirectly, can lead to substantial mismeasurement of fund manager skill. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Jordan, Bradford D.; Riley, Timothy B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition of the informed: Does the presence of short sellers affect insider selling?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, Massimo; Qian, Wenlan; Xu, Weibiao; Zhang, Hong
We study how the presence of short sellers affects the incentives of the insiders to trade on negative information. We show it induces insiders to sell more (shares from their existing stakes) and trade faster to preempt the potential competition from short sellers. An experiment and instrumental variable analysis confirm this causal relationship. The effects are stronger for "opportunistic" (i.e., more informed) insider trades and when short sellers' attention is high. Return predictability of insider sales only occurs in stocks with high short-selling potential, suggesting that short sellers indirectly enhance the speed of information dissemination by accelerating trading by insiders. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Massa, Massimo; Qian, Wenlan; Xu, Weibiao; Zhang, Hong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Resource accumulation through economic ties: Evidence from venture capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hochberg, Yael V.; Lindsey, Laura A.; Westerfield, Mark M.
Ties between similar partners in economic and financial networks are often attributed to concerns about agency costs. In this paper, we distinguish the underlying motives for tie formation between sets of potential partners in the network, thus informing the relative importance of agency cost and resource accumulation in tie formation across firms. We develop a robust and generalizable methodology that allows for the inference of similarity and/or cumulative advantage motives in the potential presence of resource trading. We estimate the model using venture capital (VC) co-investment networks, employing factor analysis to characterize orthogonal, interpretable resources for VC firms. In the VC setting, value-added resources other than capital appear to be exchanged for capital, but not for one another. We find little evidence for similarity motives as the primary driver of matching, suggesting that concerns over agency conflicts in partnering are dominated by the desire to accumulate higher levels of certain resources. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hochberg, Yael V.; Lindsey, Laura A.; Westerfield, Mark M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regression-based estimation of dynamic asset pricing models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adrian, Tobias; Crump, Richard K.; Moench, Emanuel
We propose regression-based estimators for beta representations of dynamic asset pricing models with an affine pricing kernel specification. We allow for state variables that are cross-sectional pricing factors, forecasting variables for the price of risk, and factors that are both. The estimators explicitly allow for time-varying prices of risk, time-varying betas, and serially dependent pricing factors. Our approach nests the Fama-MacBeth two-pass estimator as a special case. We provide asymptotic multistage standard errors necessary to conduct inference for asset pricing tests. We illustrate our new estimators in an application to the joint pricing of stocks and bonds. The application features strongly time-varying, highly significant prices of risk that are found to be quantitatively more important than time-varying betas in reducing pricing errors. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adrian, Tobias; Crump, Richard K.; Moench, Emanuel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Search-based peer firms: Aggregating investor perceptions through internet co-searches</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Charles M. C.; Ma, Paul; Wang, Charles C. Y.
Applying a "co-search" algorithm to Internet traffic at the SEC's EDGAR website, we develop a novel method for identifying economically related peer firms and for measuring their relative importance. Our results show that firms appearing in chronologically adjacent searches by the same individual (Search-Based Peers or SBPs) are fundamentally similar on multiple dimensions. In direct tests, SBPs dominate GICS6 industry peers in explaining cross-sectional variations in base firms' out-of-sample: (a) stock returns, (b) valuation multiples, (c) growth rates, (d) R&amp;D expenditures, (e) leverage, and (f) profitability ratios. We show that SBPs are not constrained by standard industry classification, and are more dynamic, pliable, and concentrated. We also show that co-search intensity captures the degree of similarity between firms. Our results highlight the potential of the collective wisdom of investors extracted from co-search patterns in addressing long-standing benchmarking problems in finance. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lee, Charles M. C.; Ma, Paul; Wang, Charles C. Y.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contractual incompleteness, limited liability and asset price bubbles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dow, James; Han, Jungsuk
When should we expect bubbles? Can levered intermediaries bid up risky asset prices through asset substitution? We study an economy with Financial intermediaries that issue debt and equity to buy risky assets. Asset substitution alone cannot cause bubbles because it is priced into the intermediaries' securities. But incomplete contracts and managerial agency problems can make intermediaries take excessive risk to exploit limited liability, bidding up risky asset prices. This destroys welfare through misallocation of resources. We argue that incentives for private monitoring cannot solve this problem. Finally, even without agency problems, debt subsidies will create similar effects. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dow, James; Han, Jungsuk</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO network centrality and merger performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>El-Khatib, Rwan; Fogel, Kathy; Jandik, Tomas
We study the effects on M&amp;A outcomes of CEO network centrality, which measures the extent and strength of a CEO's personal connections. High network centrality can allow CEOs to efficiently gather and control private information, facilitating value-creating acquisition decisions. We show, however, that M&amp;A deals initiated by high-centrality CEOs, in addition to being more frequent, carry greater value losses to both the acquirer and the combined entity than deals initiated by low-centrality CEOs. We also document that high-centrality CEOs are capable of avoiding the discipline of the markets for corporate control and the executive labor market, and that the mitigating effect of internal governance on CEO actions is limited. Our evidence suggests that corporate decisions can be influenced by a CEO's position in the social hierarchy, with high-centrality CEOs using their power and influence to increase entrenchment and reap private benefits. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>El-Khatib, Rwan; Fogel, Kathy; Jandik, Tomas</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High frequency market microstructure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O'Hara, Maureen
Markets are different now, transformed by technology and high frequency trading. In this paper, I investigate the implications of these changes for high frequency market microstructure (HFT). I describe the new high frequency world, with a particular focus on how HFT affects the strategies of traders and markets. I discuss some of the gaps that arise when thinking about microstructure research issues in the high frequency world. I suggest that, like everything else in the markets, research must also change to reflect the new realities of the high frequency world. I propose some topics for this new research agenda in high frequency market microstructure. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>O'Hara, Maureen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Central clearing and collateral demand</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duffie, Darrell; Scheicher, Martin; Vuillemey, Guillaume
We use an extensive data set of bilateral credit default swap (CDS) positions to estimate the impact on collateral demand of new clearing and margin regulations. The estimated collateral demands include initial margin and the frictional demands associated with the movement of variation margin through the network of market participants. We estimate the impact on total collateral demand of more widespread initial margin requirements, increased novation of CDS to central clearing parties (CCPs), an increase in the number of clearing members, the proliferation of CCPs of both specialized and non-specialized types, collateral rehypothecation practices, and client clearing. System-wide collateral demand is increased significantly by the application of initial margin requirements for dealers, whether or not the CDS are cleared. Given these dealer-to-dealer initial margin requirements, mandatory central clearing is shown to lower, not raise, system-wide collateral demand, provided there is no significant proliferation of CCPs. Central clearing does, however, have significant distributional consequences for collateral requirements across market participants. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Duffie, Darrell; Scheicher, Martin; Vuillemey, Guillaume</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>W Liquid-claim production, risk management, and bank capital structure: Why high leverage is optimal for banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeAngelo, Harry; Stulz, Rene M.
Liquidity production is a central function of banks. High leverage is optimal for banks in a model that has just enough frictions for banks to have a meaningful role in liquid-claim production. The model has a market premium for (socially valuable) safe/liquid debt, but no taxes or other traditional motives to lever up. Because only safe debt commands a liquidity premium, banks with risky assets use risk management to maximize their capacity to include such debt in the capital structure. The model can explain why banks have higher leverage than most operating firms, why risk management is central to banks' operating policies, why bank leverage increased over the last 150 years or so, and why leverage limits for regulated banks impede their ability to compete with unregulated shadow banks. (C) 2014 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>DeAngelo, Harry; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do acquirers choose between mergers and tender offers?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Offenberg, David; Pirinsky, Christo
Tender offers provide the advantage of substantially faster completion times than mergers. However, a tender offer signals to the target higher demand for its shares and raises its reservation price. In equilibrium, bidders tradeoff speed and cost. Consistent with this theory, we show that deals in more competitive environments and deals with fewer external impediments on execution are more likely to be structured as tender offers. Tender offers also require higher premiums than mergers. Finally, the rivals of the bidding firm realize significantly lower announcement returns and subsequent operating performance in tender offers than in mergers. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Offenberg, David; Pirinsky, Christo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extraordinary acquirers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golubov, Andrey; Yawson, Alfred; Zhang, Huizhong
Firm fixed effects alone explain as much of the variation in acquirer returns as all the firm- and deal-specific characteristics combined. An interquartile range of acquirer fixed effects is over 6%, comparable to the interquartile range of acquirer returns. Acquirer returns persist over time, but mainly at the top end of the distribution. Persistence continues under different chief executive officers (CEOs), and attributes of the broader management team do not explain the fixed effect. Firm-specific heterogeneity in acquirer returns suggests that some organizations are extraordinary acquirers irrespective of the leadership at the top and the deal structures they choose. Implications for the M&amp;A research are discussed. (C) 2015 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Golubov, Andrey; Yawson, Alfred; Zhang, Huizhong</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium fast trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Biais, Bruno; Foucault, Thierry; Moinas, Sophie
High speed market connections improve investors' ability to search for attractive quotes in fragmented markets, raising gains from trade. They also enable fast traders to obtain information before slow traders, generating adverse selection, and thus negative externalities. When investing in fast trading technologies, institutions do not internalize these externalities. Accordingly, they overinvest in equilibrium. Completely banning fast trading is dominated by offering two types of markets: one accepting fast traders, the other banning them. Utilitarian welfare is maximized with (i) a single market type on which fast and slow traders coexist and (ii) Pigovian taxes on investment in the fast trading technology. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Biais, Bruno; Foucault, Thierry; Moinas, Sophie</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High-frequency quoting, trading, and the efficiency of prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Conrad, Jennifer; Wahal, Sunil; Xiang, Jin
We examine the relation between high frequency quotation and the behavior of stock prices between 2009 and 2011 for the full cross section of securities in the US. On average, higher quotation activity is associated with price series that more closely resemble a random walk, and significantly lower cost of trading. We also explore market resiliency during periods of exceptionally high low-latency trading: large liquidity drawdowns in which, within the same millisecond, trading algorithms systematically sweep large volume across multiple trading venues. Although such large drawdowns incur trading costs, they do not appear to degrade the price formation process or increase the subsequent cost of trading. In an out-of-sample analysis, we investigate an exogenous technological change to the trading environment on the Tokyo Stock Exchange that dramatically reduces latency and allows co-location of servers. This shock also results in prices more closely resembling a random walk and a sharp decline in the cost of trading. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Conrad, Jennifer; Wahal, Sunil; Xiang, Jin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks' liability structure and mortgage lending during the financial crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dagher, Jihad; Kazimov, Kazim
We examine the impact of banks exposure to market liquidity shocks through wholesale funding on their supply of credit during the financial crisis using loan level data that best allow us to isolate supply-side effects. We find that banks that were more reliant on wholesale funding curtailed their credit significantly more than retail-funded banks. We also exploit the discrete fall in the liquidity of loans above the jumbo cutoff and show that this effect is significantly more pronounced for less liquid loans in line with a liquidity channel. We show that this result cannot be attributed to uneven shifts in demand. The negative relation between wholesale funding and the supply of credit is unique to the crisis episode. (C) 2015 International Monetary Fund. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dagher, Jihad; Kazimov, Kazim</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The adverse effects of systematic leakage ahead of official sovereign debt rating announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Michaelides, Alexander; Milidonis, Andreas; Nishiotis, George P.; Papakyriakou, Panayiotis
Rating agencies consult with local government officials several days prior to official announcements of sovereign debt rating changes, making information leakage likely. Using cross-country data from 1988 to 2012, we find evidence of information leakage. In particular, we find statistically and economically significant negative daily abnormal stock index returns prior to downgrade announcements. These effects are more pronounced in countries with lower institutional quality, and they persist during times with no downgrade rumors and no concurrent bad news in general. A mild post-announcement reversal consistent with overreaction to pre-event downgrade rumors highlights the adverse effects of such leakage and, thus, should be a policy concern for capital market regulators. (C) 2015 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Michaelides, Alexander; Milidonis, Andreas; Nishiotis, George P.; Papakyriakou, Panayiotis</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cross section of expected holding period returns and their dynamics: A present value approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lyle, Matthew R.; Wang, Charles C. Y.
We provide a tractable model of firm-level expected holding period returns using two firm fundamentals-book-to-market ratio and return on equity-and study the cross-sectional properties of the model-implied expected returns. We find that firm-level expected returns and expected profitability are time-varying but highly persistent and that forecasts of holding period returns strongly predict the cross section of future returns up to three years ahead. We show a highly significant predictive pooled regression slope for future quarterly returns of 0.86. The popular factor-based expected return models have either an insignificant or a significantly negative association with future returns. In supplemental analyses, we show that these forecasts are also informative of the time series variation in aggregate conditions. For a representative firm, the slope of the conditional expected return curve is more positive in good times, when expected short-run returns are relatively low, and the model-implied forecaster of aggregate returns exhibits modest predictive ability. Collectively, we provide a simple, theoretically motivated, and practically useful approach to estimating multi-period-ahead expected returns. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lyle, Matthew R.; Wang, Charles C. Y.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Generalized risk premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schneider, Paul
This paper develops an optimal trading strategy explicitly linked to an agent's preferences and assessment of the distribution of asset returns. The price of this strategy is a portfolio of implied moments, and its expected excess returns naturally accommodate compensation for higher-order moment risk. Variance risk and the equity premium approximate it to first order and it nests cross-sectional asset pricing models such as the linear Capital Asset Pricing Model (CAPM). An empirical study in the US index market compares the investment behavior of an agent with recursive long-run risk preferences to one who merely uses an identically independently distributed time series model and takes market prices as given. The two agents exhibit very similar behavior during crises and can be distinguished mostly during calm periods. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schneider, Paul</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical determinants of intertemporal choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Jeffrey R.; Ivkovic, Zoran; Weisbenner, Scott
We provide new evidence on the empirical determinants of intertemporal financial decisions. We use an exogenously imposed choice affecting nearly all Croatian retirees to study characteristics associated with choosing a larger, deferred stream of payments over a smaller, more immediate payment. Individuals are more willing to defer if they have higher incomes and are not liquidity constrained, have a longer time horizon because of better health and longer life expectancy, and have stronger bequest motives. Individuals who expect currency devaluation or political risk to reduce the value of future income are more likely to take the earlier income stream. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Brown, Jeffrey R.; Ivkovic, Zoran; Weisbenner, Scott</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Juicing the dividend yield: Mutual funds and the demand for dividends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harris, Lawrence E.; Hartzmark, Samuel M.; Solomon, David H.
Some mutual funds purchase stocks before dividend payments to artificially increase their dividends, which we call "juicing." Funds paid more than twice the dividends implied by their holdings in 7.4% of fund-years examined. Juicing is associated with larger inflows, and is more common among funds with unsophisticated investors. This behavior is consistent with an underlying investor demand for dividends, but is hard to explain by taxes or need for income, as funds can generate equivalent tax-free distributions by returning capital. Juicing is costly to investors through higher turnover and increased taxes of 0.57% to 1.52% of fund assets per year. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harris, Lawrence E.; Hartzmark, Samuel M.; Solomon, David H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do property rights matter? Evidence from a property law enactment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkowitz, Daniel; Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue
This paper considers a property law enactment that gave creditors more rights over the assets underlying their secured loans to private firms and gave private firms more protections against the potential expropriation of their assets. We find that this property law enactment led to a significant increase in firm value. We also find that the law's impact on value was more profound for firms with more tangible assets, lower internal cash flows, and stronger growth opportunities, and less profound for politically connected firms. Taken together, our findings confirm the importance of property rights protection in enhancing firm value. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berkowitz, Daniel; Lin, Chen; Ma, Yue</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market-wide attention, trading, and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yuan, Yu
Market-wide attention-grabbing events - record levels for the Dow and front-page articles about the stock market - predict the trading behavior of investors and, in turn, market returns. Both aggregate and household-level data reveal that high market-wide attention events lead investors to sell their stock holdings dramatically when the level of the stock market is high. Such aggressive selling has a negative impact on market prices, reducing market returns by 19 basis points on days following attention-grabbing events. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Yuan, Yu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment and CEO compensation under limited commitment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ai, Hengjie; Li, Rui
We extend the neoclassical investment model (Hayashi, 1982) to allow for limited commitment on compensation contracts. We consider three types of limited commitment: (i) managers cannot commit to compensation contracts that provide lower continuation utility than their outside options; (ii) shareholders cannot commit to negative net present value (NPV) projects; (iii) both the managers and the shareholders cannot commit. We characterize the optimal contract under general convex adjustment cost functions and provide examples for which closed-form solutions can be obtained. We show that, as in the data, small firms invest more, grow faster, and have a higher Tobin's Q than large firms under the optimal contract In addition, the pattern of the dependence of chief executive officer (CEO) compensation on past performance implied by our model is also consistent with empirical evidence. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ai, Hengjie; Li, Rui</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Excess control rights, bank capital structure adjustments, and lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lepetit, Laetitia; Saghi-Zedek, Nadia; Tarazi, Amine
We investigate whether excess control rights of ultimate owners in pyramids affect banks' capital ratio adjustments. When control and cash flow rights are identical, to boost capital ratios banks issue equity without cutting lending. However, when control rights exceed cash flow rights, instead of issuing equity, banks downsize by reducing lending. Such a finding is mostly prevalent in countries with weak shareholder protection or for family-controlled banks. Other factors also explain the extent to which such banks reduce lending. Our findings contribute to the capital structure adjustment literature and have critical policy implications for the implementation of Basel III and the debate on capital requirements and bank lending. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Lepetit, Laetitia; Saghi-Zedek, Nadia; Tarazi, Amine</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information reliability and welfare: A theory of coarse credit ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goel, Anand M.; Thakor, Anjan V.
An enduring puzzle is why credit rating agencies (CRAs) use a few categories to describe credit qualities lying in a continuum, even when ratings coarseness reduces welfare. We model a cheap-talk game in which a CRA assigns positive weights to the divergent goals of issuing firms and investors. The CRA wishes to inflate ratings but prefers an unbiased rating to one whose inflation exceeds a threshold. Ratings coarseness arises in equilibrium to preclude excessive rating inflation. We show that competition among CRAs can increase ratings coarseness. We also examine the welfare implications of regulatory initiatives. (C) 2015 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Goel, Anand M.; Thakor, Anjan V.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate payout, cash retention, and the supply of credit: Evidence from the 2008-2009 credit crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bliss, Barbara A.; Cheng, Yingmei; Denis, David J.
We document significant reductions in corporate payouts-both dividends and (to a larger extent) share repurchases-during the 2008-2009 financial crisis. Payout reductions are more likely in firms with higher leverage, more valuable growth options, and lower cash balances, i.e., those more susceptible to the negative consequences of an external financing shock. Moreover, firms appear to use the proceeds from the reduction in payout to maintain cash levels and to fund investment. These findings are consistent with the view that a shock to the supply of credit (net of demand effects) during the financial crisis increased the marginal benefit of cash retention, leading some firms to turn to payout reductions as a substitute form of financing. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bliss, Barbara A.; Cheng, Yingmei; Denis, David J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Vulnerable banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenwood, Robin; Landier, Augustin; Thesmar, David
We present a model in which fire sales propagate shocks across bank balance sheets. When a bank experiences a negative shock to its equity, a natural way to return to target leverage is to sell assets. If potential buyers are limited, then asset sales depress prices, in which case one bank's sales impact other banks with common exposures. We show how this contagion effect adds up across the banking sector, and how it can be estimated empirically using balance sheet data. We compute bank exposures to system-wide deleveraging, as well as the spillovers induced by individual banks. Applying the model to European banks, we evaluate a variety of interventions to reduce their vulnerability to fire sales during the sovereign debt crisis. (C) 2015 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Greenwood, Robin; Landier, Augustin; Thesmar, David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary policy and long-term real rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanson, Samuel G.; Stein, Jeremy C.
Changes in monetary policy have surprisingly strong effects on forward real rates in the distant future. A 100 basis point increase in the two-year nominal yield on a Federal Open Markets Committee announcement day is associated with a 42 basis point increase in the ten-year forward real rate. This finding is at odds with standard macro-models based on sticky nominal prices, which imply that monetary policy cannot move real rates over a horizon longer than that over which all prices in the economy can readjust. Instead, the responsiveness of long-term real rates to monetary shocks appears to reflect changes in term premia. One mechanism that could generate such variation in term premia is based on demand effects due to the existence of what we call yield-oriented investors. We find some evidence supportive of this channel. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hanson, Samuel G.; Stein, Jeremy C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price support by bank-affiliated mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golez, Benjamin; Marin, Jose M.
Fund managers are double agents; they serve both fund investors and owners of management firms. This conflict of interest may result in trading to support securities prices. Tests of this hypothesis in the Spanish mutual fund industry indicate that bank-affiliated mutual funds systematically increase their holdings in the controlling bank stock around seasoned equity issues, at the time of bad news about the controlling bank, before anticipated price drops, and after non-anticipated price drops. The results seem mainly driven by bank managers' incentives. Ownership of asset management companies thus matters and can distort capital allocation and asset prices. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Golez, Benjamin; Marin, Jose M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade credit and cross-country predictable firm returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albuquerque, Rui; Ramadorai, Tarun; Watugala, Sumudu W.
We investigate the role of trade credit links in generating cross-border return predictability between international firms. Using data from 43 countries from 1993 to 2009, we find that firms with high trade credit located in producer countries have stock returns that are strongly predictable based on the returns of their associated customer countries. This behavior is especially prevalent among firms with high levels of foreign sales. To better understand this effect we develop an asset pricing model in which firms in different countries are connected by trade credit links. The model offers further predictions about this phenomenon, including stronger predictability during periods of high credit constraints and low uninformed trading volume. We find supportive empirical evidence for these predictions. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Albuquerque, Rui; Ramadorai, Tarun; Watugala, Sumudu W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Friends or foes? The interrelationship between angel and venture capital markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hellmann, Thomas; Thiele, Veikko
This paper develops a theory of how angel and venture capital markets interact. Entrepreneurs first receive angel then venture capital funding. The two investor types are 'friends' in that they rely upon each other's investments. However, they are also 'foes,' because at the later stage the venture capitalists no longer need the angels. Using a costly search model we derive the equilibrium deal flows across the two markets, endogenously deriving market sizes, competitive structures, valuation levels, and exit rates. We also examine the role of legal protection for angel investments. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hellmann, Thomas; Thiele, Veikko</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Technology spillovers and corporate cash holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qiu, Jiaping; Wan, Chi
This study examines the effect of technology spillovers on firms' cash holdings. It finds that firms facing greater technology spillovers hold higher cash balances. This effect is more pronounced among financially constrained firms and for firms that are likely to benefit more from diffused technology, e.g., those that have newer patents, are more profitable, and face better growth opportunities. The spillover impact remains strong when product market competition and own-firm innovations are accounted for. Overall, our study identifies technology spillovers as an important factor in determining corporate cash policy. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Qiu, Jiaping; Wan, Chi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Impact of the Dodd-Frank act on credit ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dimitrov, Valentin; Palia, Darius; Tang, Leo
We analyze the impact of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (Dodd-Frank) on corporate bond ratings issued by credit rating agencies (CRAs). We find no evidence that Dodd-Frank disciplines CRAs to provide more accurate and informative credit ratings. Instead, following Dodd-Frank, CRAs issue lower ratings, give more false warnings, and issue downgrades that are less informative. These results are consistent with the reputation model of Morris (2001), and suggest that CRAs become more protective of their reputation following the passage of Dodd-Frank. Consistent with Morris (2001), we find that our results are stronger for industries with low Fitch market share, where Moody's and Standard &amp; Poor's have stronger incentives to protect their reputation (Becker and Milbourn, 2011). Our results are not driven by business cycle effects or firm characteristics, and strengthen as the uncertainty regarding the passage of Dodd-Frank gets resolved. We conclude that increasing the legal and regulatory costs to CRAs might have an adverse effect on the quality of credit ratings. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dimitrov, Valentin; Palia, Darius; Tang, Leo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do investors overpay for stocks with lottery-like payoffs? An examination of the returns of OTC stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eraker, Bjorn; Ready, Mark
We study returns on over-the-counter stocks and find that these returns are extremely negative on average. The distribution of OTC stock returns is highly positively skewed: while many of the stocks in our sample become worthless, a few do extremely well. We investigate whether this negative return premium can be rationalized by investors' preference for positively skewed payoffs. We show that the equilibrium model of Barberis and Huang (2008) provides a plausible explanation for the negative returns. We also show that OTC stocks that once traded on the regular exchanges perform much better than stocks that originate in the OTC markets. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eraker, Bjorn; Ready, Mark</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital allocation and delegation of decision-making authority within firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, John R.; Harvey, Campbell R.; Puri, Manju
We use a unique data set that contains information on more than 1,000 Chief Executive Officers (CEOs) and Chief Financial Officers (CFOs) around the world to investigate the degree to which executives delegate financial decisions and the circumstances that drive variation in delegation. Delegation does not appear to be monolithic; instead, our results show that it varies across corporate policies and also varies with the personal characteristics of the CEO. We find that CEOs delegate financial decisions for which they need the most input, when they are overloaded, and when they are distracted by recent acquisitions. CEOs delegate less when they are knowledgeable (long-tenured or with a finance background). Capital is allocated based on "gut feel" and the personal reputation of the manager running a given division. Finally, corporate politics and corporate socialism affect capital allocation in European and Asian firms. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Graham, John R.; Harvey, Campbell R.; Puri, Manju</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge funds and discretionary liquidity restrictions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aiken, Adam L.; Clifford, Christopher P.; Ellis, Jesse A.
We study hedge funds that imposed discretionary liquidity restrictions (DLRs) on investor shares during the financial crisis. DLRs prolong fund life, but impose liquidity costs on investors, creating a potential conflict of interest. Ostensibly, funds establish DLRs to limit performance-driven withdrawals that could force fire sales of illiquid assets. However, after they restrict investor liquidity, DLR funds do not reduce illiquid stock sales and underperform a control sample of non-DLR funds. Consequently, DLRs appear to negatively impact fund family reputation. After the crisis, funds from DLR families faced difficulties raising capital and were more likely to cut their fees. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Aiken, Adam L.; Clifford, Christopher P.; Ellis, Jesse A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of repatriation tax costs on US multinational investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanlon, Michelle; Lester, Rebecca; Verdi, Rodrigo
This paper investigates whether the U.S. repatriation tax for U.S. multinational corporations affects foreign investment. Our results show that the locked-out cash due to repatriation tax costs is associated with a higher likelihood of foreign (but not domestic) acquisitions. We also find a negative association between tax-induced foreign cash holdings and the market reaction to foreign deals. This result suggests that the investment activity of firms with high repatriation tax costs is viewed by the market as less value-enhancing than that of firms with low tax costs, consistent with foreign investment of firms with high repatriation tax costs possibly reflecting agency-driven behavior. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hanlon, Michelle; Lester, Rebecca; Verdi, Rodrigo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum has its moments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barroso, Pedro; Santa-Clara, Pedro
Compared with the market, value, or size factors, momentum has offered investors the highest Sharpe ratio. However, momentum has also had the worst crashes, making the strategy unappealing to investors who dislike negative skewness and kurtosis. We find that the risk of momentum is highly variable over time and predictable. Managing this risk virtually eliminates crashes and nearly doubles the Sharpe ratio of the momentum strategy. Risk-managed momentum is a much greater puzzle than the original version. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Barroso, Pedro; Santa-Clara, Pedro</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commonality in news around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dang, Tung Lam; Moshirian, Fariborz; Zhang, Bohui
Motivated by the pioneering study of Morck. Yeung, and Yu (2000), this paper investigates whether and how news commonality varies according to a country's institutional environments. Using a unique global news data set across 41 countries for the 20002009 period, we document three notable findings. First, firm-level news comoves more in countries with weaker institutional environments than in those with stronger institutional environments. Second, news commonality is positively associated with both stock return comovement and stock liquidity commonality. Third, the effect of news commonality on stock return and liquidity comovement is higher in countries with stronger institutions than in those with weaker institutions. These results suggest that a country's institutional environments affect firm-specific information production and, more importantly, support the information-efficiency view that lower price synchronicity is caused by greater capitalization of firm-specific information. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dang, Tung Lam; Moshirian, Fariborz; Zhang, Bohui</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of dynamic renegotiation and asymmetric information in financial contracting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roberts, Michael R.
Using data from Securities and Exchange Commission filings, I show that the typical bank loan is renegotiated five times, or every nine months. The pricing, maturity, amount, and covenants are all significantly modified during each renegotiation, whose timing is governed by the financial health of the contracting parties and uncertainty regarding the borrowers' credit quality. The relative importance of these factors depends on the duration of the lending relationship. I interpret these results in light of financial contracting theories and emphasize that renegotiation is an important mechanism for dynamically completing contracts and for allocating control rights ex post. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Roberts, Michael R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Scale and skill in active management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pastor, Lubos; Stambaugh, Robert F.; Taylor, Lucian A.
We empirically analyze the nature of returns to scale in active mutual fund management. We find strong evidence of decreasing returns at the industry level. As the size of the active mutual fund industry increases, a fund's ability to outperform passive:benchmarks declines. At the fund level, all methods considered indicate decreasing returns, though estimates that avoid econometric biases are insignificant. We also find that the active management industry has become more skilled over time. This upward trend in skill coincides with industry growth, which precludes the skill improvement from boosting fund performance. Finally, we find that performance deteriorates over a typical fund's lifetime. This result can also be explained by industry-level decreasing returns to scale. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Pastor, Lubos; Stambaugh, Robert F.; Taylor, Lucian A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The disintermediation of financial markets: Direct investing in private equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fang, Lily; Ivashina, Victoria; Lerner, Josh
We examine 20 years of direct private equity investments by seven large institutions. These direct investments perform better than public market indices, especially buyout investments and those made in the 1990s. Outperformance by the direct investments, however, relative to the corresponding private equity fund benchmarks is limited and concentrated among buyout transactions. Co-investments underperform the corresponding funds with which they co-invest, due to an apparent adverse selection of transactions available to these investors, while solo transactions outperform fund benchmarks. Investors' ability to resolve information problems appears to be an important driver of solo deal outcomes. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fang, Lily; Ivashina, Victoria; Lerner, Josh</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political capital and moral hazard</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kostovetsky, Leonard
This paper examines how political connections affect risk exposure of financial institutions. Using a geography-based measure. I find that politically connected firms have higher leverage and their stocks have higher volatility and beta. Furthermore, prior to the 2008 financial crisis, politically-connected financial firms had higher leverage and were more likely to increase their leverage during the housing bubble in response to local growth in median housing prices. During the crisis, higher leverage was associated with worse performance but being in a state with a US Senator on the Banking Committee was correlated with weakly improved stock returns and reduced bankruptcy probability, highlighting the value of political connections for financial firms. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kostovetsky, Leonard</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The JOBS Act and IPO volume: Evidence that disclosure costs affect the IPO decision</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dambra, Michael; Field, Laura Casares; Gustafson, Matthew T.
In April 2012, the Jumpstart Our Business Startups Act (JOBS Act) was enacted to help revitalize the initial public offering (IPO) market, especially for small firms. During the year ending March 2014, IPO volume and the proportion of small firm issuers was the largest since 2000. Controlling for market conditions, we estimate that the JOBS Act has led to 21 additional IPOs annually, a 25% increase over pre-JOBS levels. Firms with high proprietary disclosure costs, such as biotechnology and pharmaceutical firms, increase IPO activity the most. These firms are also more likely to take advantage of the act's de-risking provisions, allowing firms to file the IPO confidentially while testing-the-waters. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dambra, Michael; Field, Laura Casares; Gustafson, Matthew T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structured debt ratings: Evidence on conflicts of interest</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Efing, Matthias; Hau, Harald
We test if issuers of asset- and mortgage-backed securities receive rating favors from agencies with which they maintain strong business relationships. Controlling for issuer fixed effects and a large set of credit risk determinants, we show that agencies publish better ratings for those issuers that provide them with more bilateral securitization business. Such rating favors are larger for very complex structured debt deals and for deals issued during the credit boom period. Our analysis is based on a new deal-level rating statistic that accounts for the full distribution of tranche ratings below the AAA cut-off point of a structured debt deal. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Efing, Matthias; Hau, Harald</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A five-factor asset pricing model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.
A five-factor model directed at capturing the size, value, profitability, and investment patterns in average stock returns performs better than the three-factor model of Fama and French (FF, 1993). The five-factor model's main problem is its failure to capture the low average returns on small stocks whose returns behave like those of firms that invest a lot despite low profitability. The model's performance is not sensitive to the way its factors are defined. With the addition of profitability and investment factors, the value factor of the FF three-factor model becomes redundant for describing average returns in the sample we examine. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling financial contagion using mutually exciting jump processes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ait-Sahalia, Yacine; Cacho-Diaz, Julio; Laeven, Roger J. A.
We propose a model to capture the dynamics of asset returns, with periods of crises that are characterized by contagion. In the model, a jump in one region of the world increases the intensity of jumps both in the same region (self-excitation) as well as in other regions (cross-excitation), generating episodes of highly clustered jumps across world markets that mimic the observed features of the data. We develop and implement moment-based estimation and testing procedures for this model. The estimates provide evidence of self-excitation both in the US and the other world markets, and of asymmetric cross-excitation, with the US market typically having more influence on the jump intensity of other markets than the reverse. We propose filtered values of the jump intensities as a measure of market stress and examine their out-of-sample forecasting abilities. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ait-Sahalia, Yacine; Cacho-Diaz, Julio; Laeven, Roger J. A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing bidders in takeover contests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vladimirov, Vladimir
This paper argues that endogenizing how acquirers finance their cash bids is just as important for understanding bidding in takeovers as endogenizing acquirers' payment method choice. The paper shows that acquirers finance their cash bids with equity only if they lack access to competitive financing. This leads to underbidding and lower takeover premiums. Conversely, acquirers with access to competitive financing use debt and overbid. Endogenizing the payment method reveals that security (e.g., stock) bids carry lower premiums than cash bids, backed by competitive financing. These insights find empirical support and could help explain existing evidence, which contradicts prior theory. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Vladimirov, Vladimir</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of institutional ownership on firm transparency and information production</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boone, Audra L.; White, Joshua T.
We examine the effects of institutional ownership on firms' information and trading environments using the annual Russell 1000/2000 index reconstitution. Characteristics of firms near the index cutoffs are similar, except that firms in the top of the Russell 2000 have discontinuously higher proportional institutional ownership than firms in the bottom of the Russell 1000 primarily due to indexing and benchmarking strategies. We find that higher institutional ownership is associated with greater management disclosure, analyst following, and liquidity, resulting in lower information asymmetry. Overall, indexing institutions' predilection for lower information asymmetries facilitates information production, which enhances monitoring and decreases trading costs. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Boone, Audra L.; White, Joshua T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social learning and corporate peer effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaustia, Markku; Rantala, Ville
We find that firms are more likely to split their stock if their peer firms have recently done so. The effect is comparable to an increase of 40-50% in the share price. Splitting probability is also increasing in the announcement returns of peer splits. These results are consistent with social learning from peers' actions and outcomes. The unique features of the setting and various further tests render alternative explanations unlikely. We find no clear benefit in following successful peer splitters. Firms are sometimes suspected to succumb to imitation, and the effect we show could be a case in point. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kaustia, Markku; Rantala, Ville</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social interaction at work</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hvide, Hans K.; Oestberg, Per
Stock market investment decisions of individuals are positively correlated with those of coworkers. Sorting of unobservably similar individuals to the same workplaces is unlikely to explain this pattern, as evidenced by the investment behavior of individuals who move between plants. Purchases made under stronger coworker purchase activity are not associated with higher returns. Moreover, social interaction appears to drive the purchase of within-industry stocks. Overall, we find a strong influence of coworkers on investment choices, but not an influence that improves the quality of investment decisions. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hvide, Hans K.; Oestberg, Per</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of LBO activity based on repeated debt-equity conflicts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malenko, Andrey; Malenko, Nadya
We develop a theory of leveraged buyout (LBO) activity based on two elements: the ability of private equity-owned firms to borrow against their sponsors' reputation with creditors and externalities in sponsors' reputations due to competition and club formation. In equilibrium, the two sources of value creation in LBOs, operational improvements and financing, are complements. Moreover, sponsors that never add operational value cannot add value through financing either. Club deals are beneficial ex post by allowing low-reputation bidders with high valuations to borrow reputation from high-reputation bidders with low valuations, but they can destroy value by reducing bidders' investment in reputation. Unlike leverage of independent firms, driven only by firm-specific factors, buyout leverage is driven by economy-wide and sponsor-specific factors. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Malenko, Andrey; Malenko, Nadya</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The risk premia embedded in index options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andersen, Torben G.; Fusari, Nicola; Todorov, Viktor
We study the dynamic relation between market risks and risk premia using time series of index option surfaces. We find that priced left tail risk cannot be spanned by market volatility (and its components) and introduce a new tail factor. This tail factor has no incremental predictive power for future volatility and jump risks, beyond current and past volatility, but is critical in predicting future market equity and variance risk premia. Our findings suggest a wide wedge between the dynamics of market risks and their compensation, which typically displays a far more persistent reaction following market crises. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Andersen, Torben G.; Fusari, Nicola; Todorov, Viktor</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distilling the macroeconomic news flow</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beber, Alessandro; Brandt, Michael W.; Luisi, Maurizio
We propose a simple cross-sectional technique to extract daily factors from economic news released at different times and frequencies. Our approach can effectively handle the large number of different announcements that are relevant for tracking current economic conditions. We apply the technique to extract real-time measures of inflation, output, employment, and macroeconomic sentiment, as well as corresponding measures of disagreement among economists about these indices. We find that our procedure provides more timely and accurate forecasts of future changes in economic conditions than other real-time forecasting approaches. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Beber, Alessandro; Brandt, Michael W.; Luisi, Maurizio</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incremental variables and the investment opportunity set</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.
Variables with strong marginal explanatory power in cross-section asset pricing regressions typically show less power to produce increments to average portfolio returns, for two reasons. (1) Adding an explanatory variable can attenuate the slopes in a regression. (2) Adding a variable with marginal explanatory power always attenuates the values of other explanatory variables in the extremes of a regression's fitted values. Without a restriction on portfolio weights, the maximum Sharpe ratios in the GRS statistic of Gibbons, Ross, and Shanken (1989) provide little information about an incremental variable's impact on the portfolio opportunity set. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks as patient fixed-income investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanson, Samuel G.; Shleifer, Andrei; Stein, Jeremy C.; Vishny, Robert W.
We examine the business model of traditional commercial banks when they compete with shadow banks. While both types of intermediaries create safe "money-like" claims, they go about this in different ways. Traditional banks create money-like claims by holding illiquid fixed-income assets to maturity, and they rely on deposit insurance and costly equity capital to support this strategy. This strategy allows bank depositors to remain "sleepy": they do not have to pay attention to transient fluctuations in the market value of bank assets. In contrast, shadow banks create money-like claims by giving their investors an early exit option requiring the rapid liquidation of assets. Thus, traditional banks have a stable source of funding, while shadow banks are subject to runs and fire-sale losses. In equilibrium, traditional banks have a comparative advantage at holding fixed-income assets that have only modest fundamental risk but are illiquid and have substantial transitory price volatility, whereas shadow banks tend to hold relatively liquid assets. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hanson, Samuel G.; Shleifer, Andrei; Stein, Jeremy C.; Vishny, Robert W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring skill in the mutual fund industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berk, Jonathan B.; van Binsbergen, Jules H.
Using the value that a mutual fund extracts from capital markets as the measure of skill, we find that the average mutual fund has used this skill to generate about $3.2 million per year. Large cross-sectional differences in skill persist for as long as ten years. Investors recognize this skill and reward it by investing more capital with better funds. Better funds earn higher aggregate fees, and a strong positive correlation exists between current compensation and future performance. The cross-sectional distribution of managerial skill is predominantly reflected in the cross-sectional distribution of fund size, not gross alpha. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Berk, Jonathan B.; van Binsbergen, Jules H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tail risk premia and return predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollerslev, Tim; Todorov, Viktor; Xu, Lai
The variance risk premium, defined as the difference between the actual and risk-neutral expectations of the forward aggregate market variation, helps predict future market returns. Relying on a new essentially model-free estimation procedure, we show that much of this predictability may be attributed to time variation in the part of the variance risk premium associated with the special compensation demanded by investors for bearing jump tail risk, consistent with the idea that market fears play an important role in understanding the return predictability. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bollerslev, Tim; Todorov, Viktor; Xu, Lai</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does realized skewness predict the cross-section of equity returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amaya, Diego; Christoffersen, Peter; Jacobs, Kris; Vasquez, Aurelio
We use intraday data to compute weekly realized moments for equity returns and study their time-series and cross-sectional properties. Buying stocks in the lowest realized skewness decile and selling stocks in the highest realized skewness decile generates an average return of 19 basis points the following week with a t-statistic of 3.70. This result is robust across a wide variety of implementations and is not captured by the Fama-French and Carhart factors. The relation between realized kurtosis and next week's stock returns is positive but not always significant. We do not find a strong relation between realized volatility and next week's stock returns. (C) 2015 Elsevier BM. All rights reserved.</description><author>Amaya, Diego; Christoffersen, Peter; Jacobs, Kris; Vasquez, Aurelio</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government ownership and the cost of debt: Evidence from government investments in publicly traded firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borisova, Ginka; Fotak, Veljko; Holland, Kateryna; Megginson, William L.
We investigate how government equity ownership in publicly traded firms affects the cost of corporate debt. Using a sample of bond credit spreads from 43 countries over 1991 2010, we find that government ownership is generally associated with a higher cost of debt, consistent with state-induced investment distortions, but is associated with a lower cost of debt during financial crises and for firms more likely to be distressed, when implicit government guarantees become the dominant effect. Our results are robust to controls for the endogeneity of government ownership, and we find these effects to be specific to domestic government ownership. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Borisova, Ginka; Fotak, Veljko; Holland, Kateryna; Megginson, William L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executives' "off-the-job" behavior, corporate culture, and financial reporting risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davidson, Robert; Dey, Aiyesha; Smith, Abbie
We examine how executives' behavior outside the workplace, as measured by their ownership of luxury goods (low "frugality") and prior legal infractions, is related to financial reporting risk. We predict and find that chief executive officers (CEOs) and chief financial officers (CFOs) with a legal record are more likely to perpetrate fraud. In contrast, we do not find a relation between executives' frugality and the propensity to perpetrate fraud. However, as predicted, we find that unfrugal CEOs oversee a relatively loose control environment characterized by relatively high and increasing probabilities of other insiders perpetrating fraud and unintentional material reporting errors during their tenure. Further, cultural changes associated with an increase in fraud risk are more likely during unfrugal (vs. frugal) CEOs' reigns, including the appointment of an unfrugal CFO, an increase in executives' equity-based incentives to misreport, and a decline in measures of board monitoring intensity. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Davidson, Robert; Dey, Aiyesha; Smith, Abbie</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Female leadership and gender equity: Evidence from plant closure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tate, Geoffrey; Yang, Liu
We use unique worker-plant matched panel data to measure differences in wage changes experienced by workers displaced from closing plants. We observe larger losses among women than men, comparing workers who move from the same closing plant to the same new firm. However, we find a significantly smaller gap in hiring firms with female leadership. The results are strongest among women who are displaced from male-led plants and from less competitive industries. Our results suggest an important externality to having women in leadership positions: They cultivate more female-friendly cultures inside their firms. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tate, Geoffrey; Yang, Liu</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should one hire a corrupt CEO in a corrupt country?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mironov, Maxim
This paper examines the interaction between the propensity to corrupt (PTC) and firm performance. Using a unique data set of Moscow traffic violations, I construct the PTC of every Muscovite with a driver's license. Next, I determine the PTC for the top management of 58,157 privately held firms. I find that a 1 standard deviation increase in management PTC corresponds to a 3.6% increase in income diversion and that firms with corrupt management significantly outperform their counterparts. This study contributes to the literature that characterizes corruption using objective (instead of perception-based) measures and provides evidence regarding the positive aspects of corruption at the firm level. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Mironov, Maxim</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Suspect CEOs, unethical culture, and corporate misbehavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Biggerstaff, Lee; Cicero, David C.; Puckett, Andy
We show that firms with Chief Executive Officers (CEOs) who personally benefit from options backdating are more likely to engage in other corporate misbehaviors, suggestive of an unethical corporate culture. These firms are more likely to commit financial fraud to overstate earnings. They acquire more private companies, which could perpetuate their frauds, and their acquisitions are met with lower market responses. These misbehaviors are concentrated in firms with externally hired suspect CEOs, consistent with outside CEOs having greater discretion to shape firm culture. The costs of these misbehaviors are reflected in larger stock price declines during a market correction and increased CEO replacement. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Biggerstaff, Lee; Cicero, David C.; Puckett, Andy</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When firms talk, do investors listen? The role of trust in stock market reactions to corporate earnings announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pevzner, Mikhail; Xie, Fei; Xin, Xiangang
We examine whether the level of trust in a country affects investors' perception and utilization of information transmitted by firms through financial disclosure. Specifically, we investigate the effect of societal trust on investor reactions to corporate earnings announcements. We test two competing hypotheses. On the one hand, corporate earnings announcements are perceived as more credible by investors in more trusting societies and, therefore, elicit stronger investor reactions. On the other hand, societal trust mitigates outside investors' concern of moral hazard and reduces the value of corporate earnings announcements to them, thereby weakening their reactions to these events. We analyze the abnormal trading volume and abnormal stock return variance during the earnings announcement period in a large sample of firm-year observations across 25 countries, and we find that both measures of investor reactions to earnings announcements are significantly higher in more trusting countries. We also find that the positive effect of societal trust on investor reactions to earnings news is more pronounced when a country's investor protection and disclosure requirements are weaker, suggesting that trust acts as a substitute for formal institutions; when a country's average education level is lower, consistent with less educated people relying more on trust in making economic decisions; and when firm-level information asymmetry is higher, supporting the notion that trust plays a more important role in poorer information environments. (C) 2013 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Pevzner, Mikhail; Xie, Fei; Xin, Xiangang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lost in translation? The effect of cultural values on mergers around the world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahern, Kenneth R.; Daminelli, Daniele; Fracassi, Cesare
We find strong evidence that three key dimensions of national culture (trust, hierarchy, and individualism) affect merger volume and synergy gains. The volume of cross-border mergers is lower when countries are more culturally distant. In addition, greater cultural distance in trust and individualism leads to lower combined announcement returns. These findings are robust to year and country-level fixed effects, time-varying country-pair and deal-level variables, as well as instrumental variables for cultural differences based on genetic and somatic differences. The results are the first large-scale evidence that cultural differences have substantial impacts on multiple aspects of cross-border mergers. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ahern, Kenneth R.; Daminelli, Daniele; Fracassi, Cesare</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign corporations and the culture of transparency: Evidence from Russian administrative data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Braguinsky, Serguey; Mityakov, Sergey
Firms from developed countries carry a culture of transparency in business transactions that is opposite to the culture of hiding and insider dealing in developing and transition economies. We employ Russian administrative data on reported earnings and market values of cars to measure wage misreporting for individual employees of domestic firms in Moscow. We show that closer ties to multinationals lead to improved transparency of wage reporting in private Russian companies. Employees located closest to movers from multinationals in the job quality space experience the largest gains in transparency. We find a robust correlation between wage misreporting and accounting fraud. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Braguinsky, Serguey; Mityakov, Sergey</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Importing corruption culture from overseas: Evidence from corporate tax evasion in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeBacker, Jason; Heim, Bradley T.; Tran, Anh
We study how cultural norms and enforcement policies influence illicit corporate activities. Using confidential Internal Revenue Service (IRS) audit data, we show that corporations with owners from countries with higher corruption norms evade more tax in the U.S. This effect is strong for small corporations and decreases as the size of the corporation increases. In the mid-2000s, the United States implemented several enforcement measures to increase tax compliance. We find that these enforcement efforts were less effective in reducing tax evasion by corporations whose owners are from corrupt countries. This suggests that cultural norms can be a challenge to legal enforcement. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>DeBacker, Jason; Heim, Bradley T.; Tran, Anh</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of corporate culture</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guiso, Luigi; Sapienza, Paola; Zingales, Luigi
We study which dimensions of corporate culture are related to a firm's performance and why. We find that proclaimed values appear irrelevant. Yet, when employees perceive top managers as trustworthy and ethical, a firm's performance is stronger. We then study how different governance structures impact the ability to sustain integrity as a corporate value. We find that publicly traded firms are less able to sustain it. Traditional measures of corporate governance do not seem to have much of an impact. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Guiso, Luigi; Sapienza, Paola; Zingales, Luigi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Military CEOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benmelech, Efraim; Frydman, Carola
There is mounting evidence of the influence of personal characteristics of chief executive officers (CEOs) on corporate outcomes. In this paper we analyze the relation between military service of CEOs and managerial decisions, financial policies, and corporate outcomes. Exploiting exogenous variation in the propensity to serve in the military, we show that military service is associated with conservative corporate policies and ethical behavior. Military CEOs pursue lower corporate investment, are less likely to be involved in corporate fraudulent activity, and perform better during industry downturns. Taken together, our results show that military service has significant explanatory power for managerial decisions and firm outcomes. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Benmelech, Efraim; Frydman, Carola</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The "cultural revolution" in finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zingales, Luigi
nan</description><author>Zingales, Luigi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deflating profitability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ball, Ray; Gerakos, Joseph; Linnainmaa, Juhani T.; Nikolaev, Valeri V.
Gross profit scaled by book value of total assets predicts the cross section of average returns. Novy-Marx (2013) concludes that it outperforms other measures of profitability such as bottom line net income, cash flows, and dividends. One potential explanation for the measure's predictive ability is that its numerator (gross profit) is a cleaner measure of economic profitability. An alternative explanation lies in the measure's deflator. We find that net income equals gross profit in predictive power when they have consistent deflators. Deflating profit by the book value of total assets results in a variable that is the product of profitability and the ratio of the market value of equity to the book value of total assets, which is priced. We then construct an alternative measure of profitability, operating profitability, which better matches current expenses with current revenue. This measure exhibits a far stronger link with expected returns than either net income or gross profit. It predicts returns as far as ten years ahead, seemingly inconsistent with irrational pricing explanations. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ball, Ray; Gerakos, Joseph; Linnainmaa, Juhani T.; Nikolaev, Valeri V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are institutions informed about news?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hendershott, Terrence; Livdan, Dmitry; Schuerhoff, Norman
This paper combines daily buy and sell institutional trading volume with all news announcements from Reuters. Using institutional order flow (buy volume minus sell volume) we find a variety of evidence that institutions are informed. Institutional trading volume predicts the occurrence of news announcements. Institutional order flow predicts (i) the sentiment of the news; (ii) the stock market reaction on news announcement days; (iii) the stock market reaction on crisis news days; and (iv) earnings announcement surprises. These results suggest that significant price discovery related to news stories occurs through institutional trading prior to the news announcement date. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hendershott, Terrence; Livdan, Dmitry; Schuerhoff, Norman</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The bonding hypothesis of takeover defenses: Evidence from IPO firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, William C.; Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Yi, Sangho
We propose and test an efficiency explanation for why Firms deploy takeover defenses using initial public offering (IPO) firm data. We hypothesize that takeover defenses bond the firm's commitments by reducing the likelihood that an outside takeover will change the firm's operating strategy and impose costs on its business partners. Consistent with this hypothesis, we find that IPO firms deploy more takeover defenses when they have important business relationships to protect. An IPO firm's use of takeover defenses is positively related to the longevity of its business relationships. IPO firms' use of takeover defenses creates positive spillovers for their large customers. And IPO firms' valuation and subsequent operating performance are positively related to their use of takeover defenses when they have important business relationships. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Johnson, William C.; Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Yi, Sangho</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value versus growth investing: Why do different investors have different styles?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cronqvist, Henrik; Siegel, Stephan; Yu, Frank
We find that several factors explain an individual investor's style, i.e., the value versus growth orientation of the investor's stock portfolio. First, we find that an investor's style has a biological basis and is partially ingrained in an investor from birth. Second, we show that an investor's hedging demands as well as behavioral biases explain investment style. Finally, an investor's style is explained by life course theory in that experiences, both earlier and later in life, are related to investment style. Investors with adverse macroeconomic experiences (e.g., growing up during the Great Depression or entering the labor market during an economic recession) or who grow up in a lower socioeconomic status rearing environment have a stronger value orientation several decades later. Our research contributes a new perspective to the long-standing value and growth debate in finance. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cronqvist, Henrik; Siegel, Stephan; Yu, Frank</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Good and bad uncertainty: Macroeconomic and financial market implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Segal, Gill; Shaliastovich, Ivan; Yaron, Amir
Does macroeconomic uncertainty increase or decrease aggregate growth and asset prices? To address this question, we decompose aggregate uncertainty into 'good' and 'bad' volatility components, associated with positive and negative innovations to macroeconomic growth. We document that in line with our theoretical framework, these two uncertainties have opposite impact on aggregate growth and asset prices. Good uncertainty predicts an increase in future economic activity, such as consumption, output, and investment, and is positively related to valuation ratios, while bad uncertainty forecasts a decline in economic growth and depresses asset prices. Further, the market price of risk and equity beta of good uncertainty are positive, while negative for bad uncertainty. Hence, both uncertainty risks contribute positively to risk premia, and help explain the cross-section of expected returns beyond cash flow risk. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Segal, Gill; Shaliastovich, Ivan; Yaron, Amir</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>House prices, collateral, and self-employment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adelino, Manuel; Schoar, Antoinette; Severino, Felipe
We show the importance of the collateral lending channel for small business employment over the past decade. Small businesses in areas with greater increases in house prices experienced stronger growth in employment than large firms in the same areas and industries. To identify the role of the collateral lending channel separately from aggregate changes in demand, we show that this effect is more pronounced in industries that need little start-up capital and in which housing collateral is more important. This increase is also present in manufacturing industries, particularly those that ship goods over long distances. In aggregate, the collateral lending channel explains 15-25% of employment variation. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Adelino, Manuel; Schoar, Antoinette; Severino, Felipe</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Costs and benefits of friendly boards during mergers and acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schmidt, Breno
Finance theory predicts that board independence is not always in the shareholders' interest, in situations in which board advice is more important than monitoring, independence can decrease firm value. I test this prediction by examining the connection between takeover returns and board friendliness, using social ties between the CEO and board members as a proxy for less independent boards. I find that social ties are associated with higher bidder announcement returns when the potential value of board advice is high, but with lower returns when monitoring needs are high. The evidence suggests that friendly boards can have both costs and benefits, depending on the company's specific needs. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Schmidt, Breno</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Signal or noise? Uncertainty and learning about whether other traders are informed</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Snehal; Green, Brett
We develop a model where some investors are uncertain whether others are trading on informative signals or noise. Uncertainty about others leads to a nonlinear price that reacts asymmetrically to news. We incorporate this uncertainty into a dynamic setting where traders gradually learn about others and show that it generates empirically relevant return dynamics: expected returns are stochastic but predictable, and volatility exhibits clustering and the "leverage" effect. The model nests both the rational expectations (RE) and differences of opinions (DO) approaches and highlights a link between disagreement about fundamentals and uncertainty about other traders. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Banerjee, Snehal; Green, Brett</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The illiquidity premium: International evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amihud, Yakov; Hameed, Allaudeen; Kang, Wenjin; Zhang, Huiping
We examine the illiquidity premium in stock markets across 45 countries and present two findings. First, the average illiquidity return premium across countries is positive and significant, after controlling for other pricing factors. The premium is measured by monthly return series on illiquid-minus-liquid stocks or by the coefficient of stock illiquidity estimated from cross section Fama-MacBeth regressions. Second, a commonality exists across countries in the illiquidity return premium, controlling for common global return factors and variation in global illiquidity. This commonality is different from commonality in illiquidity itself and is greater in globally integrated markets. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Amihud, Yakov; Hameed, Allaudeen; Kang, Wenjin; Zhang, Huiping</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic linkages between monetary policy and the term structure of interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kung, Howard
This paper studies the equilibrium term structure of nominal and real interest rates and the time-varying bond risk premia implied by a stochastic endogenous growth model with imperfect price adjustment and monetary policy shocks. The production and price-setting decisions of firms drive low-frequency movements in growth and inflation rates that are negatively related. With recursive preferences, these growth and inflation dynamics are crucial for rationalizing key stylized facts in bond markets. When calibrated to macroeconomic data, the model quantitatively explains the means and volatilities of nominal bond yields and the failure of the expectations hypothesis. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kung, Howard</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does banking competition affect innovation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornaggia, Jess; Mao, Yifei; Tian, Xuan; Wolfe, Brian
We exploit the deregulation of interstate bank branching laws to test whether banking competition affects innovation. We find robust evidence that banking competition reduces state-level innovation by public corporations headquartered within deregulating states. Innovation increases among private firms that are dependent on external finance and that have limited access to credit from local banks. We argue that banking competition enables small, innovative firms to secure financing instead of being acquired by public corporations. Therefore, banking competition reduces the supply of innovative targets, which reduces the portion of state-level innovation attributable to public corporations. Overall, these results shed light on the real effects of banking competition and the determinants of innovation. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Cornaggia, Jess; Mao, Yifei; Tian, Xuan; Wolfe, Brian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial integration, housing, and economic volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loutskina, Elena; Strahan, Philip E.
The Great Recession illustrates the sensitivity of the economy to housing. This paper shows that financial integration, fostered by securitization and nationwide branching, amplified the positive effect of housing price shocks on the economy during the 1994-2006 period. We exploit variation in credit supply subsidies across local markets from government-sponsored enterprises to measure housing price changes unrelated to fundamentals. Using this instrument, we find that house price shocks spur economic growth. The effect is larger in localities more financially integrated, through both secondary loan market and bank branch networks. Financial integration thus raised the effect of collateral shocks on local economies, increasing economic volatility. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Loutskina, Elena; Strahan, Philip E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>X-CAPM: An extrapolative capital asset pricing model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barberis, Nicholas; Greenwood, Robin; Jin, Lawrence; Shleifer, Andrei
Survey evidence suggests that many investors form beliefs about future stock market returns by extrapolating past returns. Such beliefs are hard to reconcile with existing models of the aggregate stock market. We study a consumption-based asset pricing model in which some investors form beliefs about future price changes in the stock market by extrapolating past price changes, while other investors hold fully rational beliefs. We find that the model captures many features of actual prices and returns; importantly, however, it is also consistent with the survey evidence on investor expectations. (C) 2014 Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Barberis, Nicholas; Greenwood, Robin; Jin, Lawrence; Shleifer, Andrei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A comment on Christoffersen, Jacobs, and Ornthanalai (2012), "Dynamic jump intensities and risk premiums: Evidence from S&amp;P 500 returns and options"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Durham, Garland; Geweke, John; Ghosh, Pulak
Christoffersen, Jacobs, and Ornthanalai (2012) (CJO) propose an interesting and useful class of generalized autoregressive conditional heteroskedasticity (GARCH)-like models with dynamic jump intensity, and find evidence that the models not only fit returns data better than some commonly used benchmarks but also provide substantial improvements in option pricing performance. While such models pose difficulties for estimation and analysis, CJO propose an innovative approach to filtering intended to addresses them. However, some statistical issues arise that their approach leaves unresolved, with implications for the option pricing results. This note proposes a solution based on using the filter and estimator proposed by CJO but interpreted in the context of an alternative model. With respect to this model, the estimator is consistent, and likelihood-based model comparisons and hypothesis tests are valid. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Durham, Garland; Geweke, John; Ghosh, Pulak</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Non-executive employee stock options and corporate innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Xin; Fu, Kangkang; Low, Angie; Zhang, Wenrui
We provide empirical evidence on the positive effect of non-executive employee stock options on corporate innovation. The positive effect is more pronounced when employees are more important for innovation, when free-riding among employees is weaker, when options are granted broadly to most employees, when the average expiration period of options is longer, and when employee stock ownership is lower. Further analysis reveals that employee stock options foster innovation mainly through the risk-taking incentive, rather than the performance-based incentive created by stock options. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chang, Xin; Fu, Kangkang; Low, Angie; Zhang, Wenrui</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market run-ups, market freezes, inventories, and leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bond, Philip; Leitner, Yaron
We study trade between an informed seller and an uninformed buyer who have existing inventories of assets similar to those being traded. We show that these inventories could induce the buyer to increase the price (a run-up) but could also make trade impossible (a freeze) and hamper information dissemination. Competition can amplify the run-up by inducing buyers to purchase assets at a loss to prevent competitors from purchasing at lower prices and releasing bad news about inventories. In a dynamic extension, we show that a market freeze could be preceded by high prices. Finally, we discuss empirical and policy implications. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Bond, Philip; Leitner, Yaron</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>End-of-the-year economic growth and time-varying expected returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moller, Stig V.; Rangvid, Jesper
We show that macroeconomic growth at the end of the year (fourth quarter or December) strongly influences expected returns on risky financial assets, whereas economic growth during the rest of the year does not. We find this pattern for many different asset classes, across different time periods, and for US and international data. We also show that movements in the surplus consumption ratio of Campbell and Cochrane (1999), a theoretically well-founded measure of time-varying risk aversion linked to macroeconomic growth, influence expected returns stronger during the fourth quarter than the other quarters of the year. Our findings suggest that expected returns, risk aversion, and economic growth are particularly related at the end of the year, when we also expect consumers' portfolio adjustments to be concentrated. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Moller, Stig V.; Rangvid, Jesper</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fund managers under pressure: Rationale and determinants of secondary buyouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arcot, Sridhar; Fluck, Zsuzsanna; Gaspar, Jose-Miguel; Hege, Ulrich
The fastest growing segment of private equity (PE) deals is secondary buyouts (SBOs)-sales from one PE fund to another. Using a comprehensive sample of leveraged buyouts, we investigate whether SBOs are value-maximizing, or reflect opportunistic behavior. To proxy for adverse incentives, we develop buy and sell pressure indexes based on how close PE funds are to the end of their investment period or lifetime, their unused capital, reputation, deal activity, and fundraising frequency. We report that funds under pressure engage more in SBOs. Pressured buyers pay higher multiples, use less leverage, and syndicate less suggesting that their motive is to spend equity. Pressured sellers exit at lower multiples and have shorter holding periods. When pressured counterparties meet, deal multiples depend on differential bargaining power. Moreover, funds that invested under pressure underperform. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Arcot, Sridhar; Fluck, Zsuzsanna; Gaspar, Jose-Miguel; Hege, Ulrich</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Attentive insider trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alldredge, Dallin M.; Cicero, David C.
We provide evidence that some profitable insider stock selling is motivated by public information. At firms that disclose having concentrated sales relationships, insiders appear to sell their own stock profitably based on public information about their principal customers. Supplier insiders also sell more stock when public information about their customers' recent returns and earnings surprises suggests they will earn larger profits. These results are stronger when outside investor attention could be lower. Outside of this setting, insiders engage in a higher proportion of routine sales and their sales are less profitable. We do not find similar patterns for insider purchases. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Alldredge, Dallin M.; Cicero, David C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do term structures in different currencies co-move?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jotikasthira, Chotibhak; Le, Anh; Lundblad, Christian
Yield curve fluctuations across different currencies are highly correlated. This paper investigates this phenomenon by exploring the channels through which macroeconomic shocks are transmitted across borders. Macroeconomic shocks affect current and expected future short-term rates as central banks react to changing economic environments. Investors could also respond to these shocks by altering their required compensation for risk. Macroeconomic shocks thus influence bond yields both through a policy channel and through a risk compensation channel. Using data from the US, the UK, and Germany, we find that world inflation and US yield level together explain over two-thirds of the covariance of yields at all maturities. Further, these effects operate largely through the risk compensation channel for long-term bonds. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jotikasthira, Chotibhak; Le, Anh; Lundblad, Christian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does ambiguity matter? Estimating asset pricing models with a multiple-priors recursive utility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jeong, Daehee; Kim, Hwagyun; Park, Joon Y.
This paper considers asset pricing models with stochastic differential utility incorporating decision makers' concern with ambiguity on true probability measure. Under a representative agent setting, we empirically evaluate alternative preference specifications including a multiple-priors recursive utility. We find that relative risk aversion is estimated around 1-8 with ambiguity aversion and 7.4-15 without ambiguity aversion. Estimated ambiguity aversion is both economically and statistically significant and can explain up to 45% of the average equity premium. The elasticity of intertemporal substitution is higher than one, but its identification appears to be weak, as observed by previous authors. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Jeong, Daehee; Kim, Hwagyun; Park, Joon Y.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Callable bonds, reinvestment risk, and credit rating improvements: Role of the call premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tewari, Manish; Byrd, Anthony; Ramanlal, Pradipkumar
We identify the call premium in nonconvertible callable bonds as an effective contracting provision to address agency conflict due to reinvestment risk and credit rating improvements. We analyze 4,495 bonds issued between 1980 and 2012. When interest rates are high, a majority of investment-grade issues and almost the entire subset with long maturities (&gt; 20 years) include a call premium. When interest rates are low, virtually all investment-grade issues with long and short maturities are callable at par. High-yield issues are limited to short maturities. By about 4:1, they include a call premium regardless of interest rate levels. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Tewari, Manish; Byrd, Anthony; Ramanlal, Pradipkumar</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading rules, competition for order flow and market fragmentation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kwan, Amy; Masulis, Ronald; McInish, Thomas H.
We investigate competition between traditional stock exchanges and new dark trading venues using an important difference in regulatory treatment. Securities and Exchange Commission required minimum pricing increments constrain some stock spreads, causing large limit order queues. Dark pools allow some traders to bypass existing limit order queues with minimal price improvement. Using a regression discontinuity design, we find that spread constraints significantly weaken exchanges' competitiveness. As more orders migrate to dark pools, the probability of subsequent order execution there increases, raising liquidity. The ability to circumvent time priority of displayed limit orders is one cause of the rapid rise in US equity market fragmentation. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Kwan, Amy; Masulis, Ronald; McInish, Thomas H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing with arbitrage activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hugonnier, Julien; Prieto, Rodolfo
We study an economy populated by three groups of myopic agents: constrained agents subject to a portfolio constraint that limits their risk taking, unconstrained agents subject to a standard nonnegative wealth constraint, and arbitrageurs with access to a credit facility. Such credit is valuable as it allows arbitrageurs to exploit the limited arbitrage opportunities that emerge endogenously in reaction to the demand imbalance generated by the portfolio constraint The model is solved in closed-form, and we show that, in contrast to existing models with frictions and logarithmic agents, arbitrage activity has an impact on the price level and generates both excess volatility and the leverage effect We show that these results are due to the fact that arbitrageurs amplify fundamental shocks by levering up in good times and deleveraging in bad times. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Hugonnier, Julien; Prieto, Rodolfo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The failure of models that predict failure: Distance, incentives, and defaults</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rajan, Uday; Seru, Amit; Vig, Vikrant
Statistical default models, widely used to assess default risk, fail to account for a change in the relations between different variables resulting from an underlying change in agent behavior. We demonstrate this phenomenon using data on securitized subprime mortgages issued in the period 1997-2006. As the level of securitization increases, lenders have an incentive to originate loans that rate high based on characteristics that are reported to investors, even if other unreported variables imply a lower borrower quality. Consistent with this behavior, we find that over time lenders set interest rates only on the basis of variables that are reported to investors, ignoring other credit-relevant information. As a result, among borrowers with similar reported characteristics, over time the set that receives loans becomes worse along the unreported information dimension. This change in lender behavior alters the data generating process by transforming the mapping from observables to loan defaults. To illustrate this effect, we show that the interest rate on a loan becomes a worse predictor of default as securitization increases. Moreover, a statistical default model estimated in a low securitization period breaks down in a high securitization period in a systematic manner: it underpredicts defaults among borrowers for whom soft information is more valuable. Regulations that rely on such models to assess default risk could, therefore, be undermined by the actions of market participants. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Rajan, Uday; Seru, Amit; Vig, Vikrant</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The "greatest" carry trade ever? Understanding eurozone bank risks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Steffen, Sascha
We show that eurozone bank risks during 2007-2013 can be understood as carry trade behavior. Bank equity returns load positively on peripheral (Greece, Italy, Ireland, Portugal, Spain, or GIIPS) bond returns and negatively on German government bond returns, which generated carry until the deteriorating GIIPS bond returns adversely affected bank balance sheets. We find support for risk-shifting and regulatory arbitrage motives at banks in that carry trade behavior is stronger for large banks and banks with low capital ratios and high risk-weighted assets. We also find evidence for home bias and moral suasion in the subsample of GIIPS banks. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Steffen, Sascha</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can managers time the market? Evidence using repurchase price data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dittmar, Amy; Field, Laura Casares
Little is known about the price firms pay for stock repurchases. Using a data set of all U.S. repurchases from 2004 to 2011, we compare the actual average price paid monthly in a repurchase with the average market price for the same stock over various horizons. We find that firms repurchase stock at a significantly lower price than the average market price in all sample years. Less frequent repurchasers, firms that repurchase when insiders buy on their own account, and firms that experience low stock returns prior to the repurchase obtain significantly lower prices. After controlling for risk factors, repurchasing firms earn positive returns. Infrequent repurchasers earn a significantly higher return up to three years following the actual repurchase. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Dittmar, Amy; Field, Laura Casares</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Culture and R-2</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eun, Cheol S.; Wang, Lingling; Xiao, Steven C.
Consistent with predictions from the psychology literature, we find that stock prices co-move more (less) in culturally tight (loose) and collectivistic (individualistic) countries. Culture influences stock price synchronicity by affecting correlations in investors' trading activities and a country's information environment. Both market-wide and firm-specific variations are lower in tighter cultures. Individualism is mostly associated with higher firm-specific variations. Trade and financial openness weakens the effect of domestic culture on stock price comovements. These results hold for various robustness checks. Our study suggests that culture is an important omitted variable in the literature that investigates cross-country differences in stock price comovements. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Eun, Cheol S.; Wang, Lingling; Xiao, Steven C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate goodness and shareholder wealth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krueger, Philipp
Using a unique data set, I study how stock markets react to positive and negative events concerned with a firm's corporate social responsibility (CSR). I show that investors respond strongly negatively to negative events and weakly negatively to positive events. I then show that investors do value "offsetting CSR," that is positive CSR news concerning firms with a history of poor stakeholder relations. In contrast, investors respond negatively to positive CSR news which is more likely to result from agency problems. Finally, I provide evidence that CSR news with stronger legal and economic information content generates a more pronounced investor reaction. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Krueger, Philipp</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do analysts matter for governance? Evidence from natural experiments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Tao; Harford, Jarrad; Lin, Chen
Building on two sources of exogenous shocks to analyst coverage (broker closures and mergers), we explore the causal effects of analyst coverage on mitigating managerial expropriation of outside shareholders. We find that as a firm experiences an exogenous decrease in analyst coverage, shareholders value internal cash holdings less, its CEO receives higher excess compensation, its management is more likely to make value-destroying acquisitions, and its managers are more likely to engage in earnings management activities. Importantly, we find that most of these effects are mainly driven by the firms with smaller initial analyst coverage and less product market competition. We further find that after exogenous brokerage exits, a CEO's total and excess compensation become less sensitive to firm performance in firms with low initial analyst coverage. These findings are consistent with the monitoring hypothesis, specifically that financial analysts play an important governance role in scrutinizing management behavior, and the market is pricing an increase in expected agency problems after the loss in analyst coverage. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Chen, Tao; Harford, Jarrad; Lin, Chen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit lines as monitored liquidity insurance: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral; Almeida, Heitor; Ippolito, Filippo; Perez, Ander
We propose a theory of credit lines provided by banks to firms as a form of monitored liquidity insurance. Bank monitoring and resulting revocations help control illiquidity-seeking behavior of firms insured by credit lines. The cost of credit lines is thus greater for firms with high liquidity risk, which in turn are likely to use cash instead of credit lines. We test this implication for corporate liquidity management by identifying exogenous shocks to liquidity risk of firms in corporate bond and equity markets. Firms experiencing increases in liquidity risk move out of credit lines and into cash holdings. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Acharya, Viral; Almeida, Heitor; Ippolito, Filippo; Perez, Ander</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limited partner performance and the maturing of the private equity industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sensoy, Berk A.; Wang, Yingdi; Weisbach, Michael S.
We evaluate the performance of limited partners' (LPs') private equity investments over time. Using a sample of 14,380 investments by 1,852 LPs in 1,250 buyout and venture capital funds started between 1991 and 2006, we find that the superior performance of endowment investors in the 1991-1998 period, documented by prior literature, is mostly due to their greater access to the top-performing venture capital partnerships. In the subsequent 19992006 period, endowments no longer outperform, no longer have greater access to funds that are likely to restrict access, and do not make better investment selections than other types of institutional investors. Nevertheless, all investor types' private equity investments continue to outperform public markets on average. We discuss how these results are consistent with the general maturing of the industry, as private equity has transitioned from a niche, poorly understood area to a ubiquitous part of institutional investors' portfolios. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Sensoy, Berk A.; Wang, Yingdi; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Acquirer-target social ties and merger outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ishii, Joy; Xuan, Yuhai
This article investigates the effect of social ties between acquirers and targets on merger performance. We find that the extent of cross-firm social connection between directors and senior executives at the acquiring and the target firms has a significantly' negative effect on the abnormal returns to the acquirer and to the combined entity upon merger announcement. Moreover, acquirer-target social ties significantly increase the likelihood that the target firm's chief executive officer (CEO) and a larger fraction of the target firm's pre-acquisition board of directors remain on the board of the combined firm after the merger. In addition, we find that acquirer CEOs are more likely to receive bonuses and are more richly compensated for completing mergers with targets that are highly connected to the acquiring firms, that acquisitions are more likely to take place between two firms that are well connected to each other through social ties, and that such acquisitions are more likely to subsequently be divested for performance-related reasons. Taken together, our results suggest that social ties between the acquirer and the target lead to poorer decision making and lower value creation for shareholders overall. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Ishii, Joy; Xuan, Yuhai</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Freedom of choice between unitary and two-tier boards: An empirical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Belot, Francois; Ginglinger, Edith; Sloyin, Myron B.; Sushka, Marie E.
We examine board structure in France, which since 1966 has allowed firms the freedom to choose between unitary and two-tier boards. We analyze how this choice relates to characteristics of the firm and its environment. Firms with severe asymmetric information tend to opt for unitary boards; firms with a potential for private benefits extraction tend to adopt two-tier boards. Chief executive officer turnover is more sensitive to performance at firms with two-tier boards, indicating greater monitoring. Our results are broadly consistent with the Adams and Ferreira (2007) model and suggest that gains result from allowing freedom of contract about board structure. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Belot, Francois; Ginglinger, Edith; Sloyin, Myron B.; Sushka, Marie E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who works for startups? The relation between firm age, employee age, and growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ouimet, Paige; Zarutskie, Rebecca
Young firms disproportionately employ and hire young workers. On average, young employees in young firms earn higher wages than young employees in older firms. Young employees disproportionately join young firms with greater innovation potential and that exhibit higher growth, conditional on survival. We argue that the skills, risk tolerance, and joint dynamics of young workers contribute to their disproportionate share of employment in young firms. Moreover, an increase in the supply of young workers is positively related to new firm creation in high-tech industries, supporting a causal link between the supply of young workers and new firm creation. Published by Elsevier B.V.</description><author>Ouimet, Paige; Zarutskie, Rebecca</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of investment banker directors in M&amp;A</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Qianqian; Jiang, Feng; Lie, Erik; Yang, Ke
We examine how directors with investment banking experience affect firms' acquisition behavior. We find that firms with investment bankers on the board have a higher probability of making acquisitions. Furthermore, acquirers with investment banker directors experience higher announcement returns, pay lower takeover premiums and advisory fees, and exhibit superior long-run performance. Overall, our results suggest that directors with investment banking experience help firms make better acquisitions, both by identifying suitable targets and by reducing the cost of the deals. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Huang, Qianqian; Jiang, Feng; Lie, Erik; Yang, Ke</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting anomaly performance with politics, the weather, global warming, sunspots, and the stars</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Novy-Marx, Robert
Predictive regressions find that the party of the US president, the weather in Manhattan, global warming, the El Nino phenomenon, sunspots, and the conjunctions of the planets all have significant power predicting the performance of popular anomalies. The interpretation of these results has important implications for the asset pricing literature. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Novy-Marx, Robert</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond market access and investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harford, Jarrad; Uysal, Vahap B.
Prior research has shown that differential access to debt markets significantly affects capital structure. In this paper, we examine the effect of access to debt markets on investment decisions by using debt ratings to indicate bond market access. We find that rated firms are more likely to undertake acquisitions than nonrated firms. This finding remains even after accounting for firm characteristics, for the probability of being rated, and in matched sample analysis as well as in subsamples based on leverage, firm size, age and information opacity. Rated firms also pay higher premiums for their targets and receive less favorable market reaction to their acquisition announcements relative to nonrated firms. However, the average announcement returns to rated acquirers are non-negative. Collectively, these findings suggest that the lack of debt market access has a real effect on the ability to make investments as well as on the quality of these investments by creating underinvestment, instead of simply constraining overinvestment. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</description><author>Harford, Jarrad; Uysal, Vahap B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>