<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JPM6</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Levels of the game: Harder to win when professionals are the market (vol 26, pg 12, 2000)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellis, C. D.
nan</description><author>Ellis, C. D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The inconsistency of return-based style analysis - And its implications.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buetow, G. W.; Johnson, R. R.; Runkle, D. E.
The authors demonstrate that the usual application of the return-based style analysis relies on commercially available indexes that exhibit extreme multicollinearity. The subsequent results are volatile and have little meaning. As a result, the authors argue that implementing return-based style analysis with commercially available indexes can result in inaccurate and inappropriate investment decision-making. Even with multicollinearity, however, they demonstrate that the results of the analysis can be meaningful as long as the explanatory variables properly capture the investment objective of the portfolio. The authors conclude that the only way to implement return-based analysis is to use portfolio-specific benchmarks that properly capture the investment objectives of the portfolio.</description><author>Buetow, G. W.; Johnson, R. R.; Runkle, D. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value, size, and portfolio efficiency - The value effect obtains across both large- and small-stock portfolios.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chow, K. V.; Hulburt, H. M.
In this article the authors examine the effects of book-to-market value (BE/ME) on portfolio selection and efficiency. The authors classify U.S. stocks into six value/size categories and generate a large number of random portfolios for each value/size category. Using a range of portfolio ranking criteria ria, they show that portfolios composed of high BE/ME stocks significantly dominate those of low BE/ME stocks, Portfolios composed of high BE/ME stocks perform better than randomly selected portfolios. These results obtain for all ranking criteria and for all portfolio sizes examined.</description><author>Chow, K. V.; Hulburt, H. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimizing manager structure and budgeting manager risk - A user's guide for active management.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Waring, B.; Whitney, D.; Pirone, J.; Castille, C.
Selecting active managers and structuring their use has historically been more art than science. The authors explain why a manager structure can and should be approached as a problem of portfolio construction, a view that brings a whole set of tools to bear on the problem. This approach suggests optimizing to maximize expected active returns while controlling active risks. For a given risk budget, there is a single combination of the candidate managers who will best maximize the risk-adjusted expected active return of the portfolio. An optimized approach will also solve the active-passive or core-satellite allocation problem, a perennial area of indecision. The passive or core managers will naturally be held by the optimizer in inverse proportion to the active risk budget. This approach can be easily modified to process off-benchmark managers and to incorporate an optimal completion solution as part of the overall structure. This is a practical and robust manager structure solution appropriate to any investor using multiple managers or interested in the optimal active-passive mix.</description><author>Waring, B.; Whitney, D.; Pirone, J.; Castille, C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity duration, growth options, and asset pricing - The context is important in evaluation of equity duration.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornell, B.
Because much of the value of equity depends on option characteristics of investment projects, if is not feasible to calculate equity duration directly. As a result, recent literature has focused on estimating equity duration empirically. Using twenty-five size and book-to-market portfolios, the author shows that estimates of equity duration are critically dependent on the specification of the regression model used to estimate equity duration.</description><author>Cornell, B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Realized rates of return in emerging equity markets - Diversification is still the watchword.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eaker, M.; Grant, D.; Woodard, N.
The authors analyze che returns of nine emerging markets for the period from 1976 through 1997. They find that although currency movements (primarily depreciation) have a dramatic impact on individual country returns, they have a much reduced impact on real returns and an insignificant impact on the returns of a diversified portfolio. In addition, the authors demonstrate the importance of rebalancing and its effect on both the risk and return of an emerging market portfolio.</description><author>Eaker, M.; Grant, D.; Woodard, N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market's best months - They are not random; there is pattern.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Seligman, P. E.
This research demonstrates that the greatest monthly gains in the S&amp;P 500 directly follow corrections. It appears as if the cor rections themselves are the source of the exceptional performance. The author also categorizes corrections using objective criteria because the length of the rebound following a correction can be estimated by knowing the type of correction. The impact of these two insights on market performance is captured in a hypothetical timing model. The model outperforms the S&amp;P by 3.9 percentage points a year for fifty years but requires being invested only 40% of the time. The model is not intended to be a money making scheme, but instead a device to demonstrate the power of these ideas as they would play out in a quasi-real life scenario.</description><author>Seligman, P. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Meta-risks - Beyond the scope of explicit financial risks.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gray, J.
In principle, the risks in capital markets are relatively easy to assess and to manage because there is no such thing as a bad capital market risk, only a mispriced one. The author argues that too narrow a focus on those risks misses the equally important "meta-risks," those that pass beyond capital market risks. Here there are bad ones. They are intrinsically more difficult to identify, assess, and manage because they center around people and organizations and their interactions. For these risks, the author argues that an open dialectic of risk may be the ultimate form of risk management.</description><author>Gray, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>In search of the meaning of risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The investor fear gauge</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Whaley, R. E.
The Chicago Board Options Exchange's Market Volatility Index (VIX) is called the "investor fear gauge." To understand why, it is necessary to understand the index's construction. To understand how VIX performs its role, it is necessary to examine its history and its relation to stock market returns. In this article, the author describes the construction of the volatility index and examines its movements over the past fourteen years.</description><author>Whaley, R. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The unending game of chicken</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beating benchmarks - A stockpicker's reality.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Strongin, S.; Petsch, M.; Sharenow, G.
The inability of active managers to consistently outperform capitalization-weighted benchmarks can be explained by a mismatch between those benchmarks and the underlying nature of active management. The authors show that this mismatch cannot be effectively addressed either through macro-level risk controls or through improved stock selection. They develop a new approach to risk management that emphasizes diversification at the individual stock level and offers significant improvements in risk-return efficiency and portfolio manager consistency; this new approach to risk management is also significantly easier to incorporate into a bottom-up investment process. Plan sponsors can further improve the value of active management through combinations of new, more portfolio manager-friendly active manager benchmarks and completion indexes that move the overall allocations back to their original capitalization-weighted benchmarks.</description><author>Strongin, S.; Petsch, M.; Sharenow, G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An optimal frontier - Using pooling to go beyond the efficient frontier.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schirripa, F.; Tecotzky, N. D.
The optimal frontier investment method described here represents a new portfolio construction process that relies on well-established practices and theory. It incorporates the insurance concept of risk-pooling into the Markowitz portfolio optimization process. This method offers investors returns higher than had previously been thought possible, with no increase in risk. In essence, this method pools a group of investors with different risk-reward goals in a single efficient portfolio that preserves the group's average risk tolerance. The portfolio's overall return is then distributed to the investors on the basis of their preselected risk levels. Pooling each investor's risk and return goals in one combined portfolio results in higher returns for everyone, proving that in portfolio management, the whole does exceed the sum of its parts.</description><author>Schirripa, F.; Tecotzky, N. D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Practical active currency management for global equity portfolios - Value for the global equity manager.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reinert, T. F.
For global equity portfolios, a number of active currency management strategies have consistently dominated both unhedged and passively hedged strategies. The author shows that for portfolios broadly diversified across major equity markets (including the U.S., the U.K., France, Germany, and Japan), a single technically based active currency management strategy yielded the highest risk adjusted return in all rolling ten-year periods and in twenty-one of twenty-four rolling five-year periods during 1972-1999. Although equity managers may not be in the business of foreign exchange management, they should not be blind to significant currency trends that could be detrimental to portfolio performance. The author suggests some practical techniques to address these trends.</description><author>Reinert, T. F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing a closed-end investment fund - Given the discount paradox.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bierman, H.; Swaminathan, B.
Closed-end investment funds tend to sell at a discount to the market value of their investment assets. The two primary measures of success are the returns earned by the fund's investors (before- and after-tax) and the extent of the fund's market value discount from the market value of the investment assets. It is frequently assumed that the smaller the discount, the more Likely it is that the market approves of management's performance. This article considers the implications to a fund's management of these two measures of success. While there are many different explanations for these discounts, the authors focus on two tax effects and the resulting paradox. One tax effect is the fund's unrealized capital gain and the implicit future tax liability associated with it. The second tax effect is the value discount a tax-aware potential investor requires if the fund will realize future capital gains in a finite time period more rapidly than the investor would realize with a direct investment.</description><author>Bierman, H.; Swaminathan, B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Better risk management - The maximum expected compound return of discretionary wealth.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wilcox, J. W.
In this article the author shows how a single criterion, the maximization of expected compound return of discretionary wealth, can be used to improve risk management practices in a wide variety of applications. Applications include setting appropriate short-term risk tolerance, evaluating the impact of skewed and fat-tailed return distributions, and analyzing stop loss orders and portfolio insurance as well as better management of active managers. The author shows the impact of the failure of tracking error to account for the covariance between active policies and benchmark risk as well as the potential for deceptive information ratios. Finally, he shows how to convert momentum and value investor styles into option-equivalents that can then be assessed in terms of latent risk and impact on expected compound return. It becomes obvious that value investing is like selling a put and a call.</description><author>Wilcox, J. W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>US corporate pension plans - A value at risk analysis.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gupta, F.; Stubbs, E.; Thambiah, Y.
Using the universe of the 200 largest corporate pension plans in 1998, the authors report their value at risk (VaR) estimates and perform peer group comparisons on the basis of sector, plan assets, funding status, asset allocation, and performance. The results indicate that VaR estimates differ significantly for this sample, ranging fi om about 10% to 28%, with a median value of 17%. Also, plan aggressiveness increases more with plan assets than with funding status. More surprising is the finding that plan performance (i.e., actual plan returns) is not related. Although risk profiles differ across sectors, plans in the Healthcare, Technology, and Transportation sectors are the most aggressive (and risk profiles within sectors are closely aligned). The exceptions are Financials, Capital Goods, and Basic Materials.</description><author>Gupta, F.; Stubbs, E.; Thambiah, Y.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sustainable investment withdrawals - The focus is on sustainability.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pye, G. B.
The mean-variance approach permits the evaluation of portfolio strategies without otherwise first specifying preferences about risk. It is not well suited, however, to investors who must make periodic withdrawals from their investments. This includes endowment funds, foundations, and individuals after they retire. Expected utility models have been applied to such situations, but they have been difficult for practitioners to implement since preferences must be specified beforehand. By assuming such investors want to make sustainable withdrawals, the author develops a simple model for evaluating investment choices over time without making any further assumptions about preferences. Various factors that affect the size and sustainability of the withdrawals are explored.</description><author>Pye, G. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How well have taxable investors been served in the 1980s and 1990s? Needed: A change in mind-set.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arnott, R. D.; Berkin, A. L.; Ye, J.
This article examines the performance of large equity mutual funds over the past ten, fifteen, and twenty years. On both a before- and after-tax basis, the authors find that the average mutual fund underperformed the Vanguard Index 500 fund. Although part of this underperformance is attributed to a small-size bias inherent in active management, an analysis of the pure tax effects also shows that funds have not been managed in a tax-efficient manner. The authors suggest a few simple ways to improve after-tax performance.</description><author>Arnott, R. D.; Berkin, A. L.; Ye, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge funds and the Asian currency crisis - Global hedge funds did not move exchange rates.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, S. J.; Goetzmann, W. N.; Park, J. M.
The authors test the performance of a number of global hedge funds over a four-year period in order to determine whether they could have been responsible for the crash in the Asian currencies in 1997. They use Sharpe's style analysis to measure the variations in the historical exposure of these funds to Asian currencies leading up to the crisis. The results indicate that fund profits were not generally positive during the crisis, nor were funds' estimated exposures to Asian currencies unusual. Consequently the authors find no empirical evidence to support the hypothesis that George Sores, or any other hedge fund manager, was responsible for the crisis. Style analysis suggests that global managers actively vary their exposures to currencies, but over the period 1993 through 1997 these fluctuations were not found to be associated with moves in exchange rates.</description><author>Brown, S. J.; Goetzmann, W. N.; Park, J. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Semiannual seasonality in high-yield bond returns - Exploitable patterns.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fridson, M. S.
Exploitable seasonal patterns in high-yield bond returns are not limited to the widely studied "January effect." On average, the high-yield sector outperforms ten-year Treasuries by a wider margin between December 1 and May 31 than between June 1 and November 30. Within the high-yield sector, single-Bs outperform double-Bs on average between December 1 and May 31, and underperform them between June 1 and November 30. The author finds that the semiannual seasonality effect does not appear to reflect seasonality in capital flows to the high-yield sector, but arises rather from a seasonal pattern in Treasury bond returns.</description><author>Fridson, M. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>