<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>JPM4</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>DTSSM (duration times spread) - A new measure of spread exposure in credit portfolios.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben Dor, Arik; Dynkin, Lev; Hyman, Jay; Houweling, Patrick; van Leeuwen, Erik; Penninga, Olaf
nan</description><author>Ben Dor, Arik; Dynkin, Lev; Hyman, Jay; Houweling, Patrick; van Leeuwen, Erik; Penninga, Olaf</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Total return strategies for multi-asset portfolios - Dynamically managing portfolio risk.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Herold, Ulf; Maurer, Raimond; Stamos, Michael; Vo, Huy Thanh
nan</description><author>Herold, Ulf; Maurer, Raimond; Stamos, Michael; Vo, Huy Thanh</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effectiveness of minimum-variance hedging - The impact of electronic trading and exchange-traded funds.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, Carol; Barbosa, Andreza
nan</description><author>Alexander, Carol; Barbosa, Andreza</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Execution risk - It's the same as investment risk.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engle, Robert; Ferstenberg, Robert
nan</description><author>Engle, Robert; Ferstenberg, Robert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aspects of constrained long-short equity portfolios - Taking off the handcuffs.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sorensen, Eric H.; Hua, Ronald; Qian, Edward
nan</description><author>Sorensen, Eric H.; Hua, Ronald; Qian, Edward</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do hedge funds stop reporting performance? - It isn't because they're successful</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grecu, Alex; Malkiel, Burton G.; Saha, Atanu
It is well known that the disappearance of hedge funds from a database may cause biases in estimating investment returns on these funds, although there is no consensus on why hedge funds stop reporting to data-gathering services. Some studies have suggested that poor or failing funds stop reporting, while others claim that it is the better-performing funds that stop reporting because they no longer need to attract new capital. Analysis of the TASS database reveals that hedge fund returns become significantly poorer at the end of a fund's reporting life. Other analysis here applies survival time techniques to examine funds' time to failure and changes in hazard rates (probabilities of failure) over time. Larger hedge funds and better-performing funds have lower hazard rates.</description><author>Grecu, Alex; Malkiel, Burton G.; Saha, Atanu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do foreign exchange markets still trend? Easy profits are over</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pukthuanthong-Le, Kuntara; Levich, Richard M.; Thomas, Lee R.
Is it possible to trend-trade profitably in foreign currencies? Examination of both major or currency futures contracts that have been trading since the 1970s and more recent contracts on exotic currencies that have begun to trade only in the past several years shows that the era of easy profits in major foreign currencies from simple trend-following strategies is over. Trend-trading in a currency may have been advantageous in the early years of a floating-rate regime, but markets have adapted so that profits from these simple trading strategies have vanished. Newly trading currencies do appear susceptible to trend-following trading strategies, and there may remain in this case some attractive profit opportunities.</description><author>Pukthuanthong-Le, Kuntara; Levich, Richard M.; Thomas, Lee R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The volatility effect - Lower risk without lower return</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blitz, David C.; van Vliet, Pim
There is empirical evidence that stocks with low historical volatility have high risk-adjusted returns, with annual alpha spreads of global low- versus high-volatility decile portfolios of 12 percentage points over 1986-2006. This volatility effect appears independently in U.S., European, and Japanese markets. It is similar in size to classic effects such as value, size, and momentum, and cannot be explained by implicit loadings on these well-known effects. These results indicate that equity investors overpay for risky stocks. Possible explanations include leverage restrictions, inefficient two-step investment processes, and behavioral biases of private investors. To exploit the volatility effect in practice, investors might include low-risk stocks as a separate asset class in the strategic asset allocation phase of the investment process.</description><author>Blitz, David C.; van Vliet, Pim</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Original issue high-yield bonds - Explaining persistent underperformance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fridson, Martin; Sterling, Karen
In the past full market cycle, original issue high-yield bonds delivered no material total return premium over default risk-free Treasuries. This represents a bona fide market inefficiency that proved exploitable by one group engaged in actual market transactions; the corporate sellers of new issues escaped paying a default risk premium. Among the five complementary rather than mutually exclusive factors identified here that may explain this anomaly are: unawareness of the underperformance of the 01 segment; a focus on security selection; a lottery ticket effect; and the mirage of remedy based on yield. The discussion gets to the heart of the premise on which the high-yield investment concept was marketed at the dawn of its modern era in the late 1970s.</description><author>Fridson, Martin; Sterling, Karen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Divergent expectations - When investors agree to disagree</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davis, Paul L.; Pagano, Michael S.; Schwartz, Robert A.
Investors who have the same information and interpret it differently are said to have divergent (as distinct from homogeneous) expectations. Financial economists generally frown on the divergent expectations assumption, even though it is critically important in describing reality. The idea of divergent expectations paves the way to understanding price and quantity discovery as major functions of a marketplace, and goes to the heart of important questions: What drives trading, and why does market structure matter? Many issues concerning market structure and market structure regulation should be analyzed in a divergent or heterogeneous expectations context, which has implications for market participants and public policy. We benefit from paying more attention to how asset managers behave.</description><author>Davis, Paul L.; Pagano, Michael S.; Schwartz, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxation without replication - A look at a problem in synthetic indexing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chance, Don M.
It is well known that investors can structure derivatives portfolios to replicate a position in an underlying asset and synthetically create an index fund. While an individual investor can achieve perfect replication on a before-tax basis, taxes make derivatives inferior to direct investment in the index, because synthetically generated dividends and capital gains do not benefit from the preferential tax treatment accorded direct investment in the index. Derivative strategies also have lower after-tax expected returns and Sharpe ratios and are less volatile than the index. Option strategies benefit from a tax inequity favoring low exercise prices but are still inferior to direct investment in the index. Thus, synthetic indexing may be effective on a before-tax or non-taxable basis, but it falls for taxable individual investors because today's tax code disadvantages derivatives replicating strategies.</description><author>Chance, Don M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using binary variables to obtain small optimal portfolios - A quadratic integer programming resolution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Charpin, Francoise; Lacaze, Dominique
Binary modeling may be used in order to constrain the, number of stocks in an optimal portfolio. Such modeling allows an exact resolution of the number problem raised by Jansen and van Dijk in an earlier issue; their solution is only approximate. Binary variable modeling allows imposition of a minimum threshold for portfolio weights, whether by itself or along with the numerical constraint. A manager can thus limit transaction and administrative costs when tracking a benchmark or constructing an efficient portfolio.</description><author>Charpin, Francoise; Lacaze, Dominique</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock return momentum and reversal - A comprehensive study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Figelman, Ilya
Stock return momentum and reversal have been known for well over a decade. This work documents two new momentum effects that are even stronger than effects documented to date: yearly and quarterly periodicity. That is, in the long term, stock returns tend to follow a pattern every twelve months, and in the intermediate term to follow a pattern every three months. This analysis of the S&amp;P 500 over 1970-2004 includes examination of five momentum and reversal effects by industry, calendar month, and earnings announcement month. The sustainability of stock return momentum and reversal strategies of course has some implications for implementation.</description><author>Figelman, Ilya</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Timing small versus large stocks - Using artificial intelligence to decide when to be long or short</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>L'Her, Jean-Francois; Mouakhar, Tammam; Roberge, Mathieu
Historical evidence suggests that accurate timing can reap huge potential profits in trading between large and small stocks. Artificial intelligence approaches-recursive partitioning, neural networks, and genetic algorithms-are an aid in development of size-timing strategies to decide when to be long or short with respect to the U.S. Fama-French small-minus-big portfolio. AI strategies are trained on both a static learning sample and on an expandable learning sample. The results here show that most AI strategies could successfully time the US. size premium over 1990-2004. When predictions differ, a consensus strategy, or one favored by two of the three AI approaches, outperforms the SMB strategy more systematically, and reduces transaction costs.</description><author>L'Her, Jean-Francois; Mouakhar, Tammam; Roberge, Mathieu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information horizon, portfolio turnover, and optimal alpha models - Optimizing multiple factors for the best IR</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qian, Edward; Sorensen, Eric H.; Hua, Ronald
The net value-added of an investment strategy has two parts: the expected value of the alpha skill, and the cost of implementation. The first part is positive and depends on the efficacy of a return forecasting model; the second is negative and depends on portfolio turnover and trading skills. The higher the former, and the lower the latter, the happier the investor. Typically, managers give little consideration to turnover, but throw an alpha model into an optimizer, setting turnover constraints to handle transaction costs. The explicit framework here instead integrates alpha models with portfolio turnover and transaction costs. The result allows evaluation of factors in terms of net return and then optimization of multiple factors to achieve the best net information ratio. Optimal multifactor models change as portfolio turnover constraints change, providing a potential solution for model evolution as assets under management grow.</description><author>Qian, Edward; Sorensen, Eric H.; Hua, Ronald</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic portfolio analysis - Establishing a link between cause and effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinold, Richard
Dynamic portfolio analysis looks at the portfolio as a moving object to capture the essentials of a long-short investment management strategy. To see the forest rather than the trees requires simplifying assumptions, here a bare-bones two-parameter structure. One parameter measures the rate of information flow and the other the rate of trading in the portfolio. This framework yields informative results to explain the implementation efficiency of the strategy as well as the balance between the cost of trading and the benefit of trading. More significantly, it establishes a link between cause and effect. These notions can be used to engineer strategies, to analyze strategies, and to optimize the operation of strategies.</description><author>Grinold, Richard</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The surprising bond between CAPM and the meaning of liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Peter L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, Peter L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk management for hedge funds with position information - Both managers and investors could be satisfied</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jorion, Philippe
Risk management is a challenge for hedge funds because traditional risk measurement methods based on return data are unreliable for dynamic trading strategies. Yet managers can still use value at risk (VaR) methods to measure and control the market risk of hedge funds. Two key VaR features enable this:VaR 1) is based on current position information, and 2) focuses on a lower quantile of the distribution of losses or some other risk metric. For rapidly changing positions, VaR should be measured at frequent intervals, as would be the case for banks' proprietary trading portfolios. An example demonstrates the usefulness of dynamic risk measures for a hypothetical hedge fund with short option positions. Imposition of daily ex ante VaR limits using position information can be successful in controlling realized risk.</description><author>Jorion, Philippe</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What does "Coming of age" mean?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Peter L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, Peter L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real estate comes of age</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clayton, Jim; Gordon, Jacques; Fabozzi, Frank; Giliberto, S. Michael; Liang, Youguo; Hudson-Wilson, Susan
Real estate has gained wider acceptance as a legitimate institutional investment. The asset class continues to grow and adopt many of the features of the broader capital markets. International strategies, private equity strategies [with general partner - limited partner promoted fee structures], public REIT corporate governance, structured debt products (commercial mortgage-backed securities and commercial real estate collateralized debt obligations), hedge funds, as well as commercial real estate index-based derivatives are among the topics covered in this issue. Today real estate must compete in the alternative space with private equity, hedge funds, infrastructure and more. Yet, as several of the articles in this edition conclude, real estate retains its distinct features as an asset class; the role of real estate as a portfolio risk reducer looks sustainable over the long-term. Over long and short time periods, its return patterns are rarely in close synchronization with stocks and bonds, despite the adoption of the financial tools and techniques of the broader capital markets. This paradox-further integration with the broader capital markets, yet distinct and separate financial behavior-is the underlying theme of nearly all the articles in the issue.</description><author>Clayton, Jim; Gordon, Jacques; Fabozzi, Frank; Giliberto, S. Michael; Liang, Youguo; Hudson-Wilson, Susan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of corporate governance on the performance of REITs - Yes, poor governance can destroy value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bianco, Candy; Ghosh, Chinmoy; Sirmans, C. E.
The authors examine the relationship between the "external" governance index (G-Index) developed in a 2003 study Gompers et al. and performance of R-EITs in 2004 and 2006. The G-Index is a sum of takeover barriers instituted by individual R-EITs, and antitakeover provisions in the state of a firm's incorporation. For the sample of R-EITs studies, the G-Index ranges from 3 to 13, with an average of 8. When compared to firms in general, shareholder rights in R-EITs are stronger than unregulated firms. The analysis shows, as expected, a significantly negative impact of G-Index on REIT performance for 2004. However, the effect is diminished in 2006. The authors contend that this is due to the G-Index of R-EITs increasing between 2004 and 2006, creating clustering around the mean value in 2006. This would render the G-Index less important when comparing performance across firms. In view of the fact that hostile takeovers are rare among REITs, the low G-Index and the irrelevance of G-Index in more recent times suggests that external governance is ineffective for REITs. Thus, more attention should be paid to the efficacy to internal governance mechanisms.</description><author>Bianco, Candy; Ghosh, Chinmoy; Sirmans, C. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commercial real estate: New paradigm or old story? The compression of the commercial real estate risk premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ruff, Jon
The spread of mortgage securitization and a decline in business-cycle volatility have reduced the traditional risks of holding commercial real estate. These secular factors, in turn, have contributed to record property valuations. Investors seem willing to pay higher prices for the same cash flows because they believe they can borrow at lower rates and count on stable cash flow from commercial rentals in a climate of comparative certainty The result has been a sharp compression of the risk premium on commercial real estate. No doubt, this phenomenon will in part prove to be cyclical. However, the evidence suggests that, long term, the commercial real estate risk prermium will remain below its historical average.</description><author>Ruff, Jon</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are hedge fund managers better able to forecast real estate security returns than others? A cause may be the incentive fees paid to hedge fund managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Richard; Fung, Scott; Shilling, James D.; Simmons-Mosley, Tammie X.
Tests of whether hedge fund managers are better able to forecast real estate securities returns than others are reported in this article. Two main conclusions follow from the estimation results. First, it appears that real estate securities hedge fund managers may have some superior forecasting skills. Second, there is evidence that hedge fund managers prefer real estate securities that are larger, have a higher beta, and a higher residual standard deviation. The results reported are consistent with the hypothesized effects.</description><author>Chung, Richard; Fung, Scott; Shilling, James D.; Simmons-Mosley, Tammie X.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commercial real estate CDOs - Growing new opportunities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lucas, Douglas J.; Goodman, Laurie S.; Fabozzi, Frank J.; Manning, Rebecca J.
Collateralized debt obligations backed by commercial real estate (CPE CDOs) have quickly become an important and accepted part of commercial real estate finance. Issuers are drawn to CRE CDOs for efficient financing, and investors are drawn to the diversification benefits. The authors describe CRE CDOs, their evolution, current market trends, and historical performance. CRE CDOs give traditional real estate asset managers the flexibility to take advantage of relative value opportunities within the real estate market, while providing non-recourse financing that matches the average life and interest profile of the underlying asset pool. And as managers are drawn to CRE CDOs for structural flexibility and term financing, investors benefit from exposure to a diverse portfolio of managed CRE assets. As the CDO market continues to develop and evolve, there is an increasing number of managed CRE CDOs and CRE CDOs backed by commercial real estate loans. While this evolution brings new risks to CRE CDOs, it also provides new opportunities for investors. The authors also provide a framework for evaluating CRE CDO investments and discuss how rating agencies rate CRE CDOs.</description><author>Lucas, Douglas J.; Goodman, Laurie S.; Fabozzi, Frank J.; Manning, Rebecca J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What drives the return on CMBS? Likely by more than the commercial property market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xu, Xiaoqing Eleanor
Despite the significance of commercial mortgage-backed securities (CMBS) as one of the fastest growing asset classes and the increasing interest in CMBS by institutional investors, available empirical evidence on CMBS is lacking. This article sheds light on the investment performance of CMBS, the driving forces behind CMBS return variability, and the relative importance of these variables in predicting CMBS returns. Using monthly data for the Lehman Brothers fixed income indices from January 1997 to June 2006, the author finds that mean return and total risk-adjusted return on investment-grade and high-yield CMBS. clearly dominate those on investment-grade and high-yield corporate bonds, Treasuries, and stocks. The autor uses a structural vector autoregressive (VAR) model to examine what drives the excess returns on CMBS and how. Impulse response analysis suggests that the growth in industrial production, inflation rate, change in 30-year mortgage rate, change in term structure spread, and excess return on the S&amp;P 500 all have a significant and inverse contemporaneous effects on the excess returns on investment-grade and high-yield CMBS. Variance decomposition reveals that the change in mortgage rate and the term structure spread together explain 57% and 44% of the variance in investment-grade and high-yield CMBS excess returns, respectively. Changes in the amount of CMBS issuance show a significant negative lag effect on CMBS excess returns. The required returns on CMBS are positively driven by the changes in credit spread, but this positive effect is much stronger for high-yield CMBS than for investment-grade CMBS.</description><author>Xu, Xiaoqing Eleanor</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stocks are from mars real estate is from venue - The cross-section of long-run investment performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pai, Arvind; Geltner, David
How does the expected total return, or opportunity cost of capital (the discounted cash flow discount rate), differ across different types and locations of properties? This question is fundamental to institutional real estate investment portfolio and asset management. The cross-section of the long-run investment performance of real estate assets should be related to plausible measures of risk. The authors study this question using original, customized investment performance indexes constructed from the property-level NCREIF Index database. They find that a multi-factor model similar in structure to that of Fama and French predicts quite well the cross-section of long-run performance within NCPEIF But the real estate model is curiously opposite to that of the stock market. Is this an arbitrage opportunity?</description><author>Pai, Arvind; Geltner, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The pricing of non-core real estate ventures - Estimating the net expected risk-adjusted return</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Paghari, Joseph L.
The last several years have witnessed a significant shift among institutional real estate investors from "core" deals to "non-core" ventures. These non-core real estate transactions can be characterized as possessing one or more of the following traits: higher-return/higher-risk assets, greater leverage, shorter time horizons, and the use of a joint venture/operating partner. In this article, the author explores the pricing of non-core real estate investing by investigating three key aspects: 1) examining the impacts of financial leverage and demonstrating how the law of one price can be used to price non-core ventures by comparison to the core-with-leverage alternatives, 2) identifying the adverse effects of transaction costs upon investors' return (which worsen as the holding period shortens and/or the leverage ratio increases), and 3) describing the costs (e.g., because of the asymmetric nature of the operating partner's promote, computing the expected value of the promote using the venture's expected return understates the expected value of the promote) and benefits involved with the use of joint venture partners-as well as some of the agency costs these partners introduce. Finally, a preliminary examination of the NCREIF data suggests that the Joint-ventured office and industrial properties possibly provided investors with improved risk-adjusted rates of return. However, these conclusions are quite preliminary.</description><author>Paghari, Joseph L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing and index considerations in commercial real estate derivatives - Understanding the basics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Geltner, David; Fisher, Jeffrey
It is important for participants in the nascent commercial real estate derivatives market to understand the fundamentals and the subtleties of the appraisal and transaction based indexes that underpin derivatives, as well as the proper pricing of derivatives taking into account the risk and return characteristics of the index. The authors review these considerations including the implications that appraisal lag in the index has for the equilibrium pricing of derivatives' such as index swaps, and the use of such vehicles for hedging real estate risk. An important conclusion is that even if the underlying index does not represent the current equilibrium in the property market or if the property market itself is not in equilibrium, we can still use equilibrium analysis in the derivatives market to derive a fair price for an appraisal index based derivative including consideration of the effect of any lagging and smoothing in the index. The analysis highlights informational issues about indexes and property markets that present both danger and opportunity for the facilitation of a well-functioning property derivatives market in the United States and shows how usage of derivatives needs to consider the effect of possible lag in the index.</description><author>Geltner, David; Fisher, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Smoothing and implications for asset allocation choices - Model selection or calibration?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marcato, Gianluca; Key, Tony
An extensive literature on smoothing issues in real estate markets has been published, covering a range of theoretical techniques, applications to indices and asset allocation. In this article, the authors focus on the practical implications of unsmoothing model selection and calibration for asset allocation decisions in the UK, US and Australian markets and sheds light upon contradictory results in previous studies. They find that different unsmoothing techniques yield very similar asset allocation choices. Identified portfolio weights are much more sensitive to the unsmoothing parameter than to the unsmoothing method. The authors conclude that research on smoothing should focus on the identification of the best parameter rather than on the specification of the model to be used. The empirical results reported are in line with previous studies with respect to the level of the unsmoothing parameter. Moreover, current weights of asset classes in institutional portfolios suggest a parameter maximzsing the portfolio's Sharpe ratio similar to the one identified in other studies. This result also has implications for the implied volatility of real estate markets.</description><author>Marcato, Gianluca; Key, Tony</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Win private equity and hedge funds replace real estate in mixed-asset portfolios? Not likely</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bond, Shaun A.; Hwang, Soosung; Mitchell, Paul; Satchell, Stephen E.
The role of commercial real estate in the investment portfolios of institutional investors is now well established, and allocations towards real estate are increasing. However, fund managers are also gaining interest in alternative asset classes such as hedge funds, private equity, commodities, and infrastructure. This raises the question of whether real estate could fall out of favor with institutional investors. To investigate this issue, the authors examine historical return data from a wide range of asset classes. They find strong support for increasing allocations towards real estate and that real estate has significantly better risk-hedging characteristics than any of the other asset classes studied.</description><author>Bond, Shaun A.; Hwang, Soosung; Mitchell, Paul; Satchell, Stephen E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private commercial real estate equity returns and inflation - New news on hedging power</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Haibo; Hudson-Wilson, Susan
The authors estimate, for total real estate and each of four property types, the extent to which various private commercial real estate returns, namely income, capital and total return, hedge against expected and unexpected inflation during the 1978-2006 period. Overall, total returns for all of the property types, except for retail, are shown to be a strong hedge against both expected and unexpected inflation. However, and interestingly, this hedging efficacy comes mostly from capital appreciation rather than income return. Thus the inflation hedging power of real estate seems to be more a product of the capital markets, rather than of the net income generating processes of real estate's leasing and expense structures. In terms of inflation hedging capability, office is shown to be the strongest, followed by apartment and warehouse. Contrary to past studies and conventional wisdom, the retail sector is shown to have no significant hedging power against inflation.</description><author>Huang, Haibo; Hudson-Wilson, Susan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Benefits of global diversification on a real estate portfolio - That free lunch</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hastings, Adam; Nordby, Hans
Capital flows are increasingly global across all asset classes, including the real estate world. Because global real estate portfolios contain assets influenced by different national economies, with very different drivers, growth rates, and risk, the correlation of total returns between assets in these markets can be very low. Low or negative correlations provide the ultimate recipe for the "free lunch" of modern portfolio theory: returns that are the weighted average of assets within the portfolio, but volatility less than the weighted volatility of the individual assets. Unlike the case in domestic investments, however, the movement of foreign exchange rates must be considered, as unfavorable currency movements can severely hinder performance. Real estate is generally a long-hold investment strategy, but property income and ultimately the final selling price will be received in the local currency and must, at some point, be repatriated to U.S. dollars. The authors examine investments in global office properties, both with and without currency exchange rate factors, and make a compelling case for investment in the global office sector instead of investment only in the U.S. market.</description><author>Hastings, Adam; Nordby, Hans</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global commercial real estate - A strategic asset allocation study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Idzorek, Thomas M.; Barad, Michael; Meier, Stephen L.
This article explores the role of global commercial real estate in a strategic asset allocation. Global REIT and listed real estate stock indices are used to proxy the broader direct and indirect equity global commercial real estate asset classes. In a historical analysis, using traditional mean-variance optimization the author finds that adding North American real estate dramatically improves the risk and return characteristics of the resulting asset allocations, while the addition of Asian and European real estate offers little improvement. In a set of forward-looking optimization using robust asset allocation tools such as reverse optimization, the Black-Litterman model, and resampled mean-variance optimization, it is observed that global commercial real estate should play a relatively large role in strategic asset allocation moving forward. Other contributions include the development of a working version of the market portfolio that includes global commercial real estate, an analysis of the overlap between popular equity asset class proxies and indirect real estate proxies, and recognition that the popularity of indirect real estate has confused asset allocators.</description><author>Idzorek, Thomas M.; Barad, Michael; Meier, Stephen L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should owners of Nasdaq stocks fear short-selling? At common levels, average market-adjusted returns tend to be near zero.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christophe, Stephen E.; Ferri, Michael G.; Angel, James J.
It is interesting to look at the daily association between market-adjusted returns of Nasdaq stocks and the percentages of trading volume attributable to dealers and to their speculator customers. An unusually detailed and informative set of Nasdaq trading records reveals significantly negative average market-adjusted returns when speculative short-selling exceeds 10%. At the more common (lower) levels of speculative short-selling, average market-adjusted returns tend to be near zero. Even when there is considerable speculative short-selling, the associated negative market-adjusted return is, on average, only 4 to 6 basis points for each percentage point of short-selling. For many stocks, days of high speculative short-selling are not typically days of unusually low market-adjusted returns. Finally, high levels of short-selling by Nasdaq dealers are more common for stocks earning relatively higher market-adjusted returns.</description><author>Christophe, Stephen E.; Ferri, Michael G.; Angel, James J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Funds of hedge funds take the wrong risks - Sloppy manager selection and portfolio construction.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beckers, Stan; Curds, Ross; Weinberger, Simon
On average the fund of hedge funds industry over the last 15 years has delivered alpha with a high information ratio. Unfortunately, these alphas come with significant common-factor exposures for which the typical fund was unrewarded. While funds of hedge funds can deliver a valuable product, sloppy manager selection and portfolio construction typically result in less-than-pure alpha generation. A naive selection of a fund of hedge funds may thus lead to assuming relatively expensive common-factor exposure without necessarily accessing significant skill-based returns. A multifactor modeling of fund of hedge fund returns can help to identify skillful value-added.</description><author>Beckers, Stan; Curds, Ross; Weinberger, Simon</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The price of risk and the Heisenberg uncertainty principle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Peter L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, Peter L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analysis of the interest rate sensitivity of common stocks - Empirical equity duration is a useful measure.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reilly, Frank K.; Wright, David J.; Johnson, Robert R.
The association between interest rate changes and stock returns has long been of interest to investors, all the more so recently as investors and the financial and popular press have zeroed in on the effect of Federal Reserve actions on interest rates. The interest rate sensitivity of common stocks can be measured using an alternative specification of duration, empirical duration, a measure that has become accepted by fixed-income analysts and portfolio managers. Analysis of the interest rate sensitivity of the aggregate stock market considers alternative economic sectors and many industries and stock indexes that reflect different sizes and investment styles. Five important results are documented: 1) dramatic changes over time in the empirical duration of common stocks; 2) substantial differences in the total-period empirical duration for different economic sectors and different industries; 3) a significant negative relation between market risk and interest rate risk for different industries; 4) significantly different patterns of empirical duration over time for different sectors and industries; and 5) differences in interest rate sensitivity for various economic sectors, industries, and investment styles that are generally consistent with economic expectations.</description><author>Reilly, Frank K.; Wright, David J.; Johnson, Robert R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Putting economics (back) into quantitative models - The economic state of the world does matter.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhansali, Vineer
Models devoid of strong economic underpinnings are seldom useful for practical real-world investment decisions. Models that differ in subtle ways in their underlying assumptions yield significantly conflicting results. Ignoring the fundamental relation between demand and supply dynamics can produce results that fail to hold in actual markets, and that often give but false comfort in risk measurement systems and inaccurate valuations. A parsimonious model of the term structure can incorporate economics without sacrificing theoretical rigor. Its risk-neutral term structure model parameters have a strong basis in widely followed macroeconomic variables, enabling extension to other markets such as the credit market.</description><author>Bhansali, Vineer</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value and growth, theory and practice - A fallacy that value beats growth.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brush, John S.
The definition of value-based investing is widely accepted by both academics and practitioners, but there is confusion and disagreement as to the definition of growth-based investing. There is some statistical support for generic value and growth multifactor ranking models. Given different holding-period sensitivities of alpha potential for value and growth, there appear to be two ways to exploit the two styles: the typical combining of pure styles in a portfolio, or the less widely recognized use of a combined value/growth model. One important conclusion is that active style exploitation of alpha is inherently incompatible with capitalization-weighted benchmarks.</description><author>Brush, John S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal execution for portfolio transitions - Minimizing opportunity cost.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kritzman, Mark; Myrgren, Simon; Page, Sebastien
Institutional investors periodically reallocate portfolios to shift the asset mix or change investment managers. These transitions are subject to a variety of costs, including commissions, opportunity cost, and market impact. Opportunity cost refers to adverse changes in price arising from exogenous market forces; market impact refers to adverse price movements that occur in response to the purchase and sale of securities. Opportunity cost and market impact costs represent the greatest share of transition costs, and investors influence these costs by how they trade. An algorithm may be used to deterrmine the optimal sequence and size of trades that minimize opportunity cost for portfolio transitions, provided that the trades are self-financing. Trades may be partitioned into smaller units to minimize market impact. This algorithm compares favorably to the industry norm, which is to minimize sector differences as a transition unfolds.</description><author>Kritzman, Mark; Myrgren, Simon; Page, Sebastien</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust portfolio optimization - Recent trends and future directions.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fabozzi, Frank J.; Kolm, Petter N.; Pachamanova, Dessislava A.; Focardi, Sergio M.
As quantitative techniques have become commonplace in the investment industry, the mitigation of estimation and model risk in portfolio management has grown in importance. Robust optimization, which incorporates estimation error directly into the portfolio optimization process, is typically used with conventional robust statistical estimation methods. This perspective on the robust optimization approach reviews useful practical extensions and discusses potential applications for robust portfolio optimization.</description><author>Fabozzi, Frank J.; Kolm, Petter N.; Pachamanova, Dessislava A.; Focardi, Sergio M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Enhanced index investing based on goal programming - Includes passive management of a small number of stocks.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Liang-Chuan; Chou, Seng-Cho; Yang, Chau-Chen; Ong, Chorng-Shyong
Enhanced index investing involves tracking a benchmark index closely and using risk-controlled strategies to add modest value to the index. The typical approaches to construction of such portfolios involve subjective management judgments. A new approach to enhanced indexing instead formulates the problem as a dual-criteria goal programming problem. Unlike the traditional approaches, which require a fund manager to buy and sell stocks actively in order to improve returns, the proposed approach is based on the passive management of a small number of stocks. Empirical results from tests in the Taiwan stock market suggest the new approach incurs lower transaction costs and produces sustainable risk-control,led enhanced returns.</description><author>Wu, Liang-Chuan; Chou, Seng-Cho; Yang, Chau-Chen; Ong, Chorng-Shyong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gathering implicit alphas in a beta world - New questions about alternative assets.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leibowitz, Martin; Bova, Anthony
Most US. institutional portfolios have surprisingly similar betas and similar overall volatilities. Beta assumes an implicit beta for each asset class that is based on its co-movement with US. equities. This "total beta exposure" to equities, as the primary risk factor in most portfolios, accounts for 90% or more of volatility even in highly diversified funds with a low explicit allocation to equities. The implicit beta values determine corresponding implicit alphas that can add to expected fund return and yet have a minimal impact on total fund volatility. These implicit alphas are passive, in that there is no presumption of a positive outcome from direct active investment. Unlike the zero-sum active alphas that presume superior investment skill and must be "hunted," the implicit alphas are passive and non-zero-sum in nature, and rather can be "gathered" through the allocation process.</description><author>Leibowitz, Martin; Bova, Anthony</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment beliefs - Every asset manager should have them.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Slager, Alfred; Koedijk, Kees
Increased transparency and a difficult environment for returns increase the importance of well-thought out investment policies for investors, clients, and trustees; a coherent set of investment beliefs provide the basis for a good investment policy. Investment beliefs improve stakeholder governance by reducing possible conflicts of interest, and affect the innovative adaptability of an organization by setting guidelines for best practice. A survey of published investment beliefs reveals three essential elements for investment beliefs: 1) a clear view of the capital markets (the inefficiencies to exploit, the risk/return relation, the relation between asset pricing and investment horizon); 2) a competent organization (cost-effectiveness, organization-specific values); and 3) a view on societal issues that affect investments (sustainable investments, corporate governance).</description><author>Slager, Alfred; Koedijk, Kees</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does size matter? Assets under management a questionable criterion.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Gregory C.
Total assets under management, or AUM in industry parlance, represents a prime criterion in virtually every manager search a large institutional investor undertakes today. Managers are typically required to have a minimum level of AUM to be considered in the early stages of any search process-institutional investors face so many agency risks that they usually conclude there is safety in higher numbers. This analysis of the historical impact of portfolio size on the performance of institutional asset management products uses a robust database of approximately 5,000 products that includes all the major public markets asset classes typically used by institutional investors. Accounting for both survivorship bias and backfill bias, the results indicate portfolio size has had a pervasive negative impact on performance across almost all the asset classes examined. Not surprisingly, the more illiquid asset classes (small-cap equities and high-yield bonds) have been the most negatively impacted by portfolio size.</description><author>Allen, Gregory C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The great alpha merry-go-round</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cleaning a passive index - How to use portfolio optimization to satisfy CSR constraints .</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milevsky, Moshe A.; Aziz, Andrew; Goss, Allen; Comeault, Jane Thomson; Wheeler, David
nan</description><author>Milevsky, Moshe A.; Aziz, Andrew; Goss, Allen; Comeault, Jane Thomson; Wheeler, David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend reinvestment, price appreciation and capital accumulation - Capital accumulation prospects depend entirely on price appreciation.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rappaport, Alfred
nan</description><author>Rappaport, Alfred</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Socially responsible indexes - Composition, performance, and tracking error.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Statman, M.
nan</description><author>Statman, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do short-selling and margin trading impact the replication of emerging market indexes? Yes, for the decade of the nineties.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bey, Roger P.; Johnson, Larry J.
nan</description><author>Bey, Roger P.; Johnson, Larry J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Home bias makes sense for U. S. pension plans - An asset/liability model of pension plan portfolio allocation.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Craft, T. M.
nan</description><author>Craft, T. M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Peer Pressure - Industry group impacts on stock valuation precision and contrarian strategy performance.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, T. G.; Demirtas, K. O.; Hovakimian, A.; Merrick, J. J.
nan</description><author>Bali, T. G.; Demirtas, K. O.; Hovakimian, A.; Merrick, J. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The importance of being value - A different definition.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bourguignon, Francois; de Jong, Marielle
nan</description><author>Bourguignon, Francois; de Jong, Marielle</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A very long-term buy-and-hold portfolio - Surprising results.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nanda, Sudhir; Peters, Donald J.
nan</description><author>Nanda, Sudhir; Peters, Donald J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Five myths about fees - The truth behind analyzing fees, in the context of investment goals.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kahn, Ronald N.; Scanlan, Matthew H.; Siegel, Laurence B.
nan</description><author>Kahn, Ronald N.; Scanlan, Matthew H.; Siegel, Laurence B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Enhanced active equity strategies - Relaxing the long-only constraint in the pursuit of active return.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobs, B. I.; Levy, K. N.
nan</description><author>Jacobs, B. I.; Levy, K. N.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multilayer modeling of a market covariance matrix - Modeling a layer through its exposure to the previous layer.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Staub, Renato
nan</description><author>Staub, Renato</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leverage and the limits of the possible - How leverage impacts the policy portfolio</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dopfel, Frederick E.
nan</description><author>Dopfel, Frederick E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Handling parameter uncertainty in portfolio risk minimization - The robust optimization approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pachamanova, Dessislava
nan</description><author>Pachamanova, Dessislava</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The real efficient market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Peter L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, Peter L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance of institutional Japanese equity fund managers - By investment style</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Wenling
nan</description><author>Lin, Wenling</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional perspectives on real estate investing - The role of risk and uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dhar, Ravi; Goetzmann, William N.
nan</description><author>Dhar, Ravi; Goetzmann, William N.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The market in defaulted bonds and bank loans - 2005 review and 2006 predictions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altman, Edward I.; Stonberg, William
nan</description><author>Altman, Edward I.; Stonberg, William</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical credit risk - Advantages of using a market measure of credit risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheyette, Oren; Postler, Boris
nan</description><author>Cheyette, Oren; Postler, Boris</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are optimizers error maximizers? Hype versus reality?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kritzman, Mark
nan</description><author>Kritzman, Mark</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A fresh look at investment performance evaluation - Unifying best practices to improve timeliness and reliability.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Surz, Ronald J.
nan</description><author>Surz, Ronald J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portable alphas from pension mispricing - To enhance performance significantly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Franzoni, Francesco; Marin, Jose M.
nan</description><author>Franzoni, Francesco; Marin, Jose M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pooling trades in a quantitative investment process - A competitive equilibrium in the market for liquidity ensures fairness.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O'Cinneide, Colm; Scherer, Bernd; Xu, Xiaodong
nan</description><author>O'Cinneide, Colm; Scherer, Bernd; Xu, Xiaodong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Alpha as a net zero-sum game - How serious a constraint?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hill, Joanne M.
nan</description><author>Hill, Joanne M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global style investing - Region-neutral and industry-neutral value portfolios.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cavaglia, Stefano; Sefton, James; Scowcroft, Alan; Smith, Bryn
nan</description><author>Cavaglia, Stefano; Sefton, James; Scowcroft, Alan; Smith, Bryn</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Organizational architecture and decision-making - A complementary approach to measuring performance of portfolio managers.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moussavou, Jean
nan</description><author>Moussavou, Jean</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the required return under new uncertainty - Emphasizing the equity risk premium.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abate, James A.; Grant, James L.; Rowberry, Chris
nan</description><author>Abate, James A.; Grant, James L.; Rowberry, Chris</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do price-earnings ratios drive stock values? Not as great an impact as thought.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhargava, Vivek; Malhotra, D. K.
nan</description><author>Bhargava, Vivek; Malhotra, D. K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using the supply-side approach to understand and estimate equity returns - Advantages of a disciplined framework.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, Charles P.; Wilson, Jack W.
nan</description><author>Jones, Charles P.; Wilson, Jack W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the Fed model travel well? For short-run tactical allocation, yes, but not for the long haul.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>ap Gwilym, Owain; Seaton, James; Suddason, Karina; Thomas, Stephen
nan</description><author>ap Gwilym, Owain; Seaton, James; Suddason, Karina; Thomas, Stephen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyzing active investment strategies - Using tracking error variance decomposition.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ammann, Manuel; Kessler, Stephan; Tobler, Juerg
nan</description><author>Ammann, Manuel; Kessler, Stephan; Tobler, Juerg</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The relative importance of asset allocation and security selection - No clear hierarchy of investment choice.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Assoe, Kodjovi; L'Her, Jean-Francois; Plante, Jean-Francois
nan</description><author>Assoe, Kodjovi; L'Her, Jean-Francois; Plante, Jean-Francois</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Model-based transition management - A pragmatic approach applied to a multi-asset example.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Molenkamp, Jan Bertus
nan</description><author>Molenkamp, Jan Bertus</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exploring the dimensions of active management - The covariance structure of active return.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Farr, Dorsey D.
nan</description><author>Farr, Dorsey D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Implementation shortfall - From concept to practice.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kritzman, Mark; Myrgren, Simon; Page, Sebastien
nan</description><author>Kritzman, Mark; Myrgren, Simon; Page, Sebastien</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Minimum-variance portfolios in the U.S. equity market - Reducing volatility without sacrificing returns.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clarke, Roger; de Silva, Harindra; Thorley, Steven
nan</description><author>Clarke, Roger; de Silva, Harindra; Thorley, Steven</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When do economic environments change?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Peter L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, Peter L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Needles, haystacks, and hidden factors - Hybridizing fundamental and statistical factor models.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Miller, G.
Statistical factor modeling is often described as a way to identify commonality among returns in a financial market. Statistical models examine returns over many time periods, and from them identify relationships between and among the different assets, unlike fundamental factor models, which from the outset group assets that are likely to experience similar returns. Yet the statistical approach is better at finding some types of factors than others. Statistical factors generally work best with high-frequency return data, and even then may not pick up distinctions that apply to a relatively small subset of assets (such as distinctions associated with industry membership); they are most useful when they supplement fundamental factors. We see this in a case study that adds statistical factors to an MSCI Barra fundamental factor risk model.</description><author>Miller, G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Attribution - Modeling asset characteristics as portfolios.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinold, R.
This flexible, unified, and portfolio-centered approach to attribution treats attribution questions that occur before the fact (ex ante) and after the fact (ex post) symmetrically. Three important aspects of an analysis of a portfolio ex ante are its predicted risk, the information ratio (which measures the potential to add value), and the transfer coefficient (which shows the manager's ability to capture that potential). The product of these three variables is the portfolio's predicted alpha. Ex post analogues of these concepts are the predicted risk, the opportunity set (which shows how well the manager could do with perfect foresight), and the realized information coefficient (which measures the correlation between the forecast and the outcome). The product of these three quantities is the return of the portfolio. The author shows how to attribute the transfer coefficient and realized information coefficient to sources in a general manner.</description><author>Grinold, R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The paradox of the efficient market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal rebalancing for institutional portfolios - Minimizing costs using dynamic programming.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, W.; Fan, A.; Chen, L. W.; Schouwenaars, T.; Albota, M. A.
Institutional fund managers generally rebalance using ad hoc methods such as calendar periods or tolerance band triggers. Another approach is to quantify the cost of a rebalancing strategy in terms of risk-adjusted returns net of transaction costs. An optimal rebalancing strategy that actively seeks to minimize that cost uses certainty-equivalents and the transaction costs associated with a policy to define a cost-to-go function. Stochastic programming is then used to minimize expected cost-to-go. Monte Carlo simulations demonstrate that the method outperforms traditional rebalancing strategies such as periodic and 5% tolerance rebalancing.</description><author>Sun, W.; Fan, A.; Chen, L. W.; Schouwenaars, T.; Albota, M. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The capacity of an equity strategy - Defining and estimating.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vangelisti, M.
Capacity is an intuitive concept linked to diseconomies scale in equity investing. As assets under management grow beyond realization of full economies of scale, liquidity and ownership constraints erode the ability of an equity investment strategy to add value. Two ways to estimate the capacity of a quantitatively managed equity strategy are proposed in a refined definition of the term. A controlled experiment to determine the effect on performance of varying only one variable assets under management-indicates capacity estimations are sensitive to various assumptions, first and foremost about market impact costs. Capacity should thus not be thought of as a specific number, but rather as a variable whose range must be estimated.</description><author>Vangelisti, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing guarantees - Providing protection but maintraining access to potentially higher returns.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dempster, M. A. H.; Germano, M.; Medova, E. A.; Rietbergen, M. I.; Sandrini, F.; Scrowston, M.
We have seen in recent years a significant growth in investment products aimed at investors who are worried about downside potential in the financial markets. One response is a dynamic stochastic optimization model for managing products with nominal or real guarantees. An optimal dynamic portfolio allocation strategy combined with risk management allows an institution to provide the best possible portfolio returns commensurate with clients' risk aversion. Implementation of such an investment strategy is illustrated using real market data and backtested through 1999-2004.</description><author>Dempster, M. A. H.; Germano, M.; Medova, E. A.; Rietbergen, M. I.; Sandrini, F.; Scrowston, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Speed of adjustment in US financial markets - The perils of asset timing.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coggin, T. D.; Arshanapalli, B.
This study uses US. financial market data from the post-World War II era to examine whether the statistical evidence supports a flexible-weight asset allocation in U.S. financial markets. A variety of econometric tests are developed to estimate the speed of adjustment of economic time series data subject to unit roots and structural breaks. The findings suggest that successful flexible-weight asset allocation is likely to be difficult. Of all the relationships tested, only the long-term government bonds versus S&amp;P 500 relationship is cointegrated with a significant speed of adjustment parameter. This suggests a predictable long-run equilibrium relationship.</description><author>Coggin, T. D.; Arshanapalli, B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rationality of naive forecasts of long term rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reichenstein, W.
Brooks and Gray in the Fall 2004 JPM examined the accuracy of economists' long-term interest rate forecasts in Wall Street Journal surveys. They concluded that no-change naive forecasts were better than the consensus WSJ forecasts. In fact, no-change forecasts are not naive forecasts but instead rational economic forecasts. We should thus extend the Brooks and Gray conclusions that no-change forecasts are better than economists' consensus forecasts of the long-term Treasury rate to other long-term interest rates.</description><author>Reichenstein, W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial disclosure and regulation - A portfolio approach.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, M.; Benita, G.; Levy, H.
A portfolio approach is used here to analyze the value of financial disclosure to stockholders and the need for disclosure regulation. This demonstrates that in a portfolio context the degree of public financial disclosure does not influence a firm's value. Hence, if disclosure is costly, firms have no incentive to disclose information voluntarily. Under partial disclosure, however, investors select inefficient portfolios, implying a substantial welfare loss; hence, we need regulation. The analysis provides a framework for determining optimal disclosure from the point of view of social welfare.</description><author>Levy, M.; Benita, G.; Levy, H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Calculating the price of bond convexity - No free alpha. No free convexity.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smit, L.; Swart, B.
The global decline in interest rates has created a significant increase in the present value of pension funds; convexity plays an important role-the convexity bias in the yield curve is well known. While the expectations hypothesis is valid for the money market sector of the yield curve, the remainder is determined by what we can call the expected volatility hypothesis, which is based on the principle of no-arbitrage between convexity and theta in the value of a bond portfolio. The results of a term structure model that constructs the yield curve using a closed-form solution are compared, to actual data.</description><author>Smit, L.; Swart, B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From delivering to packaging of alpha - Designing hedge fund offerings that better fit investor needs.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amenc, N.; Malaise, P.; Martellini, L.
The hedge fund industry typically takes a producer (manager) rather than a consumer (investor) perspective. There ought to be new types of hedge fund offerings better suited to the needs of institutional investors. In the case of active bond portfolios, the authors present evidence that managers can use fixed-income derivatives not only to generate and deliver abnormal performance, but also to package such performance in a form that is consistent with the modern core-satellite approach to institutional portfolio management. A dynamic extension allows for asymmetric control of active management risk.</description><author>Amenc, N.; Malaise, P.; Martellini, L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A portfolio diversification index - And systematic risks of hedge fund investment styles.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kudin, A. M.; Morgan, J. S.
Despite the importance of diversification in portfolio construction, our current methods of measuring it are inefficient. Construction of a Portfolio Diversification Index (PDI) presents a new way to understand the concept. PDI, which measures the number of unique investments in a portfolio, is useful to assess marginal and cumulative diversification benefits across asset classes and across time. Implementation in hedge fund strategies reveals that various hedge funds offer less diversification than may have been thought, and that there has been reduced diversification in the past several years.</description><author>Kudin, A. M.; Morgan, J. S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market timing with Cay - Using deviation from the long-run aggregate log consumption-wealth ratio.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrade, S. C.; Babenko, I.; Tserlukevich, Y.
Market timing strategies using deviations from the long-run log consumption-wealth ratio (Cay) are tested to evaluate whether such strategies deliver superior investment performance. Several statistical tests indicate that true Cay embeds economically significant information about future market returns. At the same time, constraints such as the need to use the estimated rather than true ratio and delays in availability of macroeconomic data cast doubt on the likelihood that the market can be timed using mechanistic strategies based on Cay. Further research will ascertain whether it is possible to implement successful timing strategies using such a ratio.</description><author>Andrade, S. C.; Babenko, I.; Tserlukevich, Y.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sources of return in global investing - World markets are integrating, but only gradually</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Puchkov, A. V.; Stefek, D.; Davis, M.; Malik, A.
Traditional approaches to the important sources of return in international equity investing attribute portfolio return to countries and global industries and styles. A new framework shows that these models miss an important component of return that arises from the unique behavior of industries and styles within markets. The answer to the perennial question of international investing-what matters more, country or global industry and style selection?-is quite different in developed and emerging markets. The oft-noted spike in the importance of global industries over country influence in 1998-2002 was likely a by-product of the technology bubble. World markets are integrating, but at a very gradual pace.</description><author>Puchkov, A. V.; Stefek, D.; Davis, M.; Malik, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Indexing and statistical arbitrage - Tracking error or cointegration?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, C.; Dimitriu, A.; Malik, A.
There are two basic methodologies for portfolio optimization: tracking error variance (TEV) minimization (the industry standard for indexing), and a cointegration-optimal strategy (advocated by econometricians). Cointegration is a statistical tool that seeks to exploit a long-run equilibrium relationship between a portfolio and a benchmark, ensuring that the two are connected in the long term. For simple index tracking, the additional feature of cointegration is found to provide no clear advantages or disadvantages over TEV Both models produce optimal portfolios that outperform a price-weighted benchmark during market crashes, assuming a long enough model calibration period. When tracking becomes more difficult, ensuring a cointegration relationship enhances performance. Cointegration-optimal portfolios dominate TEV equivalents for all the statistical arbitrage strategies based on enhanced indexation in all market circumstances.</description><author>Alexander, C.; Dimitriu, A.; Malik, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Index fundamentalism revisited - Redux - Results are attributable to value and small-stock premiums</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kizer, J.; Malik, A.
The findings in "Index Fundamentalism Revisited" on the relative performance of Vanguard synthetic active and index portfolios are explained largely by differing exposures to the value and small-stock premiums. Other findings such as the relative 15-year annualized returns and relative 2000-2002 performance of the two portfolios are similarly explained. Left unexplained is the synthetic active portfolio's lower volatility relative to the synthetic index portfolio.</description><author>Kizer, J.; Malik, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multihorizon Sharpe ratios - It all depends on investment horizon</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, S.; In, F.; Malik, A.
Wavelet analysis represents a new approach to investigating the empirical relationship between the Sharpe ratio and the investment horizon for portfolios of small stocks, large stocks, and intermediate-term and long-term bonds. A wavelet multiscale approach decomposes a given time series on a scale-by-scale basis. Empirical results indicate that the wavelet variance declines as the wavelet scale increases, implying that an investor with a short investment horizon must respond to every fluctuation in realized returns, while an investor with a much longer horizon faces much less significant long-run risk associated with unknown expected returns. The long scale Sharpe ratio is much higher than the short scale, implying that the Sharpe ratio is not time-consistent. Finally, stock portfolios have higher Sharpe ratios than bond portfolios, except in certain-length periods, indicating that evaluation of the performance of stock and bond portfolios should account for investment horizon.</description><author>Kim, S.; In, F.; Malik, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Oops, our earnings were indeed preliminary - When preliminary earnings announcements and subsequent filings disagree</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hollie, D.; Livnat, J.; Segal, B.; Malik, A.
The market reacts to earnings surprises when firms report different earnings in SEC filings from earnings reported just a few weeks earlier in preliminary earnings announcements. This is a new finding. When SEC filings include material new information, investors incorporate this in pricing company shares. Market reactions are stronger in the case of downward earnings revisions than upward earnings revisions, but an inverse drift in abnormal returns occurs for upward earnings revisions after the SEC filing date. Finally, it is documented that security analysts revise their forecasts upon the preliminary earnings announcement, but ignore the new information in the SEC filings.</description><author>Hollie, D.; Livnat, J.; Segal, B.; Malik, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How risky are illiquid investments? - A practical approach to estimating volatilities and correlations for non-traded assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Budhraja, V.; de Figueiredo, R. J. P.; Malik, A.
Highly illiquid and non-traded investments-such as private real estate, leveraged buyouts, and venture capital-have historically been very hard to compare to traditional investments. This is particularly problematical when one considers how to include these assets in a traditional portfolio of assets. For the purposes of asset allocation, it is critical that illiquid asset classes are made comparable to liquid asset classes. An estimation procedure here may help to assess the true risks and diversification benefits presented by illiquid asset classes more accurately. Even though the approach involves some assumptions, it should provide a better picture of the variations in illiquid returns.</description><author>Budhraja, V.; de Figueiredo, R. J. P.; Malik, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How well do we understand ratios and spreads?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modernizing the defined-benefit pension system - A national concern</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mulvey, J. M.; Fabozzi, F. J.; Pauling, W. R.; Simsek, K. D.; Zhang, Z. J.; Malik, A.
The defined-benefit pension system may not survive into the future absent changes in the current regulatory environment. A risk-based and anticipatory approach to evaluating pension trusts is proposed as a way to diminish the probability that large and insolvent companies will transfer their pension trusts to the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation. Because current difficulties are concentrated in a few industries, there will be severe problems in the future if the healthiest companies reduce their exposure to defined-benefit pensions.</description><author>Mulvey, J. M.; Fabozzi, F. J.; Pauling, W. R.; Simsek, K. D.; Zhang, Z. J.; Malik, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficient irrational markets - Investors do not need to be rational for markets to be efficient</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gulko, L.; Malik, A.
Statistical analysis of interest rate forecasts published in the Wall Street Journal since. 1981 suggests that investors do not need to be rational for market prices to be efficient. A market populated by imperfect agents can be efficient if there are enough agents and they are suitably interconnected. That is, numbers and interaction compensate for individual imperfections. A maximum-likelihood model of a market inhabited by irrational heterogeneous investors produces a distribution of interest rate forecasts that agrees with the Wall Street Journal polls. From a practical viewpoint, if price efficiency is independent of individual rationahty then passive index investing dominates active investing, whatever the individual investor behavioral biases.</description><author>Gulko, L.; Malik, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio disaggregation in emerging market investments - Passive indexing strategies are no longer enough</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernandes, N.; Malik, A.
Liberalization of capital markets in emerging markets in the last two decades has made these countries' equity markets increasingly responsive to world factors. One of the implications of globalization for international asset allocation is that global portfolio managers can no longer add significant value by pursuing indexing strategies in emerging markets. Empirical analysis shows there are no significant gains from an aggregate investment in emerging market equities, although portfolio managers can achieve enhanced performance by specialized investment in some markets, instead of indexing across all emerging markets. Aggregate diversification across all emerging markets is no longer enough to create value. Country selection strategies are imperative if a global portfolio manager wants to outperform benchmarks.</description><author>Fernandes, N.; Malik, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global momentum strategies - A portfolio perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, J. M.; Ji, X. Q.; Martin, J. S.; Malik, A.
Here are some practical perspectives on momentum investing in stocks internationally. Momentum is generally more profitable on the long side than on the short side, making it accessible to a broad range of institutional capital, and both price and earnings momentum profits are significant globally. Earnings momentum internationally is distinct from price momentum; using price and earnings momentum in conjunction produces greater economic profits. Momentum profits co-move more weakly across markets than market indexes. Interestingly, while market correlations are much higher in down markets than in up markets, momentum correlations are low under both market conditions. There is no appreciable difference in momentum strategy profitability in up and down markets, which means timing is less important to momentum traders. Finally, momentum strategies are not riskless-there are often periods of several months when they have netted low or negative returns. The findings altogether suggest that momentum is useful in international portfolio management, but it should be implemented very thoughtfully.</description><author>Griffin, J. M.; Ji, X. Q.; Martin, J. S.; Malik, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fair trading - The ethics of trading in financial markets.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Statman, M.
Social norms, including rules of fairness, are rules of behavior enforced by the community that often make their way into law. Community rules of fairness in financial trading are important to everyone, but they are especially important to investors, to executives, to investment professionals, to students who plan to become executives or investment professionals, and to regulatory agencies such as the Securities and Exchange Commission. Surveys of both investment professionals and students illuminate some rules of fairness. Rules of fairness are found to allow a trader to gain advantage over another with information obtained with research, skill, or even luck, but not to gain advantage with inside information that other traders cannot obtain with research or skill. Rules of fairness place special burdens on traders who are relatively well-off and traders who have sure information. Rules of fairness for trading stock are different from rules of fairness for trading other goods such as automobiles, and investment professionals and students perceive rules of fairness differently.</description><author>Statman, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real estate investment trusts - An asset allocation perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, H. C.; Ho, K. Y.; Lu, C. L.; Wu, C. H.
Can investors improve their investment opportunity sets by adding a real estate investment trust (REIT) portfolio to benchmark portfolios sorted by firm size and book-to-market ratio? According to US. REIT performance data over 1980-2002, REITs after 1986 improve the mean-variance frontier set. Equity REITs appear to be non-redundant financial assets, which helps to enhance the completeness of the financial market. Mortgage REITs provide no diversification benefits in the sample period.</description><author>Chen, H. C.; Ho, K. Y.; Lu, C. L.; Wu, C. H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance of real estate portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fisher, J. D.; Goetzmann, W. N.
Actual cash flows from commercial properties over 1977-2004 underlie this simulation of the performance of real estate portfolios. The methodology relaxes implicit rebalancing and mark-to-market assumptions in time series analysis and uses the distribution of the internal rate of return to compare commercial property investment to portfolios of stocks and bonds over the same period. This approach allows consideration of the impact of the timing of capital flows on the IRR for real estate portfolios and provides insight into the benefits of diversification by property sector versus location. Cross-sectional variation in IRRs helps indicate the number of properties necessary to reduce the risk of achieving the IRR benchmark for properties in the NCREIF Property Index.</description><author>Fisher, J. D.; Goetzmann, W. N.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Impact of pension plan liabilities on real estate investment - Logical variations in real estate allocations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Craft, T. M.
Typical mean-variance models estimate pension plan allocations to public and private real estate as high as 50% or even higher. An asset/liability model of pension plan decision-making predicts much lower allocations to both private and public real estate that are closer to what we actually observe. Pension plans in different industries can have different optimal allocations to private and public real estate. Industry influences allocations to private real estate more than to public real estate.</description><author>Craft, T. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why real estate? And how? where? and when?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hudson-Wilson, S.; Gordon, J. N.; Fabozzi, F. J.; Anson, M. J. P.; Giliberto, S. M.
Real estate for institutional investors is most broadly defined to comprise private commercial real estate equity, private commercial real estate debt, public real estate equity structured as real estate investment trusts or real estate operating companies, and public commercial real estate debt structured as commercial mortgage-backed securities. Arguments made in a 2003 special issue of this journal for adding real estate to a well-managed institutional investment portfolio include: portfolio diversification and risk reduction, absolute return enhancement, inflation hedging, reflection of the investment universe, and strong cash flows. A revisit of these portfolio issues and an updated empirical analysis continue to support the rationale for real estate. Particular challenges face institutional investors who invest in real estate; the articles in this 2005 special issue address them.</description><author>Hudson-Wilson, S.; Gordon, J. N.; Fabozzi, F. J.; Anson, M. J. P.; Giliberto, S. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The quantum leap</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Copulas and coherence - Portfolio analysis in a non-normal world.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dowd, K.
Traditional portfolio theory assumes that risk factors are elliptically distributed, when most real-world risk factors do not satisfy this condition. The lack of ellipticality poses two problems: First, correlation-based approaches to statistical dependence become unreliable, and second, conventional risk measures such as the standard deviation and value at risk also become unreliable. These problems can be dealt with by using copulas to handle dependence and by using coherent risk measures. The advantages of using copulas are demonstrated in an example that shows that traditional portfolio theory can also be misleading in a non-elliptical context.</description><author>Dowd, K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The symmetric downside-risk Sharpe ratio - And the evaluation of great investors and speculators.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ziemba, W. T.
The Sharpe ratio, a most useful measure of investment performance, has the disadvantage that it is based on mean-variance theory and thus is valid basically only for quadratic preferences or normal distributions. Hence skewed investment returns can engender misleading conclusions. This is especially true for superior investors with a number of high returns. Many of these superior investors use capital growth wagering ideas to implement their strategies, which means higher growth rates but also higher variability of wealth. A simple modification of the Sharpe ratio to assume that the upside deviation is identical to the downside risk gives more realistic results.</description><author>Ziemba, W. T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate bond portfolio analysis - The CDO approach.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacob, D. P.; Adelson, M.; Whetten, M.
Most corporate bond portfolio managers use fundamental credit analysis in the security selection process and some form of the efficient frontier in the construction and ongoing management of their portfolios. This traditional approach, however, does not take into account the whole distribution of potential future credit losses on the portfolio and thus does not capture the risk of extreme events. A remedy is to apply the methodology used in the construction of collateralized debt obligations to analyze and manage the tail risk in corporate bond portfolios.</description><author>Jacob, D. P.; Adelson, M.; Whetten, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Never again - A transition to a secure private pension system.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gold, J.
We have a pension funding problem. The Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation is today exceedingly vulnerable. Too many of the proposals to reduce this vulnerability, protect plan participants, and encourage plan sponsors to stay in the game amount to special pleadings for some stakeholders, typically at the expense of others. Some other proposals promise a free lunch fueled by risky investments, deferrals of cost, and optimistic expectations. Pension plans can become and remain fully funded at all times after a suitable, although not necessarily rapid, transition. One way to introduce transparency and objectivity is through securitization, creating capital market-based transition securities that mimic the current relationships between defined-benefit pension plans and their corporate sponsors and the PBGC.</description><author>Gold, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Toward an optimal domestic large-cap equity index - Choice of a benchmark is critical.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Seegopaul, H.; Gupta, F.; Prestbo, J.
Choosing a benchmark for domestic large-cap equities is critical for plan sponsors because benchmarks play an important role in of the portfolio management decision. As the sole purpose of active management is to generate excess returns over the benchmark, it is important that an equity benchmark representing this asset class be efficient, so that any outperformance of an active manager can be considered an outcome of the manager's skill. A more efficient benchmark for large-cap equity results in a historical average information ratio of zero for the universe of active managers. The key to generating alpha in this asset class then depends on one's ability to identify skillful managers.</description><author>Seegopaul, H.; Gupta, F.; Prestbo, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>If you had everything computationally ... - Where would you put it, financially?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leinweber, D.
Some significant technological breakthroughs have transformed investment and trading over the past 30 years. In a speculative leap, the author evaluates the current state of technology and considers the changes in investment and trading that will be brought about in the future. Topics include electronic markets, extraction of information to produce alpha from expanding textual and web sources, and visualization that improves our ability to produce value in a financial environment that we increasingly share with machines.</description><author>Leinweber, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Income and cap rate effects on property appreciation - Some guidance for future pricing trends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Conner, P.; Liang, Y. G.
The strong performance of real estate and other private market asset classes in the past several years has attracted considerable interest to alternative investments. While the evidence demonstrates that property and capital market forces drive real estate pricing and thus investment Performance, measuring the contribution of these two forces is challenging. Examination of the historical relationship between real estate property market forces (which drive property earnings) and capital market forces (which largely determine cap rates) helps investors better understand the effect of the two forces on property values in the past and how changes in either might affect property values in the future.</description><author>Conner, P.; Liang, Y. G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The surprisingly small impact of asset growth on expected alpha - Warning: Optimal portfolio management required.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kahn, R. N.; Shaffer, J. S.
Managers, sponsors, and consultants all have an interest in understanding the capacity of investment products. Capacity is the maximum asset level at which a product can deliver the expected performance (on average) over time. A framework for analyzing capacity should be useful for understanding its driving forces. Under transaction cost-aware portfolio management, expected alpha net of costs turns out to decay very slowly with increasing asset levels; large errors in estimated capacity lead to only small errors in expected alpha net of costs. Building portfolios without regard to costs, however, leads to substantially lower capacity. Negative returns do not necessarily signify capacity problems, but increasing costs usually signify suboptimal portfolio management. Asset growth should be managed and size regularly compared with available capacity. Managers can increase capacity by improving their intrinsic information ratio and by reducing transaction costs, perhaps through better approaches to trading.</description><author>Kahn, R. N.; Shaffer, J. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Factor neutrality - Maintaining it can be suboptimal.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lam, D. Y.; Lee, W.
Investors have views on both factor returns and stock-specific returns, and the results they achieve may reflect both return components to varying degrees. Attempting to eliminate the impact of a particular factor may not be desirable. Application of an analytical framework to consider the potential deterioration in investment performance suggests a substantial loss in information ratio due to enforcement of factor neutrality, particularly with a limited number of stocks in a portfolio, as is often the case in the real world. The IR may be affected even if all information available is on stock-specific returns, when different universes are used to estimate the factor structure and to construct the portfolio. Maintaining factor neutrality can be suboptimal.</description><author>Lam, D. Y.; Lee, W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contextual fundamentals, models, and active management - Improving on one-size-fits-all.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sorensen, E. H.; Hua, R.; Qian, E.
Application of a multifactor alpha model across a diverse range of stocks is a popular way to forecast security expected returns, but it is a one-size-fits-all approach. An alternative alpha-modeling approach represents a parsimonious way to model securities individually in order to capture idiosyncratic return behavior in different security contexts. The investment objective is information ratio maximization through optimal alpha factor weights. This technique demonstrates the importance of factor categories such as cheapness, quality, and sentiment that vary significantly across various security contexts. Practitioners can see that the approach improves the ex post information ratio over a one-size-fits-all approach.</description><author>Sorensen, E. H.; Hua, R.; Qian, E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A factor approach to asset allocation - Exposure to global market factors.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clarke, R. G.; de Silva, H.; Murdock, R.
The typical asset allocation decision focuses on gaining exposure to systematic market risks such as equity, interest rate, and credit risk. Investors also often explicitly manage their exposure to firm-specific characteristics like size, book-to-market, or momentum. For a global portfolio, we can add another category of exposures not correlated with systematic market risks and firm-specific characteristics: global market factors that explain the cross-section of returns across individual equity, fixed income, and currency markets. Portfolios constructed to include exposures to each of these three categories of risk and return seem to be more efficient at producing diversified returns than those limited to just systematic market risks. Using this factor-based approach to asset allocation results in optimal portfolios with significantly less exposure to equity market risk than the typical institutional portfolio generated using the traditional asset allocation approach.</description><author>Clarke, R. G.; de Silva, H.; Murdock, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial markets: Truth and consequences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Direct investment in real estate - Momentum profits and their robustness to trading costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marcato, G.; Key, T.
Momentum strategies have the potential to generate extra profits in private real estate markets. Tests of a variety of frequencies of portfolio reweighting identify periods of winner and loser performance. There are strong potential gains from momentum strategies that are based on prior returns over a 6- to 12-month period. Whether these gains are attainable for real-world investors depends on transaction costs, but some momentum strategies do produce net excess returns. The, findings hold even if returns are unsmoothed to reflect underlying market prices.</description><author>Marcato, G.; Key, T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CMBS credit protection and underwriting standards - Have they declined too far?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacob, D. P.; Manzi, J. M.
Credit-enhancing features and underwriting standards in commercial mortgage-backed securities (CMBS) transactions have evolved over time since the market developed in the early 1990s. With the positive performance of commercial real estate, the boom in capital flowing into the sector, and competition among new entrants to the market, lenders have become more flexible with regard to loan terms, enabling CMBS to be sold at reduced credit enhancement levels. The competition among market players, old and new, suggests that the trend toward more relaxed lending standards may not reverse itself any time soon (not a concern as long as investors are compensated for the additional risk). While these trends are not unique to CMBS, the best strategy for an investor who has to be in the bond markets (short of moving into Treasuries) is to compare spreads across different sectors and adjust for credit enhancement and expected credit experience.</description><author>Jacob, D. P.; Manzi, J. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hotel real estate markets - Wat we know</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corgel, J. B.
In the absence of lease friction, hotel markets provide a unique laboratory for addressing how space and asset markets respond to local and macroeconomic condition changes. The knowledge gained from studying hotel markets lies scattered in bits and pieces across the literature. A consolidation of what we now know about hotel markets is useful in that case. Here are some views on what we can learn about hotel markets as the market moves closer to a peak.</description><author>Corgel, J. B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CMBS total return swaps - Offered on attractive terms so far</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goodman, L. S.; Fabozzi, F. J.
The total return swap market has been a key financial market innovation to control risk or to enhance returns. For commercial mortgage-backed securities (CMBS), several dealers offer total return swaps on various CMBS indexes and their subsectors. The authors discuss the mechanics of these CMBS swaps and the economic rationale as to why the market has offered attractive terms to those who want to gain exposure to the CMBS sector, while eliminating the idiosyncratic risk between a CMBS cash portfolio and the CMBS indexes.</description><author>Goodman, L. S.; Fabozzi, F. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New strategies for commercial real estate investment and risk management - Introducing the NPI-based derivative</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fisher, J. D.
Credit Suisse First Boston recently announced it plans to offer several derivatives based on the NCREIF Property Index that will allow investors to either buy or sell the appreciation component of the NPI. Derivatives will also allow investors to swap property sector returns from the NPI. These derivatives will let investors invest in real estate, hedge real estate risk, and rebalance portfolios through property type swaps in ways not previously possible. These risk management techniques put commercial real estate on more of a par with financial assets like stocks.</description><author>Fisher, J. D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real estate opportunity funds - Past performance as an indicator of subsequent fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hahn, T. C.; Geltner, D.; Gerardo-Lietz, N.
Real estate opportunity funds are one of the fastest-growing segments of the real estate investment industry, similar in some basic respects to other private equity and alternative investment asset classes that seek high returns by taking on more risk in highly illiquid private investments. Opportunity funds rely heavily on the skill and expertise of the fund managers, prompting a question as to whether subsequent real estate opportunity funds launched by the same manager display persistent performance. Despite strong evidence of persistence, such relative performance appears to be mean-reverting or even reversing over longer periods between fund launches. There is less persistence in returns net of management fees, suggesting that successful managers can effectively charge higher fees on subsequent funds.</description><author>Hahn, T. C.; Geltner, D.; Gerardo-Lietz, N.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyzing real estate portfolio returns - More than alpha and beta . . . there's gamma</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaiser, R. W.
Private real estate returns cannot be explained adequately by alpha and beta alone. The fact that so many real estate managers claim positive and persistent alpha performance versus the NCREIF benchmark seems simply unbelievable to public securities investors, who know that alpha is a zero-sum game. Perhaps this outperformance is simply the result of value creation strategies such as new development or redevelopment, something that can occur only in private market investing strategies that allow the investor to take control of the asset. This third component of return-value creation-is here called gamma, making the real estate portfolio return equation equal beta + alpha + gamma. An analytic approach to such three-way performance attribution indicates that gamma is likely a much more powerful explanation of private equity portfolio outperformance than alpha could ever be.</description><author>Kaiser, R. W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stand-alone centers occupied by big-box retailers - Likely poor choices for institutional investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shilling, J. D.; Simmons-Mosley, T. X.; Thode, S. F.
Investments in stand-alone centers occupied by big-box retailers do poorly as a hedge against changes in the variables that generally matter to institutional investors. The. reason is structural. Big-box retailer leases often include a go-dark option allowing the retail tenant to vacate its space before expiration of the lease. This tends to occur under high inflation (and hence the big-box retailer cash flow growth rate is high) and under high uncertainty, exactly the conditions under which institutional investors most need high returns.</description><author>Shilling, J. D.; Simmons-Mosley, T. X.; Thode, S. F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who bears the balloon risk in commercial MBS? In some cases it can be investment-grade tranches</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eppli, M. J.; Tu, C. C.
Much of the literature on the pricing of commercial mortgages underlying commercial mortgage-backed securities pools focuses on the effect of term default (default during the term of the loan), and ignores the possibility of balloon risk, the borrower's inability to pay off the mortgage at maturity through refinancing or property sale. A contingent-claims mortgage pricing model that includes two default triggers-a cash flow trigger and an asset value trigger-may be used to assess the effect of balloon risk on the pricing of CMBS tranches. Simulations of cash flows for individual loans in a CMBS framework reveal how individual tranches are affected by balloon risk. Balloon risk is low at the whole-loan level, but under a number of scenarios total credit risk and balloon risk creep into investment-grade CMBS tranches and significantly impact their valuation.</description><author>Eppli, M. J.; Tu, C. C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Privately traded real estate equity - An attractive opportunity, but not without risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anson, M. J. P.; Hudson-Wilson, S.; Fabozzi, F. J.
Private commercial real estate equity held as an individual asset or in commingled vehicles represents one of the four real estate sectors for institutional investors. Within the sector are three primary strategies: core, value-added, and opportunistic. Core properties are well-positioned real estate properties with high occupancy rates and stable cash flows. Core properties are at the lower end of the risk and return spectrum where capital gain is secondary to income generation. At the opposite end of the spectrum are opportunistic properties, which are characterized by low or unreliable income streams but great potential for appreciation. Value-added properties have mixed characteristics, and lie between the two extremes of core and opportunistic properties. One significant problem for investors in the private equity sector is valuation.</description><author>Anson, M. J. P.; Hudson-Wilson, S.; Fabozzi, F. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does location matter? Do property fundamentals vary within markets, and is this reflected in pricing?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wheaton, W. C.; Nechayev, G.
It is axiomatic that all real estate is local. The question is whether very local submarkets within an MSA behave differently in terms of their fundamentals, and if so whether this behavior is priced appropriately so that total investor returns are approximately the same across locations. Longterm data on the market fundamentals of a large sample of Atlanta apartments combined with more recent data on sales transactions allow these authors to produce very accurate capitalization rates or yields. Market absorption, construction, and short-term vacancy vary across submarkets and are particularly volatile. Despite these differences, submarket rents move much more smoothly, although different areas are different in long-term rental growth, and the differences in performance are close to perfectly priced. In areas with higher rent growth and declining vacancy, yields are lower to the extent that theory would suggest.</description><author>Wheaton, W. C.; Nechayev, G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal hedge fund allocations - Do higher moments matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, J. H.; Kritzman, M.; Page, S.
Hedge funds have return peculiarities not commonly associated with traditional investment vehicles. They are more inclined to produce return distributions with significantly non-normal skewness and kurtosis. Investor preferences may be better represented by bilinear utility functions or S-shaped value functions than by neoclassical utility functions, and mean-variance optimization is thus not appropriate for forming portfolios that include hedge funds. Portfolios of hedge funds formed using both mean-variance and full-scale optimization, given a wide range of assumptions about investor preferences, reveal that higher moments of hedge funds do not meaningfully compromise the efficacy of mean-variance optimization if investors have power utility; mean-variance optimization is not particularly effective for identifying optimal hedge fund allocations if preferences are bilinear or S-shaped; and, contrary to conventional wisdom, investors with S-shaped preferences are attracted to kurtosis as well as negative skewness.</description><author>Cremers, J. H.; Kritzman, M.; Page, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Vanguard's managers good stock-pickers or style-pickers?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reinker, K. S.; Tower, E.
Jared Kizer's article in the Winter 2005 issue indicates for Vanguard's managed funds that the return to stock-picking skill is not enough to offset the additional transactions costs of a managed portfolio. Thus, the superior performance of Vanguard's managed portfolio was due entirely to its tendency to over-weight small stocks and value stocks relative to the index portfolio during a period when stocks with these two characteristics outperformed the market. So, it is style-picking skill rather than stock-picking skill that leads to the superiority of the managed portfolio in this particular instance. Similarly, style-picking skill explains the lower risk for the managed portfolio.</description><author>Reinker, K. S.; Tower, E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance measurement manipulation - Gaming the current morningstar star system.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Winston, K.
Single scalar measures of portfolio performance are inevitably susceptible to manipulation. The Morningstar stars awarded to mutual funds on the basis of huge flows into or out of funds are an example. The system was updated in 2002 and corrects a number of problems with the older system, but-like any single scalar measure-it can be gamed.</description><author>Winston, K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relationships between implied volatility indexes and stock index returns - Are implied volatility indexes leading indicators?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giot, P.
There is a negative and statistically significant relationship between the returns of the S&amp;P 100 and the Nasdaq 100 stock indexes and their corresponding implied volatility indexes, VIX and VXN. For the S&amp;P 100, the relationship is asymmetric, as negative stock index returns are more associated than positive returns with greater changes in VIX. VIX changes when negative stock index returns are observed are greater in low-volatility periods. For the Nasdaq 100, the asymmetric effect is rather weak, but the VXN and underlying index co-movement is also somewhat muted in high-volatility trading environments. There is some evidence that positive forward-looking returns are to be expected for long positions triggered by extremely high levels of the implied volatility indexes.</description><author>Giot, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Toward better risk forecasts - Using data with higher frequency than the forecasting horizon.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gosier, K.; Madhavan, A.; Serbin, V.; Yang, J.
Volatility forecasts crucial to many financial applications usually assume implicitly that the frequency of the data should match the forecast horizon; portfolio managers typically rely on risk models estimated using monthly data to produce monthly volatility forecasts, for example. For longer-term forecasts, this practice has two drawbacks: Volatility estimates can be based on stale data; and return events occurring within long sampling intervals are obscured, confounding estimation. Monthly volatility risk measures constructed using higher-frequency data seem to be more robust than those using low-frequency data. Microstructure effects can explain the differences in estimates.</description><author>Gosier, K.; Madhavan, A.; Serbin, V.; Yang, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global integration of developed credit markets - Correlations with portfolio implications.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breger, L.; Stovel, D.
Return correlations in the U.S. dollar and euro credit markets are systematically different on at least two dimensions: returns for normal day-to-day spread changes versus spread returns associated with extreme events; and spread returns for investment-grade versus speculative issuers. A large part of the return correlation is driven by extreme global events such as the 2001 terrorist attacks or the 2002 credit crisis ensuing on the Enron meltdown. Under more normal market conditions, euro and U.S. dollar credit markets are weakly linked, especially for highly rated debt. Returns on speculative debt issued by the same issuer in different markets tend to be highly correlated; this is less so for high-grade issuers. An immediate implication is that currency diversification is much more efficient than name diversification for high-grade debt. Conversely, high-yield portfolios benefit from name or even sector diversification more than they benefit from currency diversification. Risk models need to include currency-dependent factors, particularly for investment-grade instruments. The results provide some indication of the way to use global credit factors or factor return proxies to estimate credit risk in markets lacking much corporate bond data.</description><author>Breger, L.; Stovel, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A la carte prepayments - The menu-driven approach.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, A. K.; Banerjee, S.; Malozemov, L.; Sekhar, A.
A key component in the valuation of mortgage-backed securities that distinguishes them from bullet fixed-income securities is the prepayment behavior of the underlying mortgages. Increased liquidity of NIBS markets has led to increased market efficiency, making the pricing of different types of customized MBS an important function of the underlying loan prepayment profiles. Lower-balance MBS, which prepay more slowly, are offered at a premium over to-be-announced (TBA) MBS, for example. Many other property and obligor attributes that determine prepayment should be considered in aggregate MBS valuation. A prepayment examination of the underlying loans provides a systematic way to analyze the variation in pay-ups (or concession) of customized MBS to TBAs.</description><author>Bhattacharya, A. K.; Banerjee, S.; Malozemov, L.; Sekhar, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-duration trusts and endowments - It's fecundity that matters.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garland, J. P.
Overseers of endowments and long-duration trusts should focus on how they can use cash from these funds to serve the owners' or beneficiaries' current spending needs without a negative impact on future withdrawals to meet future spending needs. As the ultimate objective of all investment portfolios is to provide spendable cash over some time frame particular to the owner's or beneficiary's circumstances, paying attention to the fecundity, or the fruitfulness, of long-duration portfolios would seem to make good sense. Cash withdrawals, effectively the fruit of a portfolio, can come from dividends, interest, portfolio asset sales, or some combination of all three. A focus on the fecundity of a typical endowment or long-duration trust fund leads to several useful insights.</description><author>Garland, J. P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Total return fixed-income portfolio management - A risk-based dynamic strategy.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Herold, U.; Maurer, R.; Purschaker, N.
The fixed-income portfolio strategy investigated here is designed to generate positive returns and be completely risk-based; it does not require any forecasts about future yield curve movements, The idea is to control the shortfall risk of a fixed-income portfolio dynamically, allowing portfolio managers to spend their available risk budgets flexibly (taking duration, yield curve, and credit positions). The total risk of the portfolio is adjusted on a daily basis to produce positive total returns (or a total return above a prespecified mimmum-return threshold).</description><author>Herold, U.; Maurer, R.; Purschaker, N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Five myths of active portfolio management - Most active managers are skilled.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berk, J. B.
Five myths are debunked here. It is not true that: the return investors earn in an actively managed fund measures the skill level of the manager; the average active manager is not skilled and therefore does not add value; if managers are skilled their returns should persist-they should be able to consistently beat the market; in light of evidence that there is little or no persistence in actively managed funds' returns, investors who pick funds on the basis of past returns are not behaving rationally; and finally, because most active managers' compensation does not depend on the return they generate, their compensation is not performance-based.</description><author>Berk, J. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An alternative approach to international growth investing - Very difterent from domestic growth investing.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pozen, R. C.; Fleishman, B. A.
Growth investing in international stocks is very different from growth investing in U.S. stocks. The tracking error between international growth and value returns has been significantly lower than the tracking error between U.S. growth and U.S. value returns. Therefore a portfolio consisting of both international growth and international value equities, as defined by EAFE, has offered less portfolio diversification than a portfolio consisting of both U.S. growth and value equities. An alternative strategy is an international growth portfolio with substantial investments in small-capitalization and emerging markets stocks, two asset classes that offer the potential for higher returns than the MSCI EAFE Growth index, with lower correlations to the MSCI EAFE Value index.</description><author>Pozen, R. C.; Fleishman, B. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The active management premium in small-cap US equities - Real, or a figment of universe construction bias?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, G. C.
Active managers of small-cap U.S. equity portfolios have consistently and significantly outperformed the Russell 2000 over the past 20 years, while active managers of large-cap U.S. equity portfolios have barely kept pace with the Russell 1000. Is small-cap a less efficient market, and a more productive place to spend active risk capital? A robust database of over 780 institutional small-cap managers allows examination of the historical behavior of the small-cap premium over the last 20 years. After taking into account survivorship bias, instant history bias, and a mild large-cap growth bias in the universe, we see the small-cap active management premium seems to have been significant and consistent over the period.</description><author>Allen, G. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Startling facts from the past</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Higher-moment portfolio theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malevergne, Y.; Sornette, D.
A new portfolio theory takes into account the non-Gaussian properties of asset returns. The non-Gaussian properties of a portfolio are quantified by the so-called moments and cumulants of its distribution of returns. Generalizing the concept of efficient frontiers, the non-Gaussian efficient frontier depends on the chosen risk measure, corresponding to different orders or combinations of centered moments or cumulants. These extended formulas let investors analyze the conditions under which it is possible to have one's cake and eat it too, in order to construct a portfolio with both higher return and fewer major risks.</description><author>Malevergne, Y.; Sornette, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New frontiers in compliance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Samuelson, P.; Schulman, E.
In an era of increased regulatory oversight (not to mention litigious clients), compliance procedures need to be forward-looking, complete, scalable, and part of the order generation process. Compliance officers and fiduciaries must have simple, understandable documented evaluations of 1) where their portfolios were, and are, in risk-return space, and 2) all trades, detailing their effect upon portfolios in terms of risk and return (and taxes, if applicable) along with a statement or code regarding their relationship to any investment restrictions.</description><author>Samuelson, P.; Schulman, E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional portfolio management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anson, M.
Institutional portfolio management has two main goals: 1) to implement the policy risk of the institutional fund as efficiently as possible, and 2) to add value. While these two goals may be accomplished by beta drivers and alpha drivers, asset managers often attempt to extract alpha from beta drivers. This leads to expensive products that add more beta than alpha. To better manage institutional portfolios, beta products must be separated from alpha products, so that the two goals can be accomplished more effectively. This has implications both for the types of products produced by money managers and the types of products purchased by the institutional investor's staff.</description><author>Anson, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantitative topics in hedge fund investing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liew, J.; French, C.
There are five current topics in hedge fund investing examined here. First is that investors should use multifactor models with observable market factors when they attempt to separate alpha from beta. Second, it is important to test for the positive serial correlation in hedge fund returns that remains a pervasive problem. Third, there are some difficulties in applying academic techniques to portfolio construction, but several pragmatic solutions may be able to overcome them. Fourth, manager selection may be more important than strategy allocation for hedge fund investing. Finally, negatively skewed returns have implications for the construction of a portfolio of hedge funds.</description><author>Liew, J.; French, C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How hedge funds fit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dopfel, F. E.
Hedge funds fit in an institutional investor's portfolio only if one can evaluate how the inclusion of hedge fund strategies would improve the performance of the entire portfolio, after considering both beta and alpha characteristics. This is more challenging than it first appears because of the opaqueness and the complexity of most hedge fund strategies. The key is to identify institutional-quality hedge funds that permit a clear understanding of the normal portfolio and provide confidence in projecting a positive, pure alpha. If these conditions can be satisfied, there are two possible approaches to incorporating institutional-quality hedge funds: 1) hedge funds as an active overlay at the total portfolio level, or 2) hedge funds as portable alpha within a traditional asset class.</description><author>Dopfel, F. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The real issue in the Social Security debate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Country versus region effects in international stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brooks, R.; Del Negro, M.
An empirical regularity in the portfolio diversification literature is the importance of country effects in explaining international return variation. A new decomposition here disaggregates these country effects into region effects and within-region country effects. Half of the return variation typically attributed to country effects seems attributable actually to region effects, a result robust across developed and emerging markets; the remaining variation is explained by within-region country effects. For the average investor, this means that diversifying across countries within Europe, for example, delivers half the risk reduction possible from diversifying across regions globally.</description><author>Brooks, R.; Del Negro, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The P/B-ROE valuation model revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wilcox, J. W.; Philips, T. K.
A two-stage stock valuation model derived from the P/B-ROE approach is shown to be a surprisingly effective tool for a broad variety of uses, including the explanation of current prices and the prediction of future return differences. This applies both to the cross-section of individual U.S. stocks and the time series of the S&amp;P 500 index. Besides offering a new closed-form expression for firm value, the model measures the investment horizon over which the market predicts exceptional profitability, demonstrates the dependence of expectations for future profitability on past volatility of return on equity, and quantifies the extent of the recent U.S. stock price bubble. Perhaps the model's most persuasive result is its no-look-ahead statistical support for tactical asset allocation.</description><author>Wilcox, J. W.; Philips, T. K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prepayment risk- and option-adjusted valuation of MBS</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levin, A.; Davidson, A.
This exploration of risk-neutrahty in MBS prepayments introduces option-adjusted valuation of MBS with consideration of prepayment risk, i.e., the risk that future prepay speeds systematically drift away from a model. A new measure, prepayment risk- and option-adjusted spread (prOAS), is suggested to replace the traditional option-adjusted spread, which varies widely across instruments. PrOAS levels the playing field by assuming that all liquid NIBS and their derivatives are traded flat to the same debenture curve, on a risk- and option-adjusted basis. There are two alternative and theoretically equivalent methods of pricing with prOAS: 1) solving pricing PDEs with risk terms explicitly for pass-throughs using the active-passive decomposed prepay model, and 2) using a risk-neutral prepayment model, which is more universal. Although the prOAS method generally works well in case studies, there are some exaggerated dynamics of prices of risk and market dislocation in times of panic that offer arbitrage opportunities.</description><author>Levin, A.; Davidson, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Simulated credit loss distribution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ramaswamy, S.
Standard portfolio credit risk models provide an assessment of the potential credit loss that could result from changes to the credit quality of different obligors held in a bond portfolio. In practice, a significant portion of the credit loss can also result from changes to credit spreads that may or may not be directly related to the obligor's creditworthiness. Comparison of the simulated credit loss distribution for an investment-grade corporate bond portfolio generated using standard credit risk models and the historical credit loss distribution of a similar portfolio indicates that the two are quite dissimilar. Several modifications can be made to the standard portfolio credit risk model to reduce this discrepancy.</description><author>Ramaswamy, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nasdaq's closing cross</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pagano, M. S.; Schwartz, R. A.
On March 29, 2004, Nasdaq significantly expanded its hybrid market structure by introducing the closing cross, an electronic price discovery call auction that sets closing trades and establishes official closing prices. Three months later, on June 25, the efficiency of the new facility was stress-tested by the Russell 2000 rebalancing, an event that involved almost 1,700 Nasdaq stocks. The efficiency of the closing cross can be analyzed by comparing price dislocations experienced at the 2004 rebalancing with those observed at the 2003 rebalancing. By and large, the findings suggest that the closing procedure is effective, especially for the smaller-cap stocks in the Russell 2000 index.</description><author>Pagano, M. S.; Schwartz, R. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial communities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Das, S. R.; Sisk, J.
Postings on Internet discussion boards provide an unusual opportunity to explore the sociological mechanics underlying the impounding of information into stock prices and to examine any implications for portfolio construction. Graph-theoretic techniques applied to contacts across the web network of stock discussion allow classification of stocks into two types: communities of connected stocks, and disconnected stocks. Connected stocks outperform others in a risk-adjusted sense. Adopting the concept of centrality from the sociology literature reveals that stocks with high centrality covary more with other stocks, suggesting greater analyst scrutiny. Classifying stocks into financial communities provides a novel way to look at risk-return trade-offs and to direct analyst attention, and offers new diversification insights for portfolio managers.</description><author>Das, S. R.; Sisk, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Drivebys systematically underperform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fridson, M.; Braylovskly, G.
Unlike traditional high-yield bond offerings, which typically entail a two-week roadshow of presentations to prospective investors, driveby offerings are announced and priced within one day. The yield spread of the average driveby deal widens versus the high-yield index in the first week and the first four weeks after issuance, while the spread of the average non-drive-by deal tightens. This finding is statistically robust. Drivebys tend to come to market when the pressure to invest surplus cash is greatest. Portfolio managers who can hold out generally have an opportunity to buy the issues more cheaply in the secondary market.</description><author>Fridson, M.; Braylovskly, G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The equity premium - What level should investors require?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bostock, P.
Investors require additional expected returns for bearing costs and risks. The equity premium is the compensation investors require for bearing the additional costs and risks of equity investment compared with government bonds ( or cash). In this framework, the equity premium is constructed by assembling the premiums paid for each source of cost and risk. The results appeal to intuition and are closer to theoretical expectations than historical equity and bond return comparisons.</description><author>Bostock, P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The benchmark index ETF performance problem - A simple solution.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gastineau, G. L.
Exchange-traded funds have generally underperformed competitive conventional mutual funds, apparently because the ETF structure and fund management process seems to discourage efforts to recapture transaction costs embedded in the benchmark index portfolio change process. An analysis of the problem produces a rather simple solution.</description><author>Gastineau, G. L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Index design and implications for index tracking - Evidence from S&amp;P 500 index funds.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frino, A.; Gallagher, D. R.; Neubert, A. S.; Oetomo, T. N.
Tracking error in index fund performance is unavoidable. It arises because the underlying index is measured as a paper portfolio, and it is assumed perfect replication can be achieved instantaneously and without cost. Tracking error has two components: exogenous tracking error (the result of index rules and maintenance procedures applied to the underlying index) and endogenous tracking error (the result of the individual activities of index managers managing open-end passive funds). An examination of a sample of S&amp;P 500 index mutual funds upon changes to the Index Divisor identifies a number of exogenous factors that are important determinants of tracking error for S&amp;P 500 index funds.</description><author>Frino, A.; Gallagher, D. R.; Neubert, A. S.; Oetomo, T. N.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Soft dollars - Or the devil made me do it.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schulman, E.
With the level of management fees, it is argued that it is not in the interest of money managers to undertake some research activities benefiting their clients, net of costs. There could thus well be underinvestment in securities research, investment platforms, or trading facilities, and so on. Making charges directly to the corpus of the fund can cure this problem, and soft dollars are an ideal conduit to effect such payments. The fact that money managers are negotiating commission dollar contracts using other people's money causes other problems, though.</description><author>Schulman, E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate model selection - A conscientious choice for mortgage investors.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levin, A.
Analysis of the most popular single-factor mortgage valuation models unambiguously rejects the lognormality of interest rates. Recent trends in the swaption market indicate normalization, supporting use of the Hull-White model, which can be quickly and accurately calibrated to at-the-money swaptions. Durations for TBA instruments come up shorter by the Hull-White model and are generally more in line with the empirical measures. The issue of negative rates is not found to be detrimental to the standard OAS pricing practice.</description><author>Levin, A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Defaults and returns on high-yield bonds - Reviewing recent experience and analytics.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altman, E. I.; Bana, G.
The year 2002 was remarkably difficult on many fronts for most financial markets. For the high-yield bond market, it was again a year of record amounts of defaults ($97.9 billion), which contributed to low recovery rates and slightly negative absolute returns. The default rate registered a record 12.8%, based on $757 billion outstanding. Despite these record default totals and rates, the market's decline was orderly, with little panic, and the year actually ended with reduced defaults and highly positive returns in the fourth quarter-a harbinger of a broad-based comeback in the high-yield bond and defaulted debt markets in 2003.</description><author>Altman, E. I.; Bana, G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which risks have been best rewarded? Duration, equity market, and short-dated credit risk.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ilmanen, A.; Byrne, R.; Gunasekera, H.; Minikin, R.
An empirical study examines the consistency of rewards for bearing various types of risks in U. S. asset markets between 1985 and early 2002. Bearing duration risk and equity market risk was amply rewarded, while bearing long-dated credit risk-buying credit-risky bonds versus governments-realized puny average profits. Bearing short-dated credit risk gave the most consistent profits of all static overweight strategies, with an information ratio near one. Wide break-even spread cushions may be one explanation for the superior reward for risk at short maturities. More fundamentally, market segmentation seems to be the main explanation, because the most consistent profit opportunities involve switching from Treasuries to top-rated non-government bonds.</description><author>Ilmanen, A.; Byrne, R.; Gunasekera, H.; Minikin, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk allocation under shortfall constraints - Improved allocation by incorporating parameter uncertainty.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Molenkamp, J. B.
Risk budgeting interpreted as efficient portfolio allocation is often based on expected outperformance, alpha or information ratio. Once this crucial input has been estimated, it is frequently treated as fully reliable. One can use historical measures to develop some sense, both theoretical and practical, of the extent of the uncertainty and use a model to characterize the uncertainty of the expected active returns. Examples demonstrate the potential impact of uncertain parameters. The model is said to be widely applicable, easy to implement, and useful in making an optimal risk allocation at different levels of investment strategy.</description><author>Molenkamp, J. B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multiple alpha sources and active management - Avenues to improve active performance.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sorensen, E. H.; Qian, E.; Schoen, R.; Hua, R.
Active portfolio managers often see themselves as assemblers of efficient portfolios that maximize information ratios through the value-added of their proprietary investment insights (alphas), but approaches to reconciling often-contradicting investment insights differ widely. A linear combination of different investment insights can be used to support an analytical framework that maximizes the information from one single source. Simulations based on this framework reveal the impact of varying two key variables-the cross-sectional correlation of alpha signals and the time series correlations of the information coefficients related to alpha signals. The latter plays a more important role, providing diversification benefit to strategy risk over time. This analytical foundation has applications in sensitivity analysis and improving active performance.</description><author>Sorensen, E. H.; Qian, E.; Schoen, R.; Hua, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Improving portfolio efficiency - Risk budgeting, implied confidence levels, and changing allocations.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Winkelmann, K.
A demanding market environment has left many investors seeking new solutions to address today's investment challenges. Questions concerning issues such as portfolio efficiency and active risk are at the forefront of investors' minds as they work through investment policy decisions. The framework here enables investors to analyze their investment policy in light of these questions, including risk budgeting and implied relative confidence levels. A typical defined-benefit portfolio illustrates the link between the active risk budget and the confidence investors place in one active strategy over another. Some important policy recommendations include introducing portable alpha and active overlay strategies, increasing allocations to hedge funds, and effectively diversifying investors' private equity portfolio.</description><author>Winkelmann, K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic versus tactical asset allocation - Beta versus alpha drivers.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anson, M.
The author divides the asset allocation decision into two asset classes: beta drivers and alpha drivers. Beta drivers, which provide broad economic exposure to the financial markets, are established by the strategic asset allocation decision. Alpha drivers are designed to provide added return beyond the return offered through passive exposure to the financial markets. Alpha drivers, chosen as part of the tactical asset allocation decision, are designed to facilitate the long-term funding goals of an organization by seeking added value. Examples of how beta and alpha drivers may be used in strategic versus tactical asset allocation are provided.</description><author>Anson, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New kids on the block</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Focardi, S. M.; Kolm, P. N.; Fabozzi, F. J.
The evolution of quantitative methods in finance is changing the investment management industry. With an altered focus in finance and investment theory, theoretical concepts such as market efficiency and market equilibrium have ceded ground to econometric methods that allow a more pragmatic investigation of asset predictability. Mean-variance optimization, one of the cornerstones of classic finance theory, presents some problems in practice, and recent developments in Bayesian modeling and robust optimization techniques circumvent some of its weaknesses. Beyond the classic framework, we must model the feedback mechanisms that we know to operate in financial markets, with caution as to model risk, data snooping, and overfitting biases.</description><author>Focardi, S. M.; Kolm, P. N.; Fabozzi, F. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Applying optimization technology to portfolio management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mulvey, J. M.
Multiperiod optimization models are typical in portfolio management. Prominent examples include fund construction, the investment/consumption problem for individual investors, and asset/liability management for global financial organizations. Powerful optimization technology can expand the range of solvable portfolio applications, especially for investment problems over time. Three primary frameworks-stochastic control, stochastic programs, and optimizing simulators-have their particular advantages. Advanced optimization tools will be useful in many future applications.</description><author>Mulvey, J. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What do investors want?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Statman, M.
Investments, like restaurants, offer both utilitarian and expressive benefits. Diners want more than the utilitarian benefits of low cost and high nutrition when they choose restaurants; they want the utilitarian benefits of tastiness, ambiance, and conformance to culture. And they also want the expressive benefits of status, patriotism, and social responsibility. Similarly, investors want more than the utilitarian benefits of low risk and high expected returns when they choose investments; they want additional utilitarian benefits, and they want expressive benefits as well. Food service trade periodicals discuss both the utilitarian benefits of restaurants and their expressive ones, but finance journals confine themselves to the utilitarian benefits of low risk and high expected returns. Might not the expressive benefits of investments be discussed in future finance journals?</description><author>Statman, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial market simulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobs, B. I.; Levy, K. N.; Markowitz, H. M.
When they want to see how complex systems work, scientists often turn to asynchronous-time simulation models, in which processes change sporadically, typically at irregular intervals, over time. Such models are rarely used in finance now, but they may prove valuable tools for understanding how markets respond to changes in the participation rates of different types of investors, for example, or to changes in regulatory or investment policies. The authors describe asynchronous simulation generally, and illustrate its capabilities in terms of an asynchronous, discrete-event stock market simulator that they developed. The JLM Market Simulator allows its users to create a model of the market, using their own inputs. JLM Sim users can vary the number of investors, traders, portfolio analysts, statisticians, and securities, as well as the decisions rules used in investing and trading. Compared with most models used today, such a simulation may be able to provide a more realistic picture of complex markets.</description><author>Jacobs, B. I.; Levy, K. N.; Markowitz, H. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can predictable patterns in market returns be exploited using real money?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malkiel, B. G.
Academic studies suggest stock market prices are to a considerable extent predictable. Investors tend to earn higher returns when the market sells at relatively low price-earnings multiples and high dividend yields. Value stocks supposedly outperform growth stocks, and smaller companies produce higher returns than larger firms. Moreover, buying losers over the past several years supposedly trumps a strategy of buying recent winners. In fact, investment strategies undertaken with real money cannot make the excess returns that academic studies suggest. Market-timing strategies based on initial valuation metrics do not outperform a buy-and-hold strategy. Value stock, small-cap, and contrarian managers do not consistently outperform the market. The strongest statistical pattern we find among actual money managers is that returns are enhanced by low expenses and low turnover.</description><author>Malkiel, B. G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A brave new world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McCulley, P.
Gains of the. 1980s and 1990s in stocks and bonds arose from a bull market in capitalism and falling inflation, conditions that do not appear on today's horizon. Instead, the years ahead promise to be marked by a bull market in government and the-end of a 20-year period of disinflation. In this environment, monetary policy will assume different aims and employ different strategies. Adjustment to the prospective weights between public and private sector in the mixed economy of the U.S., as well as to a new monetary policy regime, will be an essential requirement for investment success in-this Brave New World.</description><author>McCulley, P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Blinded by theory?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arnott, R. D.
Theories are but theories; they help us understand how the world should work. There's no harm in raising arguments that suggest the world works somewhat differently from the theory, but often the investment community accepts theories and their underlying assumptions as fact. All too often, we prefer to operate on the basis of heuristics or shortcuts, some shaped by theory and others by convention, rather than examine our core assumptions; these heuristics can set the stage for error on a massive scale. We forecast the future by extrapolating the past, and assume that retained earnings will be reinvested more wisely than if shareholders received this cash in dividends to fuel future growth. Investors and academicians too rarely test their hypotheses, or they accept the data if they contradict the theories.</description><author>Arnott, R. D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Thinking outside the benchmark</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anson, M.
The twin decades of 1980-1999 provided annual returns to the U.S. equity market in the high double digits, but moving forward over the next decade, returns are expected to be in the mid- to high single digits, just when corporate and public pension plans face both a growing retiree population and lengthening average retiree longevity. To meet these challenges, pension plans must think beyond their benchmarks, and remove the restrictions associated with strategic asset allocation models. Traditional-asset allocation models partition the financial markets into neat benchmark boxes, perhaps useful for planning purposes but surely inhibitive for alpha extraction and return maximization.</description><author>Anson, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An alternative future</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asness, C.
Hedge funds are supposed to make money all the. time, and when they fail at this, their investors redeem and go to someone else who has recently been making money. Every three or four years they deliver a one in a hundred-year flood. They are generally unregulated and generally do not tell us what they do. Yet inflows to hedge funds from institutions and others have been off the charts for the last few years. Despite some definite dark sides to the industry that need to be recognized and then ameliorated, hedge funds are central to the future of investment management. A combination of hedge funds and traditional index funds has distinct advantages over typical traditional active management.</description><author>Asness, C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The active risk puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Litterman, R.
While almost all institutional investment funds take active risk, the amount is almost uniformly a tiny fraction of the market risk that they expose themselves to. Readily available financial engineering techniques today allow funds to separate market risk from active risk. Given the lack of correlation between the two, the optimal allocation to active risk is very sensitive to the net aggregate information ratio from active management. It makes no sense that this assumption should be virtually the same, around 0.04, for all funds. Some funds will focus on indexing to reduce costs. Others will seek to increase the amount and improve the quality of their active risk. If these developing trends continue, look for interesting implications for the asset management industry.</description><author>Litterman, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investing contingent capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Layard-Liesching, R.
Passive investment of capital will not serve to meet return goals for many pension funds, a reality that is fueling huge interest in new alpha activities. Alpha strategies appear to offer incremental return with the same capital invested, but an alpha strategy can add value only because fund capital is at risk, so alpha return, should be measured relative to the contingent capital placed at risk in order to obtain the return. This contingent capital framework can also be used to evaluate new alternatives such as insurance or credit derivatives. Based on extreme value theory, it provides an improved framework for efficient use of the fund's total risk budget.</description><author>Layard-Liesching, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reengineering investment management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kritzman, M.; Thomas, L. R.
The conventional approach to building portfolios of investments is inefficient.. Our usual hierarchy of investment decisions imposes constraints on active management that are under most circumstances unnecessary and produce mean-variance-inefficient portfolios. An approach to portfolio design based on the concept of alpha portability eliminates these harmful constraints; an analogous idea is beta portability. Numerical examples reveal that alpha independence and separation are necessary but insufficient conditions for mean-variance efficiency. These features must be combined with leverage to effect portability and achieve the best expected outcome.</description><author>Kritzman, M.; Thomas, L. R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A new framework for international investing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Olma, A. R.; Siegel, L. B.
Three interrelated issues in international investing are explored here. First, despite (or because of) years of underperformance, international equity investment strategies are very much worth pursuing. Second, high levels of active risk are not necessarily a winning strategy in international equities; an aversion to active risk is just as rational in international markets as it is domestically. Finally, when investment decisions that are naturally separate are in fact separated, the efficient frontier moves up and to the left-portfolio efficiency improves-because we use more of the information collected by the analyst. Thus, in international portfolios, the investment manager should make security, country, and currency decisions independently of one another, and arguably admit short as well as long positions.</description><author>Olma, A. R.; Siegel, L. B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Will history rhyme?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goetzmann, W. N.
History tells us that global capital markets can contract as well as expand-and a long-term view of finance suggests investors should prepare for periodic segmentation as well as integration of markets in the 21st century. Anti-capitalist ideologies have historically been the vectors of attack on the cross-border flow of capital, when the fundamental cause may really be domestic hostility toward foreign ownership and control, and the roots of the conflict between domestic interests and foreign investors may be inherent in global equilibrium models. In a frictionless capital market, foreigners will always own a higher proportion of a small economy's assets. By the same token, domestic investors in small economies will always seek to export most of their capital. This equilibrium is at odds with a stable condition of national ownership and control of assets.</description><author>Goetzmann, W. N.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The backward art of investing money</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Samuelson, P. A.
Each passing decade of new Wall Street experience, the statistical record shows, confirms rather than denies the verdict that few investors can beat the market. Yes, most investors and their advisors are irrationally inefficient, but this in no way guarantees investors can thereby profit from a micro-inefficient market. Economic history confirms that markets are much more macro-inefficient than they are micro-inefficient. Neither Wall Street nor its clients understand nuances of the time-horizon problem. And, if (when?) lobbyist-driven politics let us manage some of our own Social Security funds, the odds are a hundred-to-one that the retirement nest eggs we achieve will fall materially below what broad inexpensive indexing could deliver in terms of diversified risk-corrected total returns.</description><author>Samuelson, P. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The adaptive markets hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lo, A. W.
One of the most influential ideas in the past 30 years is the efficient markets hypothesis, the idea that market prices incorporate all information rationally and instantaneously. The emerging discipline of behavioral economics and finance has challenged the EMH, arguing that markets are not rational, but rather driven by fear and greed. Research in the cognitive neurosciences suggests these two perspectives are opposite sides of the same coin. An adaptive markets hypothesis that reconciles market efficiency with behavioral alternatives applies the principles of evolution-competition, adaptation, and natural selection-to financial interactions. Extending Simon's notion of "satisficing" with evolutionary dynamics, the author argues that much of what behaviorists cite as counter-examples to economic rationality-loss aversion, overconfidence, overreaction, mental accounting, and other behavioral biases-is in fact consistent with an evolutionary model of individual adaptation to a changing environment via simple heuristics. The adaptive markets hypothesis offers a number of surprisingly concrete implications for portfolio management.</description><author>Lo, A. W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Where have thirty years gone? A trap for logicians?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, P. L.
nan</description><author>Bernstein, P. L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Response to The hierarchy of investment choice: Comment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kritzman, M.; Page, S.
nan</description><author>Kritzman, M.; Page, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The hierarchy of investment choice: comment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Staub, R.
nan</description><author>Staub, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>History of the forecasters - Naive forecasts are better than the consensus WSJ forecast.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brooks, R.; Gray, J. B.
An analysis of semiannual Wall Street Journal long-term interest rate forecasts made since 1982 by a panel of distinguished economic experts shows that the consensus forecast of long-term U.S. Treasury bond yield changes is poor. A naive forecast is more accurate.</description><author>Brooks, R.; Gray, J. B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Different approaches to risk estimation in portfolio theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Biglova, A.; Ortobelli, S.; Rachev, S.; Stoyanov, S.
Some new performance measures may be regarded as alternatives to the most popular criterion for portfolio optimization, the Sharpe ratio. Analysis of some allocation problems here takes into consideration portfolio selection models based. on different risk perceptions and sample paths of the final wealth process for each allocation problem. One new performance ratio seems to be suitable for some optimization problems, but we need a thorough classification of the set of performance measures that would be ideal for large classes of financial optimization problems.</description><author>Biglova, A.; Ortobelli, S.; Rachev, S.; Stoyanov, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uncovering the trend-following strategy - To help currency managers.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pedersen, H. H.; de Zwart, G. J.
Trend-following strategies use past price performance in an attempt to predict future price performance. While widely applied in currency markets with a good track record for major currency pairs, the strategies do not apply universally. Under what conditions does trend-following work or fail to work? A new model created from simulations and later verified on G10 currency pairs assesses trend model profitability from the statistical features of the return distribution of the asset under consideration. The results and examples facilitate the selection of appropriate currencies or assets for inclusion in trend models going forward.</description><author>Pedersen, H. H.; de Zwart, G. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Homemade leverage - Theory versus experimental evidence.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, H.; Levy, M.; Alisof, N.
if investors are rational, firms and fund managers should not worry about the degree of their leverage or investment in the riskless asset-investors can always increase or reduce leverage by borrowing or lending themselves, thus creating their own so-called homemade leverage. The CAPM, the Sharpe ratio, and the Modigliani-Miller theory of capital structure rely on this idea. But are investors capable of effectively employing homemade leverage in their decision-making? When financial practitioners and management students are asked to choose one of several funds that they can mix with a risk-free asset, almost half of them fail to integrate the cash flows from the risky asset and the risk-free asset-and thus choose very inefficient portfolios. When they can choose from mixed funds, which perform the cash flow integration for the subjects, efficient choices are made 98% of the time. Clearly fund managers should carefully consider their funds' leverage; capital structure may influence firm values by virtue of a clientele effect.</description><author>Levy, H.; Levy, M.; Alisof, N.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The style drift score - A quantitative measure.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Idzorek, T. M.; Bertsch, F.
A quantitative measure of style drift measures the variability of a portfolios effective asset mix as determined by return-based style analysis around the portfolio's average effective asset mix. A style drift score eliminates examination of countless rolling-window asset allocation graphs and rolling-window style maps; it quantifies the style drift of a portfolio in a single statistic. A style drift score is ideal for screening thousands of portfolios, comparing the style consistency of portfolios, and monitoring drift in a portfolio's style.</description><author>Idzorek, T. M.; Bertsch, F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting core-satellite investing - A dynamic model of relative risk management.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amenc, N.; Malaise, P.; Martellini, L.
Tracking error is not necessarily bad. Good tracking error would be outperformance of a portfolio with respect. to the benchmark. If they severely restrict the amounts invested in active strategies as a result of tight tracking error constraints, investors foreclose the opportunity for significant outperformance, especially during market downturns. A new methodology based on an optimal dynamic adjustment of the fractions invested in a passive core versus an active satellite portfolio allows investors to gain full access to good tracking error, while keeping bad tracking error below a given threshold. The method is a natural extension of constant-proportion portfolio insurance techniques.</description><author>Amenc, N.; Malaise, P.; Martellini, L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Toward more information-efficient portfolios - Relaxing the long-only constraint.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clarke, R. G.; de Silva, H.; Sapra, S.
The long-only constraint imposed in traditional portfolios is one of the more severe constraints in terms of its impact on potential value-added, particularly for portfolios benchmarked to a capitalization-weighted benchmark such as the SP 500; it can reduce the effectiveness of the manager's information by 50% or more. This loss can be avoided to a great degree by eliminating the long-only constraint or by creating a market-neutral portfolio with a derivatives overlay to restore market exposure. The information ratio can also be increased considerably using only underlying securities by allowing modest short positions and using the cash generated to purchase an equivalent amount of long positions, thus maintaining full market exposure.</description><author>Clarke, R. G.; de Silva, H.; Sapra, S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liability-relative investing II - Surplus optimization with beta, alpha, and an economic view of the liability.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Waring, M. B.
Here is an update of the technology for calculating surplus efficient frontiers and surplus asset allocation that separately incorporates both systematic and unsystematic (or beta and alpha) characteristics, and yields an economic view of the liability. This measure of the liability is more relevant to the asset allocation problem than the standard approaches, enabling a better risk control system for pension plans by controlled hedging of the assets against the liability. The framework allows the inclusion of alpha and active risk from active management.</description><author>Waring, M. B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic leverage - A contingent claims approach to Leveragefor capital conservation.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Souza, C.; Smirnov, M.
Dynamic leverage as defined here depends on the level of hedge fund volatility, time horizon, and the difference between the fund's net asset value and its critical liquidation level. The critical liquidation level is the level of net asset value loss from which the fund manager could not recover and the fund would need to be liquidated to meet margin calls and redemptions. Dynamic leverage may be formalized very generally as a barrier option. At some intermediate critical level (above the liquidation level), efforts to reduce risk have little influence on the chance the fund will hit the critical liquidation level. A constant dynamic leverage portfolio insurance modifies the more traditional classic portfolio insurance.</description><author>De Souza, C.; Smirnov, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>