<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Management Science1</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Sharing Guilt: How Better Access to Information May Backfire</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Inderst, Roman; Khalmetski, Kiryl; Ockenfels, Axel
We study strategic communication between a customer and an advisor who is privately informed about the most suitable choice for the customer but whose preferences are misaligned with the customer's preferences. The advisor sends a message to the customer who, in turn, can secure herself from bad advice by acquiring costly information on her own. In our experiments, we find that making the customer's information acquisition less costly leads to less prosocial behavior of the advisor. This can be explained by a model of shared guilt, which predicts a shift in causal attribution of guilt from the advisor to the customer if the latter could have avoided her ex post disappointment. We conclude that providing better access to information through, for example, consumer protection regulation or digital information aggregation and dissemination, may have unintended negative consequences on peoples' willingness to take responsibility for each other.</description><author>Inderst, Roman; Khalmetski, Kiryl; Ockenfels, Axel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Market Evolution in Channel Contracting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Long; Mishra, Birendra K.
Real markets evolve over time. They often exhibit complex behaviors, such as autocorrelation, continuity, and nonstationarity. How do these behaviors affect channel contracting? We study the problem in a bilateral channel where the retailer has private information on evolving market conditions. We characterize the optimal contract under arbitrary market evolution. The central notion is market inertia: it prices retailer's information advantage, dictates price and quantity response over time, and determines the contract complexity. Using market inertia, we identify a general property-stochastic linearity-that justifies the use of simple contracts for a much larger class of channel conditions. For practitioners, we offer refined guidance: (i) when the market has linear dynamics, simple contracts are sufficient; (ii) when the market is continuous, the quantity distortion should be pervasive; and (iii) when the market is nonstationary, the distortion can vanish, intensify, stay constant, or even go nonmonotonic over time. By highlighting the central role of realistic market behaviors, this paper advances our understanding of channel theory and practice.</description><author>Gao, Long; Mishra, Birendra K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"Hello Jumbo!" The Spatio-Temporal Rollout and Traffic to a New Grocery Chain After Acquisition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Van Lin, Arjen; Gijsbrechts, Els
Grocery retailers increasingly use acquisitions to expand their presence. Such acquisitions are risky, especially when retailers decide to subsume the acquired stores under their own banner, which can take years and demands careful planning. We show how the dynamics of consumer valuations of the old and new banner affect the traffic implications of various (spatio-temporal) rollouts, and how this can be incorporated in the conversion planning. In a store-choice model with Bayesian learning, consumers update their perceptions about the old banner as its value deteriorates, and learn about the new banner through visits. Our model thus captures consumers' responses to store conversion over time, in function of the local presence of other (own and competitive) outlets and new-banner advertising. An application to the national rollout of a Dutch EDLP player after its acquisition of a HILO chain, analyzes the shopping patterns of about 1,500 households over four years, involving over 100 store conversions. Our findings show that (i) uncertainty about the new banner dampens traffic to converted stores initially, while (ii) value deterioration of the old banner jeopardizes traffic to stores converted late, and (iii) the magnitude of these effects strongly depends on local-market characteristics, that is, competition and access to other old-banner and new-banner stores. With simulations, we show that to attract and keep customers, (i) outlets in competitive markets should not always get precedence and (ii) in locations with multiple outlets, conversions are better separated. Retailers can use these demand-side effects to their benefit in planning the rollout.</description><author>Van Lin, Arjen; Gijsbrechts, Els</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tip Pricing of Jump Propagation: Evidence from Spot and Options Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Du, Du; Luo, Dan
This paper examines the joint time series of the S&amp;P 500 index and its options with a two-factor Hawkes jump-diffusion model that captures jump propagation (i.e., the phenomenon in which the strike of one jump substantially raises the probability for more to follow). The propagation effect uncovered from the joint data is severe but short lived. On average, this component takes up more than two-thirds of the total jump risks. Our jump specification proves crucial not only in reconciling the dynamics implied from the joint data, but also in explaining the time series of option-implied volatility skew.</description><author>Du, Du; Luo, Dan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Imperfect Renegotiations in Interbank Financial Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>David, Alexander; Lehar, Alfred
Interbank financial networks enable banks to share the risks in their assets but potentially also increase systemic spillovers of insolvency from one bank to others in the network. We model a renegotiation game to explicitly examine the forgiveness of commitments of insolvent banks by solvent banks to limit the systemic transmission of financial distress. The assets of the insolvent bank can be appropriated by the forgiving bank in the two-bank network, but not the three-bank network, where they may be appropriated by the third bank, leading to a renegotiation breakdown. We also show how banks can ex ante optimally construct networks from interbank loans and derivatives to minimize the costs of such inefficient financial distress.</description><author>David, Alexander; Lehar, Alfred</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Process Utility and the Effect of Inaction Frames</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Evangelidis, Ioannis; Levav, Jonathan
We introduce a new type of utility that we call "process utility," which pertains to individuals' preference about how they want to obtain an outcome. We posit that decision makers derive utility not only from the outcome itself, but also from the process through which that outcome is obtained. We focus on two normatively equivalent processes for obtaining an outcome: action and inaction. We argue that inducing differences in how outcomes are obtained can lead to significant preference reversals. We examine process utility in binary choice where one outcome is predominantly preferred over the other. We find that when the frequently selected ("advantaged") alternative is framed as an inaction, its choice share decreases, but that when the infrequently selected ("disadvantaged") alternative is framed as an inaction, its choice share increases. Finally, we discuss potential moderators of our effects.</description><author>Evangelidis, Ioannis; Levav, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Going for Gold: An Analysis of Morningstar Analyst Ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Armstrong, Will J.; Genc, Egemen; Verbeek, Marno
We investigate Morningstar's new qualitative, forward-looking analyst ratings, which reflect independent analysts' expectations of a fund's future performance. We find relatively higher flows to funds receiving higher ratings, suggesting that the average investor values the analyst's subjective views when allocating their wealth. Performance tests show that investors would have earned significantly higher returns over our sample period by investing in funds with the highest analyst conviction. These results suggest that independent research that expands the information set to include qualitative elements may help investors make better investment allocation decisions.</description><author>Armstrong, Will J.; Genc, Egemen; Verbeek, Marno</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extracting the Wisdom of Crowds When Information Is Shared</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Palley, Asa B.; Soll, Jack B.
Using the wisdom of crowds-combining many individual judgments to obtain an aggregate estimate-can be an effective technique for improving judgment accuracy. In practice, however, accuracy is limited by the presence of correlated judgment errors, which often emerge because information is shared. To address this problem, we propose an elicitation procedure in which respondents are asked to provide both their own best judgment and an estimate of the average judgment that will be given by all other respondents. We develop an aggregation method, called pivoting, which separates individual judgments into shared and private information and then recombines these results in the optimal manner. In several studies, we investigate the method and examine the accuracy of the aggregate estimates. Overall, the empirical data suggest that the pivoting method provides an effective judgment aggregation procedure that can significantly outperform the simple crowd average.</description><author>Palley, Asa B.; Soll, Jack B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Choice Architecture, Framing, and Cascaded Privacy Choices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adjerid, Idris; Acquisti, Alessandro; Loewenstein, George
For consumers, managing privacy online requires navigating a complex process of interrelated choices. This process may be conceived of as "cascaded," in that a combination of upstream choices (e.g., of privacy settings on a social network site) and downstream choices (e.g., of what to reveal on the site) together determine ultimate privacy outcomes. In a series of experiments, we examine the potential impact of choice architecture in cascaded privacy choice settings. We investigate how changes in choice frames implemented by service providers can influence consumers' upstream disclosure settings, often in ways that they are unaware of and that may be destructive to them. Whether the effects of choice frames upstream are ultimately detrimental to individuals' privacy, however, depends on whether they are offset by more or less protective downstream choices. Thus, we also examine whether such upstream effects of choice architecture are "mitigated" through changes in downstream self-disclosure. We find, first, that various manipulations of decision frames, common in privacy contexts, significantly impact participants' upstream choice of disclosure settings. Second, we do not find evidence that the impact of choice architecture upstream is mitigated downstream: participants' self-disclosure rates do not adjust or change in response to choice architecture-induced changes in upstream choices. These findings call into question both policy makers' and industry advocates' reliance on choice-based privacy protection mechanisms, contribute to an emerging behavioral perspective on privacy decision making, and highlight the importance of accounting for the cascaded nature of privacy decision making in both policy and managerial settings.</description><author>Adjerid, Idris; Acquisti, Alessandro; Loewenstein, George</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Financial Reporting Quality on Corporate Investment Efficiency: Evidence from the Adoption of SFAS No. 123R</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dou, Yiwei; Wong, M. H. Franco; Xin, Baohua
We test for changes in investment efficiency around a shock to financial reporting quality-the adoption of SFAS No. 123R, which requires that employee stock option (ESO) costs be recognized rather than disclosed at fair value. We predict and find a reduction in underinvestment for firms heavily affected by the new standard, and these firms exhibit a decrease in the bid-ask spread and an increase in new capital raised in the post-SFAS No. 123R period. The reduction in underinvestment is more pronounced for firms whose ESO estimates are more unreliable before SFAS No. 123R, for firms that are financially constrained, and for firms with more entrenched managers. These findings are consistent with recognition of ESO costs at fair value improving financial reporting quality, which, in turn, enhances investment efficiency through the mitigation of the adverse selection problem for underinvesting firms.</description><author>Dou, Yiwei; Wong, M. H. Franco; Xin, Baohua</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Referral Priority Program: Leveraging Social Ties via Operational Incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Luyi; Debo, Laurens
The referral priority program-an emerging business practice adopted by a growing number of technology companies that manage a waitlist of customers-enables existing customers on the waitlist to gain priority access if they successfully refer new customers to the waitlist. Unlike more commonly used referral reward programs, this novel mechanism does not offer monetary compensation to referring customers, but leverages customers' own disutility of delays to create referral incentives. Despite this appealing feature, our queueing-game-theoretic analysis finds that the effectiveness of such a scheme as a marketing tool for customer acquisition and an operational approach for waitlist management depends crucially on the underlying market conditions, particularly the base market size of spontaneous customers. The referral priority program does not generate referrals when the base market size is either too large or too small. When customers do refer, the program could actually backfire-namely, by reducing the system throughput and customer welfare-if the base market size is intermediately large. This phenomenon occurs because the presence of referred customers severely cannibalizes the demand of spontaneous customers. We also compare the referral priority program with the referral reward program when the service provider optimally sets the admission price. Numerical study suggests that the referral priority program is more profitable than the referral reward program when the base market size is intermediately small.</description><author>Yang, Luyi; Debo, Laurens</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sunk Cost as a Self-Management Device</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Fuhai; Huang, Wei; Zhao, Xiaojian
The sunk cost effect has been widely observed in individual decisions. Building on an intrapersonal self-management game, the paper theoretically shows that the sunk cost effect may stem from an attempt to overcome the underinvestment problem associated with a high degree of present bias or to resolve the multi-selves coordination problem when the degree of present bias is low. Especially for individuals with severe present bias, the current self may take a costly action (which is a sunk cost for the future self) to signal the individual's high success probability that motivates his future self-disciplining behaviors. In equilibrium, a higher level of sunk cost is more likely to give rise to a higher probability for the individual to continue the project. We then conduct a laboratory experiment. The empirical findings are consistent with our theoretical implications.</description><author>Hong, Fuhai; Huang, Wei; Zhao, Xiaojian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Limit of Rationality in Choice Modeling: Formulation, Computation, and Implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jagabathula, Srikanth; Rusmevichientong, Paat
Customer preferences may not be rational, so we focus on quantifying the limit of rationality (LoR) in choice modeling applications. We define LoR as the cost of approximating the observed choice fractions from a collection of offer sets with those from the best-fitting probability distribution over rankings. Computing LoR is intractable in the worst case. To deal with this challenge, we introduce two new concepts, rational separation and choice graph, through which we reduce the problem to solving a dynamic program on the choice graph and express the computational complexity in terms of the structural properties of the graph. By exploiting the graph structure, we provide practical methods to compute LoR efficiently for a large class of applications. We apply our methods to real-world grocery sales data and identify product categories for which going beyond rational choice models is necessary to obtain an acceptable performance.</description><author>Jagabathula, Srikanth; Rusmevichientong, Paat</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Markdown as a Pricing Modality?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adida, Elodie; Ozer, Ozalp
Markdown as a pricing modality is ubiquitous in retail whereas everyday low price (EDLP) remains relatively rare (despite its several advantages, such as simplicity). This paper explores whether and why retailers can use either of these pricing modalities as an effective defense against a competitor entering the market with the alternative pricing modality. Various studies have shown that consumers are strategic and heterogeneous in their valuation of a product. Consumers are also shown to be regret-prone, and anticipation of regret affects their purchase decisions. Consumers experience availability regret when they are unable to purchase products due to stockouts and high-price regret when they miss an opportunity to purchase products at low prices. Considering such factors, consumers decide whether, when, and from which retailer to purchase the product. In such a market environment, we find that the possible entry of a competitor should deter retailers from using the EDLP pricing modality but not markdown. We also identify a new reason for the markdown retailer to ration stock (in addition to the reason for discouraging consumers to wait for the markdown). In particular, we show that the markdown retailer can use inventory rationing to preclude a cutthroat competition and bankruptcy after the entry of an EDLP retailer. We also quantify how consumer regret affects both retailers' decisions and resulting profits. In particular, in a competitive market, the EDLP retailer cannot simply disregard consumers' availability and high-price regret (even when it stocks ample inventory and does not discount prices). We show that high-price regret and availability regret have complementary effects on the markdown retailer's rationing strategy and the EDLP retailer's price decision. Finally, using a proprietary price data set from a large department store, we show that ignoring regret factors causes the markdown retailer to leave up to 20% of its profits on the table. In addition, in a competitive market, the markdown retailer rations too aggressively when regret is ignored and, as a result, leaves some of the forgone profit to its competitor-the EDLP retailer. The retail industry is often characterized by its slim profit margins. In such an environment, the aforementioned results also suggest that retailers should seriously consider investing in developing the capacity to estimate and quantify the role of regret in consumers' purchase decisions.</description><author>Adida, Elodie; Ozer, Ozalp</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Population Monotonicity in Newsvendor Games</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Xin; Gao, Xiangyu; Hu, Zhenyu; Wang, Qiong
A newsvendor game allows the players to collaborate on inventory pooling and share the resulting total cost. There are several possible ways to allocate the cost. Previous studies have focused on the core of the game. It is known that the core of the newsvendor game is nonempty, and one can use duality theory in stochastic programming to construct an allocation-referred to as the dual-based allocation-belonging to the core. Yet, an allocation that lies in the core does not necessarily guarantee the unhindered formation of a coalition, as some existing members' allocated costs may increase when new members are added in the process. In this work, we use the concept of population monotonic allocation scheme (PMAS), which requires the cost allocated to every member of a coalition to decrease as the coalition grows, to study allocation schemes in a growing population. We show that when the demands faced by the newsvendors are independent, log-concavity of their distributions is sufficient to guarantee the existence of a PMAS. Specifically, for continuous demands, log-concavity ensures that the game is convex, which in turn implies a PMAS exists. We also show that under the same condition the dual-based allocation scheme is a PMAS. For discrete and log-concave demands, however, the game may no longer be convex, but we manage to show that, even so, the dual-based allocation scheme is a PMAS. When the demands are dependent, the game is in general not convex. We derive a sufficient condition based on the dependence structure, measured by the copula, to ensure that the dual-based allocation scheme is still a PMAS. We also include an example of a game with no PMAS.</description><author>Chen, Xin; Gao, Xiangyu; Hu, Zhenyu; Wang, Qiong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Implications of Credit Risk Modeling for Banks' Loan Loss Provisions and Loan-Origination Procyclicality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhat, Gauri; Ryan, Stephen G.; Vyas, Dushyantkumar
Economic policymakers express concern that procyclical lending by banks imperils financial stability. Prior research finds that banks that record timelier loan loss provisions originate more loans during downturns, consistent with loan loss-provision timeliness mitigating loan-origination procyclicality. Motivated by this concern and research, we examine whether banks' credit risk modeling disciplines both their loan loss provisions and loan origination. We identify two forms of credit risk modeling from banks' financial report disclosures: statistical modeling of the drivers of past loan losses and stress testing of future loan losses to adverse scenarios. We show that banks' credit risk-modeling disclosures are positively associated with their loan loss-provision timeliness, with the ability of their provisions to predict future loan charge-offs, and with their loan origination during downturns. We further show that these associations vary in predictable ways across the two forms of credit risk modeling when we distinguish homogeneous from heterogeneous loans and stable periods from downturns.</description><author>Bhat, Gauri; Ryan, Stephen G.; Vyas, Dushyantkumar</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Dynamic Clustering Approach to Data-Driven Assortment Personalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Fernando; Modaresi, Sajad; Saure, Denis
We consider an online retailer facing heterogeneous customers with initially unknown product preferences. Customers are characterized by a diverse set of demographic and transactional attributes. The retailer can personalize the customers' assortment offerings based on available profile information to maximize cumulative revenue. To that end, the retailer must estimate customer preferences by observing transaction data. This, however, may require a considerable amount of data and time given the broad range of customer profiles and large number of products available. At the same time, the retailer can aggregate (pool) purchasing information among customers with similar product preferences to expedite the learning process. We propose a dynamic clustering policy that estimates customer preferences by adaptively adjusting customer segments (clusters of customers with similar preferences) as more transaction information becomes available. We test the proposed approach with a case study based on a data set from a large Chilean retailer. The case study suggests that the benefits of the dynamic clustering policy under the MNL model can be substantial and result (on average) in more than 37% additional transactions compared to a data-intensive policy that treats customers independently and in more than 27% additional transactions compared to a linear-utility policy that assumes that product mean utilities are linear functions of available customer attributes. We support the insights derived from the numerical experiments by analytically characterizing settings in which pooling transaction information is beneficial for the retailer, in a simplified version of the problem. We also show that there are diminishing marginal returns to pooling information from an increasing number of customers.</description><author>Bernstein, Fernando; Modaresi, Sajad; Saure, Denis</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The More You Know: Information Effects on Job Application Rates in a Large Field Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gee, Laura K.
This paper presents the results from a 2.3-million-person field experiment that varies whether or not a job seeker sees the number of applicants for a job posting on a large job-posting website, LinkedIn. This intervention increases the likelihood that a person will finish an application by 3.5%. Women have a larger increase in their likelihood of finishing an application than men. Overall, adding this information to a job posting may offer a light-touch way to both increase application rates and alter the diversity of the applicant pool.</description><author>Gee, Laura K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crop Planning in Sustainable Agriculture: Dynamic Farmland Allocation in the Presence of Crop Rotation Benefits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyabatli, Onur; Nasiry, Javad; Zhou, Yangfang
This paper examines crop planning decisions in sustainable agriculture-that is, how to allocate farmland among multiple crops in each growing season when the crops have rotation benefits across growing seasons. We consider a farmer who periodically allocates the farmland between two crops in the presence of revenue uncertainty where revenue is stochastically larger and farming cost is lower when a crop is grown on rotated farmland (where the other crop was grown in the previous season). We characterize the optimal dynamic farmland allocation policy and perform sensitivity analysis to investigate how revenue uncertainty of each crop affects the farmer's optimal allocation decision and profitability. Using a calibration based on a farmer growing corn and soybeans in Iowa, we show that growing only one crop over the entire planning horizon, as employed in industrial agriculture, leads to a considerable profit loss-that is, crop planning based on principles of sustainable agriculture has substantial value. We propose a simple heuristic allocation policy, which we characterize in closed form. Using our model calibration, we show that (i) the proposed policy not only outperforms the commonly suggested heuristic policies in the literature, but also provides a near-optimal performance and (ii) compared with the optimal policy, the proposed policy has a higher allocation of crops to rotated farmland, and thus, it is potentially more environmentally friendly.</description><author>Boyabatli, Onur; Nasiry, Javad; Zhou, Yangfang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Saving Patient Ryan-Can Advanced Electronic Medical Records Make Patient Care Safer?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hydari, Muhammad Zia; Telang, Rahul; Marella, William M.
The risk of patient harm resulting from medical care affects hundreds of thousands of patients and costs tens of billions of dollars every year. Advanced electronic medical records (EMRs) are expected to improve patient safety, but the evidence of their impact on patient safety is inconclusive. A key challenge to evaluating advanced EMRs' impact has been the lack of reliable patient safety data. We address this issue by analyzing a new patient safety data set from the Pennsylvania Patient Safety Authority (PSA), a state agency that aggregates patient safety data from Pennsylvania hospitals. Using a 2005-2014 panel from PSA, we identify advanced EMRs' effect using the difference-indifferences method. We find that advanced EMRs lead to a 17.5% decline in patient safety events, driven by reductions in medication errors, falls, and complication errors. Further, our analysis shows a decline in medium- and high-severity events.</description><author>Hydari, Muhammad Zia; Telang, Rahul; Marella, William M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Portfolio Execution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tsoukalas, Gerry; Wang, Jiang; Giesecke, Kay
We analyze the optimal execution problem of a portfolio manager trading multiple assets. In addition to the liquidity and risk of each individual asset, we consider cross asset interactions in these two dimensions, which substantially enriches the nature of the problem. Focusing on the market microstructure, we develop a tractable order book model to capture liquidity supply/demand dynamics in a multiasset setting, which allows us to formulate and solve the optimal portfolio execution problem. We find that cross asset risk and liquidity considerations are of critical importance in constructing the optimal execution policy. We show that even when the goal is to trade a single asset, its optimal execution may involve transitory trades in other assets. In general, optimally managing the risk of the portfolio during the execution process affects the time synchronization of trading in different assets. Moreover, links in the liquidity across assets lead to complex patterns in the optimal execution policy. In particular, we highlight cases where aggregate costs can be reduced by temporarily "overshooting" one's target portfolio.</description><author>Tsoukalas, Gerry; Wang, Jiang; Giesecke, Kay</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Your Uber Is Arriving: Pillaging On-Demand Workers Through Surge Pricing, Forecast Communication, and Worker Incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guda, Harish; Subramanian, Upender
On-demand platforms (e.g., Uber, Lyft) often rely on independent workers, who are not directly under the platform's control, to be available at the "right" time and locations to serve consumers at short notice. To manage fluctuating demand across market locations (zones), on-demand platforms share market forecasts with workers to inform them where they should be available, and use surge pricing-wherein the price at a particular zone is temporarily raised above the regular price. We analyze these platform strategies in an on-demand marketplace where independent workers can move between adjacent zones, explicitly accounting for the strategic interaction in their moving decisions. We show that, contrary to conventional wisdom, surge pricing can be useful even in zones where supply exceeds demand. Specifically, because workers are strategic agents facing costs to move and competition from other workers who move, simply informing workers where they should be available may not ensure that enough workers move to that zone. Interestingly, more workers can be made to move from a zone with excess supply of workers by strategically using a surge price to throttle demand in that zone. Such strategic surge pricing can increase total platform profit across zones, and even be more profitable than offering workers bonuses to move. Surge pricing in a zone with excess supply can also be useful to credibly communicate the need for more workers to move. In other instances, such surge pricing may be useful to avoid too many workers from moving. Our analysis offers insights for effectively managing on-demand service with independent workers.</description><author>Guda, Harish; Subramanian, Upender</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Delay Announcements on Hospital Network Coordination and Waiting Times</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dong, Jing; Yom-Tov, Elad; Yom-Tov, Galit B.
We investigate the impact of delay announcements on the coordination within hospital networks using a combination of empirical observations and numerical experiments. We offer empirical evidence that suggests that patients take delay information into account when choosing emergency service providers and that such information can help increase coordination in the network, leading to improvements in the performance of the network, as measured by emergency department wait times. Our numerical results indicate that the level of coordination that can be achieved is limited by the patients' sensitivity to waiting, the load of the system, the heterogeneity among hospitals, and, importantly, the method hospitals use to estimate delays. We show that delay estimators that are based on historical averages may cause oscillation in the system and lead to higher average wait times when patients are sensitive to delay. We provide empirical evidence that suggests that such oscillations occur in hospital networks in the United States.</description><author>Dong, Jing; Yom-Tov, Elad; Yom-Tov, Galit B.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disclosure of Pending Lawsuits and Bond Terms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lou, Yun
I examine the effect of the disclosure of pending lawsuits in 10-K/Q filings on the contractual terms of newly issued bonds. I find that firms' decisions to disclose pending lawsuits and the amount of disclosed information (i.e., the level of disclosure) have opposite effects. Specifically, firms that disclose a higher proportion of their pending lawsuits face higher yields and are more likely to include default clauses pertaining to court judgments in the bond prospectuses. However, within the subsample of firms that disclose their lawsuits, I find that firms with a higher level of disclosure regarding their pending lawsuits are rewarded with lower yields. This evidence suggests that bond investors interpret the decision to disclose pending lawsuits as a sign that the potential losses due to these lawsuits are material and reasonably possible and thus demand more stringent bond terms. However, bond investors associate a higher level of disclosure with a lower likelihood of withholding bad news and thus accept lower yields.</description><author>Lou, Yun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulation and Market Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Trebbi, Francesco; Xiao, Kairong
We examine the effects of postcrisis financial regulation, encompassing the Dodd-Frank Act and Basel III, on market liquidity of the U.S. fixed-income market. We estimate structural breaks in a large panel of liquidity measures of corporate and Treasury bonds. Our methodology does not require a priori knowledge of the timing of breaks, can capture not only sudden jumps but also breaks in slow-moving trends, and displays excellent power properties. Against the popular claim that postcrisis regulation hurt liquidity, we find no evidence of liquidity deterioration during periods of regulatory intervention. Instead, breaks toward higher liquidity are often detected.</description><author>Trebbi, Francesco; Xiao, Kairong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Analysis of search and Authentication Strategies for Online Matching Platforms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basu, Amit; Bhaskaran, Sreekumar; Mukherjee, Rajiv
Compared to offline matching markets, online matching platforms improve search in the matching process but at the same time increase the problem of authenticating the features and credentials of prospective matches. This paper examines the interplay between these two processes in online matching, using game-theoretic models. We examine whether an online matching platform should target a broad market of match-seekers or an exclusive group of high-value match-seekers, and how the platform should price its search and authentication services. Our results provide valuable insights for online matching platforms regarding the decision to offer authentication services in addition to search services, and guidelines for the pricing and positioning of these services. For instance, we show that the complementarity of the platform's optimal pricing for search and authentication services can justify the platform's offering an authentication service as a loss leader, and that higher-quality authentication services may not always justify higher authentication fees. We also develop guidelines for the platform's optimal strategies for different market conditions.</description><author>Basu, Amit; Bhaskaran, Sreekumar; Mukherjee, Rajiv</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Drivers of Product Expiration in Consumer Packaged Goods Retailing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akkas, Arzum; Gaur, Vishal; Simchi-Levi, David
Product expiration is an important problem in the consumer packaged goods (CPG) industry costing 1%-2% of gross retail sales and eroding industry profits substantially. It can be caused by several factors related to store operations, supply chain practices, and product characteristics. Existing methods used in the industry are inadequate to identify the causes of expiration, leading to inadequate efforts to reduce expiration. Using retail data for 768 SKUs and 10,000 stores (745,638 store-SKU-level observations), as well as upstream supply chain data from a CPG manufacturer, we show the extent to which expiration of products in retail stores is driven by case size, inventory aging in the supply chain, minimum order rules, manufacturers' incentive programs for the sales force, replenishment workload, and many control variables. A counterfactual analysis based on the model shows that our subject manufacturer can reduce expiration by up to $38.82 million per year by implementing four selected initiatives involving case size, supply chain aging, minimum order rules, and sales incentives. Further, targeted initiatives can be designed using combinations of these variables for subsets of products with the highest occurrence of expiration.</description><author>Akkas, Arzum; Gaur, Vishal; Simchi-Levi, David</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comment on "Naivete, Projection Bias, and Habit Formation in Gym Attendance"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marz, Oliver
I show that a central result in Acland and Levy [Acland D, Levy MR (2015) Naivete, projection bias, and habit formation in gym attendance. Management Sci. 61(1):146-160] is based on erroneously reported statistical estimates. In an experimental study, the authors provide financial incentives for regular attendance at a gym and report that these incentives induce a habit formation effect, resulting in sustained increased gym attendance after incentives are removed. This habit formation effect is not predicted by participants ex ante. The correct statistical estimates, however, do not confirm a habit formation effect. Participants' ex ante expectations are thus correct in that they do not predict a habit formation effect, as there is none.</description><author>Marz, Oliver</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Winners, Losers, and Facebook: The Role of Social Logins in the Online Advertising Ecosystem</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kraemer, Jan; Schnurr, Daniel; Wohlfarth, Michael
Social logins, such as "Log in with Facebook," improve a website's user experience and therefore enjoy great popularity among content providers (CPs) and users alike. Moreover, they also enable the social network and the CPs to share data, which individually improves their ability to place targeted advertising. On the basis of a game-theoretic model that offers a microfoundation for CPs' competition for advertisements, on the one hand, and CPs' competition for users, on the other hand, we demonstrate the strategic effects of social logins in the online advertising ecosystem. We fully characterize the market conditions under which social logins are offered and adopted, and when the adoption is actually profitable for the CPs. In particular, we show across several model extensions that the voluntary adoption of the social login may yield a prisoner's dilemma outcome for the CPs.</description><author>Kraemer, Jan; Schnurr, Daniel; Wohlfarth, Michael</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IT Investment Under Competition: The Role of Implementation Failure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xin, Mingdi; Choudhary, Vidyanand
How does competition impact firms' incentive to innovate by investing in information technology (IT)? Prior literature suggests opposite predictions on the direction in which competition drives IT investment. This paper analyzes a game theoretic model of duopoly competition and shows that an important feature of IT sheds new light on firms' investment decisions: IT implementation can fail. Without the possibility of implementation failure, the opportunity to invest in IT hurts firms' profits because the productivity gains are competed away. Implementation failure creates a possibility of cost-based differentiation and mitigates competition, although these two effects can drive firms' IT investment in opposite directions. Interestingly, a higher probability of implementation failure can lead to lower investment risks and higher expected profits. Firms in highly competitive markets are better able to recoup the returns to their IT investments and, therefore, more motivated to invest in risky IT than firms in less competitive markets.</description><author>Xin, Mingdi; Choudhary, Vidyanand</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cardinality Bundling with Spence-Mirrlees Reservation Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Jianqing; Tawarmalani, Mohit; Kannan, Karthik N.
We study the pricing of cardinality bundles, where firms set prices that depend only on the size of the purchased bundle, a practice that is increasingly being adopted by industry. The model we study, where consumer choices are discrete, was originally proposed by Hitt and Chen [Hitt L, Chen P (2005) Bundling with customer self-selection: A simple approach to bundling low-marginal-cost goods. Management Sci. 51 (10):1481-1493], and it requires that consumers' preferences obey the Spence-Mirrlees single-crossing property. We correct prior approaches and develop various structural and managerial insights. We develop a fast combinatorial technique to obtain the optimal prices. We extend our analysis to address a quantity discount problem originally proposed in Spence [Spence M (1980) Multi-product quantity-dependent prices and profitability constraints. Rev. Econom. Stud. 47(5):821-841]. We provide examples that demonstrate that the proposed approach of Spence (1980) only identifies local optima without providing guidance on selecting the globally optimal pricing function. Our insights from the discrete model are extended to this context to develop a scheme that provides solutions within an arbitrary prespecified tolerance. Consequently, we also solve the continuous version of the cardinality bundling problem.</description><author>Wu, Jianqing; Tawarmalani, Mohit; Kannan, Karthik N.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Unstructured Bargaining with Private Information: Theory, Experiment, and Outcome Prediction via Machine Learning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Camerer, Colin F.; Nave, Gideon; Smith, Alec
We study dynamic unstructured bargaining with deadlines and one-sided private information about the amount available to share (the "pie size"). Using mechanism design theory, we show that given the players' incentives, the equilibrium incidence of bargaining failures ("strikes") should increase with the pie size, and we derive a condition under which strikes are efficient. In our setting, no equilibrium satisfies both equality and efficiency in all pie sizes. We derive two equilibria that resolve the trade-off between equality and efficiency by favoring either equality or efficiency. Using a novel experimental paradigm, we confirm that strike incidence is decreasing in the pie size. Subjects reach equal splits in small pie games (in which strikes are efficient), while most payoffs are close to either the efficient or the equal equilibrium prediction, when the pie is large. We employ a machine learning approach to show that bargaining process features recorded early in the game improve out-of-sample prediction of disagreements at the deadline. The process feature predictions are as accurate as predictions from pie sizes only, and adding process and pie data together improves predictions even more.</description><author>Camerer, Colin F.; Nave, Gideon; Smith, Alec</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Norm Uncertainty and Voluntary Payments in the Field</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feldhaus, Christoph; Sobotta, Tassilo; Werner, Peter
We investigate behavioral reactions toward exogenous changes of implicit norm-relevant information in a natural field setting where customers are free to choose if and how much to pay for a service. Customers' voluntary payments are significantly affected by subtle information cues: cues that signal a high rather than a low payment norm increase payments by some 27%. Consistent with the conjecture that this effect is in large part driven by customers' uncertainty about the actual norm, responses are mitigated when explicit norm-relevant information is provided. Additional treatments suggest that the reactions to the cues are not driven by mere saliency but by the information deduced from the cues in the presence of uncertainty.</description><author>Feldhaus, Christoph; Sobotta, Tassilo; Werner, Peter</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do People Volunteer? An Experimental Analysis of Preferences for Time Donations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Alexander L.; Meer, Jonathan; Williams, J. Forrest
Why do individuals volunteer their time even when recipients receive far less value than the donor's opportunity cost? Previous models of altruism that focus on the overall impact of a gift cannot rationalize this behavior, despite its prevalence. We develop a model that allows for differential warm glow depending on the form of the donation. In a series of laboratory experiments that control for other aspects of volunteering, such as its signaling value, subjects demonstrate behavior consistent with the theoretical assumption that gifts of time produce greater utility than the same transfers in the form of money. Subjects perform an effort task, accruing earnings at potentially different wage rates for themselves or a charity of their choice, with the ability to transfer any of their personal earnings to charity at the end of the experiment. Subjects exhibit strong preferences for donating time even when differential wage rates make it costly to do so. The results provide new insights on the nature of volunteering and gift giving.</description><author>Brown, Alexander L.; Meer, Jonathan; Williams, J. Forrest</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Pay Activism Pay Off for Shareholders? Shareholder Democracy and Its Discontents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dasgupta, Sudipto; Noe, Thomas H.
Typically, shareholders are not sure whether boards act in their interest or have been captured by management. They are also less well informed than boards about firm investment opportunities and operating conditions. We develop a model, consistent with these observations, in which discretionary compensation payments to managers might increase firm value or might simply enrich managers at the expense of shareholders. After observing the board's compensation and investment policies, shareholders use Bayes's rule to update the probability that the board is captured. Shareholders are "outraged" if this updated probability is sufficiently large. Outrage is costly for the board. Shareholder democracy, by enabling outrage to constrain board actions, typically lowers firm value relative to either governance regimes that insulate boards from shareholder outrage or regimes that ban discretionary compensation altogether.</description><author>Dasgupta, Sudipto; Noe, Thomas H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Direct Test of Agency Theories of Debt: Evidence from Residential Mortgage-Backed Securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Yilin; Nadauld, Taylor D.
When a firm is facing default, equity holders have incentives to engage in asset substitution, underinvest, or directly transfer wealth. Few papers document investment distortions on account of debt-equity agency conflicts, only that the threat of distortions influence ex ante financing costs. A nonagency residential mortgage-backed security deal represents an entity that is highly leveraged where, ex ante, equity holders know they will face default. This provides an ideal laboratory for testing whether the threat of default creates any of the distortions predicted in theory. We estimate a lower bound on agency costs associated with direct wealth transfers to be in the range of $.018 per dollar.</description><author>Huang, Yilin; Nadauld, Taylor D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Failure-Aware Kidney Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dickerson, John P.; Procaccia, Ariel D.; Sandholm, Tuomas
Algorithmic matches in fielded kidney exchanges do not typically result in an actual transplant. We address the problem of cycles and chains in proposed matches failing after the matching algorithm has committed to them. We show that failure-aware kidney exchange can significantly increase the expected number of lives saved (i) in theory, on random graph models; (ii) on real data from kidney exchange match runs between 2010 and 2014; and (iii) on synthetic data generated via a model of dynamic kidney exchange. This gain is robust to uncertainty over the true underlying failure rate. We design a branchand-price-based optimal clearing algorithm specifically for the probabilistic exchange clearing problem and show that this new solver scales well on large simulated data, unlike prior clearing algorithms. Finally, we show that failure-aware matching can increase overall system efficiency and simultaneously increase the expected number of transplants to highly sensitized patients, in both static and dynamic models.</description><author>Dickerson, John P.; Procaccia, Ariel D.; Sandholm, Tuomas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Implications of Visibility on the Use of Strategic Inventory in a Supply Chain</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roy, Abhishek; Gilbert, Stephen M.; Lai, Guoming
It is now widely accepted that a retailer's use of strategic inventory can mitigate double marginalization and improve the coordination of a supply chain, potentially benefiting both the downstream retailer and an upstream manufacturer. However, this conclusion has typically been based on the assumption that the manufacturer can observe the retailer's level of inventory before making wholesale pricing decisions. In reality, there are many situations in which neither the retailer's sales nor inventory are observable to the manufacturer, effectively concealing the action taken by the retailer. We investigate the implications of such a lack of observability on the use of strategic inventory in a supply chain consisting of a single retailer and a single manufacturer. We find that the manufacturer's inability to observe inventory has significant implications for the amount of inventory and the range of holding cost for which it is held in equilibrium. In addition, we find that, in the absence of any form of uncertainty, which the manufacturer could benefit from responding to, he may prefer not to observe the retailer's inventory. On the other hand, the retailer's willingness to make her inventory visible depends on the holding cost.</description><author>Roy, Abhishek; Gilbert, Stephen M.; Lai, Guoming</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing by Competitors in Enforcement of Product Standards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Plambeck, Erica L.; Taylor, Terry A.
Firms have an incentive to test competitors' products to reveal violations of safety and environmental standards, in order to have competitors' products blocked from sale. This paper shows that testing by a regulator crowds out testing by competitors, and can reduce firms' efforts to comply with the product standard. Relying on competitor testing (i.e., having the regulator test only to verify evidence of violations provided by competitors) is most effective in large or concentrated markets in which firms have strong brands and high quality, and for standards that are highly valued by consumers. Under those conditions, firms tend to test competitors' products and exert high compliance effort. Conversely, unless compliance is highly valued by consumers, a firm with low quality does not draw testing from competitors, and so does not comply. Enforcing a product standard through competitor testing encourages entry by such low-quality, noncompliant firms and can reduce quality investment by incumbents. Stripping offending products of labels (such as "Energy Star"), instead of blocking them from the market, eliminates the problem of entry by low-quality, noncompliant firms, but may reduce incumbents' compliance efforts.</description><author>Plambeck, Erica L.; Taylor, Terry A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>It Is Time to Get Some Rest</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baucells, Manel; Zhao, Lin
We introduce the fatigue disutility model. Set in continuous time, the model formalizes the notion that fatigue accumulates with effort, decays with rest, and produces an increase in marginal instant disutility. The model is meant to be prescriptive, although it rationalizes several anomalies observed in time preference. Under very general conditions, the most efficient temporal profile of effort exhibits a high-low-high pattern. We consider a variant whereby marginal productivity decreases with fatigue, and we examine the optimal management of fatigue and productivity under various scenarios. We also reexamine the beneficial role of breaks in reducing fatigue. We bring the model to the data and provide a calibration that favorably predicts the speed profiles observed in swimming competitions.</description><author>Baucells, Manel; Zhao, Lin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring Decreasing and Increasing Impatience</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rohde, Kirsten I. M.
Many studies show that time preference data from experiments and surveys are related to field behavior. Time preference measures in these studies typically depend simultaneously on utility curvature, the level of impatience, and the change in the level of impatience. Thus, these studies do not allow one to establish which of these three components drivels) the field behavior of interest. Of these components, the change in the level of impatience is theoretically thought to be the main driver of time inconsistencies and self-control problems. To test this theoretical presumption, one has to measure the change in the level of impatience independently from utilities and levels of impatience. This paper introduces a measure of the degree of decreasing impatience, the DI-index. It measures the change of impatience independently from the level of impatience and independently from utility. It can also be used to test various discounting models. An experiment finds no correlation between the degree of decreasing impatience and self-reported self-control problems in daily life, suggesting that changing impatience is not the sole driver of self-control problems.</description><author>Rohde, Kirsten I. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility Uncertainty, Time Decay, and Option Bid-Ask Spreads in an Incomplete Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hsieh, PeiLin; Jarrow, Robert
This paper documents the fact that in options markets, the (percentage) implied volatility bid-ask spread increases at an increasing rate as the option's maturity date approaches. To explain this stylized fact, this paper provides a market microstructure model for the bid-ask spread in options markets. We first construct a static equilibrium model to illustrate the aforementioned phenomenon where risk averse and competitive option market makers quote bid and ask prices to minimize their inventory risk in an incomplete market with both directional and volatility risk. We extend this model to multiperiods and show that the same phenomenon occurs there as well. Two new implications are generated: a volatility level effect and a volatility variance effect. These implications are empirically tested, and the empirical results confirm the model's validity. Finally, we document the importance of detrending the maturity effect by showing that the detrended percentage volatility spread explains future jump intensities better than the original percentage volatility spread.</description><author>Hsieh, PeiLin; Jarrow, Robert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Order Flow Volatility and Equity Costs of Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, Tarun; Hu, Jianfeng; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Tong, Qing
We propose that the volatility of order flow is a proxy for costs of information asymmetry, as order flow volatility varies positively with parameters that also influence adverse selection costs of trading. Empirically, order flow volatility is significantly higher prior to earnings or merger announcements when information asymmetry is likely to be elevated. Levels of and shocks to order flow volatility are positively and significantly correlated with existing illiquidity proxies, and strongly predict stock returns in the cross section. The impact of order imbalance volatility shocks on stock prices is reflected within one month in large, visible stocks but takes up to four months to be fully reflected in small, "neglected" stocks.</description><author>Chordia, Tarun; Hu, Jianfeng; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Tong, Qing</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Process Flexibility in Baseball: The Value of Positional Flexibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Timothy C. Y.; Fearing, Douglas
This paper Introduces the formal study of process flexibility to the novel domain of sports analytics. In baseball, positional flexibility Is the analogous concept to process flexibility from manufacturing. We study the flexibility of players (plants) on a baseball team who produce innings-played at different positions (products). We develop models and metrics to evaluate expected and worst-case performance under Injury risk (capacity uncertainty) with continuous player-position capabilities. Using Major League Baseball data, we quantify the Impact of flexibility on team and individual performance and explore the player chains that arise when injuries occur. We discover that top teams can attribute at least one to two wins per season to flexibility alone, generally as a result of long subchains in the infield or outfield. The least robust teams to worst-case injury, those whose performance is driven by one or two star players, are over four times as fragile as the most robust teams. We evaluate several aspects of individual flexibility, such as how much value individual players bring to their team in terms of average and worst-case performance. Finally, we demonstrate the generalizability of our framework for player evaluation by quantifying the value of potential free agent additions and uncovering the true "MVP" of a team.</description><author>Chan, Timothy C. Y.; Fearing, Douglas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Truthful Cheap Talk: Why Operational Flexibility May Lead to Truthful Communication</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berman, Oded; Fazel-Zarandi, Mohammad M.; Krass, Dmitry
This paper shows that operational flexibility interacting with informational uncertainty may lead to truthful information exchange in equilibrium even when the communication is nonbinding and unverifiable, i.e., "cheap talk." We consider a model consisting of a manufacturer releasing a new product with uncertain release date and demand, and a retailer who must determine the allocation of limited capacity between a preexisting third-party product and the manufacturer's new product that may or may not be released on time. The manufacturer has a private forecast about the likelihood of the product release and/or about the demand, which he shares (either truthfully or not) with the retailer. We show that under the "traditional" supply chain structure (one-time opportunity to order) no truthful equilibrium can emerge. However, if (1) the supply chain structure allows for postponement, i.e., the ability to delay orders at a certain cost by the retailer, and (2) the manufacturer has informational uncertainty about the retailer's capacity, then truthful information exchange may emerge in equilibrium, where the manufacturer transmits his true forecast and the retailer treats the transmission as truthful. The genesis of this effect is preference reversal, where the manufacturer is not sure which way to distort the forecast to best motivate the retailer to wait for the new product. Thus, we show that a truth-revealing mechanism can emerge from a relatively rich setup featuring two-sided information asymmetry interacting with postponement.</description><author>Berman, Oded; Fazel-Zarandi, Mohammad M.; Krass, Dmitry</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Transparency Stifle or Facilitate Innovation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, James R.; Martinsson, Gustav
Corporate transparency reduces information asymmetries between firms and capital markets but increases the costs associated with information leakage to competitors. We explore how a country's information environment affects innovation, an activity characterized by high information asymmetries and potentially severe proprietary costs. Studying both long-run cross-country differences in the availability of firm-specific information to corporate outsiders, as well as quasi-experimental shocks to the information environment following transparency-enhancing security market reforms, we document significantly higher rates of R&amp;D and patenting in richer information environments. The effects of transparency are strongest in industries that rely on external equity rather than bank debt, indicating that transparency facilitates innovation by reducing the information costs associated with arm's-length financing. In contrast, transparency has no impact on physical capital accumulation, consistent with fewer information asymmetries in tangible assets. An economy's information environment has important but heterogeneous effects on the nature and extent of real economic activity.</description><author>Brown, James R.; Martinsson, Gustav</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Team Creativity, Cognition, and Cognitive Style Diversity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, Ishani; Woolley, Anita Williams
In spite of the recognized importance of team creativity for organizational success, the factors that influence it are not well understood. In this paper, we address an important gap in the literature on the impact of team diversity on team creativity. We show how team cognitive diversity both enhances and inhibits team cognition, or the manner in which information is organized and distributed within the team. We further demonstrate that team cognition is a key mechanism through which cognitive diversity influences team creativity. The paper introduces a new theoretical lens, the signal-detection perspective, which argues that cognitive diversity amplifies the signals to the location of critical cognitive resources within the team and aids in their detection, consequently enhancing the form of team cognition that is central to team creativity. We test the predictions in a longitudinal study with 112 MBA student project teams. This research advances our understanding of what makes teams creative by synthesizing and testing existing theory as well as providing a new perspective that highlights an alternative way in which a team's cognitive inputs impact team creativity.</description><author>Aggarwal, Ishani; Woolley, Anita Williams</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Calibration Committees in Subjective Performance Evaluation Systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demere, B. William; Sedatole, Karen L.; Woods, Alexander
We provide the first empirical evidence of the role that calibration committees play in subjective performance evaluation systems. Using proprietary data from a large multinational organization, we begin by showing that calibration committees adjust ratings sparingly (i.e., 25% adjustment rate), but when they do, downward adjustments are significantly more frequent and of greater magnitude than upward adjustments. Calibration committees tend to downward (upward) adjust ratings of supervisors who give higher (lower) than average initial ratings. Taken together, calibration committees improve the consistency of ratings across supervisors and mitigate leniency bias, but exacerbate centrality bias. We also show that calibration committees facilitate the appropriate allocation of decision rights by deferring rating decisions to supervisors who possess a relatively greater information advantage. That is, calibration committees are less likely to adjust the rating of a subordinate who is further removed from committee members in the organizational hierarchy. Finally, we show that calibration committees promote supervisor learning about organizational performance rating expectations through calibration adjustments. This study contributes to the literature on performance evaluation by providing new insights regarding the organizational dynamics of subjective performance evaluation systems when decision rights span hierarchical levels of the organization.</description><author>Demere, B. William; Sedatole, Karen L.; Woods, Alexander</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collusion by Algorithm: Does Better Demand Prediction Facilitate Coordination Between Sellers?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Miklos-Thal, Jeanine; Tucker, Catherine
We build a game-theoretic model to examine how better demand forecasting resulting from algorithms, machine learning, and artificial intelligence affects the sustainability of collusion in an industry. We find that, although better forecasting allows colluding firms to better tailor prices to demand conditions, it also increases each firm's temptation to deviate to a lower price in time periods of high predicted demand. Overall, our research suggests that, despite concerns expressed by policy makers, better forecasting and algorithms can lead to lower prices and higher consumer surplus.</description><author>Miklos-Thal, Jeanine; Tucker, Catherine</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Experimental Test of the Anscombe-Aumann Monotonicity Axiom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schneider, Florian H.; Schonger, Martin
Most models of ambiguity aversion satisfy the Anscombe-Aumann monotonicity axiom. Monotonicity implies a weak form of separability of preferences across events that occur with unknown probability. We construct a test of weak separability by modifying the Allais paradox, adapting it to the Anscombe-Aumann framework. Three experimental studies are conducted. Study 1 finds frequent, systematic violations of weak separability in the lab. These findings replicate in study 2, where we employ a subject pool of online workers and use a natural rather than an artificial source of uncertainty. Investigating a potential explanation of the violations, study 3 suggests that the certainty effect plays a major role.</description><author>Schneider, Florian H.; Schonger, Martin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dons Adding Inventory Increase Sales? Evidence of a Scarcity Effect in</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cachon, Gerard P.; Gallino, Santiago; Olivares, Marcelo
What is the relationship between inventory and sales? Clearly, inventory could increase sales: expanding inventory creates more choice (options, colors, etc.) and might signal a popular/desirable product. Or, inventory might encourage a consumer to continue her search (e.g., on the theory that she can return if nothing better is found), thereby decreasing sales (a scarcity effect). We seek to identify these effects in U.S. automobile sales. Our primary research challenge is the endogenous relationship between inventory and sales-e.g., dealers influence their inventory in anticipation of demand. Hence, our estimation strategy relies on weather shocks at upstream production facilities to create exogenous variation in downstream dealership inventory. We find that the impact of adding a vehicle of a particular model to a dealer's lot depends on which cars the dealer already has. If the added vehicle expands the available set of submodels (e.g., adding a four-door among a set that is exclusively two-door), then sales increase. But if the added vehicle is of the same submodel as an existing vehicle, then sales actually decrease. Hence, expanding variety across submodels should be the first priority when adding inventory- adding inventory within a submodel is actually detrimental. In fact, given how vehicles were allocated to dealerships in practice, we find that adding inventory actually lowered sales. However, our data indicate that there could be a substantial benefit from the implementation of a "maximize variety, minimize duplication" allocation strategy: sales increase by 4.4% without changing the total number of vehicles at each dealership.</description><author>Cachon, Gerard P.; Gallino, Santiago; Olivares, Marcelo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ambiguity Preferences and Portfolio Choices: Evidence from the Field</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bianchi, Milo; Tallon, Jean-Marc
We match administrative panel data on portfolio choices with survey data on preferences over ambiguity. We show that ambiguity averse investors bear more risk, due to a lack of diversification. In particular, they exhibit a form of home bias that leads to higher exposure to the domestic relative to the international stock market. While more sensitive to market factors, their returns are on average higher, suggesting that ambiguity averse investors need not be driven out of the market for risky assets. We also show that these investors rebalance their portfolio more actively and in a contrarian direction relative to past market trends, which allows them to keep their risk exposure relatively constant over time. We discuss these findings in relation to the theoretical literature on portfolio choice under ambiguity.</description><author>Bianchi, Milo; Tallon, Jean-Marc</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Learning and the Design of New Experience Goods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feldman, Pnina; Papanastasiou, Yiangos; Segev, Ella
Consumers often consult the reviews of their peers before deciding whether to purchase a new experience good; however, their initial quality expectations are typically set by the product's observable attributes. This paper focuses on the implications of social learning for a monopolist firm's choice of product design. In our model, the firm's design choice determines the product's ex ante expected quality, and designs associated with (stochastically) higher quality incur higher costs of production. Consumers are forward-looking social learners, and may choose to strategically delay their purchase in anticipation of product reviews. In this setting, we find that the firm's optimal policy differs significantly depending on the level of the ex ante quality uncertainty surrounding the product. In comparison to the case where there is no social learning, we show that (i) when the uncertainty is relatively low, the firm opts for a product of inferior design accompanied by a lower price, while (ii) when the uncertainty is high, the firm chooses a product of superior design accompanied by a higher price; interestingly, we find that the product's expected quality decreases either in the absolute sense (in the former case), or relative to the product's price (in the latter case). We further establish that, contrary to conventional knowledge, social learning can have an ex ante negative impact on the firm's profit, in particular when the consumers are sufficiently forward-looking. Conversely, we find that the presence of social learning tends to be beneficial for the consumers only provided they are sufficiently forward-looking.</description><author>Feldman, Pnina; Papanastasiou, Yiangos; Segev, Ella</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Sharing, Advice Provision, or Delegation: What Leads to Higher Trust and Trustworthiness?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ozer, Ozalp; Subramanian, Upender; Wang, Yu
In many market settings, a customer often obtains assistance from a supplier (or service provider) to make better-informed decisions regarding the supplier's product (or service). Because the two parties often have conflicting pecuniary incentives, customer trust and supplier trustworthiness play important roles in the success of these interactions. We investigate whether and how the process through which assistance is provided can foster trust and trustworthiness, and thus facilitate better cooperation. We compare three prevalent assistance processes: information sharing, advice provision, and delegation. We propose that, even if the pecuniary incentives of both parties do not vary from one assistance process to another, the assistance process itself impacts the customer's and supplier's nonpecuniary motives that give rise to trust and trustworthiness. Consequently, the assistance process affects the level of cooperation and payoffs. We test our behavioral predictions through laboratory experiments based on a retail distribution setting. We quantify the impact of different assistance processes on trust, trustworthiness and channel performance, and identify the underlying drivers of those impacts. Our results offer insight into the role of the assistance process in managing supplier assistance effectively and why certain assistance processes may lead to more successful outcomes than others even if the pecuniary incentives remain unaltered.</description><author>Ozer, Ozalp; Subramanian, Upender; Wang, Yu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Exit Through Divestment-The Effect of Accounting Bias on Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hui; Jorgensen, Bjorn N.
We analyze the effect of accounting bias on the competition and market structure of an industry. In our model, firms' interim accounting reports on investment projects may contain bias introduced by the mandatory accounting system. We find that this bias strictly decreases firms' profits when investors do not have an abandonment option, but different results emerge when we allow the investors to divest in the interim. Specifically, a conservative accounting regime may increase the likelihood of projects being discontinued, inducing some firms to exit from the product market and leaving rivals to capture their market share. A conservative regime can thus soften market competition and result in ex ante higher investment payoff, higher consumer surplus, and higher total social welfare. Since industries often have common reporting standards, we also identify the degrees of industry-wide accounting bias that maximize the expected investor payoffs. Finally, we allow for investors to coordinate their divestment decisions when both firms report unfavorable costs and show an improvement to both firm profits and consumer surplus.</description><author>Chen, Hui; Jorgensen, Bjorn N.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From the Editor</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Simchi-Levi, David
nan</description><author>Simchi-Levi, David</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intellectual Property Strategy and the Long Tail: Evidence from the Recorded Music Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Laurina
Digitization has impacted firm profitability in many media industries by lowering the cost of copying and sharing creative works. I examine the impact of digital rights management (DRM), a prevalent strategy used by firms in media industries to address piracy concerns, on music sales. I exploit a natural experiment, where different labels remove DRM from their entire catalogue of music at different times, to examine whether relaxing an album's sharing restrictions increases sales. Using a large sample of albums from all four major record labels, I find that removing DRM increases digital music sales by 10%, but relaxing sharing restrictions does not impact all albums equally. It increases the sales of lower-selling albums (i.e., the "long tail") significantly (40%) but does not benefit top-selling albums. These results suggest that reducing search costs facilitates the discovery of niche products.</description><author>Zhang, Laurina</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance and Costs of Equity: Theory and Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Di; Li, X. N.
We propose and test an alternative explanation for the existence of the positive governance-return relation in the 1990s and its disappearance in the 2000s: The governance-return relation is positive under good states of the economy and negative under bad states. Corporate governance mitigates investment distortions so that firms with strong governance have more valuable investment options during booms and more valuable divestiture options during busts than the ones with weak governance. Because investment options are riskier and divestiture options are less risky than assets in place, the expected returns of strongly governed firms are higher during booms but lower during busts than the weakly governed ones. Empirical evidence is consistent with our hypothesis.</description><author>Li, Di; Li, X. N.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Callable Contingent Capital: Valuation and Default Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tian, Weidong
This paper proposes the use of contingent capital with a call provision, in which the insurer has an option to redeem the contingent capital at any time. I characterize in detail a unique dynamic equilibrium of common stock, subordinated contingent capital, and a senior standard bond under a simple yet sufficient and necessary condition that can be implemented easily. I further show that the issuance of callable contingent capital does not affect the default risk of an outstanding senior standard bond. As a result, callable contingent capital provides an alternative design for contingent capital using a prudential capital structure for a bank that is "too big to fail."</description><author>Tian, Weidong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Superstition and Financial Decision Making</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, David; Jian, Ming; Zhang, Huai
In Chinese culture, certain digits are lucky and others unlucky. We test how such numerological superstition affects financial decision in the China initial public offering (IPO) market. We find that the frequency of lucky numerical stock listing codes exceeds what would be expected by chance. Also consistent with superstition effects, newly listed firms with lucky listing codes experience inferior post-IPO abnormal returns. Further tests suggest that our conclusions are not driven by endogeneity.</description><author>Hirshleifer, David; Jian, Ming; Zhang, Huai</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Monitoring Influences Trust: A Tale of Two Faces</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schweitzer, Maurice E.; Ho, Teck-Hua; Zhang, Xing
Monitoring changes the behavior of those who are monitored and those who monitor others. We studied behavior under different monitoring regimes in repeated trust games. We found that trustees behaved opportunistically when they anticipated monitoring-they were compliant when they knew in advance that they would be monitored, but exploited trustors when they knew in advance that they would not be monitored. Interestingly, trustors failed to anticipate how strategically their counterparts would behave. Trustors misattributed the strategic, compliant behavior they observed as signals of trustees' trustworthiness. As a result, trustors misplaced their trust when they were unable to monitor their counterparts. We discuss the managerial implications of our results for designing and implementing monitoring systems.</description><author>Schweitzer, Maurice E.; Ho, Teck-Hua; Zhang, Xing</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hierarchical Maximum Likelihood Parameter Estimation for Cumulative Prospect Theory: Improving the Reliability of Individual Risk Parameter Estimates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Murphy, Ryan O.; ten Brincke, Robert H. W.
An individual's tolerance of risk can be quantified by using decision models with tuned parameters that maximally fit a set of risky choices the individual has made. A goal of this model fitting procedure is to identify parameters that correspond to stable underlying risk preferences. These preferences can be modeled as an individual difference, indicating a particular decision maker's tastes and willingness to accept risk. Using hierarchical statistical methods, we show significant improvements in the reliability of individual risk preference parameter estimates over other common methods for cumulative prospect theory. This hierarchical procedure uses population-level information (in addition to an individual's choices) to break "ties" (or near ties) in the fit quality for sets of possible risk preference parameters. By breaking these statistical ties in a sensible way, researchers can avoid overfitting choice data and thus more resiliently measure individual differences in people's risk preferences.</description><author>Murphy, Ryan O.; ten Brincke, Robert H. W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effectiveness of Reputation in Contracting for Customized Production: Evidence from Online Labor Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Mingfeng; Liu, Yong; Viswanathan, Siva
This study examines the effects of reputation in the nascent but rapidly growing online labor markets. In these markets, contract winners (vendors) provide clients with customized products such as computer software, business plans, and artistic designs. The products are used primarily for business purposes and require time for production after project-specific contracts are awarded. These characteristics render it unclear whether online reputation will have similar effects as in online retailing, where finished and standardized products are sold for consumption. We analyze field transaction data from a major online labor market. The analyses using matched contract samples and vendor panels consistently show that despite the governing power provided by contracts as well as the litigation and arbitration options, vendors' online reputation can still be influential on clients. Vendors who have no reputation ratings are less likely to be chosen, and those with higher ratings are more likely to win subsequent bids. Importantly, however, such influences depend on the contract form that is used for a particular transaction-they are significant in output-based contracts but nonsignificant in input-based contracts. Besides extending the research on online reputation to the markets of customized production, this study shows contract form as an important boundary condition for the effectiveness of reputational information. It also provides direct managerial implications for electronic commerce in general and online labor markets in particular.</description><author>Lin, Mingfeng; Liu, Yong; Viswanathan, Siva</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Online Shopping and Platform Design with Ex Ante Registration Requirements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morath, Florian; Muenster, Johannes
We study platform design in online markets in which buying involves a (nonmonetary) cost for consumers caused by privacy and security concerns. Firms decide whether to require registration at their website before consumers learn relevant product information. We derive conditions under which a monopoly seller benefits from ex ante registration requirements and demonstrate that the profitability of registration requirements is increased when taking into account the prospect of future purchases or an informational value of consumer registration to the firm. Moreover, we consider the effectiveness of discounts (store credit) as a means to influence the consumers' registration decision. Finally, we confirm the profitability of ex ante registration requirements in the presence of price competition.</description><author>Morath, Florian; Muenster, Johannes</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sharing Aggregate Inventory Information with Customers: Strategic Cross-Selling and Shortage Reduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cui, Ruomeng; Shin, Hyoduk
This paper studies the strategy of sharing inventory information for a firm that sells two vertically differentiated products. The seller has private information on the aggregate inventory level and the inventory composition of two product variants. The seller credibly and discretionarily discloses inventory information to customers either fully or partially, i.e., disclosing the exact inventory of each product variant, the aggregate inventory level, or no information to customers. Customers form expectations of future availability and make rational purchasing decisions accordingly. In the disclosure literature, discretion usually leads to an unraveling result: sellers who learn favorable market information opt to disclose it, making full disclosure the equilibrium. This paper shows that aggregate inventory disclosure, i.e., partial disclosure, can be instead sustained as an ex post equilibrium. We demonstrate that inventory information aggregation arises when there is an ex post desire to reduce supply-demand mismatches in all inventory scenarios. Specifically, when customers' preferred products are more likely to stock out, the seller could entice more incoming consumers who hope that their desired products are in stock by withholding product composition but disclosing the aggregate inventory level. If customers' desired products are sold out, the seller can benefit from upselling or cross-selling customers' less preferred products. Alternatively, when the seller stocks more desired products, aggregate disclosure can dampen the flow of incoming customers and reduce the shortage penalty cost. This result is robust under various settings: risk-averse customers, heterogeneous customers, and horizontally differentiated products.</description><author>Cui, Ruomeng; Shin, Hyoduk</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multiattribute Loss Aversion and Reference Dependence: Evidence from the Performing Arts Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tereyagoglu, Necati; Fader, Peter S.; Veeraraghavan, Senthil
We study the prevalence of multiattribute loss aversion and reference effects in a revenue management setting based on data of individual-level purchases over a series of concert performances. The reference dependence that drives consumer choice is not only based on the price but also on observed sales (as a fraction of the seating capacity) during their past visits. We find that consumers suffer from loss aversion on both prices and seats sold: consumers incur significant utility loss when prices are above their references or when the actual seat sales are lower than their references. We suggest pricing policies that can address consumer decisions driven by such reference dependence and loss aversion.</description><author>Tereyagoglu, Necati; Fader, Peter S.; Veeraraghavan, Senthil</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Humans Are Not Machines: The Behavioral Impact of Queueing Design on Service Time</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shunko, Masha; Niederhoff, Julie; Rosokha, Yaroslav
Using behavioral experiments, we study the impact of queue design on worker productivity in service systems that involve human servers. Specifically, we consider two queue design features: queue structure, which can be either parallel queues (multiple queues with a dedicated server per queue) or a single queue (a pooled queue served by multiple servers), and queue-length visibility, which can provide either full or blocked visibility. We find that (1) the single-queue structure slows down the servers, illustrating a drawback of pooling, and (2) poor visibility of the queue length slows down the servers; however, this effect may be mitigated, or even reversed, by pay schemes that incentivize the servers for fast performance. We provide additional managerial insights by isolating two behavioral drivers behind these results-task interdependence and saliency of feedback.</description><author>Shunko, Masha; Niederhoff, Julie; Rosokha, Yaroslav</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymptotic Optimality of Tailored Base-Surge Policies in Dual-Sourcing Inventory Systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xin, Linwei; Goldberg, David A.
Dual-sourcing inventory systems, in which one supplier is faster (i.e., express) and more costly, while the other is slower (i.e., regular) and cheaper, arise naturally in many real-world supply chains. These systems are notoriously difficult to optimize because of the complex structure of the optimal solution and the curse of dimensionality, having resisted solution for over 40 years. Recently, so-called tailored base-surge (TBS) policies have been proposed as a heuristic for the dual-sourcing problem. Under such a policy, a constant order is placed at the regular source in each period, while the order placed at the express source follows a simple order-up-to rule. Numerical experiments by several authors have suggested that such policies perform well as the lead time difference between the two sources grows large, which is exactly the setting in which the curse of dimensionality leads to the problem becoming intractable. However, providing a theoretical foundation for this phenomenon has remained a major open problem. In this paper, we provide such a theoretical foundation by proving that a simple TBS policy is indeed asymptotically optimal as the lead time of the regular source grows large, with the lead time of the express source held fixed. Our main proof technique combines novel convexity and lower-bounding arguments, an explicit implementation of the vanishing discount factor approach to analyzing infinite-horizon Markov decision processes, and ideas from the theory of random walks and queues, significantly extending the methodology and applicability of a novel framework for analyzing inventory models with large lead times recently introduced by Goldberg and coauthors in the context of lost-sales models with positive lead times.</description><author>Xin, Linwei; Goldberg, David A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Making Sense of (Ultra) Low-Cost Flights Vertical Differentiation in Two-Sided Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Serio, Luigi; Tedeschi, Piero; Ursino, Giovanni
The business model of low-cost carriers is now well established and accounts for a large share of Western civil aviation, particularly in Europe. To understand why it has proven so successful, we develop a theoretical model that exploits the two-sided nature of flights as connectors of supply and demand for goods and services other than traveling itself across physical space. Carriers offer flights of different quality and may sign agreements with suppliers of goods and services at the destination so as to subsidize and foster demand from the carriers' travelers as in standard two-sided markets. Customers/travelers care about home and destination consumption and about the flight's quality. Hence, beyond the thickness of the connected sides of the market, the quality of the airline platform has an intrinsic value to travelers. We show that only low-income travelers fly with low-cost airlines, while no-frills carriers are more likely to act as a platform than legacy airlines. We study how the degree of substitution between home and destination consumption affects the equilibrium market structure of the airline industry.</description><author>Serio, Luigi; Tedeschi, Piero; Ursino, Giovanni</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Minimizing Risk Exposure When the Choice of a Risk Measure Is Ambiguous</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delage, Erick; Li, Jonathan Yu-Meng
Since the financial crisis of 2007-2009, there has been a renewed interest in quantifying more appropriately the risks involved in financial positions. Popular risk measures such as variance and value-at-risk have been found inadequate because we now give more importance to properties such as monotonicity, convexity, translation invariance, positive homogeneity, and law invariance. Unfortunately, the challenge remains that it is unclear how to choose a risk measure that faithfully represents a decision maker's true risk attitude. In this work, we show that one can account precisely for (neither more nor less than) what we know of the risk preferences of an investor/policy maker when comparing and optimizing financial positions. We assume that the decision maker can commit to a subset of the above properties (the use of a law invariant convex risk measure for example) and that he can provide a series of assessments comparing pairs of potential risky payoffs. Given this information, we propose to seek financial positions that perform best with respect to the most pessimistic estimation of the level of risk potentially perceived by the decision maker. We present how this preference robust risk minimization problem can be solved numerically by formulating convex optimization problems of reasonable size. Numerical experiments on a portfolio selection problem, where the problem reduces to a linear program, will illustrate the advantages of accounting for the fact that the choice of a risk measure is ambiguous.</description><author>Delage, Erick; Li, Jonathan Yu-Meng</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>First Impressions Matter: An Experimental Investigation of Online Financial Advice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agnew, Julie R.; Bateman, Hazel; Eckert, Christine; Iskhakov, Fedor; Louviere, Jordan; Thorp, Susan
We explore how individuals assess the quality of financial advice they receive and how they form judgments about advisers. Using an incentivized discrete choice experiment, we show that first impressions matter: consumers more often follow advisers who dispense good advice before bad. We demonstrate how clients' opinions of adviser quality can be manipulated by using an easily replicated confirmation strategy that depends on the quality of the advice and the difficulty and order of the advice topics. Our results also reveal how clients benefit from their own past experience and how they use professional credentials to guide their choices.</description><author>Agnew, Julie R.; Bateman, Hazel; Eckert, Christine; Iskhakov, Fedor; Louviere, Jordan; Thorp, Susan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Target-Adjusted Utility Functions and Expected-Utility Paradoxes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schneider, Mark; Day, Robert
Experimental tests of expected-utility theory (EU) have accumulated empirical observations in which the predictions of EU are systematically violated. The cumulative prospect theory (CPT) explains violations such as the Allais paradoxes and fourfold pattern of risk attitudes as resulting from nonlinear probability transformations. Here we show that the classical paradoxes for decisions under risk can be explained with preferences that are linear in probabilities for any choice set and that maximize an expectedutility function with respect to an endogenous target return. We introduce the maximin payoff as a plausible and even natural target return from a choice set and show that the resulting target-adjusted utility (TAU) model explains additional empirical observations such as the scale dependence of the Allais paradox that cannot be explained by standard specifications of CPT. Further, using data from three prominent laboratory experiments, we find that TAU is effective in explaining observed behaviors.</description><author>Schneider, Mark; Day, Robert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder Litigation and Ownership Structure: Evidence from a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crane, Alan D.; Koch, Andrew
We use a natural experiment to identify a causal effect of the threat of shareholder litigation on ownership structure, governance, and firm performance. We find that when it becomes harder for small shareholders to litigate, ownership becomes more concentrated and shifts from individuals to institutions. Director and officer governance protections drop among these firms, and operating performance drops among firms whose ownership structure does not change. These results suggest that the ability of shareholders to coordinate and litigate against management is important for governance.</description><author>Crane, Alan D.; Koch, Andrew</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Empirical Analysis of Self-Enforcement Mechanisms: Evidence from Hotel Franchising</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kosova, Renata; Sertsios, Giorgo
The relational contracts literature suggests that a principal can improve contract self-enforceability by specifying initial requirements that increase the agent's ex post rents. Initial requirements specified in hotel franchise agreements-size and quality tier of the hotel-offer a unique empirical setting to test this. Using proprietary data on 5,547 new franchised hotels and their revenues, we find that hotels far away from their franchisor's headquarters are larger, more likely to belong to a high quality tier, and generate higher revenues ex post. This supports the idea that the agent's ex post rents can serve as a substitute to the principal's monitoring intensity in the mitigation of agency problems. Our findings shed light on how formal contract terms can influence informal (relational) contracts between business partners.</description><author>Kosova, Renata; Sertsios, Giorgo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Idea Generation and Potential Appropriation on Entrepreneurship: An Experimental Study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hooshangi, Soheil; Loewenstein, George
Using a novel experimental paradigm, we explore how the experience of generating an idea and the possibility that another investor might adopt a rejected investment opportunity, bias the investment decisions of innovator and imitator entrepreneurs. We find that individuals who generate a business idea form biased evaluations of the economic potential of ideas, be it their own idea or somebody else's idea. On the one hand, they are overconfident about the value of, and overly likely to invest in, their own idea. On the other hand, when investing in another person's idea, even if it is not competing with their own idea, they are underconfident about the value of, and insufficiently likely to invest in, the idea. Surprisingly, we find that entrepreneurial experience exacerbates this pattern of over-and underconfidence. In addition, we find that the threat that another investor can appropriate a declined investment opportunity increases willingness to invest. We propose a theoretical account to explain the observed pattern of over-and underconfidence in imitative and innovative entrepreneurship. Our findings challenge the traditional account that lowering the cost of imitation has a disincentive effect on the investment decisions of pioneer entrepreneurs and provide evidence that a more lenient appropriability regime may, unexpectedly, have positive effects on entrepreneurship. Our findings also identify new psychological mechanisms that can play a role in important phenomena such as the emergence of spin-offs and rush to market entry.</description><author>Hooshangi, Soheil; Loewenstein, George</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Everything We Do, You Do: The Licensing Effect of Prosocial Marketing Messages on Consumer Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kouchaki, Maryam; Jami, Ata
Do prosocial corporate marketing messages promote consumers' altruistic behaviors, or do they advance self-interested and self-indulgent actions? To answer this question, the current research investigates the impact of different framings of prosocial marketing messages on consumers' behaviors and choices more generally. Results from six laboratory studies and a field experiment demonstrate that exposure to messages that praise customers for good deeds can increase subsequent self-interested and self-indulgent behaviors more than messages that publicize a company's good deeds or thank consumers for their patronage. Our findings demonstrate the possibility that a temporary boost in one's self-concept drives this observed effect. In addition, the recipient's level of support for the issue praised for moderates the effect of customer-praise messages on the recipient's less altruistic behaviors. This paper concludes with a discussion of the theoretical and managerial implications.</description><author>Kouchaki, Maryam; Jami, Ata</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Impact of Electricity Pricing Policies on Renewable Energy Investments and Carbon Emissions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kok, A. Gurhan; Shang, Kevin; Yucel, Safak
We investigate the impact of pricing policies (i.e., flat pricing versus peak pricing) on the investment levels of a utility firm in two competing energy sources (renewable and conventional), with a focus on the renewable investment level. We consider generation patterns and intermittency of solar and wind energy in relation to the electricity demand throughout a day. Industry experts generally promote peak pricing policy as it smoothens the demand and reduces inefficiencies in the supply system. We find that the same pricing policy may lead to distinct outcomes for different renewable energy sources due to their generation patterns. Specifically, flat pricing leads to a higher investment level for solar energy, and it can lead to still more investments in wind energy if a considerable amount of wind energy is generated throughout the day. We validate these results by using electricity generation and demand data of the state of Texas. We also show that flat pricing can lead to substantially lower carbon emissions and a higher consumer surplus. Finally, we explore the effect of direct (e.g., tax credit) and indirect (e.g., carbon tax) subsidies on investment levels and carbon emissions. We show that both types of subsidies generally lead to a lower emission level but that indirect subsidies may result in lower renewable energy investments. Our study suggests that reducing carbon emissions through increasing renewable energy investments requires careful attention to the pricing policy and the market characteristics of each region.</description><author>Kok, A. Gurhan; Shang, Kevin; Yucel, Safak</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Egregiousness and Boycott Intensity: Evidence from the BP Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Zhongmin; Lee, Alvin; Polonsky, Michael
Consumer boycotts are triggered by egregious events, but the literature has not distinguished the level of egregiousness from consumers' preferences or disutility associated with a given level of egregiousness, nor has the literature studied how these two components of egregiousness affect boycott intensity. We provide a model of market-level boycotts that distinguishes the two egregiousness components. Consistent with the predictions of our model, the market-level intensity of consumer boycotting of BP-branded gasoline, which was triggered by the BP Deepwater Horizon oil spill, increased with the spill's egregiousness level, approximated by the officially reported daily amount of oil leaked into the ocean and by other measures (i.e., the duration of the spill and the intensity of media coverage), and with consumers' disutility from egregiousness, approximated by an area's environmentalism and its proximity to the Gulf of Mexico.</description><author>Wang, Zhongmin; Lee, Alvin; Polonsky, Michael</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing Fair Lending Risks Using Race/Ethnicity Proxies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Yan
Fair lending analysis of nonmortgage credit products often involves proxying for race/ethnicity since such information is not required to be reported. Using mortgage data, this paper evaluates a series of proxy approaches (geo, surname, geo-surname, and Bayesian Improved Surname Geocoding (BISG)) as compared with the race/ethnicity reported under the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act (HMDA). The BISG proxy predicts the reported race/ethnicity the best as judged by prediction bias, correlation coefficient, and discriminatory power. In assessing fair lending risks where classification of race/ethnicity is called for, we propose the BISG maximum classification, which produces a more accurate estimation of mortgage pricing disparities than the current practices. The above conclusions withhold various robustness tests. Additional analysis is performed to assess the proxies on nonmortgage credits by leveraging consumer credit bureau data.</description><author>Zhang, Yan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uncertainty and Sectoral Shifts: The Interaction Between Firm-Level and Aggregate-Level Shocks, and Macroeconomic Activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalay, Alon; Nallareddy, Suresh; Sadka, Gil
This study predicts and finds that the interaction of firm-level and aggregate-level shocks explains a significant portion of shocks to macroeconomic activity. Specifically, we hypothesize that the relation between uncertainty and economic growth is most pronounced when both firm-level and aggregate-level uncertainty are high simultaneously. Similarly, we hypothesize that aggregate performance affects unemployment most when both firm-level dispersion is high and aggregate performance is low, based on the sectoral shift theory. Our hypotheses and empirical results show that the interactive effect of firm-level and aggregate-level shocks are larger than the sum of the individual effects.</description><author>Kalay, Alon; Nallareddy, Suresh; Sadka, Gil</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Targeting and Policy Illusions-Evidence from the Announcement of the Volcker Rule</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keppo, Jussi; Korte, Josef
We analyze the Volcker Rule's announcement effects on U.S. bank holding companies. In line with the rule and the banks' public compliance announcements, we find that those banks that are affected by the Volcker Rule already reduced their trading books relative to their total assets 2.34% more than other banks. However, the announcement of the rule did not reduce the banks' overall risk taking. To keep their risk targets, the affected banks raised the riskiness of their asset returns. We also find some evidence that the affected banks raised their trading risk and decreased the hedging of their banking business.</description><author>Keppo, Jussi; Korte, Josef</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overcoming Salience Bias: How Real-Time Feedback Fosters Resource Conservation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tiefenbeck, Verena; Goette, Lorenz; Degen, Kathrin; Tasic, Vojkan; Fleisch, Elgar; Lalive, Rafael; Staake, Thorsten
Inattention and imperfect information bias behavior toward the salient and immediately visible. This distortion creates costs for individuals, the organizations in which they work, and society at large. We show that an effective way to overcome this bias is by making the implications of one's behavior salient in real time, while individuals can directly adapt. In a large-scale field experiment, we gave participants real-time feedback on the resource consumption of a daily, energy-intensive activity (showering). We find that real-time feedback reduced resource consumption for the target behavior by 22%. At the household level, this led to much larger conservation gains in absolute terms than conventional policy interventions that provide aggregate feedback on resource use. High baseline users displayed a larger conservation effect, in line with the notion that real-time feedback helps eliminate "slack" in resource use. The approach is cost effective, is technically applicable to the vast majority of households, and generated savings of 1.2 kWh per day and household, which exceeds the average energy use for lighting. The intervention also shows how digitalization in our everyday lives makes information available that can help individuals overcome salience bias and act more in line with their preferences.</description><author>Tiefenbeck, Verena; Goette, Lorenz; Degen, Kathrin; Tasic, Vojkan; Fleisch, Elgar; Lalive, Rafael; Staake, Thorsten</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overcoming Algorithm Aversion: People Will Use Imperfect Algorithms If They Can (Even Slightly) Modify Them</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dietvorst, Berkeley J.; Simmons, Joseph P.; Massey, Cade
Although evidence-based algorithms consistently outperform human forecasters, people often fail to use them after learning that they are imperfect, a phenomenon known as algorithm aversion. In this paper, we present three studies investigating how to reduce algorithm aversion. In incentivized forecasting tasks, participants chose between using their own forecasts or those of an algorithm that was built by experts. Participants were considerably more likely to choose to use an imperfect algorithm when they could modify its forecasts, and they performed better as a result. Notably, the preference for modifiable algorithms held even when participants were severely restricted in the modifications they could make (Studies 1-3). In fact, our results suggest that participants' preference for modifiable algorithms was indicative of a desire for some control over the forecasting outcome, and not for a desire for greater control over the forecasting outcome, as participants' preference for modifiable algorithms was relatively insensitive to the magnitude of the modifications they were able to make (Study 2). Additionally, we found that giving participants the freedom to modify an imperfect algorithm made them feel more satisfied with the forecasting process, more likely to believe that the algorithm was superior, and more likely to choose to use an algorithm to make subsequent forecasts (Study 3). This research suggests that one can reduce algorithm aversion by giving people some control-even a slight amount-over an imperfect algorithm's forecast.</description><author>Dietvorst, Berkeley J.; Simmons, Joseph P.; Massey, Cade</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Editorial Statement-Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, Renee; Diether, Karl; Giesecke, Kay; Manso, Gustavo; Piskorski, Tomasz; Shumway, Tyler
nan</description><author>Adams, Renee; Diether, Karl; Giesecke, Kay; Manso, Gustavo; Piskorski, Tomasz; Shumway, Tyler</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Simple Multimarket Measure of Information Asymmetry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, Travis L.; So, Eric C.
We develop and implement a new measure of information asymmetry among traders. Our measure is based on the intuition that informed traders are more likely than uninformed traders to generate abnormal volume in options or stock markets. We formalize this intuition theoretically and compute the resulting multimarket information asymmetry measure (MIA) for firm-days as a function of unsigned volume totals and without estimating a structural model. Empirically, MIA has many desirable properties: it is positively correlated with spreads, price impact, and absolute order imbalances; predicts future volatility; is an effective conditioning variable for trading strategies stemming from price pressure; and detects exogenous shocks to information asymmetry.</description><author>Johnson, Travis L.; So, Eric C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cheating in the Lab Predicts Fraud in the Field: An Experiment in Public Transportation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dai, Zhixin; Galeotti, Fabio; Villeval, Marie Claire
We conduct an artefactual field experiment using a diversified sample of passengers of public transportation to study attitudes toward dishonesty. We find that the diversity of behavior in terms of (dis) honesty in laboratory tasks and in the field correlate. Moreover, individuals who have just been fined in the field behave more honestly in the lab than the other fare dodgers, except when context is introduced. Overall, we show that simple tests of dishonesty in the lab can predict moral firmness in life, although fraudsters who care about social image cheat less when behavior can be verified ex post by the experimenter.</description><author>Dai, Zhixin; Galeotti, Fabio; Villeval, Marie Claire</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing in Competitive Search Markets: The Roles of Price Information and Fairness Perceptions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anbarci, Nejat; Feltovich, Nick
We use a competitive search (price-posting) framework to experimentally examine how buyer information and fairness perceptions affect market behavior. We observe that moving from zero to one uninformed buyers leads to higher prices in both 2 (seller) x 2 (buyer) and 2 x 3 markets: the former as predicted under standard preferences, the latter the opposite of the theoretical prediction. Perceptions of fair prices-elicited in the experiment-are a powerful driver of behavior. For buyers, fair prices correlate with price responsiveness, which varies systematically across treatments and impacts sellers' pricing incentives. For sellers, fair prices correlate with underpricing, which also varies systematically across treatments.</description><author>Anbarci, Nejat; Feltovich, Nick</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dynamic Spillovers of Entry: An Application to the Generic Drug Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gallant, A. Ronald; Hong, Han; Khwaja, Ahmed
This paper examines whether experience from entry in one market can potentially enhance profitability at a future market opportunity for a related product. We formulate and estimate a dynamic game of entry in which forward-looking firms make decisions not just based on present benefits of past entry but also anticipating potential future benefits of current entry. Dynamic spillovers of entry are incorporated through a firm-specific unobservable (to the researcher) cost that depends on past entry decisions. The unobserved costs may also be serially persistent. Thus, the model allows for firm-specific unobserved heterogeneity that evolves based on firm actions. The challenge of estimating a dynamic game with serially correlated unobserved state variables subject to endogenous feedback is overcome by embedding a particle filter-based technique in a nested fixed-point algorithm. Using an application to a stylized model of entry in the generic pharmaceutical industry, we underscore the motivation for the model specification and the methodology developed. Our estimates imply positive spillover effects of entry. Moreover, these spillovers suggest heterogeneity not just across firms but also within firms over time based on their history of entry decisions. Our results illustrate that entry may potentially provide firms with additional strategic advantage in later markets and that entry spillovers may be an important factor to consider in the equilibrium evolution of the generic drug industry.</description><author>Gallant, A. Ronald; Hong, Han; Khwaja, Ahmed</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Pricing in a Distribution Channel in the Presence of Switching Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cosguner, Koray; Chan, Tat Y.; Seetharaman, P. B.
We advance the literature on dynamic oligopoly pricing models in the presence of switching costs by additionally modeling the strategic pricing role of the retailer within the distribution channel. In doing this, we study the relative dynamic pricing implications of how current retail and wholesale prices for a brand must optimally take into account past and future demand, respectively, for the brand. Using scanner data from the cola market, we find that while the retailer exploits the benefit of inertial demand by appropriately increasing the retail profit margin, the cost of investing is borne entirely by the manufacturers. We use simulation studies to show how the retailer will lose its ability to leverage the benefits of inertial demand as consumers become more price sensitive. We also show that when inertia of the more price-sensitive customer segment increases, the aggregate welfare of consumers, the retailer, and manufacturers may increase.</description><author>Cosguner, Koray; Chan, Tat Y.; Seetharaman, P. B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Styles in Product Design: An Analysis of US Design Patents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Tian Heong; Mihm, Jurgen; Sosa, Manuel E.
Products combine function and form. This paper focuses on product form. We combine state-of-the-art clustering techniques with experimental validation to identify styles (groupings of new product designs of similar form) among the more than 350,000 U.S. design patents granted from 1977 through 2010. Thus we compile, for the first time, a rich data set of styles that can serve as an empirical platform for a rigorous study of the role played by product form in new product development. Building on this platform, we analyze the determinants of "style turbulence"-the year-to-year unpredictability of changes in a style's prevalence. We find that (i) style turbulence follows a U-shaped relationship with respect to function turbulence (the turbulence of product functions associated with a given style), and (ii) style turbulence increases over time. We discuss the implications of these findings for managing design in new product development.</description><author>Chan, Tian Heong; Mihm, Jurgen; Sosa, Manuel E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cognitive Hierarchy in Capacity Allocation Games</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cui, Tony Haitao; Zhang, Yinghao
We examine a supply chain with a single supplier and multiple retailers to predict retailers' actual ordering behaviors. If retailer orders exceed supplier capacity, a proportional rationing rule applies to capacity allocation among retailers. We propose a behavior model based on cognitive hierarchy theory, in which retailers with different levels of strategic-reasoning capabilities form heterogeneous beliefs about other players' capabilities when choosing their orders. This behavioral model yields three interesting predictions. First, retailers' orders increase as the number of retailers decreases or the supplier's production capacity shrinks. Second, the orders tend to increase as the retailer population becomes more "sophisticated." Third, retailers' profits first increase in relation to their strategic-reasoning capabilities and then decrease, indicating an inverted U-shaped relationship between profits and strategic-reasoning capabilities. We experimentally examine the capacity allocation game with participants motivated by financial incentives. The experimental results and structural model estimation confirm the predictions of the behavioral model.</description><author>Cui, Tony Haitao; Zhang, Yinghao</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Randomized Markdowns and Online Monitoring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moon, Ken; Bimpikis, Kostas; Mendelson, Haim
Online retail reduces the costs of obtaining information about a product's price and availability and of flexibly timing a purchase. Consequently, consumers can strategically time their purchases, weighing the costs of monitoring and the risk of inventory depletion against prospectively lower prices. At the same time, firms can observe and exploit their customers' monitoring behavior. Using a data set tracking customers of a North American specialty retail brand, we present empirical evidence that monitoring products online is associated with successfully obtaining discounts. We develop a structural model of consumers' dynamic monitoring to find substantial heterogeneity, with consumers' opportunity costs for an online visit ranging from $2 to $25 in inverse relation to their price elasticities. Our estimation results have important implications for retail operations. The randomized markdown policy benefits retailers by combining price commitment with the exploitation of heterogeneity in consumers' monitoring costs. We estimate that the retailer's profit under randomized markdowns is 81% higher than from subgame-perfect, state-contingent pricing, because the retailer need not limit its inventory to credibly limit markdowns, which permits its jointly optimal inventory stock to expand by 133%. The welfare gain from these larger inventories splits nearly equally into retailer profit and consumer surplus. We also discuss targeting customers with price promotions using their online histories and the implications of reducing consumers' monitoring costs.</description><author>Moon, Ken; Bimpikis, Kostas; Mendelson, Haim</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deceptive Advertising with Rational Buyers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Piccolo, Salvatore; Tedeschi, Piero; Ursino, Giovanni
We study a simple game in which two sellers supply goods whose quality cannot be assessed by consumers even after consumption but can be verified with some probability by a public authority. Sellers may induce a prospective buyer into a bad purchase through comparative deceptive advertising. The central contribution of this paper is the characterization of a class of pooling equilibria in which low-quality sellers deceive a buyer who is Bayes-rational and makes a purchase decision on the basis of the available information. The analysis of these equilibria suggests that high-quality firms should pursue more intensive advertising campaigns than their low-quality competitors. Surprisingly, we find conditions under which sellers' expected profit is higher in pooling equilibria than in the separating equilibrium in which quality is reflected by prices and there is no need to waste resources in advertising. Hence, we show that there are plausible cases in which firms should be ex ante willing to tolerate some degree of deceptive advertising by low-quality competitors. In addition, although in these equilibria the buyer purchases low-quality goods with positive probability, the expected utility can be higher than in a separating equilibrium in which the buyer purchases the high-quality good for sure. In this sense, the model also offers an argument in favor of a lenient regulatory approach to deceptive advertising.</description><author>Piccolo, Salvatore; Tedeschi, Piero; Ursino, Giovanni</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sensitivity to Serial Dependency of Input Processes: A Robust Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lam, Henry
Procedures in assessing the impact of serial dependency on performance analysis are usually built on parametrically specified models. In this paper, we propose a robust, nonparametric approach to carry out this assessment, by computing the worst-case deviation of the performance measure due to arbitrary dependence. The approach is based on optimizations, posited on the model space, that have constraints specifying the level of dependency measured by a nonparametric distance to some nominal independent and identically distributed input model. We study approximation methods for these optimizations via simulation and analysis of variance. Numerical experiments demonstrate how the proposed approach can discover the hidden impacts of dependency beyond those revealed by conventional parametric modeling and correlation studies.</description><author>Lam, Henry</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Partitioning Algorithm for Markov Decision Processes with Applications to Market Microstructure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Ningyuan; Kou, Steven; Wang, Chun
We propose a partitioning algorithm to solve a class of linear-quadratic Markov decision processes with inequality constraints and nonconvex stagewise cost; within each region of the partitioned state space, the value function and the optimal policy have analytical quadratic and linear forms, respectively. Compared to grid-based numerical schemes, the partitioning algorithm gives the closed-formsolution without discretization error, and in many cases does not suffer from the curse of dimensionality. The algorithm is applied to two applications. In the main application, we present a model for limit order books with stochastic market depth to study the optimal order execution problem; stochastic market depth is consistent with empirical studies and necessary to accommodate various order activities. The optimal execution policy obtained by the algorithm significantly outperforms that of a deterministic market depth model in numerical examples. In the second application, we use the algorithm to compute the exact optimal solution to the renewable electricity management problem, for which previously only an approximate solution was known. As a comparison, we show that the approximate solution can be quite inaccurate for some initial states and thus demonstrate an advantage of the exact solution.</description><author>Chen, Ningyuan; Kou, Steven; Wang, Chun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reengineering Management Science for a Sharper Focus and Broader Appeal</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Simchi-Levi, David
nan</description><author>Simchi-Levi, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Editorial Statements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anonymous
nan</description><author>Anonymous</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Search and Periodic Price Discounts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Xing; Chan, Tat Y.; Xie, Ying
This paper empirically investigates the interplay between buyer search behavior and firm pricing strategy in a commodity market where many firms compete in price to sell homogeneous products. We use the heterogeneity in buyer search cost to rationalize why a firm offers periodic price discounts and enjoys a high profit in such a market. An estimation method is proposed to recover the nonparametric distribution of buyer search cost from the price and transaction volume data. With both data, we show that the search cost distribution can be estimated nonparametrically in a sequential search model, and estimation results from a nonsequential search model are robust to the assumption on the maximum number of searches. We also show that the commonly observed high-low pricing strategy can be an optimal strategy for firms when buyers search for price information sequentially. As an empirical application, we use the proposed method to estimate the two search models using data on a commodity product sold by a firm in a business-to-business market. The models predict a high profit margin for the firm, which is consistent with the data, but the sequential search model fits with the observed price distributions and supply costs better than the nonsequential search model.</description><author>Zhang, Xing; Chan, Tat Y.; Xie, Ying</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Economic Growth and Expected Returns Around the World: The End-of-the-Year Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moller, Stig V.; Rangvid, Jesper
Global economic growth at the end of the year strongly predicts returns from a wide spectrum of international assets, such as global, regional, and individual-country stocks, FX, and commodities. Global economic growth at other times of the year does not predict international returns. Low growth in the global economy at the end of the year predicts higher returns over the following year. It also predicts the global business cycle. When global economic growth at the end of the year is low, investors expect a worsening of the global business cycle and increase their required returns.</description><author>Moller, Stig V.; Rangvid, Jesper</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Technology, Repeated Contracts, and the Number of Suppliers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aral, Sinan; Bakos, Yannis; Brynjolfsson, Erik
Many theories address how information technology (IT) affects the number of suppliers and supply chain governance. However, their predictions are at times contradictory and there is relatively little empirical evidence with which to evaluate them. We therefore develop an integrated, multiperiod model of the optimal number of suppliers that combines search and coordination theory, transaction cost economics, and incomplete contracts theory, and we assess our theoretical predictions using a large new data set on the global IT sourcing decisions of 1,355 firms in 12 countries. Our empirical results support three key predictions about trust, IT, and supply base size. First, investments in coordination IT, which reduce search and coordination costs, are correlated with using more suppliers, while use of vendor-specific IT is associated with fewer suppliers. Second, repeated relationships and trust play a major role in supply chain governance. As firms work with fewer suppliers, they also engage in more repeated relationships. At the same time asset specificity and the need to induce relationship-specific investments are correlated not only with fewer suppliers, but also with a larger fraction of repeated relationships. Third, supply chain governance differs in human capital-intensive and physical capital-intensive industries. The correspondence between asset specificity and repetition is strong in physical capital-intensive firms and not significant in human capital-intensive firms, while the correspondence between fewer suppliers and more repeated relationships is strong in human capital-intensive firms but not significant in physical capital-intensive firms. This corroborates the differential implications of human and physical capital for bargaining power, contractual risk, and trust in buyer-supplier relationships.</description><author>Aral, Sinan; Bakos, Yannis; Brynjolfsson, Erik</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Abandon/Extract Decisions for Failed Cardiac Leads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khojandi, Anahita; Maillart, Lisa M.; Prokopyev, Oleg A.; Roberts, Mark S.; Saba, Samir F.
When a cardiac lead fails, physicians implant a new lead and may opt to extract the failed lead and/or any previously abandoned leads. Because the risk of extraction increases in lead age, physicians may extract leads to reduce the future risk of mandatory extraction, due to either infection or limited space in the vein. We develop discrete-time semi-Markov decision process models for various types of cardiac devices to determine patient-specific, lifetime-maximizing extraction policies as a function of patient age and the age of every implanted lead. We use clinical data to calibrate these models and present insightful numerical results, including comparisons to policies commonly used in practice. Our numerical experiments suggest that extracting failed leads only when forced to because of space limitations is usually a good rule of thumb, but that following the optimal policy, as opposed to the commonly used heuristic policies, can extend an average patient's expected lifetime by up to 1.2 years and decrease the likelihood of device-related death by up to 94% in some cases.</description><author>Khojandi, Anahita; Maillart, Lisa M.; Prokopyev, Oleg A.; Roberts, Mark S.; Saba, Samir F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Patent Publication and the Market for Ideas</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hegde, Deepak; Luo, Hong
In this paper, we study the effect of invention disclosure through patent publication on the market for ideas. We do so by analyzing the effects of the American Inventor's Protection Act of 1999 (AIPA)-which required U.S. patent applications to be published 18 months after their filing date rather than at patent grant-on the timing of licensing deals in the biomedical industry. We find that post-AIPA U.S. patent applications are significantly more likely to be licensed before patent grant and shortly after 18-month publication. Licensing delays are reduced by about 10 months, on average, after AIPA's enactment. These findings suggest a hitherto unexplored benefit of the patent system: by requiring inventions to be published through a credible, standardized, and centralized repository, it mitigates information costs for buyers and sellers, and thus facilitates transactions in the market for ideas.</description><author>Hegde, Deepak; Luo, Hong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Voluntary Product Safety Certification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iyer, Ganesh; Singh, Shubhranshu
This paper describes the incentives for firms to seek voluntary product safety certifications. We consider a firm that makes the decision of whether or not to seek certification prior to selling the product. We show that even when the firm and the consumers have the same beliefs about the product's safety, there are incentives for the firm to seek safety certification. The main analysis investigates the role of consumer moral hazard and shows that it can lead to greater incentives for voluntary certification when inherent product safety and effort are substitutes, but smaller incentives when they are complements. The analysis of consumer moral hazard provides a nuanced perspective on the so-called risk compensation or the "Peltzman effect" phenomenon, which postulates higher levels of accidents for safer products. In our paper, products that are successfully certified can end up with a higher incidence of accidents. We also uncover an interesting nonmonotonic relationship between effectiveness of consumers' effort and the firm's incentives to seek certification. Finally, we find that certification can be welfare enhancing in the presence of consumer moral hazard.</description><author>Iyer, Ganesh; Singh, Shubhranshu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Full-Stock-Payment Marginalization in Merger and Acquisition Transactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Bodt, Eric; Cousin, Jean-Gabriel; Roll, Richard
The number of merger and acquisition (M&amp;A) transactions paid fully in stock in the U.S. market declined sharply after 2001, when pooling and goodwill amortization were abolished by the Financial Accounting Standards Board. Did this accounting rule change really have such far reaching implications? Using a difference-in-differences test and Canada as a counterfactual, this study reveals that it did. We also report several other results confirming the role of pooling abolishment, including (i) that the decrease in full stock payment relates to CEO incentives and (ii) that previously documented determinants of the M&amp;A mode of payment cannot explain the post-pooling abolishment pattern. These results are also robust to controls for various factors, such as the Internet bubble, the exclusion of cross-border deals, the presence of Canadian cross-listed firms, the use of a constant sample of acquirers across the pooling and post-pooling abolishment periods, the use of Europe as an alternative counterfactual, and controls for the SEC Rule 10b-18 share repurchase safe harbor amendments of 2003.</description><author>de Bodt, Eric; Cousin, Jean-Gabriel; Roll, Richard</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Maintaining Beliefs in the Face of Negative News: The Moderating Role of Experience</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Staats, Bradley R.; Kc, Diwas S.; Gino, Francesca
Many models in operations management involve dynamic decision making that assumes optimal updating in response to information revelation. However, behavioral theory suggests that rather than updating their beliefs, individuals may persevere in their prior beliefs. In particular, we examine how individuals' prior experiences and the experiences of those around them alter their belief perseverance in operational decisions after the revelation of negative news. We draw on an exogenous announcement of negative news by the Food and Drug Administration and explore how it affects interventional cardiologists deciding between two types of cardiac stents. Analyzing 147,000 choices over six years, we find that individuals do respond to negative news by using the focal production tool less often. However, we find that both individuals' own experiences and others' experiences alter their responses. Moreover, although individual and other experience act as substitutes before negative news, we find that this substitution significantly curtails following the negative announcement. Finally, we find that experience leads doctors to discount negative news more rapidly over time. Two lab studies replicate our main findings and show that behavioral biases due to differences in perceptions of expertise drive the effect. Our research contributes not only to operations research but also to the practice of healthcare and operations.</description><author>Staats, Bradley R.; Kc, Diwas S.; Gino, Francesca</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Product Market Impact of Minority Stake Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nain, Amrita; Wang, Yan
We show that partial equity ownership of a rival firm reduces product market competition. Acquisitions of a minority equity stake in rival firms are followed by higher output prices and higher industry profits, particularly when barriers to entry are high. Stock-price reactions of nonparticipating competitors of the acquirer and target are positive while announcement returns of customer firms are negative. Moreover, announcement returns of rivals are significantly higher and those of customers weakly lower when the customer industry is more competitive and when the acquirer and target are larger firms.</description><author>Nain, Amrita; Wang, Yan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Choosing the Pond: On-the-Job Experience and Long-Run Career Outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gong, Jie; Sun, Ang; Wei, Zhichao
This paper investigates the value of on-the-job experience for workers' long-run career outcomes. We exploit the effects of team relegation in professional soccer by contrasting players on teams just below and just above the cutoff point of relegation. We find that players on teams relegated to a lower division have more match appearances in the short run, and they play in better leagues and earn higher wages in the long run. This gain is concentrated among individuals who are young or less experienced at the time of relegation. Because other consequences of relegation would tend to work against individuals' long-run success, the positive net gain is most likely to be the result of greater on-the-job experience. The findings have implications for firms on job assignment and for workers on managing their careers.</description><author>Gong, Jie; Sun, Ang; Wei, Zhichao</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time Matters Less When Outcomes Differ: Unimodal vs. Cross-Modal Comparisons in Intertemporal Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cubitt, Robin; McDonald, Rebecca; Read, Daniel
Unimodal intertemporal decisions involve comparing options of the same type (e.g., apples now versus apples later), and cross-modal decisions involve comparing options of different types (e.g., a car now versus a vacation later). As we show, existing models of intertemporal choice do not allow time preference to depend on whether the comparisons to be made are unimodal or cross-modal. We test this restriction in an experiment using the delayed compensation method, a new extension of the standard method of eliciting intertemporal preferences that allows for assessment of time preference for nonmonetary and discrete outcomes, as well as for both cross-modal and unimodal comparisons. Participants were much more averse to delay for unimodal than cross-modal decisions. We provide two potential explanations for this effect: one drawing on multiattribute choice, the other drawing on construal-level theory.</description><author>Cubitt, Robin; McDonald, Rebecca; Read, Daniel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Laboratory Evidence on the Effects of Sponsorship on the Competitive Preferences of Men and Women</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baldiga, Nancy R.; Coffman, Katherine B.
Sponsorship programs have been proposed as one way to promote female advancement in competitive career fields. A sponsor is someone who advocates for a protege, and in doing so, takes a stake in her success. We use a laboratory experiment to explore two channels through which sponsorship has been posited to increase advancement in a competitive workplace. In our setting, being sponsored provides a vote of confidence and/or creates a link between the protege's and sponsor's payoffs. We find that both features of sponsorship significantly increase willingness to compete among men on average, while neither of these channels significantly increases willingness to compete among women on average. As a result, sponsorship does not close the gender gap in competitiveness or earnings. We discuss how these insights from the laboratory could help to inform the design of sponsorship programs in the field.</description><author>Baldiga, Nancy R.; Coffman, Katherine B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Consumer Protection and the Cost of Financial Intermediation: Evidence from Advanced and Developing Economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pasiouras, Fotios
Using a data set of approximately 3,000 commercial banks from more than 100 countries, I examine the impact of financial consumer protection policies on the cost of financial intermediation. I find evidence that the existence of internal mechanisms for handling complaints, requirements for fair treatment, supervisory power related to consumer protection, and various disclosure requirements reduce the cost of financial intermediation in advanced countries. The results are different in the case of developing countries, where I observe that most financial consumer protection policies increase the cost of intermediation, suggesting that banks pass on regulatory burdens to their customers.</description><author>Pasiouras, Fotios</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Underwriters Compete in IPO Pricing?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lyandres, Evgeny; Fu, Fangjian; Li, Erica X. N.
We propose and implement a direct test of the hypothesis of oligopolistic competition in the U.S. underwriting market against the alternative of implicit collusion among underwriters. We construct a simple model of interaction between heterogeneous underwriters and heterogeneous firms and solve it under two alternative assumptions: oligopolistic competition among underwriters and implicit collusion among them. The two solutions lead to different equilibrium relations between the compensation of underwriters of different quality on one hand and the time-varying demand for public incorporation on the other hand. Our empirical results, obtained using 39 years of initial public offering (IPO) data, are generally consistent with the implicit collusion hypothesis that banks, especially larger ones, seem to internalize the effects of their underwriting fees and IPO pricing on their rivals.</description><author>Lyandres, Evgeny; Fu, Fangjian; Li, Erica X. N.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Pricing in Social Networks: The Word-of-Mouth Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ajorlou, Amir; Jadbabaie, Ali; Kakhbod, Ali
We study the problem of optimal dynamic pricing for a monopolist selling a product to consumers in a social network. In the proposed model, the only means of spread of information about the product is via word-of-mouth communication; consumers' knowledge of the product is only through friends who already know about the product's existence. Both buyers and nonbuyers contribute to information diffusion, while buyers are more likely to spread the news about the product. By analyzing the structure of the underlying endogenous dynamic process, we show that the optimal dynamic pricing policy for durable products with zero or negligible marginal cost drops the price to zero infinitely often. The firm uses free offers to attract low-valuation agents and to get them more engaged in the spread. As a result, the firm can reach potential high-valuation consumers in parts of the network that would otherwise remain untouched without the price drops. We provide evidence for this behavior from the smartphone app market, where price histories indicate frequent zero-price sales. Moreover, we show that despite dropping the price to zero infinitely often, the optimal price trajectory does not get trapped near zero. We demonstrate the validity of our results in the face of forward-looking consumers and homophily in word-of-mouth engagement. We further unravel the key role of the product type in the optimality of zero-price sales by showing that the price fluctuations disappear after a finite time for a nondurable product.</description><author>Ajorlou, Amir; Jadbabaie, Ali; Kakhbod, Ali</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Pricing in Social Networks: The Word-of-Mouth Effect (vol 64, pg 971, 2018)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ajorlou, Amir; Jadbabaie, Ali; Kakhbod, Ali
nan</description><author>Ajorlou, Amir; Jadbabaie, Ali; Kakhbod, Ali</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Supply Chains on Firm-Level Productivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Serpa, Juan Camilo; Krishnan, Harish
Firms in a vertical relationship are likely to affect each other's productivity. Exactly how does productivity spill over across this type of relationship (i.e., through which mechanisms)? Additionally, how does the relative importance of these mechanisms depend on the structure of the supply chain? To answer these questions, we decompose the channels of upstream productivity spillovers-from customers to suppliers-by developing a structural econometric model on a sample of approximately 22,500 supply chain dyads. We find that the "endogenous channel" (i.e., the effect of the customer's own productivity on the supplier's productivity) is by far the most important source of spillovers. This is especially true if (i) the supplier has a concentrated customer base, (ii) the supplier and the customer have similar operational characteristics, and (iii) the relationship has medium maturity. In the converse scenarios, we find, it is more important to have a partner with a portfolio of favorable "contextual" characteristics (high inventory turnover, financial liquidity, and asset turnover) than to have a productive partner.</description><author>Serpa, Juan Camilo; Krishnan, Harish</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Behavior of Suppliers in the Face of Production Disruptions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demirel, Suleyman; Kapuscinski, Roman; Yu, Man
To mitigate supply disruption risks, some manufacturers consider a flexible sourcing strategy, where they have an option of sourcing from multiple suppliers, including regular unreliable suppliers and backup reliable ones. Our objective is to evaluate the costs and benefits associated with flexible sourcing when suppliers are strategic price setters. We show that when each supplier announces a single (wholesale) price, such a game leads to a conflict of incentives and is not realistic in most practical settings. Therefore, we focus on a contingent-pricing game, with wholesale prices contingent on the manufacturer's sourcing strategy. We describe the resulting equilibrium outcomes corresponding to the manufacturer's different sourcing and inventory strategies. We show that in equilibrium, inventories are carried either by the manufacturer or by the unreliable supplier, but not both. The manufacturer does not necessarily benefit from the existence of a backup supplier and, in fact, is typically worse off. Similarly, supply chain performance may degrade. Thus, an up-front commitment to sole sourcing may be beneficial. Interestingly, suppliers may benefit from flexible sourcing even though the manufacturer does not. The main results extend to cases when partial backup sourcing is allowed, both suppliers are unreliable, recovery times are non-memoryless, an unreliable supplier may provide a richer set of contingent prices, or the supplier may be risk averse.</description><author>Demirel, Suleyman; Kapuscinski, Roman; Yu, Man</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Screening Spinouts? How Noncompete Enforceability Affects the Creation, Growth, and Survival of New Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Starr, Evan; Balasubramanian, Natarajan; Sakakibara, Mariko
This paper examines how the enforceability of noncompete covenants affects the creation, growth, and survival of spinouts and other new entrants. The impact of noncompete enforceability on new firms is ambiguous, since noncompetes reduce knowledge leakage but impose hiring costs. However, we posit that enforceability screens formation of within-industry spinouts (WSOs) relative to non-WSOs by dissuading founders with lower human capital. Using data on 5.5 million new firms, we find greater enforceability is associated with fewer WSOs, but relative to non-WSOs, WSOs that are created tend to start and stay larger, are founded by higher-earners, and are more likely to survive their initial years. In contrast, we find no impact on non-WSO entry and a negative effect on size and short-term survival.</description><author>Starr, Evan; Balasubramanian, Natarajan; Sakakibara, Mariko</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industrial Development Through Tacit Knowledge Seeding: Evidence from the Bangladesh Garment Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mostafa, Romel; Klepper, Steven
We explore how the establishment of an industry pioneer through foreign seeding of industry knowledge can subsequently catalyze the growth of a developing country's industry by involuntarily propagating the knowledge to subsequent entrants. As industry knowledge has tacit elements, we focus on mechanisms that enable experienced workers from the pioneer to seed the knowledge to new entrants. We examine the relationship between entrants' characteristics and the mechanisms exploited to access the industry knowledge, and the impact of the mechanisms exploited on firm performance. Empirical findings from two historical episodes in the Bangladesh garment industry suggest that industry knowledge seeding was essential for the initial establishment and subsequent expansion of the industry. Our paper highlights the role of experienced workers' mobility in building new firm capabilities and provides novel insights into industrialization in developing economies.</description><author>Mostafa, Romel; Klepper, Steven</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Are Losses Less Persistent Than Profits? Curtailments vs. Conservatism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lawrence, Alastair; Sloan, Richard; Sun, Estelle
It is well documented that losses are less persistent than profits and that stock prices anticipate the lower persistence of losses. Yet the underlying explanation for these results is unclear. One explanation lies in the abandonment option, whereby firms with losses are more likely to curtail operations (e.g., Hayn [Hayn C (1995) The information content of losses. J. Accounting Econom. 20(2):125-153]). Another explanation involves timely loss recognition stemming from conservative accounting (e.g., Basu [Basu S (1997) The conservatism principle and the asymmetric timeliness of earnings. J. Accounting Econom. 24(1):3-37]). We provide direct evidence that curtailments are an important factor contributing to the lower persistence of losses. An implication of our results is that popular measures of conservatism, such as the measure proposed by Basu, also reflect curtailments.</description><author>Lawrence, Alastair; Sloan, Richard; Sun, Estelle</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Discretion on Procurement Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coviello, Decio; Guglielmo, Andrea; Spagnolo, Giancarlo
We run a regression discontinuity design analysis to document the causal effect of increasing buyers' discretion on procurement outcomes in a large database for public works in Italy. Works with a value above a given threshold have to be awarded through an open auction. Works below this threshold can be more easily awarded through a restricted auction, where the buyer has some discretion in terms of who (not) to invite to bid. Our main result is that discretion increases the probability that the same firm wins repeatedly, and it does not deteriorate (and may improve) the procurement outcomes we observe. The effects of discretion persist when we repeat the analysis controlling for the geographical location, corruption, social capital, and judicial efficiency in the region of the public buyers running the auctions.</description><author>Coviello, Decio; Guglielmo, Andrea; Spagnolo, Giancarlo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Model of Product Design and Information Disclosure Investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Markopoulos, Panos M.; Hosanagar, Kartik
New technologies such as product simulators and virtual reality now allow firms to provide realistic product usage experiences and reduce buyer uncertainty about product quality. We argue that today's firms should view product design and investments to reduce buyer uncertainty as an integrated process, which is in turn influenced by how much information buyers can obtain from third-party infomediaries. We introduce a game-theoretic model of a competitive market where both quality production and quality disclosure are endogenous decisions, affected by information made available by third parties. We show that quality investment under uncertainty never exceeds the level of quality investment under perfect information. Furthermore, we show that information availability by third parties allows firms to free ride, and it especially favors lower quality firms, who can reduce their information disclosure investments more so than higherquality firms. Finally, we show that the intuitive argument that firms must improve their product quality when overall information availability in the market improves does not always hold. Instead, improved information availability may enable firms to reduce their quality in some situations.</description><author>Markopoulos, Panos M.; Hosanagar, Kartik</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identity in Charitable Giving</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kessler, Judd B.; Milkman, Katherine L.
How does priming identity affect charitable giving? We show that individuals are more likely to donate when a facet of their identity associated with a norm of generosity is primed in an appeal. In large charitable giving field experiments run by the American Red Cross, appeals that prime an individual's identity as a previous donor to the charity or as a member of a local community generate more donations. The primes are more effective when they highlight a facet of the potential donor's identity that we hypothesize to be more relevant to his sense of self: priming identity as a previous donor is more effective for more regular donors and priming identity as a local community member is more effective for people in smaller communities. Together, these results elucidate the impact of identity on behavior and demonstrate how identity primes can be implemented in practice to encourage public good provision.</description><author>Kessler, Judd B.; Milkman, Katherine L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contagion in Financial Networks: A Threat Index</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demange, Gabrielle
This paper proposes to measure the spillover effects that cross liabilities generate on the magnitude of default in a system of financially linked institutions. Based on a simple model and an explicit criterion-the aggregate debt repayments-the measure is defined for each institution, affected by its characteristics and links to others. These measures-one for each institution-summarize relevant information on the interaction between the liabilities structure and the shocks to resources, and they can be useful to determine optimal intervention policies. The approach is illustrated to evaluate the consolidated foreign claims of 10 European Union countries.</description><author>Demange, Gabrielle</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Embedding Formulations and Complexity for Unions of Polyhedra</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vielmaa, Juan Pablo
It iswell known that selecting a good mixed-integer programming (MIP) formulation is crucial for effectively obtaining a solution with state-of-the art solvers. Although best practices and guidelines for constructing good formulations abound, there is rarely a single systematic construction approach that leads to the best possible formulation. Here, we introduce embedding formulations and complexity as a new MIP formulation paradigm for systematically constructing formulations for disjunctive constraints that are optimal with respect to size. More specifically, they yield the smallest possible ideal formulation (i.e., one whose LP relaxation has integral extreme points) among all formulations that only use 0-1 auxiliary variables. We use the paradigm to characterize optimal formulations for special ordered sets of type 2 and certain piecewise linear functions of two variables. We also show that the resultant formulations can provide a significant computational advantage over all known formulations for piecewise linear functions.</description><author>Vielmaa, Juan Pablo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board Structure Mandates: Consequences for Director Location and Financial Reporting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alam, Zinat S.; Chen, Mark A.; Ciccotello, Conrad S.; Ryan, Harley E.
We examine how the director independence mandates of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) and related reforms affected board geography and the quality of financial reporting. Using 1998-2006 data on the residential addresses of individual directors, we document that the geographic proximity to headquarters of audit committees and other monitoring committees declined upon implementation of the mandates. The decrease in proximity was especially large for those firms that were both SOX noncompliant and supply constrained in local director labor markets at the time the reforms were enacted. Moreover, firms with larger SOX-related losses of director proximity experienced significantly greater post-SOX declines in earnings quality. Our findings therefore suggest that, for some firms, the director independence mandates had unintended consequences for financial reporting quality.</description><author>Alam, Zinat S.; Chen, Mark A.; Ciccotello, Conrad S.; Ryan, Harley E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Two-Sided Reputation in Certification Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bouvard, Matthieu; Levy, Raphael
In a market where sellers solicit certification to overcome asymmetric information, we show that the profit of a monopolistic certifier can be hump-shaped in its reputation for accuracy: a higher accuracy attracts high-quality sellers but sometimes repels low-quality sellers. As a consequence, reputational concerns may induce the certifier to reduce information quality, thus depressing welfare. The entry of a second certifier impacts reputational incentives: when sellers only solicit one certifier, competition plays a disciplining role and the region where reputation is bad shrinks. Conversely, this region may expand when sellers hold multiple certifications.</description><author>Bouvard, Matthieu; Levy, Raphael</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dynamics of Borrower Reputation Following Financial Misreporting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chava, Sudheer; Huang, Kershen; Johnson, Shane A.
We study the dynamics of borrower reputation in bank loan markets following revelations of financial misreporting by the borrower. Misreporting firms pay greater loan spreads than matched firms for at least six years following revelation of the misreporting, and there is no evidence of a downward trend in the misreporting premium. Following revelation, misreporting firms are more likely to engage in various actions to potentially rebuild their reputations, but even firms that engage in multiple actions continue to pay greater loan spreads for at least six years. Our results suggest that misreporting causes long-lasting and costly reputation losses that firms find very difficult or prohibitively costly to restore.</description><author>Chava, Sudheer; Huang, Kershen; Johnson, Shane A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Theory of Corporate Boards and Forced CEO Turnover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Fedaseyeu, Viktar
We model a corporate board evaluating a chief executive officer (CEO) of uncertain management ability. Each director receives a noisy private signal about CEO ability, after which directors discuss this ability and vote to retain or replace the CEO. Directors care about true CEO ability, since it affects their equity holding values; however, a CEO may impose costs of dissent on a director who votes to fire but fails to oust her. We relate the equilibrium CEO firing decision to board size, board composition, the effect of an imprecise public signal, and the cost and probability of finding a good replacement CEO.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Fedaseyeu, Viktar</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Return to Invested Capital and the Performance of Mergers and Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qian, Jun QJ; Zhu, Julie Lei
We evaluate the efficiency of capital deployment for acquiring firms before mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;As), defined as the return on invested capital net of the cost of capital, and link this measure to firms' postacquisition performance. Acquirers with higher preacquisition net returns on investment have superior long-run operating and stock performance than do acquirers with lower returns. Acquirers with low net returns on investment also underperform matching nonacquirers. The relationship between preacquisition investment return and postacquisition performance is weakened when chief executive officer turnover occurs after deal completion. These results imply that managerial ability in deploying capital and creating value for shareholders persists through M&amp;As.</description><author>Qian, Jun QJ; Zhu, Julie Lei</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Cash Hoarding: The Role of Just-in-Time Adoption</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Xiaodan
I explore the role of the just-in-time (JIT) inventory system in the increase in cash holdings by U.S. manufacturing firms. I develop a model to illustrate the mechanism through which JIT affects cash and quantify its impact. In the model, both cash and inventory can serve as working capital. As firms switch from the traditional system to JIT, they shift resources from inventory to cash to facilitate transactions with suppliers. On average, this switchover accounts for a 4.1-percentage-point increase in the cash-to-assets ratio, which is approximately 28% of the change observed in the data.</description><author>Gao, Xiaodan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Post-Earnings-Announcement Drift and the Return Predictability of Earnings Levels: One Effect or Two?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kausar, Asad
This paper examines whether earnings levels predict future returns distinct from earnings changes. I find that the predictive ability of earnings levels is subsumed by and is not incremental to the predictive ability of earnings changes. Specifically, I find that trading strategies based on net income, operating profitability, and gross profitability do not earn significant abnormal returns after controlling for earnings changes. My evidence suggests that these anomalies are an artifact of post-earnings-announcement drift and the failure to properly control for earnings changes.</description><author>Kausar, Asad</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Compensation Consultants Enable Higher CEO Pay? A Disclosure Rule Change as a Separating Device</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chu, Jenny; Faasse, Jonathan; Rau, P. Raghavendra
We investigate the impact of a firm's compensation consultant choice on executive compensation by examining shifts in consultant choice stemming from a 2009 U.S. Securities Exchange Commission requirement that firms disclose fees paid to compensation consultants for both consulting and other services. We show that the disclosure rule change acted as a separating device distinguishing firms likely to have used compensation consultants to extract rents from shareholders from firms that were likely to have used consultants to optimally set pay. We conclude that not all multiservice consultants are conflicted, while not all specialist consultants are guardians of shareholder value. Our study provides a more nuanced view of the association between compensation consultant choices and executive pay.</description><author>Chu, Jenny; Faasse, Jonathan; Rau, P. Raghavendra</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Automated Earnings Forecasts: Beat Analysts or Combine and Conquer?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ball, Ryan T.; Ghysels, Eric
Prior studies attribute analysts' forecast superiority over time-series forecasting models to their access to a large set of firm, industry, and macroeconomic information (an information advantage), which they use to update their forecasts on a daily, weekly or monthly basis (a timing advantage). This study leverages recently developed mixed data sampling (MIDAS) regression methods to synthesize a broad spectrum of high frequency data to construct forecasts of firm-level earnings. We compare the accuracy of these forecasts to those of analysts at short horizons of one quarter or less. We find that our MIDAS forecasts are more accurate and have forecast errors that are smaller than analysts' when forecast dispersion is high and when the firm size is smaller. In addition, we find that combining our MIDAS forecasts with analysts' forecasts systematically outperforms analysts alone, which indicates that our MIDAS models provide information orthogonal to analysts. Our results provide preliminary support for the potential to automate the process of forecasting firm-level earnings, or other accounting performance measures, on a high-frequency basis.</description><author>Ball, Ryan T.; Ghysels, Eric</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prehire Screening and Subjective Performance Evaluations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Bin R.; Li, Sanxi
We study a two-stage model in which the agent's ability is initially unknown to any party, but the principal can choose a prehire screening scheme to discover the agent's ability before offering a contract. Perfect screening enables the principal to fine-tune the contract to the agent's ability, but it also prevents her from enforcing a contract that is contingent on subjective interim performance measures. Given that interim performance measures are critical for motivating first-stage effort, the principal may benefit from adopting no screening or partial screening. When partial screening is employed, the halo effect-a commonly observed bias in subjective evaluation practices-emerges in the equilibrium.</description><author>Chen, Bin R.; Li, Sanxi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discrete Nonlinear Optimization by State-Space Decompositions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergman, David; Cire, Andre A.
This paper investigates a decomposition approach for binary optimization problems with nonlinear objectives and linear constraints. Our methodology relies on the partition of the objective function into separate low-dimensional dynamic programming (DP) models, each of which can be equivalently represented as a shortest-path problem in an underlying state-transition graph. We show that the associated transition graphs can be related by a mixed-integer linear program (MILP) so as to produce exact solutions to the original nonlinear problem. To address DPs with large state spaces, we present a general relaxation mechanism that dynamically aggregates states during the construction of the transition graphs. The resulting MILP provides both lower and upper bounds to the nonlinear function, and it may be embedded in branch-and-bound procedures to find provably optimal solutions. We describe how to specialize our technique for structured objectives (e.g., submodular functions) and consider three problems arising in revenue management, portfolio optimization, and healthcare. Numerical studies indicate that the proposed technique often outperforms state-of-the-art approaches by orders of magnitude in these applications.</description><author>Bergman, David; Cire, Andre A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decentralized Clearing in Financial Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Csoka, Peter; Herings, P. Jean-Jacques
We consider a situation in which agents have mutual claims on each other, summarized in a liability matrix. Agents' assets might be insufficient to satisfy their liabilities, leading to defaults. In case of default, bankruptcy rules are used to specify the way agents are going to be rationed. A clearing payment matrix is a payment matrix consistent with the prevailing bankruptcy rules that satisfies limited liability and priority of creditors. Since clearing payment matrices and the corresponding values of equity are not uniquely determined, we provide bounds on the possible levels equity can take. Unlike the existing literature, which studies centralized clearing procedures, we introduce a large class of decentralized clearing processes. We show the convergence of any such process in finitely many iterations to the least clearing payment matrix. When the unit of account is sufficiently small, all decentralized clearing processes lead essentially to the same value of equity as a centralized clearing procedure. As a policy implication, it is not necessary to collect and process all the sensitive data of all the agents simultaneously and run a centralized clearing procedure.</description><author>Csoka, Peter; Herings, P. Jean-Jacques</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High-Powered Performance Pay and Crowding Out of Nonmonetary Motives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huffman, David; Bognanno, Michael
A previous literature cautions that paying workers for performance might crowd out nonmonetary motives towork hard. Empirical evidence from the field, however, has been based on between-subjects designs that are best suited for detecting crowding out due to low-powered incentives. High-powered incentives in the workplace tend to increase output, but it is unknown whether this masks crowding out. This paper uses a within-subject experimental design and finds evidence that crowding out also extends to high-powered incentives in a real work setting with paid workers. There is individual heterogeneity, however, with a minority of workers reporting crowding in of motivation. Thus, the impact of performance pay might depend on the mix of worker types.</description><author>Huffman, David; Bognanno, Michael</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Patient Triage and Prioritization Under Austere Conditions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Zhankun; Argon, Nilay Tanik; Ziya, Serhan
In war zones and economically deprived regions, because of extreme resource restrictions, a single provider may be the sole person in charge of providing emergency care to a group of patients. An important question the provider faces under such circumstances is whether or not to perform triage and how to prioritize the patients. By choosing to triage a particular patient, the provider can determine the health condition and thus the urgency of the patient, but that will come at the expense of delaying the actual service (stabilization or initial treatment) for that patient as well as all the other patients. Motivated by this problem, which also arises in other service contexts, we consider a service system where finitely many patients, all available at time zero, belong to one of the two possible triage classes, where each class is characterized by its waiting cost and expected service time. Patients' class identities are initially unknown, but the service provider has the option to spend time on triage to determine the class of a patient. Our objective is to identify policies that balance the time spent on triage with the time spent on service by minimizing the total expected cost. We provide a complete characterization of the optimal dynamic policy and show that the optimal dynamic policy that specifies when to perform triage is determined by a switching curve, and we provide a mathematical expression for this curve. One insight that comes out of this characterization is that the server should start with performing triage when there are sufficiently many patients and never perform triage when there are few patients. Finally, we carry out a numerical study in which we demonstrate how one can use our mathematical results to develop policies that can be used in mass-casualty triage and prioritization, and we find that there are substantial benefits to using one of these policies instead of the simpler benchmarks.</description><author>Sun, Zhankun; Argon, Nilay Tanik; Ziya, Serhan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Privacy Protection, Personalized Medicine, and Genetic Testing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Miller, Amalia R.; Tucker, Catherine
This paper explores how state genetic privacy laws affect the diffusion of personalized medicine, using data on genetic testing for cancer risks. State genetic privacy regimes employ and combine up to three alternative approaches to protecting patient privacy: Rules requiring that an individual is notified about potential privacy risks; rules restricting discriminatory usage of genetic data by employers or insurance companies; and rules limiting redisclosure without the consent of the individual. We find empirically that approaches to genetic and health privacy that give users control over redisclosure encourage the spread of genetic testing, but that notification deters individuals from obtaining genetic tests. We present some evidence that the latter reflects costs imposed on the supply of genetic testing by hospitals. We find no effects of state genetic antidiscrimination laws on genetic testing rates.</description><author>Miller, Amalia R.; Tucker, Catherine</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Catastrophe Aversion and Risk Equity in an Interdependent World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernard, Carole; Rheinberger, Christoph M.; Treich, Nicolas
Catastrophe aversion and risk equity are important concepts both in risk management theory and practice. Keeney [Keeney RL (1980) Equity and public risk. Oper. Res. 28(3):527-534] was the first to formally define these concepts. He demonstrated that the two concepts are always in conflict. Yet his result is based on the assumption that individual risks are independent. It has therefore limited relevance for real-world catastrophic events. We extend Keeney's result to dependent risks and derive the conditions under which more equity and more correlation between two risks imply a more catastrophic situation. We then generalize some of the results for multiple correlated risks.</description><author>Bernard, Carole; Rheinberger, Christoph M.; Treich, Nicolas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Death, Bereavement, and Creativity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graddy, Kathryn; Lieberman, Carl
Does creativity, on average, increase or decrease during bereavement? Dates of death of relatives and close friends of 33 French artists and 15 American artists were gathered from electronic sources and biographies, and information on over 15,000 paintings was collected from the Blouin Art Sales Index and the online collections of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, the Art Institute of Chicago, the National Gallery of Art, the J. Paul Getty Museum, and the Musee d'Orsay, including more than 12,000 observations on price. An event study indicates that there is no evidence that the death of a friend or relative makes an artist more creative, and there is some evidence that prices of paintings are significantly lower during the first year following the year of death of a friend or relative. Furthermore, paintings that were created during this bereavement period are less likely to be included in a major museum's collection.</description><author>Graddy, Kathryn; Lieberman, Carl</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hormonal Contraceptives Do Not Impact Economic Preferences: Evidence from a Randomized Trial</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ranehill, Eva; Zethraeus, Niklas; Blomberg, Liselott; von Schoultz, Bo; Hirschberg, Angelica Linden; Johannesson, Magnus; Dreber, Anna
A growing body of correlational studies suggests that sex hormones such as those contained in, or affected by, oral contraceptives (OCs) may impact economic behavior. However, despite widespread use of OCs among women in Western countries, little is known about their potential behavioral effects. The present study investigates whether OCs causally influence economic preferences. We randomly allocate 340 women aged 18-35 to three months of a widely used OC or placebo treatment. At the end of treatment, we conduct an economic experiment measuring altruism, financial risk taking, and willingness to compete. The statistical power is 80% to detect an effect size equal to a Cohen's d of 0.30 at the 5% level. We find no significant effects of OCs on any of the measured preferences, indicating that this widely used OC treatment, commonly used throughout the world, does not significantly affect the measured economic preferences. Further, we find no relation between menstrual cycle phase and economic preferences in the placebo group.</description><author>Ranehill, Eva; Zethraeus, Niklas; Blomberg, Liselott; von Schoultz, Bo; Hirschberg, Angelica Linden; Johannesson, Magnus; Dreber, Anna</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategy and the Strategist: How It Matters Who Develops the Strategy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Van den Steen, Eric
This paper addresses primarily two questions. First, when (and why) should a company's strategy be developed by its CEO versus by some outside analyst or other insider? Second, how does strategy interact with vision (in the sense of a strong belief about the right course of action)? The paper studies these questions using a functional definition of strategy as "the smallest set of choices to optimally guide other choices." Among other things, the paper shows that strategy formulation by the CEO leads to both better strategy and better execution, and that a strategist's vision may improve execution. In the process, the paper also identifies criteria that make a decision strategic and derives explanations why strategies often reflect the background of the strategist.</description><author>Van den Steen, Eric</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentives and Ratcheting in a Multiproduct Firm: A Field Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brahm, Francisco; Poblete, Joaquin
We develop a model and derive behavioral predictions for a multiproduct sales force subject to goals set based on past performance. We test these predictions using a field experiment in which 53 salespersons from a Chilean beverage company face exogenous variations in monthly sales goals. Confirming our predictions, we found that (1) absent strategic considerations-no goal ratcheting-salespersons increase (decrease) sales in the product category for which the return to effort increases (decreases), (2) including strategic considerations behavior reverses: salespersons who expect high goal ratcheting decrease (increase) sales in the category for which the return to effort increases (decreases), (3) sales did not change for the average salespersons, reflecting heterogeneity in the expectations of goal ratcheting rather than unresponsiveness to incentives. Our study points at the importance of the dynamics of incentive design, in particular, the importance of understanding the dynamics of goal setting in firms.</description><author>Brahm, Francisco; Poblete, Joaquin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Pricing Under Debt: Spiraling Distortions and Efficiency Losses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Besbes, Omar; Iancu, Dan A.; Trichakis, Nikolaos
Firms often finance their inventory through debt and subsequently sell it to generate profits and service the debt. Pricing of products is consequently driven by inventory and debt servicing considerations. We show that limited liability under debt induces sellers to charge higher prices and to discount products at a slower pace. We find that these distortions result in revenue losses that compound over time, leading to some form of performance spiral down. We quantify the extent to which these inefficiencies can be mitigated by practical debt contract terms that emerge as natural remedies from our analysis, and find debt amortization or financial covenants to be the most effective, followed by debt relief and early repayment options.</description><author>Besbes, Omar; Iancu, Dan A.; Trichakis, Nikolaos</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Procurement Policies for Mobile-Promotion Platforms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aseri, Manmohan; Dawande, Milind; Janakiraman, Ganesh; Mookerjee, Vijay
Mobile-promotion platforms enable advertisers (individual users or businesses) to directly launch their personalized mobile advertising campaigns. These platforms contract with advertisers to provide a certain number of impressions on mobile apps in their desired sets of geographic locations (usually cities or zip codes) within their desired time durations (for example, a month); the execution of each such a contract is referred to as a campaign. To fulfill the demands of the campaigns, the platform bids in real time at an ad exchange to win mobile impressions arising over the desired sets of locations of the campaigns and then allocates the acquired impressions among the ongoing campaigns. The core features that characterize this procurement problem-supply is uncertain, supply cannot be inventoried, and there are demand-side commitments to be met-are applicable to a variety of other business settings aswell. Our analysis in this paper offers near-optimal policies for both a static model and a dynamic model of campaign arrivals. The static model represents a subscription-based setting, where customers provide information of their campaigns in advance to the platform. The dynamic model represents a setting where campaigns arrive randomly and the platform reacts to these arrivals in real time; for this model, our rolling-horizon policy periodically recomputes the platform's procurement (or bidding) and allocation decisions. We establish performance bounds on our policies for both models and demonstrate the attractiveness of these bounds on real data. By isolating important structural features of a given set of campaigns, we discuss practical implementation issues and offer procurement-policy recommendations for a variety of settings based on these features.</description><author>Aseri, Manmohan; Dawande, Milind; Janakiraman, Ganesh; Mookerjee, Vijay</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>User-Generated Content and Competing Firms' Product Design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kwark, Young; Chen, Jianqing; Raghunathan, Srinivasan
Firms employ various techniques to obtain information about consumer taste/location and valuation prior to making product design decisions. User-generated content has become an important information source. The vast variety and volume of user-generated content makes firms better informed about consumers (precision-improving effect), and the common and public nature of user-generated content makes firms' information more correlated (correlation-increasing effect). We examine the impact of user-generated content in a setting in which two competing firms that are uncertain about consumer location or valuation design and sell horizontally differentiated products. We find that user-generated content has very different implications for competing firms' location decisions and quality decisions. When firms are uncertain about consumer taste and choose their product locations, whether firms and/or consumers benefit from the user-generated content depends on which of the two effects dominates. We find that only when the correlation-increasing effect is moderate, a win-win scenario for both firms and consumers occurs, but the society always benefits from user-generated content. Stronger consumer preference strengthens the overall impact of user-generated content. In sharp contrast, when firms face uncertain consumer valuation of quality and choose product quality, they do not benefit from user-generated content, but consumers may benefit or lose from it. When the correlation-increasing effect is significant, both firms and consumers, and therefore the society, are hurt by user-generated content. Stronger consumer preference mitigates the negative impact but amplifies the positive impact of user-generated content in this case.</description><author>Kwark, Young; Chen, Jianqing; Raghunathan, Srinivasan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of Multidimensional Rating Systems: Evidence from a Natural Experiment and Randomized Experiments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Pei-Yu; Hong, Yili; Liu, Ying
Online product ratings offer information on product quality. Scholars have recently proposed the potential of designing multidimensional rating systems to better convey information on multiple dimensions of products. This study investigates whether and how multidimensional rating systems affect consumer satisfaction (measured by product ratings), based on both observational data and two randomized experiments. Our identification strategy of the observational study hinges on a natural experiment on TripAdvisor when the website started to allow consumers to rate multiple dimensions of the restaurants, as opposed to only providing an overall rating, in January 2009. We further obtain rating data on the same set of restaurants from Yelp, which controls for the unobserved restaurant quality over time and allows us to identify the causal effect using a difference-in-differences approach. Results from the econometric analyses show that ratings in a single-dimensional rating system have a downward trend and a higher dispersion, whereas ratings in a multidimensional rating system are significantly higher and convergent. Findings from two randomized experiments suggest that the multidimensional rating system helps consumers find products that better fit their preferences and increases the confidence of their choices. We also show that the observed results cannot be explained by the priming effect due to rating system interface or a list of other alternative explanations. The combined evidence from the natural experiment and randomized experiments support the view that the multidimensional rating system enhances rating informativeness and provide implications for designing online rating systems that help consumers match their preferences with product attributes.</description><author>Chen, Pei-Yu; Hong, Yili; Liu, Ying</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Communication, Incentives, and the Execution of a Strategic initiative</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hutchison-Krupat, Jeremy
Senior leadership has two primary levers to influence a direct report: incentives and communication. Financial incentives are credible and precisely specified but offer limited flexibility. In contrast, communication is flexible but lacks precision, and must be deemed credible to affect a direct report's actions. We study a setting where senior leadership seeks to add a new initiative to their organization's portfolio. The initiative's potential to create value is not initially well understood. Senior leadership eventually obtains more precise information on the initiative's value and subsequently may communicate this information to their direct report. We analyze senior leadership's incentive and communication decisions, and ultimately their portfolio decision. We find that senior leadership's communication only affects a direct report's actions when a new initiative's potential to create value is sufficiently uncertain. Additionally, we find instances where an organization may benefit from communication that offers lessspecificity.</description><author>Hutchison-Krupat, Jeremy</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should Intangible Investments Be Reported Separately or Commingled with Operating Expenses? New Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Enache, Luminita; Srivastava, Anup
We propose a new method to estimate intangible investment outlays, other than expenditures on advertising and research and development, that are reported on a commingled basis with operating expenses in the selling, general, and administrative category of expenses. These outlays, aimed at improving organizational knowledge and capabilities, are the largest category of intangible investments and the fastest-growing category of operating investments. They affect future firm performance and risk. Predictability of future earnings and stock returns improves when these outlays are distinguished from operating expenses. Thus, benefits could accrue from reporting them separately.</description><author>Enache, Luminita; Srivastava, Anup</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Design of Sparse but Efficient Structures in Operations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yan, Zhenzhen; Gao, Sarah Yini; Teo, Chung Piaw
It is widely believed that a little flexibility added at the right place can reap significant benefits for operations. Unfortunately, despite the extensive literature on this topic, we are not aware of any general methodology that can be used to guide managers in designing sparse (i.e., slightly flexible) and yet efficient operations. We address this issue using a distributionally robust approach to model the performance of a stochastic system under different process structures. We use the dual prices obtained from a related conic program to guide managers in the design process. This leads to a general solution methodology for the construction of efficient sparse structures for several classes of operational problems. Our approach can be used to design simple yet efficient structures for workforce deployment and for any level of sparsity requirement, to respond to deviations and disruptions in the operational environment. Furthermore, in the case of the classical process flexibility problem, our methodology can recover the k-chain structures that are known to be extremely efficient for this type of problem when the system is balanced and symmetric. We can also obtain the analog of 2-chain for nonsymmetrical system using this methodology.</description><author>Yan, Zhenzhen; Gao, Sarah Yini; Teo, Chung Piaw</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding Uncontested Director Elections</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ertimur, Yonca; Ferri, Fabrizio; Oesch, David
We examine the determinants and consequences of voting outcomes in uncontested director elections. Exploiting a unique hand-collected data set of the rationale behind proxy advisors' recommendations-the primary driver of voting outcomes-we document the director and board characteristics on which voting shareholders focus (as well as those that they neglect), their evolution over time, and their relative importance. Absent a negative recommendation, high votes withheld are infrequent, highlighting the agenda-setting role of proxy advisors. While high votes withheld rarely result in director turnover, our analyses show that firms often respond to an adverse vote by explicitly addressing the underlying concern. Overall, it appears that shareholders use their votes in uncontested director elections to get directors to address specific problems, rather than to vote them onto or off of the board, but they do so only on matters highlighted by the proxy advisors.</description><author>Ertimur, Yonca; Ferri, Fabrizio; Oesch, David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictably Angry-Facial Cues Provide a Credible Signal of Destructive Behavior (vol 64, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Leeuwen, Boris; Noussair, Charles N.; Offerman, Theo; Suetens, Sigrid; van Veelen, Matthijs; van de Ven, Jeroen
nan</description><author>van Leeuwen, Boris; Noussair, Charles N.; Offerman, Theo; Suetens, Sigrid; van Veelen, Matthijs; van de Ven, Jeroen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Prospect Theory Explain the Disposition Effect? A New Perspective on Reference Points</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Meng, Juanjuan; Weng, Xi
There has been recent debate about whether prospect theory can explain the disposition effect. Using both theory and simulation, this paper shows that prospect theory often predicts the disposition effect when lagged expected final wealth is the reference point under the principle of preferred personal equilibrium, regardless of whether the reference point is updated or not. When initial wealth is the reference point, however, there is often no disposition effect. Models that use a reference point with no lag under the principle of preferred personal equilibrium or that determine the reference point using the principle of disappointment aversion cannot explain why the investor bought a stock in the first place. Reference point adjustment weakens the disposition effect, leads to more aggressive initial stock purchase strategies, and predicts history dependence in stock holding.</description><author>Meng, Juanjuan; Weng, Xi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Millennial-Style Learning: Search Intensity, Decision Making, and Information Sharing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlin, Bruce; Jiang, Li; Spiller, Stephen A.
The growing use of online educational content and related video services has changed the way people access education, share knowledge, and possibly make life decisions. In this paper, we characterize how video content affects individual decision making and willingness to share in the context of a personal financial decision. We find that distracting advertising curtails the time people invest in searching for the best alternative and causes worse decisions. Content geared toward giving better instructions helps to overcome this effect. Such actionable content improves both search quality and financial decisions. However, including such content may decrease sharing unless it is perceived to be sufficiently useful. As such, there is a potential risk to adding actionable content to videos. Our work has important implications for policies guiding financial literacy training, and it also has broader impact for education in the information age.</description><author>Carlin, Bruce; Jiang, Li; Spiller, Stephen A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity Provision and the Cross Section of Hedge Fund Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jame, Russell
I investigate whether hedge funds that supply liquidity earn superior returns. Using transaction data, I find that hedge funds following short-term contrarian strategies (i.e., liquidity suppliers) earn significantly higher returns on their equity trades and holdings. Similarly, using commercial databases, I find that hedge funds with greater exposure to a liquidity provision factor earn significantly higher excess returns and Sharpe ratios. The superior performance of liquidity-supplying hedge funds arises from strategies that are more complex than mechanical short-term reversal strategies. For example, among stocks with similar past returns, liquidity-supplying funds are more likely to trade against stocks heavily traded by constrained mutual funds and less likely to trade against stocks heavily traded by unconstrained mutual funds. The outperformance of liquidity-supplying funds is also concentrated in periods of low funding liquidity, suggesting that less-binding financial constraints contribute to their superior returns.</description><author>Jame, Russell</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Offshore Expertise for Onshore Companies: Director Connections to Island Tax Havens and Corporate Tax Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Chao; Kubick, Thomas R.; Miletkov, Mihail K.; Wintoki, M. Babajide
Theory and recent empirical literature suggest that social and professional connections may influence corporate policy. However, inference may be biased by the possibility that firms who share peers also share unobserved characteristics that are correlated with observed policy. Using a novel identification strategy, we predict and find that director connections through well-known island tax havens have a significant effect on corporate tax policy. Specifically, we find that U.S. firms with directors who are connected to firms domiciled on the islands of the Bahamas, Bermuda, or the Caymans exhibit significantly greater tax avoidance than other U.S. firms. The presence or arrival of an island director is associated with a reduction of between one and three percentage points in the firm's effective tax rate. We also observe a significant increase in the use of tax haven subsidiaries following the arrival of the island director.</description><author>Jiang, Chao; Kubick, Thomas R.; Miletkov, Mihail K.; Wintoki, M. Babajide</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Rich Domain of Ambiguity Explored</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Zhihua; Mueller, Julia; Wakker, Peter P.; Wang, Tong
Ellsberg and others suggested that decision under ambiguity is a rich empirical domain with many phenomena to be investigated beyond the Ellsberg urns. We provide a systematic empirical investigation of this richness by varying the uncertain events, the outcomes, and combinations of both. Although ambiguity aversion is prevailing, we also find systematic ambiguity seeking, confirming insensitivity. We find that ambiguity attitudes depend on the kind of uncertainty (the source) but not on the kind of outcomes. Ambiguity attitudes are closer to rationality (ambiguity neutrality) for natural uncertainties than for artificial Ellsberg urn uncertainties. This also appears from the reductions of monotonicity violations and of insensitivity. Ambiguity attitudes have predictive power across different outcomes and sources of uncertainty, with individual-specific components. Our rich domain serves well to test families of weighting functions for fitting ambiguity attitudes. We find that two-parameter families, capturing not only aversion but also insensitivity, are desirable for ambiguity even more than for risk. The Goldstein-Einhorn family performed best for ambiguity.</description><author>Li, Zhihua; Mueller, Julia; Wakker, Peter P.; Wang, Tong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Quality Ladder Model Predictions in Nonrandom Holdout Samples</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xu, Linli; Silva-Risso, Jorge M.; Wilbur, Kenneth C.
In light of recent calls for further validation of structural models, this paper evaluates the popular dynamic quality ladder (DQL) model using a nonrandom holdout approach. The model is used to predict data following a regime shift-that is, a change in the environment that produced the estimation data. The prediction performance is evaluated relative to a benchmark vector autoregression (VAR) model across three automotive categories and multiple prediction horizons. Whereas the VAR model performs better in all scenarios in the compact car category, the DQL model tends to perform better on multiple-year horizons in both the midsize car and full-size pickup categories. A supplementary data analysis suggests that DQL model performance in the nonrandom holdout prediction task is better in categories that are more affected by the regime shift, helping to validate the usefulness of the dynamic structural model for making predictions after policy changes.</description><author>Xu, Linli; Silva-Risso, Jorge M.; Wilbur, Kenneth C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder Protection and Agency Costs: An Experimental Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>LaRiviere, Jacob; McMahon, Matthew; Neilson, William
Two competing principal-agent models explain why firms pay dividends. The substitute model proposes that corporate insiders pay dividends to signal and build trust with outside shareholders who lack legal protection. The outcome model, in contrast, surmises that when shareholders have legal protection, they demand dividends from insiders to prevent them from expropriating corporate funds. Either way, dividends represent an agency cost paid to align the interests of shareholders and insiders. Expropriations by insiders and reduced investment by shareholders are also agency costs, but they are difficult to identify with archival data. Using a laboratory experiment, we identify the impact of strengthened shareholder protection on all three types of agency costs. Dividend payout ratios are five times larger with stronger investor protection, insider expropriation ratios are twice as high, and outsider investment falls by 45%. Thus, we find evidence that strengthening shareholder protection introduces previously unidentified agency costs into the insider-investor relationship.</description><author>LaRiviere, Jacob; McMahon, Matthew; Neilson, William</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Copyright Affect Reuse? Evidence from Google Books and Wikipedia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nagaraj, Abhishek
While digitization has greatly increased the reuse of knowledge, this study shows how these benefits might be mitigated by copyright restrictions. I use the digitization of in-copyright and out-of-copyright issues of Baseball Digest magazine by Google Books to measure the impact of copyright on knowledge reuse in Wikipedia. I exploit a feature of the 1909 Copyright Act whereby material published before 1964 has lapsed into the public domain, allowing for the causal estimation of the impact of copyright across this sharp cutoff. I find that, while digitization encourages knowledge reuse, copyright restrictions reduce citations to copyrighted issues of Baseball Digest by up to 135% and affect readership by reducing traffic to affected pages by 20%. These impacts are highly uneven: copyright hurts the reuse of images rather than text and affects Wikipedia pages for less-popular players greater than more-popular ones.</description><author>Nagaraj, Abhishek</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Impact of Queue Configuration on Service Time: Evidence from a Supermarket</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Jingqi; Zhou, Yong-Pin
We study how queue configuration affects human servers' service time by comparing dedicated queues with shared queues using field data from a natural experiment in a supermarket. We hypothesize that queue configuration may affect servers' service rate through several mechanisms: pooling may affect service rate directly as a result of social loafing effect and competition effect and indirectly via its impact on queue length. To investigate these impacts, we take advantage of the supermarket's checkout layout and use a data set containing both checkout transaction details and queue information collected from video recordings in the supermarket. After we control for the queue length, we find that servers in dedicated queues are about 10.7% faster than those in shared queues, mainly because of the social loafing effect. We also demonstrate that pooling has an indirect negative effect on service time through its impact on queue length. In addition, the queue configuration's direct effect and its indirect queue length effect function independently of each other. In aggregation, the social loafing effect dominates, and servers slow down (a 6.86% increase in service time) in shared queues.</description><author>Wang, Jingqi; Zhou, Yong-Pin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hiring Preferences in Online Labor Markets: Evidence of a Female Hiring Bias</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Jason; Wang, Jing
Online labor marketplaces facilitate the efficient matching of employers and workers across geographical boundaries. The exponential growth of this nascent online phenomenon holds important social and economic implications, as the hiring decisions made on these online platforms implicate the incomes of millions of workers worldwide. Despite this importance, limited effort has been devoted to understanding whether potential hiring biases exist in online labor platforms and how they may affect hiring outcomes. Using a novel proprietary data set from a leading online labor platform, we investigate the impact of gender-based stereotypes on hiring outcomes. After accounting for endogeneity via a holistic set of job and worker controls, a matched sample approach, and a quasi-experimental technique, we find evidence of a positive hiring bias in favor of female workers. An experiment was used to uncover the underlying gender-specific traits that could influence hiring outcomes. We find that the observed hiring bias diminishes as employers gain more hiring experience on the platform. In addition, the female hiring bias appears to stem solely from the consideration of applicants from developing countries, and not those from developed countries. Subanalyses show that women are preferred in feminine-typed occupations while men do not enjoy higher hiring likelihoods in masculine-typed occupations. We also find that female employers are more susceptible to the female hiring bias compared to male employers. Our findings provide key insights for several groups of stakeholders including policy makers, platform owners, hiring managers, and workers. Managerial and practical implications are discussed.</description><author>Chan, Jason; Wang, Jing</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Doing Well by Making Well: The Impact of Corporate Wellness Programs on Employee Productivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gubler, Timothy; Larkin, Ian; Pierce, Lamar
This paper investigates the impact of a corporate wellness program on worker productivity using a panel of objective health and productivity data from 111 workers in five laundry plants. Although almost 90% of companies use wellness programs, existing research has focused on cost savings from insurance and absenteeism. We find productivity improvements based both on program participation and postprogram health changes. Sick and healthy individuals who improved their health increased productivity by about 10%, with surveys indicating sources in improved diet and exercise. Although the small worker sample limits both estimate precision and our ability to isolate mechanisms behind this increase, we argue that our results are consistent with improved worker motivation and capability. The study suggests that firms can increase operational productivity through socially responsible health policies that improve both workers' wellness and economic value, and provides a template for future large-scale studies of health and productivity.</description><author>Gubler, Timothy; Larkin, Ian; Pierce, Lamar</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Awareness Reduces Racial Bias</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pope, Devin G.; Price, Joseph; Wolfers, Justin
Can raising awareness of racial bias subsequently reduce that bias? We address this question by exploiting the widespread media attention highlighting racial bias among professional basketball referees that occurred in May 2007 following the release of an academic study. Using new data, we confirm that racial bias persisted in the years after the study's original sample but prior to the media coverage. Subsequent to the media coverage, though, the bias disappeared. Several potential mechanisms may have produced this result, including voluntary behavior changes by individual referees, adjustments by players to new information, and changes in referee behavior due to institutional pressure. These results suggest a new kind of Hawthorne effect in which greater scrutiny of even subtle forms of bias can bring about meaningful change.</description><author>Pope, Devin G.; Price, Joseph; Wolfers, Justin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Implications of Market Spillovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fazli, Amir; Shulman, Jeffrey D.
In recent years, several firms have decided to withdraw from profitable markets, believing the move will be beneficial for their overall business. For instance, CVS dropped tobacco products from its shelves in 2014, while Aldi dropped confectionery from its checkout lines in 2016. Findings from consumers' evaluation of such moves suggest there exists a negative market spillover from selling in a market, such that a firm's participation in one market reduces consumers' willingness to pay for the firm's products in other markets. On the other hand, certain socially favorable markets, such as markets for environment-friendly products, have been shown to create a positive market spillover for their sellers, increasing consumers' willingness to pay in other markets the sellers participate in. We build an analytical model of two competing firms to examine how firms react to a market spillover and find the conditions under which different firms would sell in the spillover-producing market. Our analysis of how firms' profits are affected by market spillovers identifies the consumers' reservation value in the spillover-producing market, the relative size of the two markets, and the extent of the market spillover as key factors determining which firms benefit from a market spillover. Interestingly, we find it is possible for both firms to make more profit with a negative market spillover compared to when there is no market spillover, while a positive market spillover can actually result in lower profits for both firms compared to no market spillover.</description><author>Fazli, Amir; Shulman, Jeffrey D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competitive vs. Complementary Effects in Online Social Networks and News Consumption: A Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sismeiro, Catarina; Mahmood, Ammara
Using hourly traffic and readership data from a major news website, and taking advantage of a global Facebook outage, we study the relationship between social networks and online news consumption. More specifically, we test if online social networks compete with content providers or instead play a complementary role by promoting and attracting traffic to external websites. During the outage, consistent with a promotional effect, we observe a significant decrease in traffic and unique visitors to the news website lasting beyond the outage hours. We further find that direct referrals from Facebook links grossly underestimated the actual impact of Facebook in generating traffic. Instead, during the outage, we observe a more significant reduction in visitors arriving at the news website from search engines or directly typing the website URL or using bookmarks. Additionally, readership of articles and types of pages viewed also changed during the outage. Although we observe a drop in news consumption during the outage hours for all news categories, the subsequent news consumption differs across categories. Time sensitive categories like sports and local news see an increase in consumption, whereas news on women issues or health topics see a decrease. Analysis of individual-level visit and readership behavior during the outage also reveals that Facebook not only introduces selectivity bias by attracting shallower readers but also changes readership patterns (in the absence of Facebook, visitors engage in more in-depth reading). To test the generalizability of our results, we study the impact of the outage on referrals from other social media outlets, on other news sites, and on other content and e-commerce sites. We find similar effects on other news providers, whereas data from nonnews sites, including e-commerce, show no major outage effects. Overall, our results have important managerial implications. We highlight how our results unearth the importance of search engine optimization and of strong branding for news websites, if providers want to harness fully the power of their social media presence.</description><author>Sismeiro, Catarina; Mahmood, Ammara</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Approximation Algorithms for Capacitated Perishable Inventory Systems with Positive Lead Times</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chao, Xiuli; Gong, Xiting; Shi, Cong; Yang, Chaolin; Zhang, Huanan; Zhou, Sean X.
Managing perishable inventory systems with positive lead times and finite ordering capacities is important but notoriously difficult in both theory and computation. The optimal control policy is extremely complicated, and no effective heuristic policy has been proposed in the literature. In this paper, we develop an easy-to-compute approximation algorithm for this class of problems and prove that it admits a theoretical worst-case performance guarantee under independent and many commonly used positively correlated demand processes. Our worst-case analysis departs significantly from those in the previous studies, requiring several novel ideas. In particular, we introduce a transient unit-matching rule to dynamically match the supply and demand units, and the notion of associated demand processes that provides the right future demand information to establish the desired results. Our numerical study demonstrates the effectiveness of the proposed algorithm.</description><author>Chao, Xiuli; Gong, Xiting; Shi, Cong; Yang, Chaolin; Zhang, Huanan; Zhou, Sean X.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Design Incentives Under Collective Extended Producer Responsibility: A Network Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gui, Luyi; Atasu, Atalay; Ergun, Ozlem; Toktay, L. Beril
A key goal of Extended Producer Responsibility (EPR) legislation is to provide incentives for producers to design their products for recyclability. EPR is typically implemented in a collective system, where a network of recycling resources are coordinated to fulfill the EPR obligations of a set of producers, and the resulting system cost is allocated among these producers. Collective EPR is prevalent because of its cost efficiency advantages. However, it is considered to provide inferior design incentives compared to an individual implementation (where producers fulfill their EPR obligations individually). In this paper, we revisit this assertion and investigate its fundamental underpinnings in a network setting. To this end, we develop a new biform game framework that captures producers' independent design choices (noncooperative stage) and recognizes the need to maintain the voluntary participation of producers for the collective system to be stable (cooperative stage). This biform game subsumes the network-based operations of a collective system and captures the interdependence between producers' product design and participation decisions. We then characterize the manner in which design improvement may compromise stability and vice versa. We establish that a stable collective EPR implementation can match and even surpass an individual implementation with respect to product design outcomes. In particular, we show that when the processing technology efficiency and product recyclability are substitutes (complements), a recycling network where processor capacity pooling leads to sufficiently low (high) cost reduction will lead to superior designs in the collective system and maintain its stability, and we propose cost allocation mechanisms to achieve this dual purpose.</description><author>Gui, Luyi; Atasu, Atalay; Ergun, Ozlem; Toktay, L. Beril</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Advertising Content and Consumer Engagement on Social Media: Evidence from Facebook</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Dokyun; Hosanagar, Kartik; Nair, Harikesh S.
We describe the effect of social media advertising content on customer engagement using data from Facebook. We content-code 106,316 Facebook messages across 782 companies, using a combination of Amazon Mechanical Turk and natural language processing algorithms. We use this data set to study the association of various kinds of social media marketing content with user engagement-defined as Likes, comments, shares, and click-throughs-with the messages. We find that inclusion of widely used content related to brand personality-like humor and emotion-is associated with higher levels of consumer engagement (Likes, comments, shares) with a message. We find that directly informative content-like mentions of price and deals-is associated with lower levels of engagement when included in messages in isolation, but higher engagement levels when provided in combination with brand personality-related attributes. Also, certain directly informative content, such as deals and promotions, drive consumers' path to conversion (click-throughs). These results persist after incorporating corrections for the nonrandom targeting of Facebook's EdgeRank (News Feed) algorithm and so reflect more closely user reaction to content than Facebook's behavioral targeting. Our results suggest that there are benefits to content engineering that combines informative characteristics that help in obtaining immediate leads (via improved click-throughs) with brand personality-related content that helps in maintaining future reach and branding on the social media site (via improved engagement). These results inform content design strategies. Separately, the methodologywe apply to content-code text is useful for future studies utilizing unstructured data such as advertising content or product reviews.</description><author>Lee, Dokyun; Hosanagar, Kartik; Nair, Harikesh S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Theory of Disclosure in Speculative Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hertzberg, Andrew
This paper presents a theory of disclosure in a market where investors have heterogeneous beliefs and face short-sale constraints. Assets trade above fundamentals reflecting the value of the option to sell to more optimistic investors in the future. The initial seller has an incentive to commit to an imprecise disclosure policy, despite the negative effect this has on the fundamental value of the asset, in order to increase the potential for disagreement and hence the magnitude of the speculative premium. I show that there is a strategic complementarity between sellers in their disclosure decisions. This explains why financial misreporting and episodes of speculation occur together in waves and demonstrates that the endogenous choice of imprecise disclosure amplifies the extent to which assets are overpriced.</description><author>Hertzberg, Andrew</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Making Out Globally: Individualism, Investor Attention, and the Cross Section of Expected Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheon, Yong-Ho; Lee, Kuan-Hui
We examine the role of cultural difference in the pricing of positive extreme returns (MAX) for 47,000 stocks from 42 countries from 1990 to 2012. We find that investors overpay for stocks with high MAX and that MAX-premium, the spread from long-short strategy based on low- and high-MAX stocks, is both statistically and economically significant worldwide. The negative relation between idiosyncratic volatility and expected returns, or idiosyncratic volatility puzzle, exists only for stocks with high MAX, implying that the puzzle may arise from the overpayment for stocks with high MAX and the subsequent return reversal. Consistent with the expectation that overpayment will be stronger for overconfident investors, the MAX-premium is larger in countries with high individualism index (IDV) than it is in countries with low IDV. Furthermore, we find the MAX-premium to be larger and the difference in the MAX-premium between high- and low-IDV countries to be more pronounced when VIX and volatility are high. Our findings suggest that the attention-grabbing feature of stocks with high MAX affects the pricing of extreme positive returns asymmetrically depending on the cultural differences across countries.</description><author>Cheon, Yong-Ho; Lee, Kuan-Hui</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revolving Ratina Analysts and Ratings of Mortgage-Backed and Asset-Backed Securities: Evidence from LinkedIn</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, John; Wang, Isabel Y.; Wang, K. Philip
This study examines whether revolving rating analysts who transition from major rating agencies to issuers are associated with any rating inflation in the issuers' mortgage-backed securities (MBS) or asset-backed securities (ABS). Using professional profiles posted on LinkedIn to identify revolving rating analysts with structured finance rating experience, we find that the more the issuers employ such analysts, the more likely that ratings of issuers' MBS and ABS new issuances are inflated compared with otherwise similarly rated securities. Additional analyses show that the impact of revolving rating analysts is more pronounced in complex deals and when the revolving analysts are more senior, indicating that rating expertise in structured finance may play a role in MBS and ABS rating inflation. Finally, we find that at least for AAA-rated MBS and ABS, investors fail to see through the rating inflation associated with revolving rating analysts.</description><author>Jiang, John; Wang, Isabel Y.; Wang, K. Philip</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Chief for a Day: Elite Capture and Management Performance in a Field Experiment in Sierra Leone</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Voors, Maarten; Turley, Ty; Bulte, Erwin; Kontoleon, Andreas; List, John A.
We use a field experiment in Sierra Leone to examine how the identity of the manager influences rent seeking and performance in participatory development projects. Specifically, we vary the composition of a committee responsible for implementing a development project-local elites or randomly selected villagers. The design is unique in that it permits us to explore the effectiveness of two alternative local governance modalities and the extent of elite capture in community projects. We find little evidence that local elites capture project resources. We do observe they are better managers of development projects. Improved performance covaries with a proxy for power of the local chief.</description><author>Voors, Maarten; Turley, Ty; Bulte, Erwin; Kontoleon, Andreas; List, John A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gender Composition and Group Confidence Judgment: The Perils of All-Male Groups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keck, Steffen; Tang, Wenjie
We explore the joint effects of group decision making and group gender composition on the calibration of confidence judgments. Participants in two laboratory experiments, individually and in groups of three, stated confidence interval estimates for general-knowledge questions and for financial forecasts. Across both studies, our results reveal that groups with at least one female member are significantly better calibrated than all-male groups. This effect is mediated by the extent to which group members share opinions and information during the group discussion. Moreover, we find that compared to a statistical aggregation of individual confidence intervals, group discussions have a neutral or positive effect on the quality of confidence judgments for groups with at least one female group member; in contrast, group discussion actually harms confidence calibration for all-male groups. Overall, our findings indicate that compared to all-male groups, even the inclusion of a small proportion of female members can have a strong effect on the quality of group confidence judgment.</description><author>Keck, Steffen; Tang, Wenjie</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Oh What a Beautiful Morning ! Diurnal InfIuences on Executives and Analysts: Evidence from Conference Calls</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Jing; Demers, Elizabeth; Lev, Baruch
This study provides novel evidence that expert economic agents' work-related activities are systematically influenced by the time of day. We use archival data derived from time-stamped quarterly earnings conference calls together with linguistic algorithms to measure and track the moods of executives and analysts at different times of the day. The evidence indicates that the tone of conference call discussions deteriorates markedly over the course of the trading day, with both analysts' and executives' moods becoming more negative as the day wears on. Capital market pricing tests reveal that the time-of-day-induced negative tone leads to temporary stock mispricings. Our findings are relevant because the diurnal variations in behavior documented in the context of quarterly earnings calls are likely to extend across other important corporate communication, decision making, and performance situations, leading to potentially significant economic consequences.</description><author>Chen, Jing; Demers, Elizabeth; Lev, Baruch</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informational Shocks, Off-Label Prescribing, and the Effects of Physician Detailing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shapiro, Bradley T.
The relationship between pharmaceutical detailing and prescriptions for non-FDA-approved (off-label) use has been the subject of regulatory scrutiny, with more than $12 billion in regulatory settlements for off-label promotion since 2004. Using the case of AstraZeneca's antipsychotic drug, Seroquel, I study the extent to which off-label prescriptions are caused by detailing. Using a physician panel that connects detailing exposure to medical charts, I exploit within-physician variation to identify detailing effects. I find the effect of detailing on off-label prescriptions is small in both absolute and relative terms. Detailing on net tilts the prescribing distribution toward on-label.</description><author>Shapiro, Bradley T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Simultaneous Preferences for Hedging and Doubling Down: Focal Prospects, Background Positions, and Nonconsequentialist Conceptualizations of Uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Markle, Alex B.; Rottenstreich, Yuval
Most theories of decision making are consequentialist. They presume that people evaluate prospects on the basis of potential outcomes. However, people may often conceptualize prospects in part nonconsequentially. Consider someone evaluating a new, "focal" prospect given an unresolved "background" position to which that person is already exposed. If the two are positively correlated, the individual may conceptualize the focal prospect as a bet "with" the individual's background position; if they are negatively correlated, the individual may conceptualize the focal prospect as a bet "against" the individual's background position. Because people like to be consistent, this nonconsequentialist conceptualization may induce a taste for betting "with" the background position. Such bets constitute risk-seeking doubling down, not risk-averse hedging. Indeed, we observe that relative to corresponding background-less choices, participants with unresolved background positions are relatively risk-seeking, favoring positively rather than negatively correlated focal prospects. They also sometimes show a simultaneous taste for both doubling down and hedging.</description><author>Markle, Alex B.; Rottenstreich, Yuval</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Does Advertising Depend on Competition? Evidence from US Brewing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chandra, Ambarish; Weinberg, Matthew
The relationship between market structure and advertising has been extensively studied, but has generated sharply opposing theoretical predictions, as well as inconclusive empirical findings, likely because of severe endogeneity concerns. We exploit the 2008 merger of Miller and Coors in the U.S. brewing industry to examine how changes in local concentration affect firms' advertising behavior. Well-established regional preferences over beer brands, and the sharp increase in concentration from the merger, make this an excellent setting to analyze this question. We find a significant positive effect of local market concentration on advertising expenditures: a 100-point increase in the Herfindahl-Hirschmann Index measure of concentration increases advertising per capita by about 5%. Our findings shed light on how and when firms choose to deploy advertising.</description><author>Chandra, Ambarish; Weinberg, Matthew</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Autoscaling in Cloud Computing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fazli, Amir; Sayedi, Amin; Shulman, Jeffrey D.
Web-based firms often rely on cloud-based computational resources to serve customers, but the number of customers they will serve is rarely known at the time of product launch. A recent innovation in cloud computing, known as autoscaling, allows companies to automatically scale their computational load up or down to match customer demand. We build a game theory model to examine how autoscaling will affect firms' decisions to enter a new market and the resulting equilibrium prices, profitability, and consumer surplus. The model produces novel results depending on the likelihood of a firm's success in the new market, differentiation among potential entrants, and the cost of computational capacity. For instance, in contrast to previous capacity commitment models with demand certainty, we show that autoscaling can mitigate price competition if the likelihood of a firm's success in the market is moderate and the cost of capacity is sufficiently low. This is because without autoscaling, the firms' uncertainty about demand would lead to excessive computational capacities and thus aggressive price competition. We also find that when the likelihood of success is sufficiently high, autoscaling facilitates entry for one firm yet deters a second firm from simultaneously entering the market.</description><author>Fazli, Amir; Sayedi, Amin; Shulman, Jeffrey D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Training Aspiring Entrepreneurs to Pitch Experienced Investors: Evidence from a Field Experiment in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clingingsmith, David; Shane, Scott
Accredited investors finance more than 75,000 U.S. startups annually. We explain how training aspiring entrepreneurs to pitch their new business ideas to these investors affects their odds of continued funding discussions. We model accredited investors' decision to continue investigation as a real option whose value is a function of their experience and the information contained in the entrepreneurs' pitches. We derive four hypotheses from the model, which we test through a field experiment that randomly assigns pitch training at four elevator pitch competitions. The data support all four hypotheses and are inconsistent with alternative explanations.</description><author>Clingingsmith, David; Shane, Scott</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Mechanisms with Martingale Utilities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balseiro, Santiago R.; Mirrokni, Vahab S.; Leme, Renato Paes
We study the dynamic mechanism design problem of a seller who repeatedly sells independent items to a buyer with private values. In this setting, the seller could potentially extract the entire buyer surplus by running efficient auctions and charging an upfront participation fee at the beginning of the horizon. In some markets, such as Internet advertising, participation fees are not practical since buyers expect to inspect items before purchasing them. This motivates us to study the design of dynamic mechanisms under successively more stringent requirements that capture the implicit business constraints of these markets. We first consider a periodic individual rationality constraint, which limits the mechanism to charge at most the buyer's value in each period. While this prevents large upfront participation fees, the seller can still design mechanisms that spread a participation fee across multiple initial auctions. These mechanisms have the unappealing feature that they provide close-to-zero buyer utility in earlier auctions in exchange for higher utility in later auctions. To address this problem, we introduce a martingale utility constraint, which imposes the requirement that from the perspective of the buyer, the next item's expected utility is equal to the present one's. Our main result is providing a dynamic auction satisfying martingale utility and periodic individual rationality whose loss in profit with respect to first-best (full extraction of buyer surplus) is optimal up to polylogarithmic factors. The proposed mechanism is a dynamic two-tier auction with a hard floor and a soft floor that allocates the item whenever the buyer's bid is above the hard floor and charges the minimum of the bid and the soft floor.</description><author>Balseiro, Santiago R.; Mirrokni, Vahab S.; Leme, Renato Paes</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Workload Management in Telemedical Physician Triage and Other Knowledge-Based Service Systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saghafian, Soroush; Hopp, Wallace J.; Iravani, Seyed M. R.; Cheng, Yao; Diermeier, Daniel
Telemedical physician triage (TPT) is an example of a hierarchical knowledge-based service system (HKBSS) in which a second level of decision agent (telemedical physician) renders a decision on cases referred to him or her by the primary level agents (triage nurses). Managing the speed-versus-quality trade-off in such systems presents a unique challenge because of the interplay between agent knowledge and flow of work between the two levels. We develop a novel model of agent knowledge, based on the beta distribution, and deploy it in a partially observable Markov decision process model to describe the optimal policy for deciding which cases (patients) to refer to the second level for further evaluation. We show that this policy has a monotone control-limit structure that reduces the fraction of decisions made at the upper level as workload increases. Because the optimal policy is complex, we use structural insights from it to design two practical heuristics. These heuristics enable an HKBSS to adapt efficiently to workload shifts by adjusting the criteria for referring decisions to the upper level based on partial real-time queue length information. Finally, we conduct analytic and numerical analyses to derive insights into the management of a TPT system. We find that (1) the telemedical physician should evaluate more patients as congestion in the emergency room waiting area increases; (2) training that improves accuracy of the physician and/or nurses can be effective even if it only does so for a single patient type, but training that improves consistency must do so for all patient types to be effective; and (3) patient classification in triage should consider environmental and operational conditions in addition to the patient's medical condition.</description><author>Saghafian, Soroush; Hopp, Wallace J.; Iravani, Seyed M. R.; Cheng, Yao; Diermeier, Daniel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Hot-Hand Fallacy: Cognitive Mistakes or Equilibrium Adjustments? Evidence from Major League Baseball</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, Brett; Zwiebel, Jeffrey
We test for a "hot hand" (i.e., short-term predictability in performance) in Major League Baseball using panel data. We find strong evidence for its existence in all 10 statistical categories we consider. The magnitudes are significant; being "hot" corresponds to between one-half and one standard deviation in the distribution of player abilities. Our results are in notable contrast to the majority of the hot-hand literature, which has generally found either no hot hand or a very weak hot hand in sports, often employing basketball shooting data. We argue that this difference is attributable to endogenous defensive responses: basketball presents sufficient opportunity for transferring defensive resources to equate shooting probabilities across players, whereas baseball does not. We then develop a method to test whether baseball teams do respond appropriately to hot opponents. Our results suggest teams respond in a manner consistent with drawing correct inference about the magnitude of the hot hand except for a tendency to overreact to very recent performance (i.e., the last five attempts).</description><author>Green, Brett; Zwiebel, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effects of Recommendation Neutrality and Sponsorship Disclosure on Trust vs. Distrust in Online Recommendation Agents: Moderating Role of Explanations for Organic Recommendations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Weiquan; Xu, Jingjun; Wang, May
We extend the extant research on neutral recommendation agents (RAs) to those that lack recommendation neutrality and are biased toward sponsors. We first investigate the effects of recommendation neutrality on users' trust and distrust in RAs by comparing a biased RA with sponsorship disclosure with a neutral RA. We then apply a contingency approach to examine the effects of sponsorship disclosure on users' trust and distrust in biased RAs, with explanations for organic recommendations as a contingent factor. A laboratory experiment was conducted in the United States. We determine that users' trust in the biased RA with sponsorship disclosure is lower and that their distrust is higher than that in the neutral RA. Results also show that user trust in a biased RA increases only when explanations for organic recommendations and sponsorship disclosure are both provided. Users' perceived psychological contract violations of an RA have been verified as a key mediator of the examined effects. However, explanations for organic recommendations, sponsorship disclosure, or their combination fail to significantly lower users' distrust in a biased RA. A second experiment conducted in Hong Kong confirms the major findings of the experiment conducted in the United States. Theoretical contributions and practical implications for e-commerce RAs are discussed.</description><author>Wang, Weiquan; Xu, Jingjun; Wang, May</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Many Gifts of Status: How Attending to Audience Reactions Drives the Use of Status</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sharkey, Amanda J.; Kovacs, Balazs
The majority of extant studies involving status argue that status enters into choice and evaluation because people personally believe that status serves as a signal of quality. However, this mechanism seems less plausible in cases when consensus on the meaning of quality is lacking. To understand how and why status often nonetheless enters into evaluation in those cases, this paper contributes to a growing body of work that proposes that individuals and organizations are particularly likely to base their choices and evaluations on status when they are concerned with the reactions of others. We provide an empirical test of this argument by analyzing how the sales gap between prizewinning books and their shortlisted-only peers (as well as a second similar-content control group) changes during the December holidays, when the purchase of books as gifts increases relative to purchases for one's own personal use. Results show that the sales gap widens with the increased orientation toward gift giving, consistent with our theoretical arguments about how attending to audience reactions drives the use of status. Analyses of two online experiments allow for further clarification of the mechanism behind our findings.</description><author>Sharkey, Amanda J.; Kovacs, Balazs</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bricks-and-Mortar Entry by Online Retailers in the Presence of Consumer Sales Taxes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arya, Anil; Mittendorf, Brian
This paper presents a parsimonious model of the bricks-and-mortar entry choice of online retailers in light of consumer sales taxes. On the one hand, a retailer benefits by entry since the second distribution channel enables it to reach new customers, giving it a leg up on rivals. On the other hand, physical entry typically compels the retailer to start collecting sales taxes even for online transactions, making its consumers particularly price sensitive. This paper examines this trade-off to characterize a retailer's entry decision, as well as the market-level equilibrium of bricks-and-mortar penetration. The paper then layers in supply market considerations-namely, the retailer's procurement of products from upstream suppliers. The analysis demonstrates that sales taxes not only reduce the consumers' willingness to pay for products in the retail market, but also dampen the retailer's willingness to pay for the products in the wholesale arena. This reluctance influences the clearing price in the supply market and, thus, the firm's decision to establish the physical retail store.</description><author>Arya, Anil; Mittendorf, Brian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Team Leadership and Performance: Combining the Roles of Direction and Contribution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rahmani, Morvarid; Roels, Guillaume; Karmarkar, Uday S.
In knowledge-intensive projects, one of the challenges project team leaders often face is how to combine their roles of direction and contribution. In this paper, we propose a game-theoretic model of team leadership of coproductive projects and study how team leaders should combine their directing and contributing efforts depending on the team and project characteristics. Our analysis reveals that two types of team leadership approaches arise in equilibrium, namely, "participatory" team leadership, under which the team leader gives the team members full discretion on their choice of effort, and "directive" team leadership, under which the team leader demands team members exert higher effort than what they would choose to exert voluntarily. We find that directive team leadership is optimal when the team members have low incentives, that is, when their rewards are low, the size of the team is large, or failure is not too costly (e.g., continuation is possible); otherwise, participatory team leadership is optimal. Moreover, we show that a higher degree of effort complementarity (as in innovative projects) leads to greater alignment between the team leader's and team members' contributing efforts, which, under directive team leadership, also implies greater alignment between the team leader's directing and contributing efforts. Finally, the team leader should set the team size and team members' rewards in a way that accentuates the difference between the two team leadership approaches. That is, under directive team leadership, she should set a large team size and offer the team members low rewards whereas under participatory team leadership she should set a small team size and offer the team members high rewards.</description><author>Rahmani, Morvarid; Roels, Guillaume; Karmarkar, Uday S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Revelation of Life-Changing Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schweizer, Nikolaus; Szech, Nora
Information about the future may be instrumentally useful yet scary. For example, many patients shy away from precise genetic tests about their dispositions for severe diseases. They are afraid that a bad test result could render them desperate as a result of anticipatory feelings. We show that partially revealing tests are typically optimal when anticipatory utility interacts with an instrumental need for information. The same result emerges when patients rely on probability weighting. Optimal tests provide only two signals, which renders them easily implementable. While the good signal is typically precise, the bad one remains coarse. This way, patients have a substantial chance to learn that they are free of the genetic risk in question. Yet even if the test outcome is bad, they do not end in a situation without hope.</description><author>Schweizer, Nikolaus; Szech, Nora</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Costs and Beliefs Implied by Direct Stock Ownership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartha, Daniel
This paper develops and estimates an economic model of the costs and beliefs required to rationalize household direct stock ownership. In the model, investors believe they can learn information about individual stock returns through costly research. The model identifies the distributions of both research costs and beliefs about the predictability of individual stock returns. Identification depends only on households' wealth and portfolio choices. The model also provides a novel explanation for many empirical features of household portfolios. Parameter estimates suggest that most households have modest beliefs about the benefits of individual stock research, although a minority must expect extraordinary returns.</description><author>Bartha, Daniel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Residual Inflation Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Illeditsch, Philipp Karl
I decompose inflation risk into (i) a component that is correlated with factors that determine investors' preferences and investment opportunities and real returns on real assets with risky cash flows (stocks, corporate bonds, real estate, commodities, etc.), and (ii) a residual inflation risk component. In equilibrium, only the first component earns a risk premium. Therefore, investors should avoid exposure to the residual component. All nominal bonds, including money-market accounts, have constant nominal cash flows, and thus their real returns are equally exposed to residual inflation risk. In contrast, inflation-protected bonds provide a means to avoid cash flow and residual inflation risk. Hence, every investor should put 100% of herwealth in real assets (inflation-protected bonds, stocks, corporate bonds, real estate, commodities, etc.) and finance every long/short position in nominal bonds with an equal amount of other nominal bonds or by borrowing/lending cash; that is, investors should hold a zero-investment portfolio of nominal bonds and cash.</description><author>Illeditsch, Philipp Karl</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Overconfidence, Firm Valuation, and Corporate Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adebambo, Biljana N.; Yan, Xuemin
Behavioral theory predicts that investor overconfidence leads to overpricing because overconfident investors overestimate the quality of their information and underestimate risk. We test this prediction by using a measure of investor overconfidence derived from the characteristics and holdings of U.S. equity mutual fund managers. We find that firms with more overconfident investors are relatively overvalued based on the market-to-book ratio and a misvaluation measure. The result is stronger among stocks with greater mutual fund ownership, particularly by active mutual funds. Firms with more overconfident investors also exhibit lower subsequent stock returns, issue more equity, and invest more. Overall, our findings suggest that investor overconfidence is significantly related to firm valuation and corporate decisions.</description><author>Adebambo, Biljana N.; Yan, Xuemin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Get in Line: Chapter 11 Restructuring in Crowded Bankruptcy Courts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iverson, Benjamin
Bankruptcy costs depend not only on the laws that govern financial distress but also on the ability of the court to rehabilitate distressed firms. This paper tests whether Chapter 11 restructuring outcomes are affected by time constraints in busy bankruptcy courts. Using the passage of the Bankruptcy Abuse Prevention and Consumer Protection Act as an exogenous shock to caseloads, I find that commercial banks report lower charge-offs on business lending when court caseloads decline, suggesting that the costs of financial distress are lower in less-congested courts. Further, court caseload affects how restructuring takes place. Less-busy bankruptcy judges liquidate fewer small firms, but more large firms. When caseload declines, large firms spend less time in court and firms that are dismissed from court are less likely to refile for bankruptcy. In addition, firms are less likely to sell assets or obtain debtor-in-possession financing in less-busy courts.</description><author>Iverson, Benjamin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Risk Is Weird: Unexplained Transaction Features Lower Valuations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mislavsky, Robert; Simonsohn, Uri
We define transactions asweird when they include unexplained features, that is, features not implicitly, explicitly, or self-evidently justified, and propose that people are averse to weird transactions. In six experiments, we show that risky options used in previous research paradigms often attained uncertainty via adding an unexplained transaction feature (e.g., purchasing a coin flip or lottery), and behavior that appears to reflect risk aversion could instead reflect an aversion to weird transactions. Specifically, willingness to pay drops just as much when adding risk to a transaction as when adding unexplained features. Holding transaction features constant, adding additional risk does not further reduce willingness to pay. We interpret our work as generalizing ambiguity aversion to riskless choice.</description><author>Mislavsky, Robert; Simonsohn, Uri</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Simulating Macro-Level Effects from Micro-Level Observations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smith, Edward Bishop; Rand, William
We consider the fruits of integrating agent-based modeling (ABM) with lab-based experimental research with human subjects. While both ABM and lab experiments have similar aims-to identify the rules, tendencies, and heuristics by which individual agents make decisions and respond to external stimuli-they work toward their common goal in notably different ways. Behavioral-lab research typically exposes human subjects to experimental manipulations, or treatments, to make causal inferences by observing variation in response to the treatment. ABM researchers ascribe individual simulated "agents" with decision rules describing their behavior and subsequently attempt to replicate "macro" level empirical patterns. Integration of ABM and lab experiments presents advantages for both sets of researchers. ABM researchers will benefit from exposure to a larger set of empirically validated mechanisms that can add nuance and refinement to their models of human behavior and system dynamics. Lab-oriented researchers will gain from ABM a method for assessing the validity and magnitude of their findings, adjudicating between competing mechanisms, developing new theory to test in the lab, and exploring macro-level, long-run implications of subtle, micro-level observations that can be difficult to observe in the field. We offer an example of this mixed-method approach related to status, social networks, and job search and issue guidance for future research attempting such integration.</description><author>Smith, Edward Bishop; Rand, William</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Once in the Door: Gender, Tryouts, and the Initial Salaries of Managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sterling, Adina D.; Fernandez, Roberto M.
Although women pursue managerial credentials at nearly the same rate as men, gender disparities in wages exist because of the shortfall in wages women sustain relative to men at the onset of their careers. This article develops a tryout approach to test for the presence of demand-side contributions to initial wage inequality while also developing and testing theory on why it may be lessened through internships. Using detailed data on graduates from an elite management program from 2009-2010, our analyses reveal that internships are associated with the gap in men's and women's initial salaries. For men, there is no difference in salary offers from employers where an internship occurs versus one where an internship does not occur. However, women receive higher salaries from employers where an internship first takes place.</description><author>Sterling, Adina D.; Fernandez, Roberto M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When More Is Less: Field Evidence on Unintended Consequences of Multitasking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goes, Paulo B.; Ilk, Noyan; Lin, Mingfeng; Zhao, J. Leon
Online customer service chats provide new opportunities for firms to interact with their customers and have become increasingly popular in recent years for firms of all sizes. One reason for their popularity is the ability for customer service agents to multitask (i.e., interact with multiple customers at a time) thereby increasing the system "through-put" and agent productivity. Yet little is known about how multitasking impacts customer satisfaction-the ultimate goal of customer engagements. We address this question using a proprietary data set from an S&amp;P 500 service firm that documents agent multitasking activities (unobservable to customers) in the form of server logs, customer service chat transcripts, and postservice customer surveys. We find that agent multitasking leads to longer in-service delays for customers and lower problem resolution rates. Both lead to lower customer satisfaction, although the impact varies for different customers. Our study is among the first to document the link between multitasking and customer satisfaction, and it has implications for the design of agent time allocation in contact centers and more broadly for how firms can best manage customer relations in new service channels enabled by information technology.</description><author>Goes, Paulo B.; Ilk, Noyan; Lin, Mingfeng; Zhao, J. Leon</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring Agency Costs over the Business Cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Westermann, Ramona
This paper investigates the joint effects of manager-shareholder agency conflicts and macroeconomic risk on corporate policies and firm value. I first derive the implications of a structural model of a firm with assets in place and an investment opportunity, run by a self-interested manager who captures part of the firm's net income as private benefits. The model implies that dynamic aggregate agency costs are driven by firms in the upper half of the distribution of private benefits. Managers of those firms capture 0.8% of firms' net income on average, thereby decreasing aggregate firm value by 1.7%. These agency costs are procyclical (1.9% in booms and 1.4% in recessions) because managerial underleverage decreases default costs particularly in recessions. Furthermore, the model can explain empirical regularities, including the joint level and cyclicality of leverage.</description><author>Westermann, Ramona</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Contingent Wisdom of Dyads: When Discussion Enhances vs. Undermines the Accuracy of Collaborative Judgments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Minson, Julia A.; Mueller, Jennifer S.; Larrick, Richard P.
We evaluate the effect of discussion on the accuracy of collaborative judgments. In contrast to prior research, we show that discussion can either aid or impede accuracy relative to the averaging of collaborators' independent judgments, as a systematic function of task type and interaction process. For estimation tasks with a wide range of potential estimates, discussion aided accuracy by helping participants prevent and eliminate egregious errors. For estimation tasks with a naturally bounded range, discussion following independent estimates performed on par with averaging. Importantly, if participants did not first make independent estimates, discussion greatly harmed accuracy by limiting the range of considered estimates, independent of task type. Our research shows that discussion can be a powerful tool for error reduction, but only when appropriately structured: Decision makers should form independent judgments to consider a wide range of possible answers, and then use discussion to eliminate extremely large errors.</description><author>Minson, Julia A.; Mueller, Jennifer S.; Larrick, Richard P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Tax Trading with Carryover Losses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ehling, Paul; Gallmeyer, Michael; Srivastava, Sanjay; Tompaidis, Stathis; Yang, Chunyu
We study portfolio choice with multiple stocks and capital gains taxation, assuming that capital losses can only offset current or future realized capital gains. We show, through backtesting using empirical distributions, that optimal equity holdings over an extended period are significantly lower on average than benchmark holdings suggested in the literature. Using value and growth or small and large portfolios, the backtests show that allocations remain persistently underdiversified. Carryover losses have large economic significance since they can dramatically shrink the no-trade region. Finally, the backtested economic cost of incorrectly modeling capital losses is at least 8% of lifetime wealth.</description><author>Ehling, Paul; Gallmeyer, Michael; Srivastava, Sanjay; Tompaidis, Stathis; Yang, Chunyu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unusual News Flow and the Cross Section of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Bodnaruk, Andriy; Scherbina, Anna; Tang, Yi
We document that stocks that experience sudden increases in idiosyncratic volatility underperform otherwise similar stocks in the future, and we propose that this phenomenon can be explained by the Miller conjecture [Miller E (1977) Risk, uncertainty, and divergence of opinion. J. Finance 32(4): 1151-1168]. We show that volatility shocks can be traced to unusual firm-level news flow, which temporarily increases the level of investor disagreement about the firm value. At the same time, volatility shocks pose a barrier to short selling, preventing pessimistic investors from expressing their views. In the presence of divergent opinions and short-selling constraints, prices initially reflect optimistic views but adjust downward in the future as investors' opinions converge.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Bodnaruk, Andriy; Scherbina, Anna; Tang, Yi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>