<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Management Science3</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Sourcing Under Supplier Responsibility Risk: The Effects of Certification, Audit, and Contingency Payment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Li; Lee, Hau L.
Companies that source from emerging economies often face supplier responsibility risks, namely, financial and reputational burdens that the companies have to bear when their suppliers' engagement in noncomplying labor and environmental practices becomes public. To mitigate such risks, companies can invest in screening mechanisms and design incentive schemes in sourcing contracts. Common mitigation instruments include supplier certification, process audits, and contingency payments. The interactions of these instruments are often not well understood. We first note that the effectiveness of any mitigation instrument depends on how it changes the economic trade-offs faced by a supplier in compliance to social and environmental standard, and hence we develop a model that explicitly captures such trade-offs. As a result, our model endogenizes the supplier's noncompliance probability and connects it with various factors, including the supplier's intrinsic ethical level that is unobservable to the buyer. We then study the buyer's optimal contracting problem under different mitigation instruments. We find that although the process audit and contingency payment instruments can directly lower supplier responsibility risk, they, acting alone, are not as effective as the supplier certification instrument in screening suppliers with different ethical levels. Nevertheless, these instruments are all complementary to each other; when used jointly, they make supplier screening more effective and result in lower sourcing cost. These findings provide explanations for some of the observed practices used in industry to mitigate supplier responsibility risks.</description><author>Chen, Li; Lee, Hau L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Person-Organization Fit and Incentives: A Causal Test</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andersson, Ola; Huysentruyt, Marieke; Miettinen, Topi; Stephan, Ute
We investigate the effects of organizational culture and personal values on performance under individual and team contest incentives. We develop a model of regard for others and in-group favoritism that predicts interaction effects between organizational values and personal values in contest games. These predictions are tested in a computerized lab experiment with exogenous control of both organizational values and incentives. In line with our theoretical model, we find that prosocial (proself)-orientated subjects exert more (less) effort in team contests in the primed prosocial organizational values condition, relative to the neutrally primed baseline condition. Further, when the prosocial organizational values are combined with individual contest incentives, prosocial subjects no longer outperform their proself counterparts. These findings provide, to our knowledge, a first, affirmative, causal test of person-organization fit theory. They also suggest the importance of a "triple-fit" between personal preferences, organizational values, and incentive mechanisms for prosocially orientated individuals.</description><author>Andersson, Ola; Huysentruyt, Marieke; Miettinen, Topi; Stephan, Ute</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effective Reminders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calzolari, Giacomo; Nardotto, Mattia
We study the effects of reminders on people's behavior in investment activities characterized by up-front costs and delayed benefits, such as getting an education and maintaining a healthy lifestyle. We conduct a field experiment and show that simple weekly reminders induce users of a gym to substantially increase their gym attendance over an extensive period. Users' response to reminders is immediate (within hours) and recurrent for any subsequent reminder, which can be explained by limited attention. We find some evidence of habit formation, leading to more frequent physical activity also after treatment, although with an effect smaller than during treatment. Simple reminders are thus a cost-effective policy tool.</description><author>Calzolari, Giacomo; Nardotto, Mattia</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Gender and Business Trainings Affect Business Outcomes? Experimental Evidence from Vietnam</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bulte, Erwin; Lensink, Robert; Vu, Nhung
We use a randomized control trial to evaluate the impact of a business training for female clients of a microfinance institution in northern Vietnam, and we consider the impact on (i) business knowledge, (ii) practices, and (ii) outcomes, as well as (iv) firm entry and exit decisions. In addition, we vary the nature of the intervention by inviting husbands to participate in the trainings for a subsample of our respondents. To gauge both short-termand medium-termeffects, we combine data from two separate postintervention surveys. We find evidence of economically substantive impacts on knowledge, practices, and outcomes, and on the extensive margin (entry and exit). We also document that it takes time for the "downstream" outcomes of the trainings to materialize; although we find evidence of medium-term effects, no such evidence exists for the short term. Inviting husbands to participate in the trainings does not affect any of our knowledge or practice measures, but we document weak evidence for differential impact on (agricultural) sales and profits.</description><author>Bulte, Erwin; Lensink, Robert; Vu, Nhung</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Interplay Between Forward-Looking Measures and Target Setting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bouwens, Jan; Kroos, Peter
We examine whether financial targets are based on both forward-looking and financial information, rather than on financial information only. We collect sales and performance appraisal data of store managers in a retail chain. The firm issues directives focused on the provision of excellent customer service and assesses store managers' compliance with these directives subjectively. We demonstrate that, controlling for current sales, compliance with directives scores predicts future sales performance. We find that, next to objective sales information, this forward-looking information is impounded in the next year's sales target. Finally, we find some evidence that suggests that incorporating forward-looking information improves the accuracy of sales targets.</description><author>Bouwens, Jan; Kroos, Peter</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Comovement of Investor Attention</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drake, Michael S.; Jennings, Jared; Roulstone, Darren T.; Thornock, Jacob R.
Prior literature has documented that investor attention and constraints on that attention are associated with the pricing of stocks. We introduce the concept of attention comovement, which is the extent to which investor attention to a firm is explained by attention paid to the firm's industry and the market in general. We find that attention comovement is nontrivial for the average firm and is related to firm characteristics, such as size and visibility. We also find that the comovement of investor attention has market consequences, in that it is positively associated with excess stock return comovement. Finally, we show that a firm's earnings announcement contributes to the transfer of attention from one firm to its peer firms. Our results provide insights about the information flows underlying return comovement and aid in understanding the micro and macronature of investor attention.</description><author>Drake, Michael S.; Jennings, Jared; Roulstone, Darren T.; Thornock, Jacob R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring the Efficiency of Category-Level Sales Response to Promotions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Trivedi, Minakshi; Gauri, Dinesh K.; Ma, Yu
In this study, we focus on measuring the efficiency of category-level sales response to promotions across various categories and stores. Our heterogeneous stochastic frontier model allows us to attribute portions of this efficiency to specific characteristics of the stores and categories. Using our full PEM (promotional efficiency frontier) model, we analyze the efficiency of 20 frequently bought categories of a supermarket retailer and apply it to store-category-level data. We find that the average efficiency of category and store sales response across all categories and stores is 84.34%, with low values in categories such as spreads and fresh seafood and high values in categories such as frozen entrees and meat. We find that the variation in efficiency of this sales response can be attributed to specific store and category characteristics such as selling area of store, distance to competition, number of stock-keeping units in the category, and average interpurchase time. Unobserved heterogeneity is captured by the latent class approach that provides support for the existence of three segments. An understanding of the roles played by these characteristics in the efficiency of sales response can aid managers in devising a strategy that maximizes sales.</description><author>Trivedi, Minakshi; Gauri, Dinesh K.; Ma, Yu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Ratings and Credit Risk: Is One Measure Enough?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hilscher, Jens; Wilson, Mungo
This paper investigates the information in corporate credit ratings. If ratings are to be informative indicators of credit risk, they must reflect what a risk-averse investor cares about: both raw default probability and systematic risk. We find that ratings are relatively inaccurate measures of raw default probability-they are dominated as predictors of failure by a simple model based on publicly available financial information. However, ratings do contain relevant information since they are related to a measure of exposure to common (and undiversifiable) variation in default probability ("failure beta"). Systematic risk is shown to be related to joint default probabilities in the context of the Merton [ Merton RC (1974) On the pricing of corporate debt: The risk structure of interest rates. J. Finance 29(2):449-470] model. Empirically, it is related to credit default swap spreads and risk premia. Given the multidimensional nature of credit risk, it is not possible for one measure to capture all the relevant information.</description><author>Hilscher, Jens; Wilson, Mungo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Choice Based on Third-Degree Stochastic Dominance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Post, Thierry; Kopa, Milos
We develop an optimization method for constructing investment portfolios that dominate a given benchmark portfolio in terms of third-degree stochastic dominance. Our approach relies on the properties of the semivariance function, a refinement of an existing "superconvex" dominance condition, and quadratic constrained programming. We apply our method to historical stock market data using an industry momentum strategy. Our enhanced portfolio generates important performance improvements compared with alternatives based on mean-variance dominance and second-degree stochastic dominance. Relative to the Center for Research in Security Prices all-share index, our portfolio increases average out-of-sample return by almost seven percentage points per annum without incurring more downside risk, using quarterly rebalancing and without short selling.</description><author>Post, Thierry; Kopa, Milos</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Managerial Ability in Corporate Tax Avoidance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koester, Allison; Shevlin, Terry; Wangerin, Daniel
Most prior studies model tax avoidance as a function of firm-level characteristics and do not consider how individual executive characteristics affect tax avoidance. This paper investigates whether executives with superior ability to efficiently manage corporate resources engage in greater tax avoidance. Our results show that moving from the lower to upper quartile of managerial ability is associated with a 3.15% (2.50%) reduction in a firm's one-year (five-year) cash effective tax rate. We examine how higher-ability managers reduce income tax payments and find that they engage in greater state tax planning activities, shift more income to foreign tax havens, make more research and development credit claims, and make greater investments in assets that generate accelerated depreciation deductions. Identifying a manager characteristic related to firms' tax policy decisions adds to our understanding of the factors that explain the substantial variation in corporate income tax payments across firms.</description><author>Koester, Allison; Shevlin, Terry; Wangerin, Daniel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning to Manage and Managing to Learn: The Effects of Student Leadership Service</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Michael L.; Lu, Fangwen
Employers and colleges value individuals with leadership service, but there is limited evidence on whether leadership service itself creates skills. Identification in this context has proved difficult because settings in which leadership service accrues to individuals for ostensibly random reasons are rare. In this study we estimate the effects of random assignment to classroom leadership positions in a Chinese secondary school. We find that leadership service increases test scores, increases students' political popularity in the classroom, makes students more likely to take initiative, and shapes students' beliefs about the determinants of success. The results suggest that leadership service may impact human capital and is not solely a signal of preexisting skills.</description><author>Anderson, Michael L.; Lu, Fangwen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Task Decomposition and Newsvendor Decision Making</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Yun Shin; Siemsen, Enno
We conduct three behavioral laboratory experiments to compare newsvendor order decisions placed directly to order decisions submitted in a decomposed way by soliciting point forecasts, uncertainty estimates, and service-level decisions. Decomposing order decisions in such a way often follows from organizational structure and can lead to performance improvements compared with ordering directly. However, we also demonstrate that if the critical ratio is below 50%, or if the underlying demand uncertainty is too high, task decomposition may not be preferred to direct ordering. Under such conditions, decision makers are prone to set service levels too high or to suffer from excessive random judgment error, which reduces the efficacy of task decomposition. We further demonstrate that if accompanied by decision support in the form of suggested quantities, task decomposition becomes the better-performing approach to newsvendor decision making more generally. Decision support and task decomposition therefore appear as complementary methods to improve decision performance in the newsvendor context.</description><author>Lee, Yun Shin; Siemsen, Enno</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inventory, Risk Shifting, and Trade Credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chod, Jiri
This paper has two objectives. First, we show how debt financing distorts a retailer's inventory decision when the retailer orders multiple items that differ in cost, revenue, or demand parameters. Taking advantage of limited liability, a debt-financed retailer favors items with a low salvage value, those with a high profit margin, and those that represent a large proportion of the total inventory investment. Second, we argue that this distortion is mitigated when the financing is provided by the supplier who can observe the actual order quantities before determining the credit terms. Borrowing goods rather than borrowing cash limits the retailer's ability to deviate from the first-best inventory decision. On the flip side, few suppliers can access capital at the same low cost as banks. We study a combination of bank and supplier financing that allows the retailer to get the best of both worlds.</description><author>Chod, Jiri</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Sources of the Communication Gap</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Simin; Offerman, Theo; van de Ven, Jeroen
Face-to-face communication drastically increases cooperation rates in social dilemmas. We test which factors are the most important drivers of this communication gap. We distinguish three main categories. First, communication may decrease social distance. Second, communication may enable subjects to assess their opponent's cooperativeness ("type detection") and condition their own action on that information. Third, communication allows subjects to make promises, which create commitment for subjects who do not want to break a promise. We find that communication increases cooperation very substantially. In our experiment, we find that commitment value is an important factor, but the largest part of the increase can be attributed to type detection. We do not find evidence that social distance plays a role.</description><author>He, Simin; Offerman, Theo; van de Ven, Jeroen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>OrganJet: Overcoming Geographical Disparities in Access to Deceased Donor Kidneys in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ata, Baris; Skaro, Anton; Tayur, Sridhar
There are over 90,000 patients in the United States waiting for a kidney transplant. Under the current allocation policy, the vast majority of deceased organs are allocated locally. This causes significant disparities in waiting times and access to transplant across different geographical areas. To ameliorate this inequity, we propose an operational solution that offers affordable jet services (OrganJet) to patients on the transplant waiting list, allowing them to list in multiple different, and possibly very distant, donation service areas (DSAs) of their choosing. First, using a fluid approximation, we formulate the patients' problem of choosing a location to multiple list as a selfish routing game in which each patient tries to minimize his "congestion cost," i.e., maximize his life expectancy. Through a combination of numerical, simulation, and analytical results, we show that multiple listing can lead to a significant improvement in geographic equity. In the special case when sufficiently many patients can multiple list, the geographic inequity disappears. Moreover, the supply of deceased donor organs increases under multiple listing, leading to more transplants and saved lives. We also consider a diffusion approximation and study the resulting multiple-listing game. The equilibrium outcome under the diffusion approximation is a second-order perturbation of that under the selfish routing formulation. In particular, the geographic equity metric, waiting times, and probabilities of receiving a transplant at various DSAs in equilibrium are second-order perturbations of those predicted by the selfish routing equilibrium. Hence, the analysis under the diffusion approximation also supports the finding that multiple listing leads to an improvement in geographic equity. In addition, restricting attention to the special case of sufficiently many patients multiple listing leads to an explicit characterization of the equilibria, which in turn yields additional structural insights. Last, we undertake a simulation study that supports aforementioned findings.</description><author>Ata, Baris; Skaro, Anton; Tayur, Sridhar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Continuous Pricing with Strategic Consumers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Briceno-Arias, Luis; Correa, Jose R.; Perlroth, Andres
An important economic problem is that of finding optimal pricing mechanisms to sell a single item when there are a random number of buyers who arrive over time. In this paper, we combine ideas from auction theory and recent work on pricing with strategic consumers to derive the optimal continuous time pricing scheme in this situation. Under the assumption that buyers are split among those who have a high valuation and those who have a low valuation for the item, we obtain the price path that maximizes the seller's revenue. We conclude that, depending on the specific instance, it is optimal to either use a fixed price strategy or to use steep markdowns by the end of the selling season. As a complement to this optimality result, we prove that under a large family of price functions there is an equilibrium for the buyers. Finally, we derive an approach to tackle the case in which buyers' valuations follow a general distribution. The approach is based on optimal control theory and is well suited for numerical computations.</description><author>Briceno-Arias, Luis; Correa, Jose R.; Perlroth, Andres</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Behavior-Based Pricing in Vertically Differentiated Industries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rhee, Ki-Eun; Thomadsen, Raphael
We study behavior-based pricing (BBP) in a vertically differentiated model. Vertical differentiation is innately asymmetric because all customers prefer the higher-quality product when prices are equal. This asymmetry causes BBP to have different properties than symmetric horizontally differentiated models. We highlight two dimensions that affect the analysis: the role of quality-adjusted cost differences between the firms and the role of consumer discounting relative to firm discounting. In the second period, consistent with the prior literature, we find that there are conditions based on market shares and quality-adjusted costs under which either the low-quality firm or the high-quality firm-but not both-will reward its current customers with lower prices than it charges to new customers. We then consider whether these conditions can arise in a two-period equilibrium. We find that if consumers sufficiently discount the future periods, then firms at enough of a competitive disadvantage will reward their customers: i.e., the low-quality firm will reward its current customers if the quality-adjusted cost differential between the two firms is small, while the high-quality firm will reward its current customers if this cost differential is large. Conversely, we find that if consumers do not discount the future very much, then the firm at a competitive disadvantage (i.e., a low-quality firm competing against a low-cost high-quality firm, or a high-quality firm that has very high costs) can earn greater profits with BBP than without BBP, although there are cases where both firms may benefit from BBP.</description><author>Rhee, Ki-Eun; Thomadsen, Raphael</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Network Analysis of Search Dynamics: The Case of Stock Habitats</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leung, Alvin Chung Man; Agarwal, Ashish; Konana, Prabhudev; Kumar, Alok
There is an increasing attention in information systems to be able to predict outcomes using search frequency on popular portals. This growing literature focuses on revealing demand patterns of individual assets (e.g., products, stocks, services). However, users typically search many different assets together (e.g., correlated searches) and leave a digital footprint, which can help provide insights on the behaviors of a group of assets. Furthermore, such group behavior can be used to predict outcomes (e.g., demand, stock returns) in the future. We analyze the underlying behavior of distinct subnetworks formed by correlated user searches for multiple items in the stock market and use such information for return prediction. Using cosearch data for stocks from Yahoo! Finance, we find 50-79 search clusters representing 230-349 stocks among Russell 3000 stocks at different time periods. These clusters reveal interesting habitats where the returns of stocks within a cluster tend to comove after controlling for known determinants of comovement. When a stock enters (departs) a cluster, the focal stock return comoves (detaches) with the cluster returns. Thus, search cluster-based habitats reveal aggregate investment preferences and are more granular than fundamental-based habitats. We find that search-based habitats can also improve return predictability of related stocks.</description><author>Leung, Alvin Chung Man; Agarwal, Ashish; Konana, Prabhudev; Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The First Deal: The Division of Founder Equity in New Ventures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hellmann, Thomas; Wasserman, Noam
We examine the trade-off between efficiency and equality within the context of entrepreneurial founding teams. Using a formal theory where founders may have preferences over relative outcomes, we derive predictions about the antecedents and consequences of dividing equity equally among all founders. Using proprietary survey data, we empirically test the predictions. Our central finding is that teams that split equity equally are less likely to raise funds from outside investors. The relationship appears not to be causal, but instead driven by selection effects across heterogeneous teams with varying degrees of inequality aversion.</description><author>Hellmann, Thomas; Wasserman, Noam</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overconfident Competing Newsvendors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Meng; Petruzzi, Nicholas C.; Zhang, Jun
Overconfidence is one of the most consistent, powerful, and widespread cognitive biases affecting decision making in situations characterized by random outcomes. In this paper, we study the effects and implications of overconfidence in a competitive newsvendor setting. In this context, overconfidence is defined as a cognitive bias in which decision makers behave as though the outcome of an uncertain event is less risky than it really is. This bias unequivocally leads to a lower expected profit for a newsvendor that does not compete on inventory availability. Nevertheless, it can be a positive force for competing newsvendors. Indeed, we find that when the product's profit margin is high, overconfidence can lead to a first-best outcome. In a similar vein, we also show that the more biased of two competing newsvendors is not necessarily destined to a smaller expected profit than its less biased competitor.</description><author>Li, Meng; Petruzzi, Nicholas C.; Zhang, Jun</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Investors and Bubbles: An Analysis of the Baosteel Call Warrant Bubble</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gong, Binglin; Pan, Deng; Shi, Donghui
This paper provides an analysis of the impact of new investors on the bubble surrounding the Baosteel call warrant, the first derivative traded in China after a nine-year suspension. We empirically show that new investors initiated the bubble at the opening call auction and were the key driving force to sustain the bubble until the maturity of the warrant.</description><author>Gong, Binglin; Pan, Deng; Shi, Donghui</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Omnichannel Retail Operations with Buy-Online-and-Pick-up-in-Store</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Fei; Su, Xuanming
Many retailers have recently started to offer customers the option to buy online and pick up in store (BOPS). We study the impact of the BOPS initiative on store operations. We build a stylized model where a retailer operates both online and offline channels. Customers strategically make channel choices. The BOPS option affects customer choice in two ways: by providing real-time information about inventory availability and by reducing the hassle cost of shopping. We obtain three findings. First, not all products are well suited for in-store pickup; specifically, it may not be profitable to implement BOPS on products that sell well in stores. Second, BOPS enables retailers to reach new customers, but for existing customers, the shift from online fulfillment to store fulfillment may decrease profit margins when the latter is less cost effective. Finally, in a decentralized retail system where store and online channels are managed separately, BOPS revenue can be shared across channels to alleviate incentive conflicts; it is rarely efficient to allocate all the revenue to a single channel.</description><author>Gao, Fei; Su, Xuanming</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Plant Operations and Product Recalls in the Automotive Industry: An Empirical Investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shah, Rachna; Ball, George P.; Netessine, Serguei
While there is overwhelming support for the negative consequences of product recalls, empirical evidence of operational drivers of recalls is almost nonexistent. In this study, we identify product variety (measured as the number of factory installed options), plant variety (measured as the number of models per assembly line in a plant), and capacity utilization as drivers of subsequent manufacturing-related recalls. We examine their individual and joint effects using a unique data set compiled for a seven-year period by linking assembly line production data for North American automotive manufacturers with recall data from the National Highway Traffic and Safety Administration. We show that manufacturing-related recalls are positively associated with product variety and plant utilization, but not with plant variety. We also find that the joint effect of plant variety and utilization is positively associated with increased recalls. In quantitative terms, a one-standard-deviation increase in the number of options (four additional options) is associated with two additional recalls and costs $46.2 million to automakers over the sample duration. We observe similar results with plant utilization, and find that a car built in a plant that is being utilized above 100% capacity is associated with more than eight additional recalls corresponding to an incremental cost of $167 million.</description><author>Shah, Rachna; Ball, George P.; Netessine, Serguei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Finance Policies and Social Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fracassi, Cesare
This paper shows that managers are influenced by their social peers when making corporate policy decisions. Using biographical information about executives and directors of U.S. public companies, we define social ties from current and past employment, education, and other activities. We find that more connections two companies share with each other, more similar their capital investments are. To address endogeneity concerns, we find that companies invest less similarly when an individual connecting them dies. The results extend to other corporate finance policies. Furthermore, central companies in the social network invest in a less idiosyncratic way and exhibit better economic performance.</description><author>Fracassi, Cesare</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extrapolative Beliefs in Perceptual and Economic Decisions: Evidence of a Common Mechanism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frydman, Cary; Nave, Gideon
Acritical component of both economic and perceptual decision making under uncertainty is the belief-formation process. However, most research has studied belief formation in economic and perceptual decision making in isolation. One reason for this separate treatment may be the assumption that there are distinct psychological mechanisms that underlie belief formation in economic and perceptual decisions. An alternative theory is that there exists a common mechanism that governs belief formation in both domains. Here, we test this alternative theory by combining a novel computational modeling technique with two well-known experimental paradigms. We estimate a drift-diffusion model (DDM) and provide an analytical method to decode prior beliefs from DDM parameters. Subjects in our experiment exhibit strong extrapolative beliefs in both paradigms. In line with the common mechanism hypothesis, we find that a single computational model explains belief formation in both tasks and that individual differences in belief formation are correlated across tasks.</description><author>Frydman, Cary; Nave, Gideon</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading Time in a Congested Environment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Luyi; Debo, Laurens; Gupta, Varun
The first in, first out (FIFO) queue discipline respects the order of arrivals, but is not efficient when customers have heterogeneous waiting costs. Priority queues, in which customers with higher waiting costs are served first, are more efficient but usually involve undesirable queue-jumping behaviors that violate bumped customers' property rights over their waiting spots. To have the best of both worlds, we propose time-trading mechanisms, in which customers who are privately informed about their waiting costs mutually agree on the ordering in the queue by trading positions. If a customer ever moves back in the queue, she will receive an appropriate monetary compensation. Customers can always decide not to participate in trading and retain their positions as if they are being served FIFO. We design the optimal mechanisms for the social planner, the service provider, and an intermediary who might mediate the trading platform. Both the social planner's and the service provider's optimal mechanisms involve a flat admission fee and an auction that implements strict priority. If a revenue-maximizing intermediary operates the trading platform, it should charge a trade participation fee and implement an auction with some trade restrictions. Therefore, customers are not strictly prioritized. However, relative to a FIFO system, the intermediary delivers value to the social planner by improving efficiency, and to the service provider by increasing its revenue.</description><author>Yang, Luyi; Debo, Laurens; Gupta, Varun</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Targeting Affects Customer Search: A Field Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fong, Nathan M.
It has become common practice for retailers to personalize direct marketing efforts based on customer transaction histories as a tactic to increase sales. Targeted email offers featuring products in the same category as a customer's previous purchases generate higher purchase rates. However, a targeted offer emphasizing familiar products could result in curtailed search for unadvertised products, as a closely matched offer weakens a customer's incentives to search beyond the targeted items. In a field experiment using email offers sent by an online wine retailer, targeted offers resulted in decreased search activity on the retailer'swebsite. This effect is driven by a lower rate of search by customers who visit the site, rather than a lower incidence of search. There are several ways this could potentially hurt retailers and consumers, such as reduced cross-selling and fewer opportunities for customers to explore new products.</description><author>Fong, Nathan M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Superreplication of Financial Derivatives via Convex Programming</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kahale, Nabil
We give a method based on convex programming to calculate the optimal super-replicating and subreplicating prices and corresponding hedging portfolios of a financial derivative in terms of other financial derivatives in a discrete-time setting. Our method produces a model that matches the superreplicating (or subreplicating) price within an arbitrary precision and is consistent with the other financial derivatives prices. Applications include robust replication in terms of call prices with various strikes and maturities of forward start options, volatility and variance swaps and derivatives, cliquet calls, barrier options, and lookback and Asian options. Numerical examples show that, in some cases, the best superreplicating and/or subreplicating prices are within 10% of the price obtained by a standard model but considerably differ from it in other cases. Our method can incorporate bid-ask spreads, interest rates and dividends, and various limitations to the diffusion model.</description><author>Kahale, Nabil</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internationalization and Bank Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane; Roman, Raluca A.
This paper documents a positive relation between internationalization and bank risk. This is consistent with the empirical dominance of the market risk hypothesis, whereby internationalization increases banks' risk due to market-specific factors in foreign markets, over the diversification hypothesis, whereby internationalization allows banks to reduce risk through diversification of their operations. The results continue to hold following a variety of robustness tests, including those for endogeneity and sample selection bias. We also find that the magnitude of this effect is more pronounced during financial crises. The results appear to be at least partially explained by agency problems related to poor corporate governance.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane; Roman, Raluca A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding Bank-Run Contagion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Martin; Trautmann, Stefan T.; Vlahu, Razvan
We study experimental coordination games to examine through which transmission channels and under which information conditions a panic-based depositor run at one bank may trigger a panic-based depositor run at another bank. We find that withdrawals at one bank trigger withdrawals at another bank by increasing players' beliefs that other depositors in their own bank will withdraw, making them more likely to withdraw as well. Observed withdrawals only affect depositors' beliefs, and are thus contagious when they form an informative signal about bank fundamentals.</description><author>Brown, Martin; Trautmann, Stefan T.; Vlahu, Razvan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The International Diversification of Banks and the Value of Their Cross-Border M&amp;A Advice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rajamani, Anjana; van der Poel, Marieke; de Jong, Abe; Ongena, Steven
We examine the impact of the international diversification of banks on the value of their advice in 1,705 cross-border merger and acquisition (M&amp;A) transactions. We find that bidders engaging internationally diversified advisors face lower announcement returns. An increase of one standard deviation in advisor diversification is associated with an announcement return lower by 92 basis points for a bidder acquiring a listed target. The lower bidder returns are attributable to the lower synergies of the deals being completed. Our evidence suggests that internationally diversified advisors offer lower-quality advice to their clients, since their reputational concerns are weakened by having access to multiple geographies from which they can derive fee-based income. We present further evidence that financial incentives in the form of the advisor's involvement in deal financing and market incentives in the form of the potential to gain market share in the bidder country may mitigate some of the negative effects of the international diversification of the advisors.</description><author>Rajamani, Anjana; van der Poel, Marieke; de Jong, Abe; Ongena, Steven</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consistency as a Signal of Skills</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Falk, Armin; Zimmermann, Florian
This paper studies the role of consistency as a signaling device. We propose a two-period model that highlights the informativeness of consistency as a signal of skills and allows for the analysis of consequences for behavior. In a simple principal-agent experiment, we test the basic intuition of the model. We show that consistency is indeed associated with skills. Consequently, consistency is valued by others, inducing people to act consistently.</description><author>Falk, Armin; Zimmermann, Florian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Delegated Bidding and the Allocative Effect of Accounting Rules</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marinovica, Ivan
This paper studies the efficiency and distributive effects of three prominent accounting methods in auction settings when bidders' incentives are linked to accounting income. The purchase price method (PP) requires the acquirer to book the acquisition at historical cost, thereby underestimating the asset value by the amount of the acquirer's surplus in the transaction. The exit value method (EV) is downward biased and forces the acquirer to book an accounting loss on the date of acquisition. EV connects otherwise independent valuations inducing a reporting-based winner's curse and can even lead to fire-sale-like values. Relative to PP, EV implies lower asset prices, a decrease (increase) in the surplus of the seller (acquirer), and an increase in the probability that the asset attains its best use when the market is sufficiently competitive. Finally, I examine an alternative method in which the asset is valued at its perceived value-in-use (VU). Under this method, the acquirer bids more aggressively to increase perceived value-in-use, leading to a shift of surplus from the acquirer to the seller. Yet VU is unbiased and always maximizes the probability that the asset attains its best use.</description><author>Marinovica, Ivan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Friends Become Competitors: The Design of Resource Exchange Alliances</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chun, So Yeon; Kleywegt, Anton J.; Shapiro, Alexander
Many carriers, such as airlines and ocean carriers, collaborate through the formation of alliances. The rules of alliances are important for both the stability of the alliance and the profitability of the alliance members. In this paper, we address the design of resource exchange alliances, a type of alliance agreement widely used in practice, especially in the ocean cargo industry. Resource exchange alliances often increase competition among alliance members since the members can sell substitutable products after the exchange. We propose a resource exchange model that takes into account the resulting competition and alliance profit allocation among alliance members. The problem of determining the optimal amounts of resources to exchange is formulated as a stochastic mathematical program with equilibrium constraints (MPECs). Although MPEC problems are, in general, very difficult to solve, we successfully demonstrate an efficient solution approach and provide valuable insights for the resource exchange design problem. In particular, we show that the resource exchange alliance we propose can induce greater profit for the alliance members (both total and individual profits) even though it leads to greater competition.</description><author>Chun, So Yeon; Kleywegt, Anton J.; Shapiro, Alexander</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Delays on Service Times in the Intensive Care Unit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Carri W.; Farias, Vivek F.; Escobar, Gabriel J.
Mainstream queueing models are frequently employed in modeling healthcare delivery in a number of settings, and they further are used in making operational decisions for the same. The vast majority of these queueing models ignore the effects of delay experienced by a patient awaiting care. However, long delays may have adverse effects on patient outcomes and can potentially lead to a longer length of stay (LOS) when the patient ultimately does receive care. This work sets out to understand these delay issues from an operational perspective. Using data of more than 57,000 emergency department (ED) visits, we use an instrumental variable approach to empirically measure the impact of delays in intensive care unit (ICU) admission, i.e., ED boarding, on the patient's ICU LOS for multiple patient types. Capturing these empirically observed effects in a queueing model is challenging because the effect introduces potentially long-range correlations in service and interarrival times. We propose a queueing model that incorporates these measured delay effects and characterizes approximations to the expected work in the system when the service time of a job is adversely impacted by the delay experienced by that job. Our approximation demonstrates an effect of system load on work that grows much faster than the traditional 1/1(1-rho) relationship seen in most queueing systems. As such, it is imperative that the relationship of delays and LOS be better understood by hospital managers so that they can make capacity decisions that prevent even seemingly moderate delays from causing dire operational consequences.</description><author>Chan, Carri W.; Farias, Vivek F.; Escobar, Gabriel J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Catching Falling Knives: Speculating on Liquidity Shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colliard, Jean-Edouard
Many market participants invest resources to acquire information about liquidity rather than fundamentals. I show that agents using such information can reduce the magnitude of short-lived pricing errors by trading against liquidity shocks. However, the short-run stabilizing effect of this behavior also makes it more difficult to identify liquidity shocks, a signal-jamming effect that slows down price discovery in the long run. As more agents invest in nonfundamental information, market prices become more resilient to liquidity shocks but also recover more slowly from temporary price deviations.</description><author>Colliard, Jean-Edouard</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic Influences on Optimal Equity-Credit Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Capponi, Agostino; Frei, Christoph
We introduce an equity-credit portfolio framework taking into account the structural interaction of market and credit risk, along with their systemic dependencies. We derive an explicit expression for the optimal investment strategy in stocks and credit default swaps (CDSs). We exploit its representation structure and analyze the mechanisms driving the optimal investment decisions. The transmission of market risk premia is the key mechanism through which systemic influences affect the optimal investment strategy. We develop a novel calibration procedure and find that systemic dependencies are statistically significant when the model is fitted to historical time series of equity and CDS data. An empirical analysis with data of companies in the Dow Jones Industrial Average 30 reveals the critical role of systemic risk in portfolio monitoring.</description><author>Capponi, Agostino; Frei, Christoph</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring Multichannel Advertising Response</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zantedeschi, Daniel; Feit, Eleanor McDonnell; Bradlow, Eric T.
Advances in data collection have made it increasingly easy to collect information on advertising exposures. However, translating this seemingly rich data into measures of advertising response has proven difficult, largely because of concerns that advertisers target customers with a higher propensity to buy or increase advertising during periods of peak demand. We show how this problem can be addressed by studying a setting where a firm randomly held out customers from each campaign, creating a sequence of randomized field experiments that mitigates (many) potential endogeneity problems. Exploratory analysis of individual holdout experiments shows positive effects for both email and catalog; however, the estimated effect for any individual campaign is imprecise, because of the small size of the holdout. To pool data across campaigns, we develop a hierarchical Bayesian model for advertising response that allows us to account for individual differences in purchase propensity and marketing response. Building on the traditional ad- stock framework, we are able to estimate separate decay rates for each advertising medium, allowing us to predict channel-specific short-and long-term effects of advertising and use these predictions to inform marketing strategy. We find that catalogs have substantially longer-lasting impact on customer purchase than emails. We show how the model can be used to score and target individual customers based on their advertising responsiveness, and we find that targeting the most responsive customers increases the predicted returns on advertising by approximately 70% versus traditional recency, frequency, and monetary value-based targeting.</description><author>Zantedeschi, Daniel; Feit, Eleanor McDonnell; Bradlow, Eric T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Targeted Discount Offers Serve as Advertising? Evidence from 70 Field Experiments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sahni, Navdeep S.; Zou, Dan; Chintagunta, Pradeep K.
The prevalence and widespread usage of email has given businesses a direct and cost-effective way of providing consumers with targeted discount offers. While these discounts are expected to increase the demand for the promoted products, are they effective in increasing revenues? Do they have effects beyond acting as price reductions? We study these questions using individual-level data from 70 randomized experiments run by a large online ticket resale platform. We estimate the redemption rates of the offers and also measure the broader impact of emailed promotions by comparing purchases by individuals who received the experimental promotions with purchases by those who did not receive the offers because of the experimental randomization. We find that the offers cause the average expenditure to increase significantly, by $3.03 ( a 37.2% increase) during the promotion window. However, the redemption rate of these offers is low. Importantly, 90% of these gains are not through redemption of the offers. The individuals who spent more on the platform in the past are more responsive to the offers, and the effect of the offers is significantly higher among individuals who did not transact on the platform in the year before the offer was given. Interestingly, the offer causes carryover to the week after the promotion expires; we find that spending increases by $ 1.55 in the week after the offer expires. Additionally, we find evidence for cross category spillovers to nonpromoted products: offers not applicable to a ticket genre cause an increase in spending in that genre. We conclude that emailed offers can serve as a form of "advertising" for the firm's products, in addition to being tools for price discrimination.</description><author>Sahni, Navdeep S.; Zou, Dan; Chintagunta, Pradeep K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Formal Theory of Strategy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Van den Steena, Eric
What makes a decision strategic? When is strategy most important? This paper formally studies these questions, starting from a (functional) definition of strategy as the smallest set of choices to optimally guide (or force) other choices. The paper shows that this definition coincides with the equilibrium outcome of a "strategy formulation game," in which such strategy endogenously creates a hierarchy among decisions. With respect to what makes a decision strategic and what makes strategy valuable, the paper considers the effect of commitment, reliability, and irreversibility of a decision; the presence of uncertainty (and the type of uncertainty); the number and strength of its interactions and the centrality of a decision; its level and importance; the development of capabilities; and competition.</description><author>Van den Steena, Eric</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Principles-Based Standards and Earnings Attributes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Folsom, David; Hribar, Paul; Mergenthaler, Richard D.; Peterson, Kyle
This study examines the relation between principles-based standards and earnings attributes. We create a firm-year-specific variable that measures the extent to which firms' financial reporting is affected by principles-based standards. We find that firms' earnings are more informative and persistent and have a larger positive association with future cash flows, on average, when firms' standards are more principles based. We also find evidence that managers use the added discretion provided by principles-based standards to manage earnings when firms are near bankruptcy, issuing equity, or experiencing high growth, and if earnings are near prominent earnings benchmarks. Overall, our evidence is consistent with managers using the discretion provided by principles-based standards to communicate better the economic substance of transactions, on average, but also with some managers using the added discretion strategically when managerial incentives exist to increase reported earnings.</description><author>Folsom, David; Hribar, Paul; Mergenthaler, Richard D.; Peterson, Kyle</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Pricing with Downside Liquidity Risks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anthonisz, Sean A.; Putnins, Alis J.
We develop a parsimonious liquidity-adjusted downside capital asset pricing model to investigate whether phenomena such as downward liquidity spirals and flights to liquidity impact expected asset returns. We find strong empirical support for the model. Downside liquidity risk (sensitivity of stock liquidity to negative market returns) has an economically meaningful return premium that is 10 times larger than its symmetric analogue. The expected liquidity level and downside market risk are also associated with meaningful return premiums. Downside liquidity risk and its associated premium are higher during periods of low marketwide liquidity and for stocks that are relatively small, illiquid, volatile, and have high book-to-market ratios. These results are consistent with investors requiring compensation for holding assets susceptible to adverse liquidity phenomena. Our findings suggest that mitigation of downside liquidity risk can lower firms' cost of capital.</description><author>Anthonisz, Sean A.; Putnins, Alis J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What's Your Identification Strategy? Innovation in Corporate Finance Research</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bowen, Donald E.; Fresard, Laurent; Taillard, Jerome P.
We study the diffusion of techniques designed to identify causal relationships in corporate finance research. We estimate that the diffusion started in the mid-1990s, lagged 20 years compared to economics, and is now used in the majority of corporate finance articles. Consistent with recent theories of technology diffusion, the adoption varies across researchers based on individuals' expected net benefits of adoption. Younger scholars, holders of PhDs in economics, and those working at top institutions adopt faster. Adoption is accelerated through networks of colleagues and alumni and is also facilitated by straddlers who cross over from economics to finance. Our findings highlight new forces that explain the diffusion of innovation and shape the norms of academic research.</description><author>Bowen, Donald E.; Fresard, Laurent; Taillard, Jerome P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment Decisions Under Ambiguity: Evidence from Mutual Fund Investor Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, C. Wei; Tiwari, Ashish; Tong, Lin
We provide novel evidence on the role of ambiguity aversion in determining the response of mutual fund investors to fund performance. Our analysis is motivated by theoretical models of decision making by ambiguity-averse investors. A key implication of the models is that when investors face information signals of uncertain quality, they place a greater weight on the worst signal. We find strong empirical support for this prediction in the form of heightened sensitivity of investor fund flows to the worst performance measure across multiple horizons. This effect is particularly pronounced for retail funds in contrast to institutional funds.</description><author>Li, C. Wei; Tiwari, Ashish; Tong, Lin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Supplier Competition and Cost Improvement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Cuihong; Wan, Zhixi
Buyers have two levers to enhance their supply base performance: fostering supplier competition and inducing suppliers to improve. The competition-improvement relation between the two levers has important implications for supply base design. We study a buyer facing two potential suppliers that can exert cost-reduction efforts, examining the interplay of supplier competition and supplier cost improvement under various information structures (i.e., the supplier effort is observable or unobservable) and commitment capabilities (i.e., the buyer may not commit, or may commit to a full or partial procurement mechanism, before suppliers exert efforts). We find that the two identical suppliers may choose unequal efforts, resulting in an asymmetric equilibrium outcome that enhances the performance of dual sourcing. Moreover, the competition-improvement relation depends on the effort observability. Whereas supplier competition always leads to lower improvement effort when the effort is unobservable, it may induce higher effort when the effort is observable. Thus, a trade-off between supplier competition and supplier effort is not always necessary in supply base design. Comparing the observable-and unobservable-effort cases, we demonstrate a detrimental effect of supplier effort observability on the buyer profits. Finally, we show that more commitment expands the presence of asymmetric equilibria, enhancing dual sourcing, and the partial commitment strengthens the positive effect of competition on observable efforts while maintaining the detrimental effect of effort observability.</description><author>Li, Cuihong; Wan, Zhixi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disruption Risk and Optimal Sourcing in Multitier Supply Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Erjie; Iancu, Dan A.; Swinney, Robert
We study sourcing in a supply chain with three levels: a manufacturer, tier 1 suppliers, and tier 2 suppliers prone to disruption from, e.g., natural disasters such as earthquakes or floods. The manufacturer may not directly dictate which tier 2 suppliers are used but may influence the sourcing decisions of tier 1 suppliers via contract parameters. The manufacturer's optimal strategy depends critically on the degree of overlap in the supply chain: if tier 1 suppliers share tier 2 suppliers, resulting in a "diamond-shaped" supply chain, the manufacturer relies less on direct mitigation (procuring excess inventory and multisourcing in tier 1) and more on indirect mitigation (inducing tier 1 suppliers to mitigate disruption risk). We also show that while the manufacturer always prefers less overlap, tier 1 suppliers may prefer a more overlapped supply chain and hence may strategically choose to form a diamond-shaped supply chain. This preference conflict worsens as the manufacturer's profit margin increases, as disruptions become more severe, and as unreliable tier 2 suppliers become more heterogeneous in their probability of disruption; however, penalty contracts-in which the manufacturer penalizes tier 1 suppliers for a failure to deliver ordered units-alleviate this coordination problem.</description><author>Ang, Erjie; Iancu, Dan A.; Swinney, Robert</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Known Unknowns: A Critical Determinant of Confidence and Calibration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Walters, Daniel J.; Fernbach, Philip M.; Fox, Craig R.; Sloman, Steven A.
We propose that an important determinant of judged confidence is the evaluation of evidence that is unknown or missing, and overconfidence is often driven by the neglect of unknowns. We contrast this account with prior research suggesting that overconfidence is due to biased processing of known evidence in favor of a focal hypothesis. In Study 1, we asked participants to list their thoughts as they answered two-alternative forced-choice trivia questions and judged the probability that their answers were correct. Participants who thought more about unknowns were less overconfident. In Studies 2 and 3, we asked participants to list unknowns before assessing their confidence. "Considering the unknowns" reduced overconfidence substantially and was more effective than the classic "consider the alternative" debiasing technique. Moreover, considering the unknowns selectively reduced confidence in domains where participants were overconfident but did not affect confidence in domains where participants were well-calibrated or underconfident.</description><author>Walters, Daniel J.; Fernbach, Philip M.; Fox, Craig R.; Sloman, Steven A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of Nothing: Asymmetric Attention to Opportunity Costs Drives Intertemporal Decision Making</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Read, Daniel; Olivola, Christopher Y.; Hardisty, David J.
This paper proposes a novel account of impatience: People pay more attention to the opportunity costs of choosing larger, later rewards than to the opportunity costs of choosing smaller, sooner ones. Eight studies show that when the opportunity costs of choosing smaller, sooner rewards are subtly highlighted, people become more patient, whereas when the opportunity costs of choosing larger, later rewards are highlighted this has no effect. This pattern is robust to variations in the choice task, to the participant population, and to whether the choices are incentivized or hypothetical. We argue that people are naturally aware of the opportunity costs of delayed rewards but pay less attention to those associated with smaller, sooner ones. We conclude by discussing implications for theory and policy.</description><author>Read, Daniel; Olivola, Christopher Y.; Hardisty, David J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Do People Prefer Carrots to Sticks? A Robust "Matching Effect" in Policy Evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Evers, Ellen R. K.; Inbar, Yoel; Blanken, Irene; Oosterwijk, Linda D.
For a policy to succeed, it must not only be effective in changing behavior but must also be accepted by stakeholders. Here, we report seven sets of studies demonstrating strong framing effects on the acceptance of equivalent policies. Policies targeting desirable voluntary behavior are preferred when they are framed as advantaging those who act desirably (rather than disadvantaging those who do not). Conversely, policies targeting obligations are preferred when they are framed as disadvantaging those who fail to act desirably (rather than advantaging those who do). These differences in policy acceptance do not result from common causes of framing effects, such as a misunderstanding of outcomes or insufficient deliberation about the implications. Rather, the framing effects we document follow from beliefs about when punishment is and is not appropriate. We conclude with a field experiment demonstrating framing effects in a setting where policy acceptance directly affects respondents' outcomes.</description><author>Evers, Ellen R. K.; Inbar, Yoel; Blanken, Irene; Oosterwijk, Linda D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Mechanisms in Online Peer-to-Peer Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wei, Zaiyan; Lin, Mingfeng
Online peer-to-peer lending (P2P lending) has emerged as an appealing new channel of financing in recent years. A fundamental but largely unanswered question in this nascent industry is the choice of market mechanisms, i.e., how the supply and demand of funds are matched, and the terms (price) at which transactions will occur. Two of the most popular mechanisms are auctions (where the "crowd" determines the price of the transaction through an auction process) and posted prices (where the platform determines the price). While P2P lending platforms typically use one or the other, there is little systematic research on the implications of such choices for market participants, transaction outcomes, and social welfare. We address this question both theoretically and empirically. We first develop a game-theoretic model that yields empirically testable hypotheses, taking into account the incentive of the platform. We then test these hypotheses by exploiting a regime change from auctions to posted prices on one of the largest P2P lending platforms. Consistent with our hypotheses, we find that under platform-mandated posted prices, loans are funded with higher probability, but the preset interest rates are higher than borrowers' starting interest rates and contract interest rates in auctions. More important, all else equal, loans funded under posted prices are more likely to default, thereby undermining lenders' returns on investment and their surplus. Although platform-mandated posted prices may be faster in originating loans, auctions that rely on the crowd to discover prices are not necessarily inferior in terms of overall social welfare.</description><author>Wei, Zaiyan; Lin, Mingfeng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Resource Allocation Under Demand Uncertainty and Private Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Belloni, Alexandre; Lopomo, Giuseppe; Wang, Shouqiang
We study the effect of multilateral private information on the efficiency of markets where capacity-constrained upstream agents supply a resource to downstream entities facing uncertain end-demands. We analyze two models: a "pooling system," in which a single downstream principal pools a resource from multiple upstream agents; and a "distribution system," in which one upstream principal allocates a resource across multiple downstream agents. We show that the presence of multilateral private information does not hinder efficiency in the pooling system. In contrast, in the distribution system, the quantities allocated to downstream agents can exceed, as well as fall short of, their first-best levels. These results shed light on the recently improved performance of U.S. agricultural produce market, and the observed episodes of shortages/oversupplies in flu vaccine and other seasonal markets.</description><author>Belloni, Alexandre; Lopomo, Giuseppe; Wang, Shouqiang</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robustly Strategic Consumption-Portfolio Rules with Informational</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Luo, Yulei
This paper provides a tractable continuous-time, constant absolute risk aversion-Gaussian framework to explore how the interactions of fundamental uncertainty, model uncertainty due to a preference for robustness, and state uncertainty due to information-processing constraints (rational inattention) affect strategic consumption-portfolio rules and precautionary savings in the presence of uninsurable labor income. Specifically, after solving the model explicitly, I compute and compare the elasticities of strategic asset allocation and precautionary savings to risk aversion, robustness, and inattention. Furthermore, for plausibly estimated and calibrated model parameters, I quantitatively analyze how the interactions of model uncertainty and state uncertainty affect the optimal share invested in the risky asset and show that they can provide a potential explanation for the observed stockholding behavior of households with different education and income levels.</description><author>Luo, Yulei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short- and Long-Run Business Conditions and Expected Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Qi; Tao, Libin; Wu, Weixing; Yu, Jianfeng
Numerous studies argue that the market risk premium is associated with expected economic conditions and show that proxies for expected business conditions indeed predict aggregate market returns. By directly estimating short- and long-run expected economic growth, we show that short- run expected economic growth is negatively related to future returns, whereas long-run expected economic growth is positively related to aggregate market returns. In addition, our findings indicate that the risk premium has both high- and low-frequency fluctuations and highlight the importance of distinguishing short- and long-run economic growth in macro-asset pricing models.</description><author>Liu, Qi; Tao, Libin; Wu, Weixing; Yu, Jianfeng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentive-Based Capital Requirements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eufinger, Christian; Gill, Andrej
This paper proposes a new regulatory approach that implements capital requirements contingent on executive incentive schemes. We argue that excessive risk taking in the financial sector originates from the shareholder moral hazard created by government guarantees rather than from corporate governance failures within banks. The idea behind the proposed regulatory approach is thus that the more the compensation structure decouples the interests of bank managers from those of shareholders by curbing risk-taking incentives, the higher the leverage the bank is permitted to take on. Consequently, the risk-shifting incentives caused by government guarantees and the risk-mitigating incentives created by the compensation structure offset each other such that the manager chooses the socially efficient investment policy.</description><author>Eufinger, Christian; Gill, Andrej</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Communication of Performance Schemes: Evidence from a Field Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Englmaier, Florian; Roider, Andreas; Sunde, Uwe
In corporate practice, incentive schemes are often complicated even for simple tasks. Hence, the way they are communicated might matter. In a natural field experiment, we study a minimally invasive change in the communication of a well-established incentive scheme-a reminder regarding the piece rate at the beginning of the shift. The experiment was conducted in a large firm where experienced managers work in a team production setting and where incentives for both quantity and quality of output are provided. While the treatment conveyed no additional material information and left the incentive system unchanged, it had significant positive effects on quantity and on managers' compensation. These effects are economically sizable and robust to alternative empirical specifications. We consider various potential mechanisms, but our preferred explanation is that the treatment raised the salience of incentives.</description><author>Englmaier, Florian; Roider, Andreas; Sunde, Uwe</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fantasy and Dread: The Demand for Information and the Consumption Utility of the Future</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ganguly, Ananda; Tasoff, Joshua
We present evidence that intrinsic demand for information about the future is increasing in expected future consumption utility. In the first experiment, subjects may resolve a lottery now or later. The information is useless for decision making, but the larger the reward, the more likely subjects are to pay to resolve the lottery early. In the second experiment, subjects may pay to avoid being tested for herpes simplex virus type 1 (HSV-1) and the more highly feared type 2 (HSV-2). Subjects are three times more likely to avoid testing for HSV-2, suggesting that more aversive outcomes lead to more information avoidance. In a third experiment, subjects make choices about when to get tested for a fictional disease. Some subjects behave in a way consistent with expected utility theory, and others exhibit greater delay of information for more severe diseases. We also find that information choice is correlated with positive affect, ambiguity aversion, and time preference, as some theories predict.</description><author>Ganguly, Ananda; Tasoff, Joshua</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fostering Public Good Contributions with Symbolic Awards: A Large-Scale Natural Field Experiment at Wikipedia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gallus, Jana
This natural field experiment tests the effects of purely symbolic awards on volunteer retention in a public goods context. The experiment is conducted at Wikipedia, which faces declining editor retention rates, particularly among newcomers. Randomization assures that award receipt is orthogonal to previous performance. The analysis reveals that awards have a sizeable effect on newcomer retention, which persists over the four quarters following the initial intervention. This is noteworthy for indicating that awards for volunteers can be effective even if they have no impact on the volunteers' future career opportunities. The awards are purely symbolic, and the status increment they produce is limited to the recipients' pseudonymous online identities in a community they have just recently joined. The results can be explained by enhanced self-identification with the community, but they are also in line with recent findings on the role of status and reputation, recognition, and evaluation potential in online communities.</description><author>Gallus, Jana</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sequential Search with Refinement: Model and Application with Click-Stream Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yuxin; Yao, Song
We propose a structural model of consumer sequential search under uncertainty about attribute levels of products. Our identification of the search model relies on exclusion restriction variables that separate consumer utility and search cost. Because such exclusion restrictions are often available in online click-stream data, the identification and corresponding estimation strategy is generalizable for many online shopping websites where such data can be easily collected. Furthermore, one important feature of online search technology is that it gives consumers the ability to refine search results using tools such as sorting and filtering based on product attributes. The proposed model can integrate consumers' decisions of search and refinement. The model is instantiated using consumer click-stream data of online hotel bookings provided by a travel website. The results show that refinement tools have significant effects on consumer behavior and market structure. We find that the refinement tools encourage 33% more searches and enhance the utility of purchased products by 17%. Most websites by default rank search results according to their popularity, quality, or relevance to consumers (e.g., Google). When consumers are unaware of such default ranking rules, they may engage in disproportionately more searches using refinement tools. Consequently, overall consumer surplus may deteriorate when total search cost outweighs the enhanced utility. In contrast, if the website simply informs consumers that the default ranking already reflects product popularity, quality, or relevance, consumers search less and their surplus improves. We also find that refinement tools lead to a less concentrated market structure.</description><author>Chen, Yuxin; Yao, Song</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Communication for Capacity Alignment with Pricing in a Supply Chain</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chu, Leon Yang; Shamir, Noam; Shin, Hyoduk
We study a supply chain comprised of a retailer who sources a product from a manufacturer. The retailer has superior forecast information about market demand, and the manufacturer builds the capacity and sets the wholesale price prior to demand realization. We explore forecast information sharing between the retailer and the manufacturer by means of cheap talk. We show that meaningful forecast information can be shared truthfully only before the manufacturer sets both the capacity and the wholesale price. By sharing the demand forecast with the manufacturer, the retailer faces the tradeoffs between inflating the forecast to convince the manufacturer to increase capacity and deflating the forecast to persuade the manufacturer to offer a lower wholesale price. When the value of forecast information sharing is high, the trade-offs are balanced, and incentives are aligned, leading to truthful information sharing. Moreover, we find that larger demand uncertainty can promote credible information sharing and, surprisingly, can benefit both firms. Finally, we demonstrate that under general distributions, in equilibrium, firms share forecasts as a form of range/interval, which has been also implemented in practice.</description><author>Chu, Leon Yang; Shamir, Noam; Shin, Hyoduk</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficient Algorithms for the Dynamic Pricing Problem with Reference Price Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Xin; Hu, Peng; Hu, Zhenyu
We analyze a finite-horizon dynamic pricing model in which demand at each period depends on not only the current price but also past prices through reference prices. A unique feature but also a significant challenge in this model is the asymmetry in reference price effect, which implies that the underlying optimization problem is nonsmooth and no standard optimization methods can be applied. We identify a few key structural properties of the problem, which enable us to develop strongly polynomial-time algorithms to compute the optimal prices for several plausible scenarios. We complement our exact algorithms by proposing an approximation heuristic and provide an upper bound on the optimal objective value. Finally, we conduct numerical experiments to study the optimal price path and demonstrate the value of dynamic pricing when demands are seasonal. We further compare numerically one of the exact algorithms with the heuristic and offer managerial suggestions.</description><author>Chen, Xin; Hu, Peng; Hu, Zhenyu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inventory Management Based on Target-Oriented Robust Optimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lim, Yun Fong; Wang, Chen
We propose a target-oriented robust optimization approach to solve a multiproduct, multiperiod inventory management problem subject to ordering capacity constraints. We assume the demand for each product in each period is characterized by an uncertainty set that depends only on a reference value and the bounds of the demand. Our goal is to find an ordering policy that maximizes the sizes of all the uncertainty sets such that all demand realizations from the sets will result in a total cost lower than a prespecified cost target. We prove that a static decision rule is optimal for an approximate formulation of the problem, which significantly reduces the computation burden. By tuning the cost target, the resultant policy can achieve a balance between the expected cost and the associated cost variance. Numerical experiments suggest that although only limited demand information is used, the proposed approach performs comparably to traditional methods based on dynamic programming and stochastic programming. More importantly, our approach significantly outperforms the traditional methods if the latter assume inaccurate demand distributions. We demonstrate the applicability of our approach through two case studies from different industries.</description><author>Lim, Yun Fong; Wang, Chen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Elasticity of Intertemporal Substitution in Consumption in the Presence of Inertia: Empirical Evidence from a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kapoor, Mudit; Ravi, Shamika
This paper estimates the elasticity of intertemporal substitution in consumption (sigma) by exploiting a natural experiment provided by a change in the Indian banking legislation. The new legislation authorized banks to offer higher interest rates on deposits to citizens above 60 years of age. We find evidence that households exhibit inertia in reoptimization and are sensitive to the timing of the actual change in the interest rate. Households do not respond to the predictable changes in future interest rates induced by the change in the legislation. We incorporate this and estimate the sigma to be approximately equal to 2.2.</description><author>Kapoor, Mudit; Ravi, Shamika</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Bayesian Methodology for Systemic Risk Assessment in Financial Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gandy, Axel; Veraart, Luitgard A. M.
We develop a Bayesian methodology for systemic risk assessment in financial networks such as the interbank market. Nodes represent participants in the network, and weighted directed edges represent liabilities. Often, for every participant, only the total liabilities and total assets within this network are observable. However, systemic risk assessment needs the individual liabilities. We propose a model for the individual liabilities, which, following a Bayesian approach, we then condition on the observed total liabilities and assets and, potentially, on certain observed individual liabilities. We construct a Gibbs sampler to generate samples from this conditional distribution. These samples can be used in stress testing, giving probabilities for the outcomes of interest. As one application we derive default probabilities of individual banks and discuss their sensitivity with respect to prior information included to model the network. An R package implementing the methodology is provided.</description><author>Gandy, Axel; Veraart, Luitgard A. M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bidding for Bidders? How the Format for Soliciting Supplier Participation in NYOP Auctions Impacts Channel Profit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fay, Scott; Zeithammer, Robert
In a name-your-own-price (NYOP) auction, consumers bid for a product or service. If a bid exceeds the concealed threshold price, the consumer receives the product at her bid price. This paper examines how to optimize the interactions between the NYOP retailer and service providers, while, at the same time, managing the bid acceptance rates in order to induce the desired consumer bidding behavior. Channel profit is impacted by how the retailer decides whether or not a given consumer bid will be accepted and, if so, which service provider is chosen to supply a unit of the product to the consumer. We devise a mechanism, the modified second-price auction, which maximizes channel profit.</description><author>Fay, Scott; Zeithammer, Robert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anticipated Regret and Product Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Baojun; Narasimhan, Chakravarthi; Turut, Ozge
When a firm introduces a product with new features, some consumers may find it difficult to assess their valuations for these new attributes. Their purchase decisions made under such uncertainty may lead to postpurchase regret. It has been experimentally shown that consumers may anticipate their potential postpurchase regret and make their current choices to mitigate or minimize it. That is, a consumer's anticipated regret can significantly impact his purchase decision. Given the trend that firms in various markets invoke regret to stimulate sales, this paper analytically explores whether and how anticipated regret affects competing firms' profits and product innovation. Our analyses reveal that the presence of anticipated regret can increase or decrease firms' profits, and foster or hinder product innovation depending on whether it makes the consumer segments more or less polarized; in other words, anticipated regret has a nonmonotonic effect on firms' profits and the entrant's optimal quality. Therefore, anticipated regret may sometimes create a win-win or a lose-lose situation for both firms. Regardless of whether the impact of anticipated regret on firms' profits is positive or negative, the magnitude of that impact tends to be higher for the low-quality firm.</description><author>Jiang, Baojun; Narasimhan, Chakravarthi; Turut, Ozge</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comment on "Strategic Information Management Under Leakage in a Supply Chain"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tian, Lin; Jiang, Baojun
Anand and Goyal [Anand KS, Goyal M (2009) Strategic information management under leakage in a supply chain. Management Sci. 55(3):438-452] propose a horizontal differentiation model to study information leakage and demand signaling in a supply chain. The authors present a composite equilibrium consisting of separating and pooling outcomes in different parameter regions and claim that it satisfies the intuitive criterion. We show that their analysis for the pooling equilibrium has errors and also that all pooling outcomes are actually eliminated by the intuitive criterion. The positive note is that if the undefeated equilibrium or the lexicographically maximum sequential equilibrium refinement is adopted, a similar composite equilibrium will be achieved, which will lead to qualitatively the same results as in the original paper.</description><author>Tian, Lin; Jiang, Baojun</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Model of Mental Accounting and Reference Price Adaptation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baucells, Manel; Hwang, Woonam
Consumers possess a mental account that stores the worth of items purchased and yet to be consumed. Reference prices act as the book values of these items. Movements in the account-the comparison between the reference price and the price paid at entry, and the comparison between the benefit of consumption and the reference price at exit-yield hedonic benefits. The reference price is determined by a psychological process of adaptation to the price evoked by the trade. The model is integrative in that it explains a wide array of observed anomalies such as sunk-cost effects, payment depreciation, reluctance to trade, preference for prepayment, and the flat-rate bias. The model also generates new testable implications.</description><author>Baucells, Manel; Hwang, Woonam</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Local Capital Market Conditions Affect Consumers' Borrowing Decisions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Butler, Alexander W.; Cornaggia, Jess; Gurun, Umit G.
This paper uses detailed data from an online peer-to-peer lending intermediary to test whether local access to finance affects consumers' willingness to pay for loans. After controlling for local economic conditions and borrower credit quality, we find that borrowers who reside in areas with good access to bank finance request loans with lower interest rates. This effect is stronger for borrowers with poor credit and those seeking small loans, suggesting that local access to finance is more important for marginal borrowers. Overall, our findings shed light on how consumers substitute between alternative sources of finance.</description><author>Butler, Alexander W.; Cornaggia, Jess; Gurun, Umit G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Investors Value Dividend-Smoothing Stocks Differently?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Larkin, Yelena; Leary, Mark T.; Michaely, Roni
It is widely documented that managers strive to maintain smooth dividends. Yet, it is not clear if this behavior reflects investors' preferences. In this paper, we study whether investors indeed value dividend-smoothing stocks differently by exploring the implications of dividend smoothing for firms' investor clientele, stock prices, and cost of capital. We find that retail investors are less likely to hold dividend-smoothing stocks, while institutional investors, and especially mutual funds, are more likely. However, this preference does not result in any detectable relation between the smoothness of a firm's dividends and the expected return, or market value, of its stock. Together, the evidence suggests that firms adjust the supply of smoothed dividends to match investors' demand. Dividend smoothing affects the composition of a firm's shareholders but has little impact on its stock price.</description><author>Larkin, Yelena; Leary, Mark T.; Michaely, Roni</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Threat of Exclusion and Implicit Contracting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Martin; Serra-Garcia, Marta
Implicit contracts can mitigate moral hazard in labor, credit, and product markets. The enforcement mechanism underlying an implicit contract is the threat of exclusion: the agent fears that he will lose future income if the principal breaks off the relationship. This threat may be very weak in environments where an agent can appropriate income-generating resources provided by the principal. For example, in credit markets with weak creditor protection, borrowers may be able to appropriate borrowed funds and generate investment income without requiring further loans. We examine implicit contracting in a lending experiment where the threat of exclusion is exogenously varied. We find that weak exclusion undermines implicit contracting: it leads to a more frequent breakdown of credit relationships as well as to smaller loans.</description><author>Brown, Martin; Serra-Garcia, Marta</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Opacity, Credit Rating Shopping, and Bias</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sangiorgi, Francesco; Spatt, Chester
We develop a rational expectations model in which an issuer purchases credit ratings sequentially, deciding which to disclose to investors. Opacity about contacts between the issuer and rating agencies induces potential asymmetric information about which ratings the issuer obtained. While the equilibrium forces disclosure of ratings when the market knows these have been generated, endogenous uncertainty about whether there are undisclosed ratings can arise and lead to selective disclosure and rating bias. Although investors account for this bias in pricing, selective disclosure makes ratings noisier signals of project value, leading to inefficient investment decisions. Our paper suggests that regulatory disclosure requirements are welfare enhancing.</description><author>Sangiorgi, Francesco; Spatt, Chester</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Bags Fly Free? An Empirical Analysis of the Operational Implications of Airline Baggage Fees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nicolae, Mariana; Arikan, Mazhar; Deshpande, Vinayak; Ferguson, Mark
In 2008, the majority of U.S. airlines began charging for the second checked bag, and then for the first checked bag. One of the often cited reasons for this action by the airlines' executives was that this would influence customers to travel with less baggage and thus improve cost and operational performance. A popular customer belief, however, is that airline departure delays got worse due to an increase and size of customer carry-on baggage. A notable exception to the charging for checked bags trend was Southwest Airlines, which turned their resistance to this practice into a "Bags Fly Free" marketing campaign. Using a publicly available database of the airlines' departure performance, we investigate whether the implementation of checked bag fees was really associated with better operational performance metrics. At the aggregate level, using all publicly recorded U.S. flights from May 1, 2007, to May 1, 2009, we find that the airlines that began charging for checked bags saw a significant relative improvement in their on-time departure performance in the time periods after the baggage fees were implemented. Surprisingly, we also find that airlines that did not charge for checked bags also saw an improvement, although not as big, when competing airlines flying the same origin-destination city markets implemented the fees. The improvement in on-time departure performance was the largest for flights during peak evening departure time blocks.</description><author>Nicolae, Mariana; Arikan, Mazhar; Deshpande, Vinayak; Ferguson, Mark</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Size of the LGBT Population and the Magnitude of Antigay Sentiment Are Substantially Underestimated</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coffman, Katherine B.; Coffman, Lucas C.; Ericson, Keith M. Marzilli
We demonstrate that widely used measures of antigay sentiment and the size of the lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (LGBT) population are misestimated, likely substantially. In a series of online experiments using a large and diverse but nonrepresentative sample, we compare estimates from the standard methodology of asking sensitive questions to measures from a "veiled" methodology that precludes inference about an individual but provides population estimates. The veiled method increased self-reports of antigay sentiment, particularly in the workplace: respondents were 67% more likely to disapprove of an openly gay manager when asked with a veil, and 71% more likely to say it should be legal to discriminate in hiring on the basis of sexual orientation. The veiled methodology also produces larger estimates of the fraction of the population that identifies as LGBT or has had a sexual experience with a member of the same sex. Self-reports of nonheterosexual identity rose by 65%, and same-sex sexual experiences by 59%. We conduct a "placebo test" and show that for nonsensitive placebo items, the veiled methodology produces effects that are small in magnitude and not significantly different from zero in seven out of eight items. Taken together, the results suggest antigay discrimination might be a more significant issue than formerly considered, as the nonheterosexual population and antigay workplace-related sentiment are both larger than previously measured.</description><author>Coffman, Katherine B.; Coffman, Lucas C.; Ericson, Keith M. Marzilli</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gatekeepers at Work: An Empirical Analysis of a Maternity Unit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Freeman, Michael; Savva, Nicos; Scholtes, Stefan
We use a detailed operational and clinical data set from a maternity hospital to investigate how workload affects decisions in gatekeeper-provider systems, where the servers act as gatekeepers to specialists but may also attempt to serve customers themselves, albeit with a probability of success that is decreasing in the complexity of the customers' needs. We study the effect of workload during a service episode on gatekeepers' service configuration decisions and the rate at which gatekeepers refer customers to a specialist. We find that gatekeeper-providers (midwives in our context) make substantial use of two levers to manage their workload (measured as patients per midwife): they ration resource-intensive discretionary services (epidural analgesia) for customers with noncomplex service needs (mothers with spontaneous onset of labor) and, at the same time, increase the rate of specialist referral (physician-led delivery) for customers with complex needs (mothers with pharmacologically induced labor). The workload effect in the study unit is surprisingly large and comparable in size to those for leading clinical risk factors: when workload increases from two standard deviations below to two standard deviations above the mean, noncomplex cases are 28.8% less likely to receive an epidural, leading to a cost reduction of 8.7%, while complex cases are 14.2% more likely to be referred for a physician-led delivery, leading to a cost increase of 2.6%. These observations are consistent with overtreatment at both high and low workload levels, albeit for different types of patients, and suggest that smoothing gatekeeper workload would reduce variability in customer service experience.</description><author>Freeman, Michael; Savva, Nicos; Scholtes, Stefan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Observability Increases the Demand for Commitment Devices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Exley, Christine L.; Naecker, Jeffrey K.
Previous research often interprets the choice to restrict one's future opportunity set as evidence for sophisticated time inconsistency. We propose an additional mechanism that may contribute to the demand for commitment technology: the desire to signal to others. We present a field experiment where participants can choose to give up money if they do not follow through with an action. When commitment choices are made public rather than kept private, we find significantly higher uptake rates.</description><author>Exley, Christine L.; Naecker, Jeffrey K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gender Differences in Stereotypes of Risk Preferences: Experimental Evidence from a Matrilineal and a Patrilineal Society</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pondorfer, Andreas; Barsbai, Toman; Schmidt, Ulrich
We use a controlled experiment to analyze gender differences in stereotypes about risk preferences of men and women across two distinct island societies in the Pacific: the patrilineal Palawan in the Philippines and the matrilineal Teop in Papua New Guinea. We find no gender differences in actual risk preferences, but we find evidence for culture-specific stereotypes. Like men in Western societies, Palawan men overestimate women's actual risk aversion. By contrast, Teop men underestimate women's actual risk aversion. We argue that the observed differences in stereotypes between the two societies are determined by the different social status of women.</description><author>Pondorfer, Andreas; Barsbai, Toman; Schmidt, Ulrich</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debtor Rights, Credit Supply, and Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cerqueiro, Geraldo; Hegde, Deepak; Penas, Maria Fabiana; Seamans, Robert C.
Firms' innovative activities can be sensitive to public policies that affect the availability of capital. In this paper, we investigate the effects of regional and temporal variation in U.S. personal bankruptcy laws on firms' innovative activities. We find that bankruptcy laws that provide stronger debtor protection decrease the number of patents produced by small firms. Stronger debtor protection also decreases the average quality, and variance in quality, of firms' patents. We find evidence that the negative effect of stronger debtor protection on experimentation and innovation may be due to the decreased availability of external financing in response to stronger debtor rights, an effect amplified in industries with a high dependence on external financing. Hence, while it is typically assumed that stronger debtor protection encourages innovation by reducing the cost of failure for innovators, we show that it can instead dampen innovative activities by tightening the availability of external financing to innovative firms.</description><author>Cerqueiro, Geraldo; Hegde, Deepak; Penas, Maria Fabiana; Seamans, Robert C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Moral Hazard in Dynamic Risk Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cvitanic, Jaksa; Possamai, Dylan; Touzi, Nizar
We consider a contracting problem in which a principal hires an agent to manage a risky project. When the agent chooses volatility components of the output process and the principal observes the output continuously, the principal can compute the quadratic variation of the output, but not the individual components. This leads to moral hazard with respect to the risk choices of the agent. To find the optimal contract, we develop a novel approach to solving principal-agent problems: first, we identify a family of admissible contracts for which the optimal agent's action is explicitly characterized; then, we show that we do not lose on generality when finding the optimal contract inside this family, up to integrability conditions. To do this, we use the recent theory of singular changes of measures for Ito processes. We solve the problem in the case of CARA preferences and show that the optimal contract is linear in these factors: the contractible sources of risk, including the output, the quadratic variation of the output and the cross-variations between the output and the contractible risk sources. Thus, like sample Sharpe ratios used in practice, path-dependent contracts naturally arise when there is moral hazard with respect to risk management. In a numerical example, we show that the loss of efficiency can be significant if the principal does not use the quadratic variation component of the optimal contract.</description><author>Cvitanic, Jaksa; Possamai, Dylan; Touzi, Nizar</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Customer Referral Incentives and Social Media</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lobel, Ilan; Sadler, Evan; Varshney, Lav R.
We study how to optimally attract new customers using a referral program. Whenever a consumer makes a purchase, the firm gives her a link to share with friends, and every purchase coming through that link generates a referral payment. The firm chooses the referral payment function and consumers play an equilibrium in response. The optimal payment function is nonlinear and not necessarily monotonic in the number of successful referrals. If we approximate the optimal policy using a linear payment function, the approximation loss scales with the square root of the average consumer degree. Using a threshold payment, the approximation loss scales proportionally to the average consumer degree. Combining the two, using a linear payment function with a threshold bonus, we can achieve a constant bound on the approximation loss.</description><author>Lobel, Ilan; Sadler, Evan; Varshney, Lav R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price-Matching Guarantees with Endogenous Consumer Search</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Juncai; Kumar, Nanda; Ratchford, Brian T.
Price-matching guarantees (PMGs) are offered in a wide array of product categories in retail markets. PMGs offer consumers the assurance that, should they find a lower price elsewhere within a specified period after purchase the retailer will match that price and refund the price difference. The goal of this study is to explain the following stylized facts: (1) many retailers that operate both online and offline implement PMG offline but not online; (2) the practices of PMG vary considerably across retail categories; and (3) some retailers launch specialized websites that automatically check competitors' prices for consumers after purchase. To this end, we build a sequential search model that endogenizes consumers' pre- and postpurchase search decisions. We find that PMG expands retail demand but intensifies price competition on two dimensions. PMG drives retailers to offer deeper promotions because it increases the overall extent of consumer search, which we call the primary competition-intensifying effect. We also find a new secondary competition-intensifying effect, which results from endogenous consumer search. As deeper promotions incentivize consumers to continue price search, retailers are forced to lower the "regular" price to deter consumers from searching. The strength of the secondary competition-intensifying effect increases with the ratio of product valuation to search cost, which explains the variation in PMG practices online versus offline and across retail categories. We show that an asymmetric equilibrium exists such that one retailer offers PMG while the other does not. In this equilibrium, the PMG retailer may benefit from launching a price check website to facilitate consumers' postpurchase search.</description><author>Jiang, Juncai; Kumar, Nanda; Ratchford, Brian T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do We Really Need to Change the Decision Maker? Counterintuitive Escalation of Commitment Results in Real Options Contexts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boulding, William; Guha, Abhijit; Staelin, Richard
A robust finding in the escalation literature, termed as the preference effect, is that involvement in the period 1 initial project assessment decision increases the tendency for decision makers to stick with a losing course of action during the period 2 project reassessment decision. The proposed solution is to bring in a new decision maker in period 2. Across multiple studies, we show that providing period 1 information in real options format increases the tendency for decision makers to view period 2 focal event information as both more negative and more important. Consequently, such decision makers exhibit less escalation in period 2, i.e., exhibit behavior opposite to the preference effect. This suggests that, in real option contexts, not only do we not need to bring in a new decision maker, but also (counterintuitively) it is beneficial to retain the same decision maker in situations where escalation is likely to occur.</description><author>Boulding, William; Guha, Abhijit; Staelin, Richard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Platform Integration and Demand Spillovers in Complementary Markets: Evidence from Facebook's Integration of Instagram</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Zhuoxin; Agarwal, Ashish
Social media platform owners often choose to provide tighter integration with their own complementary applications (i.e., first-party applications) as compared to that with other complementary third-party applications. We study the impact of such integration on consumer demand for first-party applications and competing third-party applications by exploring Facebook's integration of Instagram, an application in its photo-sharing application ecosystem. We find that consumers obtain additional value from Instagram after its integration with Facebook, leading to a large increase in the use of Instagram for Facebook photo sharing. Further, we find that the growth of Instagram's user base has a positive spillover effect on big third-party applications and a negative spillover effect on small third-party applications in Facebook's photo-sharing ecosystem. As a result, while small third-party applications face reduced demand after integration, big third-party applications experience a small increase in demand. Thus, the overall demand for the entire photo-sharing application ecosystem actually increases, which suggests that Facebook's integration strategy benefits the complementary market overall. Our results highlight the role of platform integration for first-party applications and the application ecosystem overall, and they have implications for strategic management of first-party applications in the presence of third-party applications.</description><author>Li, Zhuoxin; Agarwal, Ashish</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stature, Obesity, and Portfolio Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Addoum, Jawad M.; Korniotis, George; Kumar, Alok
Using multiple U.S. and European data sources, we show that observed physical attributes are related to participation in financial markets. Specifically, we find that individuals who are relatively tall and of normal weight are more likely to hold stocks in their financial portfolios. We consider several potential mechanisms that could drive the relation between physical attributes and portfolio decisions. We find that teenage social experiences as well as genetic and prenatal endowments that are fixed at birth are the two channels through which height affects financial decisions. Furthermore, we find that the relation between body mass index and portfolio decisions is largely driven by education and race.</description><author>Addoum, Jawad M.; Korniotis, George; Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Implications of Nonlinear Pricing Kernels</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, Caio; Garcia, Rene
Based on a family of discrepancy functions, we derive nonparametric stochastic discount factor bounds that naturally generalize variance, entropy, and higher-moment bounds. These bounds are especially useful to identify how parameters affect pricing kernel dispersion in asset pricing models. In particular, they allow us to distinguish between models where dispersion comes mainly from skewness from models where kurtosis is the primary source of dispersion. We analyze the admissibility of disaster, disappointment aversion, and long-run risk models with respect to these bounds.</description><author>Almeida, Caio; Garcia, Rene</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal and Naive Diversification in Currency Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ackermann, Fabian; Pohl, Walt; Schmedders, Karl
DeMiguel et al. [DeMiguel V, Garlappi L, Uppal R (2009) Optimal versus naive diversification: How inefficient is the 1/N portfolio strategy? Rev. Financial Stud. 22(5): 1915-1953] showed that in the stock market, it is difficult for an optimized portfolio constructed using mean-variance analysis to outperform a simple, equally weighted portfolio because of estimation error. In this paper, we demonstrate that portfolio optimization can be made to work in currency markets. The key difference between the two settings is that in currency markets interest rates provide a predictor of future returns that is free of estimation error, which permits the application of mean-variance analysis. We show that over the last 26 years, a mean-variance efficient portfolio constructed in this fashion has a Sharpe ratio of 0.91, versus only 0.15 for the equally weighted portfolio. We also consider the practical implementation of this strategy.</description><author>Ackermann, Fabian; Pohl, Walt; Schmedders, Karl</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Probit Choice Model Under Sequential Search with an Application to Online Retailing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Jun B.; Albuquerque, Paulo; Bronnenberg, Bart J.
We develop a probit choice model under optimal sequential search and apply it to the study of aggregate demand of consumer durable goods. In our joint model of search and choice, we derive an expression for the probability of choice that obeys the full set of restrictions imposed by optimal sequential search. Estimation of our partially analytic model avoids the computation of high-dimensional integrations in the evaluation of choice probabilities, which is of particular benefit when search sets are large. We demonstrate the advantages of our approach in data experiments and apply the model to aggregate search and choice data from the camcorder product category at Amazon.com. We show that the joint use of search and choice data provides better performance in terms of inferences and predictions than using search data alone and leads to realistic estimates of consumer substitution patterns.</description><author>Kim, Jun B.; Albuquerque, Paulo; Bronnenberg, Bart J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expertise in Online Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Despotakis, Stylianos; Hafalir, Isa; Ravi, R.; Sayedi, Amin
We examine the effect of the presence of expert buyers on other buyers, the platform, and the sellers in online markets. We model buyer expertise as the ability to accurately predict the quality, or condition, of an item, modeled as its common value. We show that nonexperts may bid more aggressively, even above their expected valuation, to compensate for their lack of information. As a consequence, we obtain two interesting implications. First, auctions with a "hard close" may generate higher revenue than those with a "soft close." Second, contrary to the linkage principle, an auction platform may obtain a higher revenue by hiding the item's common-value information from the buyers. We also consider markets where both auctions and posted prices are available and show that the presence of experts allows the sellers of high-quality items to signal their quality by choosing to sell via auctions.</description><author>Despotakis, Stylianos; Hafalir, Isa; Ravi, R.; Sayedi, Amin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bayesian Estimation of a Dynamic Model of Two-Sided Markets: Application to the US Video Game Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhou, Yiyi
This paper develops and estimates a structural model of two-sided markets with durable platform intermediaries and affiliated products. It models buyers' purchase decisions of platforms and affiliated products and sellers' decisions of price setting and entry, accounting for the dynamic interaction between the two distinct groups of platform participants. To estimate the proposed model, this paper develops a Bayesian Markov chain Monte Carlo estimation approach that incorporates nonparametric approximation and interpolation methods. The proposed model and estimation method are applied to the 32/64-bit generation of the U.S. video game industry. The results of counterfactual experiments show that the dynamic behavior of platform participants has significant impacts on platform adoption and the affiliated product market, and that a failed platform could have survived if it had priced the two sides properly in a dynamic two-sided market environment.</description><author>Zhou, Yiyi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Herd Behavior and Mutual Fund Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koch, Andrew
I develop fund-level measures of the similarity in trading of mutual fund managers, resulting in the identification of leaders, contemporaneously herding managers, and followers. I find evidence of a persistent group of funds whose trades lead the aggregate trades of the mutual fund industry; these leader funds exhibit strong subsequent performance, consistent with informed trading. By contrast, there is no evidence that managers that trade together, either contemporaneously or with a lag, outperform. These findings suggest that managers of leader funds receive in advance private signals regarding the information upon which other funds focus.</description><author>Koch, Andrew</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Investment Shocks Explain the Cross Section of Equity Returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garlappi, Lorenzo; Song, Zhongzhi
Using two macro-based measures and one return-based measure of investment-specific technology (IST) shocks, we find that over the 1964-2012 period, exposure to IST shocks cannot explain cross-sectional return spreads based on book-to-market, momentum, asset growth, net share issues, accrual, and price-to-earnings ratio. Only one of the two macro-based measures can explain a sizable portion of the value premium over the longer 1930-2012 period. We also find that the IST risk premium estimates are sensitive to the sample period, the data frequency, the test assets, and the econometric model specification. Impulse responses of aggregate investment and consumption indicate potential measurement problems in IST proxies, which may contribute to the sensitivity of IST risk premium estimates and the failure of IST shocks to explain cross-sectional returns.</description><author>Garlappi, Lorenzo; Song, Zhongzhi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incompatible European Partners? Cultural Predispositions and Household Financial Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haliassos, Michael; Jansson, Thomas; Karabulut, Yigitcan
The recent influx of migrants and refugees into Europe and elsewhere raises questions as to whether migrant behavior reflects cultural predispositions and whether assimilation through exposure to host institutions can be expected. The paper focuses on financial behavior and uses high-quality administrative data on migrants and refugees to Sweden. It uncovers differences across cultural groups in how behavior relates to household characteristics, and shows that differences diminish with exposure to host country institutions, even for large cultural distances. Interestingly, robust cultural classification of European countries based on genetic distance or on Hofstede's cultural dimensions fails to identify a single "southern" culture but points to a "northern" culture. Our results also have implications for the potential of European institutional harmonization, exogenously imposed during the fiscal crisis, to alleviate cultural differences in financial behavior.</description><author>Haliassos, Michael; Jansson, Thomas; Karabulut, Yigitcan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Conditional Beta Is Alive and Well in the Cross Section of Daily Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Engle, Robert F.; Tang, Yi
This paper presents evidence for a significantly positive link between the dynamic conditional beta and the cross section of daily stock returns. An investment strategy that takes a long position in stocks in the highest conditional beta decile and a short position in stocks in the lowest conditional beta decile produces average returns and alphas in the range of 0.60%-0.80% per month. We provide an investor attention-based explanation of this finding. We show that stocks with high conditional beta have strong attention-grabbing characteristics, leading to a higher fraction of buyer-initiated trades for these stocks. We also find that stocks recently bought perform significantly better than stocks recently sold. Hence, the high beta stocks that investors are more likely to buy have higher expected returns than the low beta stocks that investors are more likely to sell.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Engle, Robert F.; Tang, Yi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Justice Under Uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cettolin, Elena; Riedl, Arno
Uncertain outcomes are an inevitable feature of policy choices and their public support often depends on their perceived justice. We theoretically and experimentally explore just allocations when recipients are exposed to certainty and uncertainty. In the experiment, uninvolved participants unequivocally choose to allocate resources equally between recipients, when there is certainty. In stark contrast, with uncertainty just allocations are widely dispersed and recipients exposed to higher degrees of uncertainty are allocated less. The observed allocations can be well organized by four different theoretical views of justice, indicating that uninvolved participants differ fundamentally in their views on justice under uncertainty.</description><author>Cettolin, Elena; Riedl, Arno</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Indirect Reciprocity and Charitable Giving-Evidence from a Field Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khadjavi, Menusch
This paper investigates two channels of prosociality: indirect reciprocity and charitable giving. We conducted a natural field experiment in a hair salon in Hamburg, Germany, over the course of four months. In the baseline, we collected data on customers' tips-a scenario absent indirect reciprocity and donations. In two treatments we had the hairdresser collect donations to a charity. In one treatment the hairdresser pointed out the opportunity to donate. Our data indicate that the voluntary activity of collecting donations in the salon led to greater tips for the hairdresser and significant donations. In the second treatment, the hairdresser unconditionally donated to the charity before the customers could. This donation did not increase tips further compared with the collection-only treatment. Our data indicate that indirect reciprocity works in the field. We find evidence that indirect reciprocity and charitable giving work as complements.</description><author>Khadjavi, Menusch</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the Unemployment Benefit Institution Affect the Productivity of Workers? Evidence from the Field</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blancom, Mariana; Dalton, Patricio S.; Vargas, Juan F.
This paper studies the effects of unemployment benefit schemes on individual productivity. We created employment and unemployment in the field and compared workers' productivity under no unemployment benefits to productivity under two different unemployment schemes. In one scheme, the unemployed received an unconditional monetary transfer. In the other, the monetary transfer was obtained conditional on the unemployed spending some time on an ancillary activity. Our results challenge the standard economic theory prediction that unemployment benefits, especially unconditional compensations, hinder workers' effort. We find that workers employed under the unconditional scheme are more productive than workers under the conditional one, and both schemes make workers more productive than having no unemployment benefit. We discuss two possible explanations for our results based on reciprocity and differential psychological costs of unemployment across unemployment benefit schemes.</description><author>Blancom, Mariana; Dalton, Patricio S.; Vargas, Juan F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Restructuring Charges, FAS 146, and the Accrual Anomaly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhojraj, Sanjeev; Sengupta, Partha; Zhang, Suning
In this study, we examine the role of restructuring charges in the existence and subsequent weakening of the widely documented accrual anomaly. We find that prior to 2003, the significant positive abnormal hedge returns experienced by accrual based strategies were influenced by a subset of firms with high restructuring charges. After 2003, with the introduction of the Statement of Financial Accounting Standards No. 146 changing the accounting for restructuring charges, restructuring firms no longer experience significant abnormal returns, thereby weakening the accrual anomaly. Our results suggest that the regulatory changes have had an effect on impairing the role of restructuring charges in the accrual anomaly by improving the market's ability to correctly assess the valuation implications of restructuring charges in the low accruals portfolios.</description><author>Bhojraj, Sanjeev; Sengupta, Partha; Zhang, Suning</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comment and Response to "Do Client Characteristics Really Drive the Big N Audit Quality Effect? New Evidence from Propensity Score Matching" by Mark DeFond, David H. Erkens, and Jieying Zhang</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeFond, Mark; Erkens, David H.; Zhang, Jieying
This discussion presents the comments by the authors of Lawrence et al. [Lawrence A, Minutti-Meza M, Zhang P (2011) Can Big 4 versus non-Big 4 differences in audit-quality proxies be attributed to client characteristics? Accounting Rev. 86(1): 259-286] to the critique of their study in DeFond et al. [DeFond M, Erkens DH, Zhang J (2017) Do client characteristics really drive the Big N audit quality effect? New evidence from propensity score matching. Management Sci. 63(11):3628-3649] and response by the authors of the latter study.</description><author>DeFond, Mark; Erkens, David H.; Zhang, Jieying</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Behavioral Model of Forecasting: Naive Statistics on Mental Samples</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tong, Jordan; Feiler, Daniel
Most operations models assume individuals make decisions based on a perfect understanding of random variables or stochastic processes. In reality, however, individuals are subject to cognitive limitations and make systematic errors. We leverage established psychology on sample naivete to model individuals' forecasting errors and biases in a way that is portable to operations models. The model has one behavioral parameter and embeds perfect rationality as a special case. We use the model to mathematically characterize point and error forecast behavior, reflecting an individual's beliefs about the mean and variance of a random variable. We then derive 10 behavioral phenomena that are inconsistent with perfect rationality assumptions but supported by existing empirical evidence. Finally, we apply the model to two operations settings, inventory management and queuing, to illustrate the model's portability and discuss its numerous predictions. For inventory management, we characterize order decisions assuming behavioral demand forecasting. The model predicts that even under automated cost optimization, one should expect a pull-to-center effect. It also predicts that this effect can be mitigated by separating point forecasting from error forecasting. For base stock models, it predicts that safety stocks are too small (large) for short (long) lead times. We also express the steady-state behavior of a queue with balking, assuming rational joining decisions but behavioral wait-time forecasts. The model predicts that joining customers tend to be disappointed in their experienced waits. Also, for long (short) lines, it predicts customers have more (less) disperse wait-time beliefs and tend to overestimate (underestimate) the true wait-time variance.</description><author>Tong, Jordan; Feiler, Daniel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer Choice Models with Endogenous Network Effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Ruxian; Wang, Zizhuo
Network externality arises when the utility of a product depends not only on its attributes but also on the number of consumers who purchase the same product. In this paper, we study consumer choice models that endogenize such network externality. We first characterize the choice probabilities under such models and conduct studies on comparative statics. Then we investigate the assortment optimization problem under such choice models. Although the problem is generally NP-hard, we show that a new class of assortments, called quasi-revenue-ordered assortments, which consist of a revenue-ordered assortment plus at most one additional item, are optimal under mild conditions. We also propose an iterative estimation method to calibrate such choice models, for both uncensored and censored data cases. An empirical study on a mobile game data set shows that our proposed model can provide better fits for the data, increase the prediction accuracy for consumer choices, and potentially increase revenue.</description><author>Wang, Ruxian; Wang, Zizhuo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Joint Panel Sizing and Appointment Scheduling in Outpatient Care</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zacharias, Christos; Armony, Mor
Patients nationwide experience difficulties in accessing medical care in a timely manner due to long backlogs of appointments. Medical practices aim to utilize their valuable resources efficiently, deliver timely access to care, and at the same time they strive to provide short waiting times for patients present at the medical facility. We address the joint problem of determining the panel size of a medical practice and the number of offered appointment slots per day, so that patients do not face long backlogs and the clinic is not overcrowded. We explicitly model the two time scales involved in accessing medical care: appointment delay (order of days, weeks) and clinic delay (order of minutes, hours). Closed-form expressions are derived for the performance measures of interest based on diffusion approximations. Our model captures many features of the complex reality of outpatient care, including patient no-shows, balking behavior, and random service times. Our analysis provides theoretical and numerical support for the optimality of an "open access" policy in outpatient scheduling when we account for both types of delay, and it demonstrates the importance of considering panel sizing and scheduling decisions in a joint framework.</description><author>Zacharias, Christos; Armony, Mor</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option Pricing for a Jump-Diffusion Model with General Discrete Jump-Size Distributions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fu, Michael C.; Li, Bingqing; Li, Guozhen; Wu, Rongwen
We obtain a closed-form solution for pricing European options under a general jump-diffusion model that can incorporate arbitrary discrete jump-size distributions, including nonparametric distributions such as an empirical distribution. The flexibility in the jump-size distribution allows the model to better capture leptokurtic features found in real-world data. The model uses a discrete-time framework and leads to a pricing formula that is provably convergent to the continuous-time price as the discretization is increased. The solution is easy to implement with fast convergence properties. Numerical results illustrate the efficiency and accuracy of the proposed model and highlight its robustness and flexibility.</description><author>Fu, Michael C.; Li, Bingqing; Li, Guozhen; Wu, Rongwen</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Selling Out: The Inauthenticity Discount in the Craft Beer Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frake, Justin
This paper investigates why audiences devalue organizations that behave inauthentically. One explanation is that inauthenticity leads to lower perceptions of product quality. This stems from the audience's doubt of an inauthentic actor's capability and commitment to produce high-quality goods. Another explanation is that audiences discount the symbolic value-or what the object represents-of products from inauthentic organizations. I empirically test each of these mechanisms in the craft beer industry. First, I exploit exogenous variation in consumers' knowledge of craft brewers' inauthentic identity (whether they are owned by a corporate brewer) to empirically demonstrate an inauthenticity discount. Next, I decompose audience evaluations to show that knowledge of a producer's inauthenticity does not have a statistically significant impact on evaluators' sensory experience of the product-its taste, smell, appearance, or mouthfeel-but that it does affect audience evaluations of the product's symbolic value.</description><author>Frake, Justin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Editorial Statement-Business Strategy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gans, Joshua
nan</description><author>Gans, Joshua</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Legal-System Arbitrage and Parent-Subsidiary Capital Structures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Suman; Noe, Thomas H.
This paper develops a new theory of the capital structure of parent-subsidiary organizations based on legal-system arbitrage: the capital structure of parent-subsidiary organizations is chosen to minimize the agency costs generated by selective renegotiation of claims written on the component legal entities. We show that optimal mixes of parent-subsidiary-level financing minimize the default premia associated with the organization's overall financing package by equating the marginal enforceability of debt contracts written at the parent and subsidiary levels. The enforceability of creditor claims depends not only on the legal regime but also on the size of the debt claims and the liquidation value of the firm's assets. Small claims written under a weak creditor rights regime may be more enforceable than large claims written under a regime with strong creditor protection. Thus, all optimal mixes involve some borrowing at the subsidiary level even if the subsidiary legal regime features weaker creditor protection than the parent regime. However, the mix between parent and subsidiary financing tilts toward the regime that features stronger creditor protection.</description><author>Banerjee, Suman; Noe, Thomas H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Weather and the Psychology of Purchasing Outdoor Movie Tickets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buchheim, Lukas; Kolaska, Thomas
The consequences of many economic decisions materialize only in the future. To make informed choices in such decision problems, consumers need to anticipate the likelihood of future states of the world, the state dependence of their preferences, and the choice alternatives that may become relevant. This complex task may expose consumers to psychological biases like extrapolative expectations, projection bias, or salience. We test whether customers are affected by such biases when they buy advance tickets for an outdoor movie theater, a real-world situation that, because of the availability of reliable weather forecasts, closely resembles a stylized decision problem under risk. We find that customers' decisions are heavily influenced by the weather at the time of purchase, even though the latter is irrelevant for the experience of visiting the theater in the future. The empirical evidence cannot be fully explained by a range of candidate rational explanations, but is consistent with the presence of the aforementioned psychological mechanisms.</description><author>Buchheim, Lukas; Kolaska, Thomas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Waiting To Give: Stated and Revealed Preferences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Craig, Ashley C.; Garbarino, Ellen; Heger, Stephanie A.; Slonim, Robert
We estimate and compare the effect of increased time costs on consumer satisfaction and behavior. We are able to move beyond the existing literature, which focuses on satisfaction and intention, and estimate the effect of waiting time on return behavior. Further, we do so in a prosocial context and our measure of cost is the length of time a blood donor spends waiting. We find that relying on satisfaction data masks important time cost sensitivities; namely, it is not how the donor feels about the wait time that matters for return behavior, but rather the actual duration of the wait. Consistent with theory we develop, our results indicate that waiting has a significant longer-term social cost: we estimate that a 38% increase (equivalent to one standard deviation) in the average wait would result in a 10% decrease in donations per year.</description><author>Craig, Ashley C.; Garbarino, Ellen; Heger, Stephanie A.; Slonim, Robert</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Client Characteristics Really Drive the Big N Audit Quality Effect? New Evidence from Propensity Score Matching</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeFond, Mark; Erkens, David H.; Zhang, Jieying
A large auditing literature concludes that Big N auditors provide higher audit quality than non-Big N auditors. Recently, however, a high-profile study suggests that propensity score matching (PSM) on client characteristics eliminates the Big N effect [Lawrence A, Minutti-Meza M, Zhang P (2011) Can Big 4 versus non-Big 4 differences in audit-quality proxies be attributed to client characteristics? Accounting Rev. 86(1):259-286]. We conjecture that this finding may be affected by PSM's sensitivity to its design choices and/or by the validity of the audit quality measures used in the analysis. To investigate, we examine random combinations of PSM design choices that achieve covariate balance, and four commonly used audit quality measures. We find that the majority of these design choices support a Big N effect for most of the audit quality measures. Overall, our findings show that it is premature to suggest that PSM eliminates the Big N effect.</description><author>DeFond, Mark; Erkens, David H.; Zhang, Jieying</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monopoly Pricing in the Presence of Social Learning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crapis, Davide; Ifrach, Bar; Maglaras, Costis; Scarsini, Marco
Amonopolist offers a product to a market of consumers with heterogeneous quality preferences. Although initially uninformed about the product quality, they learn by observing past purchase decisions and reviews of other consumers. Our goal is to analyze the social learning mechanism and its effect on the seller's pricing decision. Consumers follow an intuitive, non-Bayesian decision rule. Under conditions that we identify, we show that consumers eventually learn the product's quality. We show how the learning trajectory can be approximated in settings with high demand intensity via a mean-field approximation that highlights the dynamics of this learning process, its dependence on the price, and the market heterogeneity with respect to quality preferences. Two pricing policies are studied: a static price and one with a single price change. Finally, numerical experiments suggest that pricing policies that account for social learning may increase revenues considerably relative to policies that do not.</description><author>Crapis, Davide; Ifrach, Bar; Maglaras, Costis; Scarsini, Marco</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Mandatory Overtime Laws Improve Quality? Staffing Decisions and Operational Flexibility of Nursing Homes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lu, Susan Feng; Lu, Lauren Xiaoyuan
During the 2000s, over a dozen U.S. states passed laws that prohibit healthcare employers from mandating overtime for nurses. Using a nationwide panel data set from 2004 to 2012, we find that these mandatory overtime laws reduced the service quality of nursing homes, as measured by an increase in deficiency citations. This outcome can be explained by two undesirable changes in the staffing hours of registered nurses: decreased hours of permanent nurses and increased hours of contract nurses per resident day. We observe that the increase in deficiency citations concentrates in the domains of administration and quality of care rather than quality of life, and the severity levels of the increased citations tend to be minor rather than major. We also find that the laws' negative effect on quality is more severe in nursing homes with higher percentages of Medicare-covered residents. These observations are consistent with the predictions of a stochastic staffing model that incorporates demand uncertainty and operational flexibility. Furthermore, we rule out an alternative hypothesis that the quality decline is induced by an increase in nurse wages.</description><author>Lu, Susan Feng; Lu, Lauren Xiaoyuan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Confidence Calibration in a Multiyear Geopolitical Forecasting Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moore, Don A.; Swift, Samuel A.; Minster, Angela; Mellers, Barbara; Ungar, Lyle; Tetlock, Philip; Yang, Heather H. J.; Tenney, Elizabeth R.
This research examines the development of confidence and accuracy over time in the context of forecasting. Although overconfidence has been studied in many contexts, little research examines its progression over long periods of time or in consequential policy domains. This study employs a unique data set from a geopolitical forecasting tournament spanning three years in which thousands of forecasters predicted the outcomes of hundreds of events. We sought to apply insights from research to structure the questions, interactions, and elicitations to improve forecasts. Indeed, forecasters' confidence roughly matched their accuracy. As information came in, accuracy increased. Confidence increased at approximately the same rate as accuracy, and good calibration persisted. Nevertheless, there was evidence of a small amount of overconfidence (3%), especially on the most confident forecasts. Training helped reduce overconfidence, and team collaboration improved forecast accuracy. Together, teams and training reduced overconfidence to 1%. Our results provide reason for tempered optimism regarding confidence calibration and its development over time in consequential field contexts.</description><author>Moore, Don A.; Swift, Samuel A.; Minster, Angela; Mellers, Barbara; Ungar, Lyle; Tetlock, Philip; Yang, Heather H. J.; Tenney, Elizabeth R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Early Task Initiation and Other Load-Adaptive Mechanisms in the Emergency Department</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Batt, Robert J.; Terwiesch, Christian
We study a multistage service process that adapts to system occupancy level. Using operational data from more than 140,000 patient visits to a hospital emergency department, we show that the system-level performance of the emergency department is an aggregation of several simultaneous server-level workload response mechanisms. We identify early task initiation as a between-stage adaptive response mechanism that occurs when an upstream stage initiates tasks that are normally handled by a downstream stage. We show that having some diagnostic tests ordered during the triage process reduces treatment time by 20 minutes, on average. However, ordering too many tests at triage can lead to an increase in the total number of tests performed on the patient. We also demonstrate the presence of other response mechanisms such as queuing delays for tasks such as medication delivery, and rushing as nurses spend less time with their patients when the queue length is high.</description><author>Batt, Robert J.; Terwiesch, Christian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Editorial Statement-Operations Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corbett, Charles; Gaur, Vishal; Simchi-Levi, David; Taylor, Terry
nan</description><author>Corbett, Charles; Gaur, Vishal; Simchi-Levi, David; Taylor, Terry</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Target Firm-Specific Information and Acquisition Efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martin, Xiumin; Shalev, Ron
This study investigates whether firm-specific information about targets improves acquisition efficiency. We define acquisition efficiency as the total surplus generated by an acquisition and measure it as the difference in the value of the merged firm and the sum of the two firms operating separately. We find a positive association between target firm-specific information and acquisition efficiency that is driven mainly by diversifying acquisitions. Additional evidence suggests that both the likelihood of the withdrawal of an announced acquisition and the likelihood of a future divestiture of a target decrease with target firm-specific information. Taken together, our findings suggest that the availability of this information improves merger and acquisitions efficiency.</description><author>Martin, Xiumin; Shalev, Ron</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Frenemies: How Do Financial Firms Vote on Their Own Kind?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keswani, Aneel; Stolin, David; Tran, Anh L.
The financial sector is unique in being largely self-governed: the majority of financial firms' shares are held by other financial institutions. This raises the possibility that the monitoring of financial firms is especially undermined by conflicts of interest as a result of personal and professional links between these firms and their shareholders. To investigate this possibility, we scrutinize the aspect of the financial sector's self-governance that is directly observable: mutual fund companies' voting on their peers' stocks. We find that considerations specific to investee firms' membership in the same industry as their investors do indeed impact voting. This impact is in the direction of supporting the investee's management. We show that the own-industry effect reduces director efficacy and lowers firm value as a result. We extend our analysis to other financial companies and show that they also tend to vote more favorably when it comes to their peers. Our results suggest that peer support is a corrupting factor in the financial sector's governance.</description><author>Keswani, Aneel; Stolin, David; Tran, Anh L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Disciplinary Effects of Proxy Contests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fos, Vyacheslav
Using a manually collected data set of all proxy contests from 1994 through 2012, I show that proxy contests play an important role in hostile corporate governance. Target shareholders benefit from proxy contests: the average abnormal returns reach 6.5% around proxy contest announcements. Proxy contests that address firms' business strategies and undervaluation are most beneficial for shareholders. By contrast, proxy contests that aim at changing capital structure and governance do not lead to higher firm values. Relative to matching firms, future targets are smaller, they have higher stock liquidity, higher institutional and activist ownership, lower leverage and market valuation, and higher investments. Whereas most of these characteristics predict proxy contests in time series, prior to proxy contests, targets also experience poor stock performance, decreases in investments, increases in cash reserves and payouts to shareholders, and increases in management's entrenchment. These changes in corporate policies are consistent with targets' attempts to affect the probability of a proxy contest.</description><author>Fos, Vyacheslav</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Temporal Profiles of Instant Utility During Anticipation, Event, and Recall</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baucells, Manel; Bellezza, Silvia
We propose the anticipation-event-recall (AER) model. Set in a continuous time frame, the AER model formally links the three components of total utility (i.e., utility from anticipation, event utility, and utility from recall). The AER model predicts the temporal profiles of instant utility experienced before, during, and after a given event. Total utility is calculated as the integral of instant utility. The model builds on the psychological elements of conceptual consumption, adaptation, and time distance. By virtue of its rich formulation, the AER model produces a wide set of insights and testable predictions, including the U shape of instant utility during anticipation and the optimal duration of anticipation for a given event. Using both real and hypothetical events, we provide empirical evidence in support of the main implications of the AER model.</description><author>Baucells, Manel; Bellezza, Silvia</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing Catastrophic Climate Risks Under Model Uncertainty Aversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Loic; Emmerling, Johannes; Tavoni, Massimo
We propose a robust risk management approach to deal with the problem of catastrophic climate change that incorporates both risk and model uncertainty. Using an analytical model of abatement, we show how aversion to model uncertainty influences the optimal level of mitigation. We disentangle the role of preferences from the structure of model uncertainty, which we define by means of a simple measure of disagreement across models. With data from an expert elicitation about climate change catastrophes, we quantify the relative importance of these two effects and calibrate a numerical integrated assessment model of climate change. The results indicate that the structure of model uncertainty, and specifically how model disagreement varies in abatement, is the key driver of optimal abatement and that model uncertainty warrants a higher level of climate change mitigation.</description><author>Berger, Loic; Emmerling, Johannes; Tavoni, Massimo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Queueing Models of Case Managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campello, Fernanda; Ingolfsson, Armann; Shumsky, Robert A.
Many service systems use case managers, servers who are assigned multiple customers and have frequent, repeated interactions with each customer until the customer's service is completed. Examples may be found in healthcare (emergency department physicians), contact centers (agents handling multiple online chats simultaneously) and social welfare agencies (social workers with multiple clients). We propose a stochastic model of a baseline case-manager system, formulate models that provide performance bounds and stability conditions for the baseline system, and develop two approximations, one of which is based on a two-time-scale approach. Numerical experiments and analysis of the approximations show that increasing case throughput by increasing the probability of case completion can lead to much greater waiting-time reductions than increasing service speed. Many systems place an upper limit on the number of customers simultaneously handled by each case manager. We examine the impact of these caseload limits on waiting time and describe effective, heuristic methods for setting these limits.</description><author>Campello, Fernanda; Ingolfsson, Armann; Shumsky, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Win-Win Capacity Allocation Contracts in Coproduction and Codistribution Alliances</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roels, Guillaume; Tang, Christopher S.
In some strategic alliances, a firm shares its manufacturing capacity with another, and the latter shares its distribution capacity with the former. Even though such bidirectional alliances have become more common, they remain challenging to manage because of the frequent disputes over capacity allocation, especially when demand is uncertain. In this paper, we investigate whether there exists a contractual mechanism that can mitigate the extent of these disputes while improving the profits of all participating firms. We consider two types of bidirectional contracts, namely, the ex post transfer payment contract and the ex ante capacity reservation contract. By modeling the capacity allocation and the bidirectional contract design as a noncooperative game between two firms with noncompeting product lines, we show that, relative to a situation with no contract, either contract can improve the alliance's total profit in equilibrium. In terms of distribution of the total surplus, we find that capacity reservation contracts always make both firms better off, whereas ex post transfer payment contracts may make one firm worse off. Hence, capacity reservation contracts are more likely to be implemented in practice in such bidirectional alliances.</description><author>Roels, Guillaume; Tang, Christopher S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crowd Wisdom Relies on Agents' Ability in Small Groups with a Voting Aggregation Rule</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keuschnigg, Marc; Ganser, Christian
In the last decade, interest in the "wisdom of crowds" effect has gained momentum in both organizational research and corporate practice. Crowd wisdom relies on the aggregation of independent judgments. The accuracy of a group's aggregate prediction rises with the number, ability, and diversity of its members. We investigate these variables' relative importance for collective prediction using agent-based simulation. We replicate the "diversity trumps ability" proposition for large groups, showing that samples of heterogeneous agents outperform same-sized homogeneous teams of high ability. In groups smaller than approximately 16 members, however, the effects of group composition depend on the social decision function employed: diversity is key only in continuous estimation tasks (averaging) and much less important in discrete choice tasks (voting), in which agents' individual abilities remain crucial. Thus, strategies to improve collective decision making must adapt to the predictive situation at hand.</description><author>Keuschnigg, Marc; Ganser, Christian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>It's a Man's Job: Income and the Gender Gap in Industrial Research</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoisl, Karin; Mariani, Myriam
This study examines differences in income and job performance between women and men in creative, highly skilled jobs tasked with achieving technological inventions. By building on data pertaining to 9,692 inventors from 23 countries, this study shows that female inventors represent only 4.2% of total inventors, and they earn about 14% less than their male peers. The gap persists even when controlling for sources of heterogeneity, the selection of inventors into types of jobs and tasks, and potential parenthood, instrumented by exploiting a source of variation related to religious practices. The income gap is not associated with differences in the quality of the inventions that female and male inventors produce. Thus, even in this human capital-intensive profession, where capabilities and education are important assets, and productivity differentials can be observed, women earn less than men, though they contribute to the development of high-quality inventions as much as men do.</description><author>Hoisl, Karin; Mariani, Myriam</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentive Alignment and Coordination of Project Supply Chains</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Shi; Lee, Hau
We consider a project supply chain where a manufacturer carries out a sequence of tasks, and each task requires certain key materials from a supplier. Since a fixed-price contract cannot attain channel coordination, we focus on time-based incentive contracts. Our proposed contract requires optimization of the material delivery schedule as well as the fraction and the timing of a delayed payment to each supplier. Under the contract, the manufacturer's profit is affected by the variance but not by the mean of a supplier's lead time. Each supplier benefits from a reduction in the mean or variance of his own lead time, whereas the supplier's profit is independent of the duration of the on-site tasks and the lead times of other suppliers. The contract is also robust in various scenarios: in particular, coordination can be achieved even if the manufacturer's estimate of the average delivery lead time is inaccurate.</description><author>Chen, Shi; Lee, Hau</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private Equity and Industry Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Shai; Lerner, Josh; Sorensen, Morten; Stromberg, Per
The growth of the private equity industry has spurred concerns about its impact on the economy. This analysis looks across nations and industries to assess the impact of private equity on industry performance. We find that industries where private equity funds invest grow more quickly in terms of total production and employment and appear less exposed to aggregate shocks. Our robustness tests provide some evidence that is consistent with our effects being driven by our preferred channel.</description><author>Bernstein, Shai; Lerner, Josh; Sorensen, Morten; Stromberg, Per</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ensembles of Overfit and Overconfident Forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grushka-Cockayne, Yael; Jose, Victor Richmond R.; Lichtendahl, Kenneth C.
Firms today average forecasts collected from multiple experts and models. Because of cognitive biases, strategic incentives, or the structure of machine-learning algorithms, these forecasts are often overfit to sample data and are overconfident. Little is known about the challenges associated with aggregating such forecasts. We introduce a theoretical model to examine the combined effect of overfitting and overconfidence on the average forecast. Their combined effect is that the mean and median probability forecasts are poorly calibrated with hit rates of their prediction intervals too high and too low, respectively. Consequently, we prescribe the use of a trimmed average, or trimmed opinion pool, to achieve better calibration. We identify the random forest, a leading machine-learning algorithm that pools hundreds of overfit and overconfident regression trees, as an ideal environment for trimming probabilities. Using several known data sets, we demonstrate that trimmed ensembles can significantly improve the random forest's predictive accuracy.</description><author>Grushka-Cockayne, Yael; Jose, Victor Richmond R.; Lichtendahl, Kenneth C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Gender Diversity Promote Nonconformity?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amini, Makan; Ekstrom, Mathias; Ellingsen, Tore; Johannesson, Magnus; Stromsten, Fredrik
Failure to express minority views may distort the behavior of company boards, committees, juries, and other decision-making bodies. Devising a newexperimental procedure to measure such conformity in a judgment task, we compare the degree of conformity in groups with varying gender composition. Overall, our experiments offer little evidence that gender composition affects expression of minority views. A robust finding is that a subject's lack of ability predicts both a true propensity to accept others' judgment (informational social influence) and a propensity to agree despite private doubt (normative social influence). Thus, as an antidote to conformity in our experiments, high individual ability seems more effective than group diversity.</description><author>Amini, Makan; Ekstrom, Mathias; Ellingsen, Tore; Johannesson, Magnus; Stromsten, Fredrik</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Past the Point of Speeding Up: The Negative Effects of Workload Saturation on Efficiency and Patient Severity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jaeker, Jillian A. Berry; Tucker, Anita L.
Service organizations face a trade-off between high utilization and responsiveness. High utilization can improve financial performance, but causes congestion, which increases throughput time. Employees may manage this trade-off by reducing processing times during periods of high workload, resulting in an inverted U-shaped relationship between utilization and throughput time. Using two years of inpatient data from 203 California hospitals, we find evidence that patient length of stay (LOS) increases as occupancy increases, until a tipping point, after which patients are discharged early to alleviate congestion. More interestingly, we find a second tipping point-at 93% occupancy-beyond which additional occupancy leads to a longer LOS. These results are indicative of a workload-related "saturation effect" where employees can no longer overcome high workload by speeding up. Our data suggest that the saturation effect is due to an increase in the workload requirements of the remaining patients. Collectively, we find that the underlying relationship between occupancy and LOS is N-shaped. Consequently, managers who seek cost efficiencies via a strategy of high utilization in tandem with speeding up may find that their strategy backfires because there is a point at which employees are no longer able to compensate for a high workload by working harder, and throughput time counterproductively increases. We perform a counterfactual analysis and find that an alternate strategy of employing flexible labor when faced with high occupancy levels might be a more productive approach, and could save the hospitals in our sample up to $138 million over 23 months.</description><author>Jaeker, Jillian A. Berry; Tucker, Anita L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agility and Proximity Considerations in Supply Chain Design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lim, Michael K.; Mak, Ho-Yin; Shen, Zuo-Jun Max
Strategic supply chain design decisions are critical to the long-term success of a business. Traditional facility location models for supply chain design focus on the trade-offs between the costs and benefits of proximity, i.e., the distance between facilities and customers. These strategic-focused models do not consider the supply chain's agility, i.e., its ability to quickly respond to unexpected fluctuations in customer needs. In this paper, we study the problem of designing a supply chain distribution network under demand uncertainty and analyze how the optimal design characteristics of proximity and agility depend on various input parameters. We are able to draw managerial insights on how agility considerations may invalidate well-established and widely accepted qualitative results derived from traditional models. In particular, we show that it is optimal to increase the density of distribution centers (DCs) when the shortage penalty cost increases, and to decrease the density of DCs when a certain unit transportation cost parameter increases. Through these findings, our work conveys the message that traditional, proximity-based facility location models can be inadequate for designing modern responsive supply chains, and calls for the need to develop a new class of models for the task.</description><author>Lim, Michael K.; Mak, Ho-Yin; Shen, Zuo-Jun Max</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Formal Enforcement Actions and Bank Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delis, Manthos D.; Staikouras, Panagiotis K.; Tsoumas, Chris
Employing a unique data set for the period 2000-2010, this paper examines the impact of formal enforcement actions targeting the core of the banks' financial safety and soundness in terms of bank capital, risk, and performance. We find that, on average, these actions reduce both the risk-weighted assets and the nonperforming loans ratios of punished banks, but there is no increase in the level of regulatory capital. These effects are less powerful during the postcrisis period, suggesting that banks' scope to improve their safety and soundness condition in crisis periods is much more limited. We also find, albeit with some limitations, that the timing of formal enforcement actions is important: the more the actions are deferred relative to the continuous deterioration of the banks' financial condition, the more limited their impact on the risk-based capital ratio, while actions taken earlier help banks to improve their financial soundness.</description><author>Delis, Manthos D.; Staikouras, Panagiotis K.; Tsoumas, Chris</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Backtesting Expected Shortfall: Accounting for Tail Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Du, Zaichao; Escanciano, Juan Carlos
The Basel Committee on Banking Supervision (BIS) has recently sanctioned expected shortfall (ES) as the market risk measure to be used for banking regulatory purposes, replacing the well-known value at risk (VaR). This change is motivated by the appealing theoretical properties of ES as a measure of risk and the poor properties of VaR. In particular, VaR fails to control for "tail risk." In this transition, the major challenge faced by financial institutions is the unavailability of simple tools for evaluation of ES forecasts (i.e., backtesting ES). The main purpose of this paper is to propose such tools. Specifically, we propose backtests for ES based on cumulative violations, which are the natural analogue of the commonly used backtests for VaR. We establish the asymptotic properties of the tests, and investigate their finite sample performance through some Monte Carlo simulations. An empirical application to three major stock indexes shows that VaR is generally unresponsive to extreme events such as those experienced during the recent financial crisis, whereas ES provides a more accurate description of the risk involved.</description><author>Du, Zaichao; Escanciano, Juan Carlos</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Pricing in the Presence of Social Learning and Strategic Consumers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Papanastasiou, Yiangos; Savva, Nicos
When a product of uncertain quality is first introduced, consumers may choose to strategically delay their purchasing decisions in anticipation of the product reviews of their peers. This paper investigates how the presence of social learning affects the strategic interaction between a dynamic-pricing monopolist and a forward-looking consumer population, within a simple two-period model. Our analysis yields three main insights. First, we find that the presence of social learning has significant structural implications for optimal pricing policies: In the absence of social learning, decreasing price plans are always preferred by the firm; by contrast, in the presence of social learning we find that (i) if the firm commits to a price path ex ante (preannounced pricing), an increasing price plan is typically announced, whereas (ii) if the firm adjusts price dynamically (responsive pricing), prices are initially low and may either rise or decline over time. Second, we establish that under both preannounced and responsive pricing, even though the social learning process exacerbates strategic consumer behavior (i.e., increases strategic purchasing delays), its presence results in an increase in expected firm profit. Third, we illustrate that, contrary to results reported in existing literature on strategic consumer behavior, in settings where social learning is significantly influential, preannounced pricing policies are generally not beneficial for the firm.</description><author>Papanastasiou, Yiangos; Savva, Nicos</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Effectiveness of Uniform Subsidies in Increasing Market Consumption</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levi, Retsef; Perakis, Georgia; Romero, Gonzalo
We study the problem faced by a central planner trying to increase the consumption of a good, such as new malaria drugs in Africa. The central planner allocates subsidies to its producers, subject to a budget constraint and endogenous market response. The policy most commonly implemented in practical applications of this problem is uniform, in the sense that it allocates the same per-unit subsidy to every firm, primarily because of its simplicity and perceived fairness. Surprisingly, we identify sufficient conditions of the firms' marginal costs such that uniform subsidies are optimal, even if the firms' efficiency levels are arbitrarily different. Moreover, this insight is usually preserved even if the central planner is uncertain about the specific market conditions. Further in many cases, uniform subsidies simultaneously attain the best social welfare solution. Additionally, simulation results in relevant settings where uniform subsidies are not optimal suggest that they induce a nearly optimal market consumption. On the other hand, if the firms face a fixed cost of entry to the market, then the performance of uniform subsidies can be significantly worse, suggesting the need for an alternative policy in this setup.</description><author>Levi, Retsef; Perakis, Georgia; Romero, Gonzalo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Sales Agents in Information Disclosure: Evidence from a Field Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allcott, Hunt; Sweeney, Richard L.
With a large nationwide retailer, we run a natural field experiment to measure the effects of energy use information disclosure, customer rebates, and sales agent incentives on demand for energy-efficient durable goods. Although a combination of large rebates plus sales incentives substantially increases market share, information and sales incentives alone each have zero statistical effect and explain at most a small fraction of the low baseline market share. Sales agents strategically comply only partially with the experiment, targeting information to more interested consumers but not discussing energy efficiency with the disinterested majority. These results suggest that seller-provided information is not a major barrier to energy-efficiency investments at current prices in this context.</description><author>Allcott, Hunt; Sweeney, Richard L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Delay Announcements Shape Customer Behavior? An Empirical Study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yu, Qiuping; Allon, Gad; Bassamboo, Achal
In this paper, we explore the impact of delay announcements using an empirical approach by analyzing the data from a medium-sized call center. We first explore the question of whether delay announcements impact customers' behavior using a non-parametric approach. The answer to this question appears to be ambiguous. We thus turn to investigate the fundamental mechanism by which delay announcements impact customer behavior, by constructing a dynamic structural model. In contrast to the implicit assumption made in the literature that announcements do not directly impact customers' waiting costs, our key insights show that delay announcements not only impact customers' beliefs about the system but also directly impact customers' waiting costs. In particular, customers' per-unit waiting cost decreases with the offered waiting times associated with the announcements. The results of our counterfactual analysis show that it may not be necessary to provide announcements with very fine granularity.</description><author>Yu, Qiuping; Allon, Gad; Bassamboo, Achal</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mitigating Delays and Unfairness in Appointment Systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qi, Jin
We consider an appointment system where heterogeneous participants are sequenced and scheduled for service. Because service times are uncertain, the aims are to mitigate the unpleasantness experienced by the participants in the system when their waiting times or delays exceed acceptable thresholds and to address fairness in the balancing of service levels among participants. To evaluate uncertain delays, we propose the Delay Unpleasantness Measure, which takes into account the frequency and intensity of delays above a threshold, and introduce the concept of lexicographic min-max fairness to design appointment systems from the perspective of the worst-off participants. We focus our study in the healthcare industry in balancing physicians' overtime and patients' waiting times in which patients are distinguished by their service time characterizations. The model can be adapted in the robust setting when the underlying probability distribution is not fully available. To capture the correlation between uncertain service times, we suggest using the mean absolute deviations as the descriptive statistics in the distributional uncertainty set to preserve the linearity of the model. The optimal sequencing and scheduling decisions can be derived by solving a sequence of mixed-integer programming problems, and we report the insights from our computational studies.</description><author>Qi, Jin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Judgment Extremity and Accuracy Under Epistemic vs. Aleatory Uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tannenbaum, David; Fox, Craig R.; Ulkumen, Gulden
People viewuncertain events as knowable in principle (epistemic uncertainty), as fundamentally random (aleatory uncertainty), or as some mixture of the two. We showthat people make more extreme probability judgments (i. e., closer to 0 or 1) for events they view as entailing more epistemic uncertainty and less aleatory uncertainty. We demonstrate this pattern in a domain where there is agreement concerning the balance of evidence (pairings of teams according to their seed in a basketball tournament) but individual differences in the perception of the epistemicness/aleatoriness of that domain (Study 1), across a range of domains that vary in their perceived epistemicness/aleatoriness (Study 2), in a single judgment task for which we only vary the degree of randomness with which events are selected (Study 3), and when we prime participants to see events as more epistemic or aleatory (Study 4). Decomposition of accuracy scores suggests that the greater judgment extremity of more epistemic events can manifest itself as a trade-off between enhanced resolution and diminished calibration. We further relate our findings to the hard-easy effect and also show that differences between epistemic and aleatory judgment are amplified when judges have more knowledge concerning relevant events.</description><author>Tannenbaum, David; Fox, Craig R.; Ulkumen, Gulden</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Suppliers Climb the Value Chain: A Theory of Value Distribution in Vertical Relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wan, Zhixi; Wu, Brian
Although offshore outsourcing has become an important strategy to lower production costs among Western firms, it gives rise to the phenomenon of value chain climbing-suppliers in emerging markets can develop capabilities by supplying, with aspirations to compete with the buyers in the product market. We build an analytical model to study the impact of value chain climbing on value distribution in vertical relationships. The analysis identifies a set of dominant relationships, characterizes how the buyer's optimal choice among these relationships depends on firms' relative competitiveness in the product market and the supplier's speed of capability development, and shows how the optimal choice evolves with the dynamics of the supplier's capability development. The results provide new insights into our understanding of value distribution in vertical relationships across different contexts and over time. By endogenizing the supplier's entry into the product market, our study enriches the literatures on vertical relationships, market entry, and the management of global value chains.</description><author>Wan, Zhixi; Wu, Brian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Factors Associated with the Year-End Decline in Working Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frankel, Richard; Levy, Hagit; Shalev, Ron
Working capital is an important indicator of firm operational efficiency. All else being equal, lower levels signal greater efficiency. Managers are thus likely to be motivated to report lower levels of working capital at times of greater external attention. We find that working capital levels decrease in the fourth fiscal quarter significantly more than expected, conditional on seasonal changes in economic activity. The decrease subsequently reverses in the following first fiscal quarter. Evidence indicates that firms manage down year-end working capital through transactions that increase year-end operating cash flow and that firms spread this activity over allworking capital accounts. Finally, the temporary decrease in year-end working capital is correlated with compensation benchmarks and analysts' annual cash flow forecasts. The temporary drop is also more pronounced for firms with industry dominance.</description><author>Frankel, Richard; Levy, Hagit; Shalev, Ron</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning by Doing in Multiproduct Manufacturing: Variety, Customizations, and Overlapping Product Generations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Egelman, Carolyn D.; Epple, Dennis; Argote, Linda; Fuchs, Erica R. H.
Extending research on organizational learning to multiproduct environments is of particular importance given that the vast majority of products are manufactured in such environments. We investigate learning in a multiproduct facility drawing on exceptionally rich data for a manufacturing firmthat is a leading producer of high-technology hardware components. Weekly data for 10 years from the firm's production and human resource tracking systems are augmented by surveys of managers and engineers and by extensive firsthand observation. We find that productivity improves when multiple generations of the firm's primary product family are produced concurrently, reflecting the firm's ability to augment and transfer knowledge from older to newer product generations. No significant transfer of knowledge is evident between the primary product family and other products. Productivity is, however, adversely affected when the production facility is faced with extensive within-product buyer-specific customizations. We develop the implications of these findings for theory and practice.</description><author>Egelman, Carolyn D.; Epple, Dennis; Argote, Linda; Fuchs, Erica R. H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Aversion and Wealth: Evidence from Person-to-Person Lending Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Paravisini, Daniel; Rappoport, Veronica; Ravina, Enrichetta
We estimate risk aversion from investors' financial decisions in a person-to-person lending platform. We develop a method that obtains a risk-aversion parameter from each portfolio choice. Since the same individuals invest repeatedly, we construct a panel data set that we use to disentangle heterogeneity in attitudes toward risk across investors, from the elasticity of risk aversion to changes in wealth. We find that wealthier investors are more risk averse in the cross section and that investors become more risk averse after a negative housing wealth shock. Thus, investors exhibit preferences consistent with decreasing relative risk aversion and habit formation.</description><author>Paravisini, Daniel; Rappoport, Veronica; Ravina, Enrichetta</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Two New Features in Discrete Choice Experiments to Improve Willingness-to-Pay Estimation That Result in SDR and SADR: Separated (Adaptive) Dual Response</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schlereth, Christian; Skiera, Bernd
Discrete choice experiments such as choice-based conjoint and dual response are popular preference elicitation methods, yet, they can suffer from context effects, extreme response behavior, and problems with estimating consumers' willingness to pay accurately when the purchase probability is high. This study proposes two new features to avoid these limits: (a) strictly separating all forced and all free choice questions and (b) an adaptive mechanism to select fewer, but more informative, free choice questions. The use of these two features invokes two new discrete choice experiment methods: separated dual response (SDR), with just the first feature, and separated adaptive dual response (SADR), with both features. A conceptual comparison, simulation study, tests to address endogeneity concerns, and three empirical studies demonstrate the appeal of these two new features, relative to the benefits of existing discrete choice experiments, especially when estimating willingness to pay.</description><author>Schlereth, Christian; Skiera, Bernd</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Dynamic Network Measure of Technological Change</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Funk, Russell J.; Owen-Smith, Jason
This article outlines a network approach to the study of technological change. We propose that new inventions reshape networks of interlinked technologies by shifting inventors' attention to or away from the knowledge on which those inventions build. Using this approach, we develop novel indexes of the extent to which a new invention consolidates or destabilizes existing technology streams. We apply these indexes in analyses of university research commercialization and find that, although federal research funding pushes campuses to create inventions that are more destabilizing, deeper commercial ties lead them to produce technologies that consolidate the status quo. By quantifying the effects that new technologies have on their predecessors, the indexes we propose allow patent-based studies of innovation to capture conceptually important phenomena that are not detectable with established measures. The measurement approach presented here offers empirical insights that support theoretical development in studies of innovation, entrepreneurship, technology strategy, science policy, and social network theory.</description><author>Funk, Russell J.; Owen-Smith, Jason</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Lean Improve Labor Standards? Management and Social Performance in the Nike Supply Chain</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Distelhorst, Greg; Hainmueller, Jens; Locke, Richard M.
This study tests the hypothesis that lean manufacturing improves the social performance of manufacturers in emerging markets. We analyze an intervention by Nike, Inc., to promote the adoption of lean manufacturing in its apparel supply chain across 11 developing countries. Using difference-in-differences estimates from a panel of more than 300 factories, we find that lean adoption was associated with a 15 percentage point reduction in noncompliance with labor standards that primarily reflect factory wage and work hour practices. However, we find a null effect on factory health and safety standards. This pattern is consistent with a causal mechanism that links lean to improved social performance through changes in labor relations, rather than improved management systems. These findings offer evidence that capability-building interventions may reduce social harm in global supply chains.</description><author>Distelhorst, Greg; Hainmueller, Jens; Locke, Richard M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distilling the Wisdom of Crowds: Prediction Markets vs. Prediction Polls</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atanasov, Pavel; Rescober, Phillip; Stone, Eric; Swift, Samuel A.; Servan-Schreiber, Emile; Tetlock, Philip; Ungar, Lyle; Mellers, Barbara
We report the results of the first large-scale, long-term, experimental test between two crowdsourcing methods: prediction markets and prediction polls. More than 2,400 participants made forecasts on 261 events over two seasons of a geopolitical prediction tournament. Forecasters were randomly assigned to either prediction markets (continuous double auction markets) in which theywere ranked based on earnings, or prediction polls in which they submitted probability judgments, independently or in teams, and were ranked based on Brier scores. In both seasons of the tournament, prices from the prediction market were more accurate than the simple mean of forecasts from prediction polls. However, team prediction polls outperformed prediction markets when forecasts were statistically aggregated using temporal decay, differential weighting based on past performance, and recalibration. The biggest advantage of prediction pollswas at the beginning of long-duration questions. Results suggest that prediction polls with proper scoring feedback, collaboration features, and statistical aggregation are an attractive alternative to prediction markets for distilling the wisdom of crowds.</description><author>Atanasov, Pavel; Rescober, Phillip; Stone, Eric; Swift, Samuel A.; Servan-Schreiber, Emile; Tetlock, Philip; Ungar, Lyle; Mellers, Barbara</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Geography and the Market for CEOs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yonker, Scott E.
I examine the role of geography in the market for CEOs and find that firms hire locally five times more often than expected if geography were irrelevant to the matching process. This local matching bias is widespread and exists even among the largest U.S. firms. Tests reveal that both labor supply and demand influence local matching. Compensation and unforced turnover are lower for local than for nonlocal CEOs, and the compensation of local CEOs depends on local labor market factors, unlike that of nonlocal CEOs. These findings suggest the presence of market segmentation and contrast with much of the prior literature, which explicitly or implicitly assumes a single national market.</description><author>Yonker, Scott E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Adverse Incentives in Crowdfunding</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hildebrand, Thomas; Puri, Manju; Rocholld, Joerg
This paper analyzes the substantially growing markets for crowdfunding, in which retail investors lend to borrowers without financial intermediaries. Critics suggest that these markets allow sophisticated investors to take advantage of unsophisticated investors. The growth and viability of these markets critically depend on the underlying incentives. We provide evidence of perverse incentives in crowdfunding that are not fully recognized by the market. In particular, we look at group leader bids in the presence of origination fees and find that these bids are (wrongly) perceived as a signal of good loan quality, resulting in lower interest rates. Yet these loans actually have higher default rates. These adverse incentives are overcome only with sufficient skin in the game and when there are no origination fees. The results from the analysis in this paper provide more general implications for crowdfunding, its structure, and its regulation.</description><author>Hildebrand, Thomas; Puri, Manju; Rocholld, Joerg</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Contracts Signal Social Norms? Experimental Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Danilov, Anastasia; Sliwka, Dirk
We investigate whether incentive schemes signal social norms and thus affect behavior beyond their direct economic consequences. A one-shot principal-agent experiment is studied where prior to contract choice principals are informed about the past actions of other agents and thus have more information about norms of behavior. Compared with a setting in which principals are uninformed, agents exert substantially higher effort under a fixed wage contract when they are aware that an informed principal chose this contract. The informed principal's choice apparently signals a norm not to exploit trust, which leads to more trustworthy behavior. This mechanism's robustness is explored in further experiments.</description><author>Danilov, Anastasia; Sliwka, Dirk</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Much Is a Win Worth? An Application to Intercollegiate Athletics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Doug J.
Intercollegiate athletics in the United States have become a multibillion-dollar industry over the past several decades. In this study, we investigate the short-and longterm direct monetary effects of operating a winning athletics program for an academic institution of higher education. We construct a unique panel data set from multiple sources and utilize the latest dynamic panel data estimation methods to account for heterogeneity while also addressing endogeneity concerns. We find that success in men's football and basketball has a significant impact on a school's respective football and basketball revenues; however, the effect is different based on the type of school. We find that regular season wins in football account for most of the increase in revenue for established schools, whereas invitations to prestigious postseason bowl games play a big part for less-established schools. Furthermore, we find that student population and education quality dissipate the effect of athletic success on monetary payoffs. We find that success in basketball carries over more from the past than in football with additional contemporaneous marginal effects for established schools. We do find, however, that past athletic success carries over significantly to the present in both football and basketball, suggesting the significance of the long-term monetary effect of athletic success to many academic institutions in the United States.</description><author>Chung, Doug J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Sampling, Belief Synchronization, and Collective Illusions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Denrell, Jerker; Le Mens, Gael
We demonstrate that a sampling-based mechanism can offer an alternative explanation for belief synchronization in social groups and the persistence of collective illusions. Our model assumes that people are more likely to sample popular alternatives than unpopular alternatives. We show that this mechanism is sufficient to explain belief synchronization: a strong majority of opinions will likely emerge in favor of one alternative. The reason is that the group is unlikely to move away from a state in which one alternative is very unpopular. If by chance most people come to dislike alternative A, they are all unlikely to sample it again and their opinions of A remain the same. When A is in fact the best alternative, a collective illusion has emerged because people mistakenly believe that a suboptimal alternative is the best. Our model implies that such a collective illusion is persistent. The model thus offers an existence proof that a collective illusion can occur even in settings where people do not infer that popular alternatives are better. The model also casts new light on the effect of online recommendation systems on attitude homogenization and the effect of majority voting on beliefs and attitudes.</description><author>Denrell, Jerker; Le Mens, Gael</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intertemporal Uncertainty Avoidance: When the Future Is Uncertain, People Prefer the Present, and When the Present Is Uncertain, People Prefer the Future</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hardisty, David J.; Pfeffer, Jeffrey
Three studies explored the effects of uncertainty on people's time preferences for financial gains and losses. In general, individuals seek to avoid uncertainty in situations of intertemporal choice. While holding the expected value of payouts constant, participants preferred immediate gains and losses if the future was uncertain, and preferred future gains and losses if the present was uncertain. This pattern of preferences is incompatible with current models of intertemporal choice, in which people should consistently prefer to have gains now and losses later. This pattern of uncertainty avoidance is also not explained by prospect theory models, which predict risk seeking for losses. We discuss these findings in relation to previous literature.</description><author>Hardisty, David J.; Pfeffer, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance, Accounting Conservatism, and Manipulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caskey, Judson; Laux, Volker
We develop a model to analyze how board governance affects firms' financial reporting choices and managers' incentives to manipulate accounting reports. In our setting, ceteris paribus, conservative accounting is desirable because it allows the board of directors to better oversee the firm's investment decisions. This feature of conservatism, however, causes the manager to manipulate the accounting system to mislead the board and distort its decisions. Effective reporting oversight curtails managers' ability to manipulate, which increases the benefits of conservative accounting and simultaneously reduces its costs. Our model predicts that stronger reporting oversight leads to greater accounting conservatism, manipulation, and investment efficiency.</description><author>Caskey, Judson; Laux, Volker</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Strategic Role of Business Insurance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Serpa, Juan Camilo; Krishnan, Harish
The use of business insurance has been traditionally studied in a single-firmsetting, but in reality preventing operational accidents involves the (unobservable) efforts of multiple firms. We show that, in a multifirm setting, insurance can be used strategically as a commitment mechanism to prevent excessive free riding by other firms. In the presence of wealth imbalances, contracts alone leave wealth-constrained firms with inefficiently low incentives to exert effort (because of limited liability) and firms with sufficient wealth with excessive incentives. Insurance allows the latter to credibly commit to lower effort, thereby mitigating the incentives of the wealth-constrained firms to free ride. This finding shows that insurance can improve the efficiency of risk management efforts by decreasing free-riding problems.</description><author>Serpa, Juan Camilo; Krishnan, Harish</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Postretirement Benefit Plans and Real Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartram, Sohnke M.
This paper shows that the real investment by nonfinancial firms is systematically related to the size of their defined-benefit plan. In particular, these plans allow research and development (R&amp;D)-intensive firms to retain and borrowfrom their employees, which is attractive since they have high adjustment costs, require a stable cash flow, have less collateral, have assets that are harder to value, and have high asymmetric information and agency costs. By contrast, capital expenditures benefit from credit multiplier effects with regard to regular debt, which substitutes for postretirement obligations. As a result, firms with defined-benefit plans have 12% more R&amp;D and 5% less capital expenditure compared with otherwise similar firms, and they vary contributions as a function of cash flow and real investment. The role of postretirement plans is attenuated in countries with available alternative funding sources. The results are robust to controlling for other dimensions of financial policy-cash holdings, debt maturity, dividends, preferred stock, convertible debt, and leverage-that also affect real investment.</description><author>Bartram, Sohnke M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantitative Easing and Volatility Spillovers Across Countries and Asset Classes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Zihui; Zhou, Yinggang
We identify networks of volatility spillovers and examine time-varying spillover intensities with daily implied volatilities of U.S. Treasury bonds, global stock indices, and commodities. The U.S. stock market is the center of the international volatility spillover network, and its volatility spillover to other markets has intensified since 2008. Moreover, U.S. quantitative easing alone explains 40%-55% of intensifying spillover from the United States. The addition of interest rate and currency factors does not diminish the dominant role of quantitative easing. Our findings highlight the primary contribution of U.S. unconventional monetary policy to volatility spillovers and potential global systemic risk.</description><author>Yang, Zihui; Zhou, Yinggang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Brokers of Insiders Tip Other Clients?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McNally, William J.; Shkilko, Andriy; Smith, Brian F.
We examine trading activity around insider transactions on the Toronto Stock Exchange and find evidence that some traders mimic insider positions. Our unique data set allows us to establish a direct connection between insiders, their brokerages, and the brokerages' other clients. The findings are consistent with the possibility that some brokerages tip their clients about insider trades. Insiders in our sample have good timing; returns are usually positive (negative) after insider purchases (sales). Insiders' good timing translates to the mimicking transactions, which appear to be profitable net of trading costs. Evidence consistent with tipping is observed mainly for smaller independent brokerages.</description><author>McNally, William J.; Shkilko, Andriy; Smith, Brian F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Newsvendor Mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cho, Soo-Haeng; Wang, Xin
This paper studies a merger between price-setting newsvendors in an oligopolistic market. It is well known that inventory pooling can greatly reduce inventory costs in a centralized distribution system because it helps reduce aggregate demand uncertainty. Although such statistical economies of scale are important benefits of a retail merger, the extant literature models cost savings from a merger only through reduction in a postmerger firm's marginal cost. In this paper, we develop a model of a retail merger under uncertain demand that distinguishes between cost savings from conventional economies of scale and those from statistical economies of scale, and we show that these two sources of cost savings have substantially different impacts on firms' decisions in a postmerger market. Contrary to the existing theory of mergers developed under deterministic demand, we find that although inventory pooling enables the postmerger firm to achieve cost savings, it always induces firms to raise their prices, and we find that marginal cost reduction induces firms to lower their prices only when it is substantial-consequently, larger cost synergies can benefit even nonparticipant firms. Finally, even if a merger induces all firms to raise their prices, it can still improve expected consumer welfare by increasing firms' service levels under uncertain demand.</description><author>Cho, Soo-Haeng; Wang, Xin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Impact of Uncertain Cost Reduction When Selling to Strategic Customers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shum, Stephen; Tong, Shilu; Xiao, Tingting
Many products undergo cost reductions over their product life cycles. However, strategic customers may have more incentive to wait if they expect a cost reduction to lead to a price drop. A firm that does not face any uncertainty can use pricing strategies such as price commitment and price matching to alleviate the strategic waiting of customers. However, these pricing strategies provide less flexibility than dynamic pricing for a firm facing uncertainty. In this paper, we examine the impact of cost reduction under dynamic pricing, price commitment, and price matching when cost reduction can come from production learning or from technology advancement. The firm makes pricing decisions when facing uncertainty in future cost, and strategic customers decide whether to wait when facing uncertainty in future price. We show that in general the firm's profit is higher when future cost is more uncertain, but not necessarily when cost reduction is more significant. In addition, production learning and technology advancement can have opposite effects on the optimal pricing decisions and the choice of pricing strategy.</description><author>Shum, Stephen; Tong, Shilu; Xiao, Tingting</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Surprising Effectiveness of Hostile Mediators</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Ting; Gino, Francesca; Norton, Michael I.
Contrary to the tendency of mediators to defuse negative emotions between adversaries by treating them kindly, we demonstrate the surprising effectiveness of hostile mediators in resolving conflict. Hostile mediators generate greater willingness to reach agreements between adversaries (Experiment 1). Consequently, negotiators interacting with hostile mediators are better able to reach agreements in incentive-compatible negotiations than those interacting with nice mediators (Experiment 2). By serving as common enemies, hostile mediators cause adversaries in conflict to feel more connected and become more willing to reach agreement (Experiments 3 and 4). Finally, we manipulate the target of mediators' hostility to document the moderating role of common enemies: mediators who directed their hostility toward both negotiators (bilateral hostility)-becoming a common enemy-increased willingness to reach agreement; those who directed hostility at just one negotiator (unilateral hostility) did not serve as common enemies, eliminating the hostile mediator effect (Experiment 5). We discuss theoretical and practical implications, and we suggest future directions.</description><author>Zhang, Ting; Gino, Francesca; Norton, Michael I.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Experience Meets Description: How Dyads Integrate Experiential and Descriptive Information in Risky Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lejarraga, Tomas; Muller-Trede, Johannes
How do teams make joint decisions under risk when some team members learn about a prospect from description and others learn from experience? In a series of experiments, we find that two-person teams composed of one participant who learns from description and a second participant who learns from experience arrive at shared decisions via mutual concessions. In doing so, they attenuate individual biases, such as the overweighting and underweighting of the probability of rare events. The social interaction thus leads dyads to make shared decisions that follow normative standards more closely than the decisions made by individual decision makers. Finally, in processing experiential information, dyads appear to be sensitive to the reliability of the experience: the more reliable the experiential information, the larger its influence on the dyad's decision.</description><author>Lejarraga, Tomas; Muller-Trede, Johannes</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Correlations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ehling, Paul; Heyerdahl-Larsen, Christian
Correlations of equity returns have varied substantially over time and remain a source of continuing policy debate. This paper studies stock market correlations in an equilibrium model with heterogeneous risk aversion. In the model, preference heterogeneity causes variations in the volatility of aggregate risk aversion from good to bad states. At times of high volatility in aggregate risk aversion, which is a common factor in returns, we see high correlations. The model matches average industry return correlations and changes in correlations from business cycle peaks to troughs and replicates the dynamics of expected excess returns and standard deviations. Model-implied aggregate risk aversion explains average industry correlations, expected excess returns, standard deviations, and turnover volatility in the data. We find supportive evidence for the model's prediction that industries with low dividend-consumption correlation have low average return correlation but experience disproportional increases in return correlations in recessions.</description><author>Ehling, Paul; Heyerdahl-Larsen, Christian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Professional Investment Managers Skilled? Evidence from Syndicated Loan Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liebscher, Roberto; Maehlmann, Thomas
Theory predicts that individual investor's incentives to uncover new information about asset values are low if asset prices are efficient. This, in turn, implies that heterogeneity in investment manager skill, if present, should be most clearly visible among managers that focus on asset classes with less informationally efficient prices. We investigate this argument using a large sample of syndicated bank loan portfolios managed by collateralized loan obligation (CLO) managers. Using a CLO's equity tranche cashon-cash return to measure performance, we find strong persistence that is robust to an extensive set of risk controls. Although investors seem to derive their expectation about management quality from a manager's realized performance and allocate more capital to "skilled" managers, top performers cope to stay ahead of net-of-fees. This questions the rationality of managers and the efficiency of the syndicated loan market.</description><author>Liebscher, Roberto; Maehlmann, Thomas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt Covenants and Cross-Sectional Equity Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Helwege, Jean; Huang, Jing-Zhi; Wang, Yuan
This paper investigates the impact of debt covenant protection on the cross section of equity returns with a firm-level covenant index and four subindices. We find that firms withweaker covenant protection ( lower covenant index levels) earn significantly higher risk-adjusted equity returns than do those firms with greater covenant protection. These results are stronger for covenant indices that are related to investments, subsequent financing, and event risk. The difference between high and low covenant index stocks is more pronounced when agency problems between shareholders and debtholders are more severe, suggesting that the covenant effect arises from an inability to control shareholder risk taking.</description><author>Helwege, Jean; Huang, Jing-Zhi; Wang, Yuan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Labeling by Competing NGOs: A Model with Multiple Issues and Entry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heyes, Anthony; Martin, Steve
In many settings firms rely on nongovernmental organizations (NGOs) to certify prosocial attributes embodied in their products. We provide a model of competition between NGOs in the provision of labeling services. Competition between a fixed number ofNGOs features a "race to the top" in labeling standards, but entry ofNGOs offering new labels pushes standards down. In a wide range of settings NGO entry and competition results in too many labels being adopted, with each label being too stringent. Compared to a setting in which firms can credibly communicate the social attributes of their products, labels demand greater prosocial behavior than is desired by firms, although with proliferation of the number of labels this discrepancy disappears. In contrast to existing models, firms may engage in excessive corporate social responsibility when they rely on an NGO as a certifying intermediary.</description><author>Heyes, Anthony; Martin, Steve</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the Past Predict the Future? The Case of Delay Announcements in Service Systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ibrahim, Rouba; Armony, Mor; Bassamboo, Achal
Motivated by the recent interest in making delay announcements in large service systems, such as call centers, we investigate the accuracy of announcing the waiting time of the last customer to enter service (LES). In practice, customers typically respond to delay announcements by either balking or by becoming more or less impatient, and their response alters system performance. We study the accuracy of the LES announcement in single-class, multiserver Markovian queueing models with announcement-dependent customer behavior. We show that, interestingly, even in this stylized setting, the LES announcement may not always be accurate. This motivates the need to study its accuracy carefully and to determine conditions under which it is accurate. Since the direct analysis of the system with customer response is prohibitively difficult, we focus on manyserver, heavy-traffic analysis instead. We consider the quality-and-efficiency-driven and efficiency-driven many-server, heavy-traffic regimes and prove, under both regimes, that the LES prediction is asymptotically accurate if and only if asymptotic fluctuations in the queue length process are small as long as some regulatory conditions apply. This result provides an easy check for the accuracy of LES announcements in practice. We supplement our theoretical results with an extensive simulation study to generate practical managerial insights.</description><author>Ibrahim, Rouba; Armony, Mor; Bassamboo, Achal</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Operating Flexibility Harmful Under Debt?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iancu, Dan A.; Trichakis, Nikolaos; Tsoukalas, Gerry
We study the inefficiencies stemming from a firm's operating flexibility under debt. We find that flexibility in replenishing or liquidating inventory, by providing risk-shifting incentives, could lead to borrowing costs that erase more than one-third of the firm's value. In this context, we examine the effectiveness of practical and widely used covenants in restoring firm value by limiting such risk-shifting behavior. We find that simple financial covenants can fully restore value for a firm that possesses a midseason inventory liquidation option. In the presence of added flexibility in replenishing or partially liquidating inventory, financial covenants fail, but simple borrowing base covenants successfully restore firm value. Explicitly characterizing optimal covenant tightness for all these cases, we find that better market conditions, such as lower inventory depreciation rate, higher gross margins, or increased product demand, are typically associated with tighter covenants. Our results suggest that inventory-heavy firms can reap the full benefits of additional operating flexibility, irrespective of their leverage, by entering simple debt contracts of the type commonly employed in practice. For such contracts to be effective, however, firms with enhanced flexibility and/or operating in better markets must also be willing to abide by more and/or tighter covenants.</description><author>Iancu, Dan A.; Trichakis, Nikolaos; Tsoukalas, Gerry</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When the Meaning of Work Has Disappeared: Experimental Evidence on Employees' Performance and Emotions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chadi, Adrian; Jeworrek, Sabrina; Mertins, Vanessa
This experiment tests for a causal relationship between the meaning of work and employees' motivation to perform well. The study builds on an existing employer-employee relationship, adding realism to the ongoing research of task meaning. Owing to an unexpected project cancelation, we are able to study how varying the information provided about the meaning of previously conducted work-without the use of deception, but still maintaining a high level of control-affects subsequent performance. We observe a strong decline in exerted effort when we inform workers about the meaninglessness of a job already done. Our data also suggests that providing a supplemental alternative meaning perfectly compensates for this negative performance effect. Individual characteristics such as reciprocal inclinations and trust prompt different reactions. The data also show that the meaning of work affects workers' emotions, but we cannot establish a clear relationship between emotional responses and performance.</description><author>Chadi, Adrian; Jeworrek, Sabrina; Mertins, Vanessa</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creating Reciprocal Value Through Operational Transparency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buell, Ryan W.; Kim, Tami; Tsay, Chia-Jung
We investigate whether organizations can create value by introducing visual transparency between consumers and producers. Although operational transparency has been shown to improve consumer perceptions of service value, existing theory posits that increased contact between consumers and producers may diminish work performance. Two field and two laboratory experiments in food service settings suggest that transparency that (1) allows customers to observe operational processes (process transparency) and (2) allows employees to observe customers (customer transparency) not only improves customer perceptions but also increases service quality and efficiency. The introduction of this transparency contributed to a 22.2% increase in customer-reported quality and reduced throughput times by 19.2%. Laboratory studies revealed that customers who observed process transparency perceived greater employee effort and thus were more appreciative of the employees and valued the service more. Employees who observed customer transparency felt that their work was more appreciated and more impactful and thus were more satisfied with their work and more willing to exert effort. We find that transparency, by visually revealing operating processes to consumers and beneficiaries to producers, generates a positive feedback loop through which value is created for both parties.</description><author>Buell, Ryan W.; Kim, Tami; Tsay, Chia-Jung</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reference-Dependent Preferences: Evidence from Marathon Runners</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Eric J.; Dechow, Patricia M.; Pope, Devin G.; Wu, George
Theories of reference-dependent preferences propose that individuals evaluate outcomes as gains or losses relative to a neutral reference point. We test for reference dependence in a large data set of marathon finishing times (n = 9; 789; 093). Models of reference-dependent preferences such as prospect theory predict bunching of finishing times at reference points. We provide visual and statistical evidence that round numbers (e.g., a four-hour marathon) serve as reference points in this environment and as a result produce significant bunching of performance at these round numbers. Bunching is driven by planning and adjustments in effort provision near the finish line and cannot be explained by explicit rewards (e.g., qualifying for the Boston Marathon), peer effects, or institutional features (e.g., pacesetters).</description><author>Allen, Eric J.; Dechow, Patricia M.; Pope, Devin G.; Wu, George</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>FORE! An Analysis of CEO Shirking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Biggerstaff, Lee; Cicero, David C.; Puckett, Andy
Using golf play as a measure of leisure, we provide direct evidence that some CEOs shirk their responsibilities to the detriment of firm shareholders. CEOs with lower equity-based incentives play more golf and those that golf the most are associated with firms that have lower operating performance and firm values. Numerous tests accounting for the possible endogenous nature of these relations support a conclusion that CEO shirking causes lower firm performance. New CEOs and those at firms with more independent boards are more likely to be replaced when they shirk, but those with long tenures or less independent boards appear to avoid discipline.</description><author>Biggerstaff, Lee; Cicero, David C.; Puckett, Andy</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Unions Affect Innovation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bradley, Daniel; Kim, Incheol; Tian, Xuan
We examine the effect of unionization on firm innovation, using a regression discontinuity design that relies on "locally" exogenous variation generated by elections that pass or fail by a small margin of votes. Passing a union election results in an 8.7% (12.5%) decline in patent quantity (quality) three years after the election. A reduction in R&amp;D expenditures, reduced productivity of inventors, and departures of innovative inventors appear to be plausible underlying mechanisms through which unionization impedes firm innovation. In response to unionization, firms move their innovation activities away from states where union elections win. Our paper provides new insights into the real effects of unionization.</description><author>Bradley, Daniel; Kim, Incheol; Tian, Xuan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Return Smoothing, Liquidity Costs, and Investor Flows: Evidence from a Separate Account Platform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Charles; Farnsworth, Grant; Liang, Bing; Lo, Andrew W.
We use a new hedge fund data set from a separate account platform to examine (1) how much of hedge fund return smoothing is due to main fund-specific factors, such as managerial reporting discretion and (2) the costs of removing hedge fund share restrictions. These accounts trade pari passu with matching hedge funds but feature third-party reporting and permissive share restrictions. We use these properties to estimate that 33% of reported smoothing is due to managerial reporting methods. The platform's fund-level liquidity is associated with a 1.7% performance reduction on an annual basis. Investor flows chase monthly past performance on the platform but not in the associated funds.</description><author>Cao, Charles; Farnsworth, Grant; Liang, Bing; Lo, Andrew W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Costly Control: An Examination of the Trade-off Between Control Investments and Residual Risk in Interfirm Transactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Shannon W.; Dekker, Henri C.; Van den Abbeele, Alexandra
Transaction cost economics predicts that investments in management control will enable risky interfirm transactions. Risk is rarely eliminated, because firms trade off costs of management control and expected costs of control loss (together, the "cost of control"). The resultant solution typically comprises a mix of control investments with residual performance and residual relational risks. Transaction cost economics also predicts that the control-residual risk trade-off will vary with the cost of control. We use survey data on 287 risky information technology transactions to test whether the control-residual risk trade-off varies predictably with two partnership-specific factors that proxy for variation in the cost of control: prior ties between exchange partners and the criticality of strategic resources to the transaction. The results support the hypotheses, providing novel evidence on trade-offs that managers make when investing in management controls while also prudently accepting some risks.</description><author>Anderson, Shannon W.; Dekker, Henri C.; Van den Abbeele, Alexandra</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Redesigning Benders Decomposition for Large-Scale Facility Location</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fischetti, Matteo; Ljubic, Ivana; Sinnl, Markus
The uncapacitated facility location (UFL) problem is one of the most famous and most studied problems in the operations research literature. Given a set of potential facility locations and a set of customers, the goal is to find a subset of facility locations to open and to allocate each customer to open facilities so that the facility opening plus customer allocation costs are minimized. In our setting, for each customer the allocation cost is assumed to be a linear or separable convex quadratic function. Motivated by recent UFL applications in business analytics, we revise approaches that work on a projected decision space and hence are intrinsically more scalable for large-scale input data. Our working hypothesis is that many of the exact (decomposition) approaches that were proposed decades ago and discarded soon after need to be redesigned to take advantage of the new hardware and software technologies. To this end, we "thin out" the classical models from the literature and use (generalized) Benders cuts to replace a huge number of allocation variables by a small number of continuous variables that model the customer allocation cost directly. Our results showthat Benders decomposition allows for a significant boost in the performance of a mixed-integer programming solver. We report the optimal solution of a large set of previously unsolved benchmark instances widely used in the available literature. In particular, dramatic speedups are achieved for UFL problems with separable quadratic allocation costs, which turn out to be much easier than their linear counterparts when our approach is used.</description><author>Fischetti, Matteo; Ljubic, Ivana; Sinnl, Markus</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Higher Prices for Larger Quantities? Nonmonotonic Price-Quantity Relations in B2B Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Wei; Dasu, Sriram; Ahmadi, Reza
We study a microprocessor company selling short-life-cycle products to a set of buyers that includes large consumer electronic goods manufacturers. The seller has a limited capacity for each product and negotiates with each buyer for the price. Our analysis of their sales data reveals that larger purchases do not always result in bigger discounts. Instead, the discount curve is like an "N." While existing theories cannot explain this non-monotonic pattern, we develop an analytical model and show that the nonmonotonicity is rooted in how sellers value capacity when negotiating with a buyer. Large buyers accelerate the selling process and small buyers are helpful in consuming the residual capacity. However, satisfying midsized buyers may be costly because supplying these buyers can make it difficult to utilize the remaining capacity, which is often too much for small buyers but not enough for large buyers. We briefly discuss the implications for capacity rationing and posted pricing as well as potential applications to other industries.</description><author>Zhang, Wei; Dasu, Sriram; Ahmadi, Reza</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Product Rotation in the Presence of Strategic Customers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Fernando; Martinez-de-Albeniz, Victor
Dynamic product rotation is perceived as a useful lever to increase sales. The effect over individual customers is, however, unclear: more choice in the future may induce them to postpone a purchase if the current offer is not sufficiently appealing, hoping to buy a better product in the future; moreover, visiting a store to learn about a new product may be costly, thereby diminishing the value of product updates. We analyze a model of strategic customer behavior in the face of a rotating product offering, with variable assortment depth. We find that the customers' visit and purchase decisions follow a relatively simple structure: a customer should visit the store only when new products have been introduced and purchase a product if the value it provides is higher than a threshold. We then use this structure to examine the retailer's optimal product-rotation policy. The structure of the optimal policy depends on product-rotation costs and capacity constraints. When capacity constraints are tight, the retailer spreads out product introductions throughout the selling season. Strategic customers tend to become more demanding (their purchasing thresholds increase) as the frequency of product rotation increases, so the marginal benefit of each additional product rotation decreases. In contrast, the purchasing thresholds for myopic customers-who buy the first item that fits their needs-are independent of the number of products introduced in the season. As a result, when the cost of product rotation is low, the frequency of product updates is higher when the retailer sells to strategic customers, whereas the opposite is true when the cost of product rotation is high. When capacity constraints are less stringent and product-rotation costs are convex in the assortment depth, we find that the level of product variety should increase as the season progresses when the firm sells to strategic customers, while the level of product variety stays constant over the season when faced with myopic customers. Finally, when there are no capacity constraints, it is optimal to introduce all products in a single period.</description><author>Bernstein, Fernando; Martinez-de-Albeniz, Victor</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mixed-Integer Rounding Enhanced Benders Decomposition for Multiclass Service-System Staffing and Scheduling with Arrival Rate Uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bodur, Merve; Luedtke, James R.
We study server scheduling in multiclass service systems under uncertainty in the customer arrival volumes. Common practice in such systems is to first identify staffing levels and then determine schedules for the servers that cover these levels. We propose a new stochastic integer programming (SIP) model that integrates these two decisions, which can yield lower scheduling costs by exploiting the presence of alternative server configurations that yield similar quality of service. We find that a branch-and-cut algorithm based on Benders decomposition may fail due to the weakness of the relaxation bound. We propose a novel application of mixed-integer rounding to improve the Benders cuts used in this algorithm, a technique that is applicable to any SIP with integer first-stage decision variables. Numerical examples illustrate the computational efficiency of the proposed approach and the potential benefit of solving the integrated model compared to considering the staffing and scheduling problems separately.</description><author>Bodur, Merve; Luedtke, James R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Behavior-Based Pricing, Production Efficiency, and Quality Differentiation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jing, Bing
In a two-period vertical duopoly, we examine how behavior-based price discrimination (BPD) affects the firms' endogenous quality differentiation and profits. The firms' relative production efficiency, defined as the ratio between their unit cost difference and quality difference, plays a crucial role. With exogenous product qualities, BPD always decreases the profits of the more efficient firm, but increases those of the sufficiently less efficient firm. Anticipating its period 2 disadvantage in price discrimination, the less efficient firm competes more vigorously and also gains more in period 1 than its competitor. For the sufficiently less efficient firm, its period 1 gain dominates its period 2 loss, and its total profits increase. With endogenous quality choices, BPD does not alter the low-end quality (at the lower bound of the quality space), but increases the high-end quality, enlarging quality differentiation. This is because under BPD, each firm's profit gain decreases (or its profit loss increases) in its relative production efficiency. Interestingly, BPD may increase both firms' profits under endogenous quality differentiation. Aside from causing mismatch between consumers and products, we further show that BPD lowers social welfare through inducing excessive quality differentiation.</description><author>Jing, Bing</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Meeting of the Minds: Informal Agreements and Social Norms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krupka, Erin L.; Leider, Stephen; Jiang, Ming
Using coordination games, we elicit social norms directly for two different games where either an agreement to take the first best action has been reached or where no such agreement exists. We combine the norms data with separately measured choice data to predict changes in behavior. We demonstrate that including social norms as a utility component significantly improves predictive performance. Then we compare social norms to guilt aversion and lying aversion. We estimate that honoring an agreement in the double dictator game is worth giving up approximately 10% of total earnings and more than 120% in the Bertrand game. We show that informal agreements affect behavior through their direct effect on social norms as well as through an indirect effect on beliefs.</description><author>Krupka, Erin L.; Leider, Stephen; Jiang, Ming</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Strategies for Flood Prevention</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eijgenraam, Carel; Brekelmans, Ruud; den Hertog, Dick; Roos, Kees
Flood prevention policy is of major importance to the Netherlands since a large part of the country is below sea level and high water levels in rivers may also cause floods. In this paper we propose a dike height optimization model to determine economically efficient flood protection standards. We improve the model proposed by David van Dantzig [van Dantzig D (1956) Economic decision problems for flood prevention. Econometrica 24(3):276-287] after a devastating flood in the Netherlands in 1953. Our model is nonconvex, but we derive an explicit simple expression for the global optimal solution, which is periodic. We also discuss how to use this optimal investment policy to derive an efficient flood protection standard. The rather simple expression for this standard gives us much insight into how it depends on several relevant economic and climate model parameters. This approach has been applied to all dike rings in the Netherlands, and the resulting standards have been stated in the new Delta Programme 2015, which has been accepted by the government.</description><author>Eijgenraam, Carel; Brekelmans, Ruud; den Hertog, Dick; Roos, Kees</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Closed-Form Solutions for Robust Inventory Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mamani, Hamed; Nassiri, Shima; Wagner, Michael R.
We propose and analyze robust optimization models of an inventory management problem, where cumulative purchase, inventory, and shortage costs over n periods are minimized for correlated nonidentically distributed demand. We assume that the means and covariance matrix of stochastic demand are known; the distributions are not needed. We derive closed-form ordering quantities for both symmetric and asymmetric uncertainty sets, under capacitated inventory constraints, in both static and dynamic settings. The behaviors of our robust strategies differ qualitatively depending on the symmetry of the uncertainty set. For instance, considering our simplest static problem, (1) if the uncertainty set is symmetric, then there is positive ordering in all periods, whereas (2) if the set is asymmetric, then there is a set of periods in the middle of the planning horizon with zero orders. We also link the symmetry of the uncertainty set to the symmetry of the demand distribution. Finally, we present encouraging computational results where our solution compares favorably to previously studied, more complex robust solutions.</description><author>Mamani, Hamed; Nassiri, Shima; Wagner, Michael R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Choosing the Devil You Don't Know: Evidence for Limited Sensitivity to Sample Size-Based Uncertainty When It Offers an Advantage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kutzner, Florian L.; Read, Daniel; Stewart, Neil; Brown, Gordon
Many decision makers seek to optimize choices between uncertain options such as strategies, employees, or products. When performance targets must be met, attending to observed past performance is not enough to optimize choices-option uncertainty must also be considered. For example, for stretch targets that exceed observed performance, more uncertain options are often better bets. A significant determinant of option uncertainty is sample size: for a given option, the smaller the sample of information we have about it, the greater the uncertainty. In two studies, choices were made between pairs of uncertain options with the goal of exceeding a specified performance target. Information about the options differed in the size of the sample drawn from them, sample size, and the observed performance of those samples, the proportion of successes or "hits" in the sample. We found people to be sensitive to sample size-based uncertainty only when differences in observed performance were negligible. We conclude that in the presence of performance targets, people largely fail to capitalize on the value advantages of small samples in the presence of stretch targets.</description><author>Kutzner, Florian L.; Read, Daniel; Stewart, Neil; Brown, Gordon</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Battle of the Channels: The Impact of Tablets on Digital Commerce</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xu, Kaiquan; Chan, Jason; Ghose, Anindya; Han, Sang Pil
The introduction of tablets in online retailing has created an additional touch-point through which e-commerce firms can interact with consumers. In this paper, we seek to understand and measure the causal impact of tablets on e-commerce sales. In doing so, we examine the complementary and substitution impact of the tablet channel on the smartphone and PC channels. We rely on a unique data set from Alibaba, the largest e-commerce firm in the world, and exploit a natural experiment via the iPad app introduction to empirically identify our results. The results show that users' adoption of tablets enhanced the overall growth of Alibaba's e-commerce market, with an annual increase of approximately US$923.5 million. Our results demonstrate that the tablet channel acts as a substitute for the PC channel while it acts as a complement for the smartphone channel. Furthermore, the use of tablets spurs casual browsing, which leads to the purchase of more impulse products and a wider diversity of products. Cross-device browsing behavior is found to enhance sales outcomes, and the degree of interrelationships between devices varies across the course of the day. We provide insights for retailers about how they can increase their sales volume and revenue in the emerging tablet economy.</description><author>Xu, Kaiquan; Chan, Jason; Ghose, Anindya; Han, Sang Pil</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Ability and Credit Risk Assessment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bonsall, Samuel B.; Holzman, Eric R.; Miller, Brian P.
Research on the credit rating process has primarily focused on how rating agencies incorporate firm characteristics into their rating opinions. We contribute to this literature by examining the impact of managerial ability on the credit rating process. Given debt market participants' interest in assessing default risk, we begin by documenting that higher managerial ability is associated with lower variability in future earnings and stock returns. We then show that higher managerial ability is associated with higher credit ratings (i.e., lower assessments of credit risk). To provide more direct identification of the impact of managerial ability, we examine chief executive officer (CEO) replacements and document that ratings increase (decrease) when CEOs are replaced with more (less) able CEOs. Finally, we show that managerial ability also has capital market implications by documenting that managerial ability is associated with bond offering credit spreads. Collectively, our evidence suggests that managerial ability is an important factor that bond market participants impound into their assessments of firm credit risk.</description><author>Bonsall, Samuel B.; Holzman, Eric R.; Miller, Brian P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do People Anticipate Loss Aversion?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Imas, Alex; Sadoff, Sally; Samek, Anya
There is growing interest in the use of loss contracts that offer performance incentives as up-front payments that employees can lose. Standard behavioral models predict a trade-off in the use of loss contracts: employees will work harder under loss contracts than under gain contracts, but, anticipating loss aversion, they will prefer gain contracts to loss contracts. In a series of experiments, we test these predictions by measuring performance and preferences for payoff-equivalent gain and loss contracts. We find that people indeed work harder under loss than gain contracts, as the theory predicts. Surprisingly, rather than a preference for the gain contract, we find that people actually prefer loss contracts. In exploring mechanisms for our results, we find suggestive evidence that people do anticipate loss aversion but select into loss contracts as a commitment device to improve performance, using one bias, loss aversion, to address another, dynamic inconsistency.</description><author>Imas, Alex; Sadoff, Sally; Samek, Anya</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disagreement, Underreaction, and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cen, Ling; Wei, K. C. John; Yang, Liyan
We explore analysts' earnings forecast data to improve on one popular disagreement measure-the analyst forecast dispersion measure-proposed by Diether et al. [Diether KB, Malloy CJ, Scherbina A (2002) Differences of opinion and the cross section of stock returns. J. Finance 57: 2113-2141]. Our analysis suggests that changes in the standard deviations of forecasted earnings can work as a complementary disagreement measure that is comparable across stocks and immune from other return-predictive information contained in the normalization scalars of analyst forecast dispersion measures. We also document evidence that the change-based disagreement measure predicts future cross-sectional returns significantly only when changes in the mean forecasts are negative. This finding suggests that the interaction between disagreement and underreaction to earnings news affects asset prices.</description><author>Cen, Ling; Wei, K. C. John; Yang, Liyan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Online Grocery Retail: Revenue Models and Environmental Impact</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Belavina, Elena; Girotra, Karan; Kabra, Ashish
This paper compares the financial and environmental performance of two revenue models for the online retailing of groceries: the per-order model, where customers pay for each delivery, and the subscription model, where customers pay a set fee and receive free deliveries. We build a stylized model that incorporates (i) customers with ongoing uncertain grocery needs and who choose between shopping offline or online and (ii) an online retailer that makes deliveries through a proprietary distribution network. We find that subscription incentivizes smaller and more frequent grocery orders, which reduces food waste and creates more value for the customer; the result is higher retailer revenues, lower grocery costs, and potentially higher adoption rates. These advantages are countered by greater delivery-related travel and expenses, which are moderated by area geography and routing-related scale economies. Subscription also leads to lower food waste-related emissions but to higher delivery-related emissions. Ceteris paribus, the perorder model is preferable for higher-margin retailers with higher-consumption product assortments that are sold in sparsely populated markets spread over large, irregular areas with high delivery costs. Geographic and demographic data indicate that the subscription model is almost always environmentally preferable because lower food waste emissions dominate higher delivery emissions.</description><author>Belavina, Elena; Girotra, Karan; Kabra, Ashish</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>First-Order and Second-Order Ambiguity Aversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lang, Matthias
Different models of uncertainty aversion imply strikingly different economic behavior. The key to understanding these differences lies in the dichotomy between first-order and second-order ambiguity aversion, which I define here. My definition and its characterization are independent of specific representations of decisions under uncertainty. I showthat with second-order ambiguity aversion, a positive exposure to ambiguity is optimal if and only if there is a subjective belief such that the act's expected outcome is positive. With first-order ambiguity aversion, zero exposure to ambiguity can be optimal. Examples in finance, insurance, and contracting demonstrate the economic relevance of this dichotomy.</description><author>Lang, Matthias</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contract Structure for Joint Production: Risk and Ambiguity Under Compensatory Damages</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ryall, Michael D.; Sampson, Rachelle C.
We develop a model in which the parties to a joint production project have a choice of specifying contractual performance in terms of actions or deliverables. Penalties for noncompliance are not specified; rather, they are left to the courts under the legal doctrine of compensatory damages. We analyze three scenarios of increasing uncertainty: full information, where implications of partner actions are known; risk, where implications can be probabilistically quantified; and ambiguity, where implications cannot be so quantified. Under full information, action requirements dominate: they always induce the maximum economic value. This dominance vanishes in the risk scenario. Under ambiguity, deliverables specifications can interact with compensatory damages to create a form of "ambiguity insurance," where ambiguity aversion is assuaged in a way that increases the aggregate, perceived value of the project. This effect does not arise under contracts specifying action requirements. Thus, deliverables contracts may facilitate highly novel joint projects that would otherwise be foregone as a result of excessive uncertainty. Suggested empirical implications include the choice of contract clause type depending on the level of uncertainty in a joint development project, one application being the level of partner experience with interfirm collaborations.</description><author>Ryall, Michael D.; Sampson, Rachelle C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Secretary Problem with a Selection Committee: Do Conformist Committees Hire Better Secretaries?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alpern, Steve; Baston, Vic
This paper analyzes a variation of the secretary problem in which two selectors with different fields of interest each want to appoint one of the n candidates with as much expertise as possible in their field. Selectors simultaneously vote to accept or reject: Unanimous decisions are respected, and candidates with a split decision are hired with probability p. Each candidate arrives with expertise x and y in the two fields, uniformly and independently distributed on [0; 1] and observable to both selectors. If a candidate with expertise pair (x, y) is hired by unanimous decision, the payoffs to the selectors are simply x and y. However, to model the level of conformity in the firm, we deduct a positive "consensus cost" c from the utility of a selector who has rejected a candidate who is nevertheless hired. We show(Theorem 1) that each stage game has a unique equilibrium in which there are two thresholds, z &lt; nu; and say selector I accepts candidate (x,y) if x &gt; nu or x &gt; z and y &gt; nu. We show that for sufficiently large p and c, decisions are unanimous, and that as the number n of candidates goes to infinity, the equilibrium value of the game goes to the golden mean. We show that as the consensus cost c increases from 0, this hurts the selectors (Theorem 4) but helps the firm (Theorem 6), whose utility from hiring candidate (x,y) is a weighted average of x and y. Thus a little conformity is good for the firm.</description><author>Alpern, Steve; Baston, Vic</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Signaling Low Margin Through Assortment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuksov, Dmitri; Lin, Yuanfang
Oftentimes, close competitors carry partially overlapping assortments in seeming contradiction to the principle of maximum differentiation. One of the justifications of such practice is that an overlapping assortment with competitive prices on the common products may prevent further consumer search and therefore could be useful even when profits from the overlapping products do not justify the costs of carrying them. In this paper, we examine the validity of this intuition and show that such strategy may indeed be optimal when consumers are uncertain about prices they might find elsewhere and face shopping costs for discovery of all prices. Specifically, we showthat the (larger) assortment with product overlap may signal a "competitive" price of the relatively unique product and prevent further consumer search for a lower price on it. An implication of this finding is that a consumer may rationally behave as if she likes a larger assortment even if the assortment is enlarged by adding products the consumer has no interest in. Furthermore, we show that the optimal pricing strategy may include pricing of common products or products with known costs at a loss, which provides a novel explanation of loss-leader pricing.</description><author>Kuksov, Dmitri; Lin, Yuanfang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fee or Free: When Should Firms Charge for Online Content?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lambrecht, Anja; Misra, Kanishka
Many online content providers aim to compensate for a loss in advertising revenues by charging consumers for access to content. However, such a choice is not straightforward because subscription fees typically deter customers, and a resulting decline in viewership further reduces advertising revenues. This research examines whether firms that offer both free and paid content can benefit from adjusting the amount of content offered for free. We find that firms should offer more free-and not paid-content in periods of high demand. We motivate theoretically that this policy, which we term "countercyclical offering," may be optimal for firms when consumers are heterogeneous in their valuation of online content and this heterogeneity varies over time. Using unique data from an online content provider, we then provide empirical evidence that firms indeed engage in countercyclical offering and increase the share of free content in periods of high demand.</description><author>Lambrecht, Anja; Misra, Kanishka</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Licensing Contracts: Control Rights, Options, and Timing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crama, Pascale; De Reyck, Bert; Taneri, Niyazi
Research and development (R&amp;D) collaborations, common in high-tech industries, are challenging to manage because of technical and market risks as well as incentive problems. We investigate how control rights, options, payment terms, and timing allow the innovator to capture maximum value from its R&amp;D collaborations with a marketer. Our study reveals a counterintuitive result; the innovator may, under certain conditions, prefer to grant launch control rights or buyout options to the marketer despite the fact that both terms restrict its downstream actions. We demonstrate that a menu of contracts is not necessary to address the adverse selection problem because the menu can be replicated by a single option contract. We show that timing, through renegotiation or delayed contracting, as well as the careful allocation of control rights and options can have a significant influence on the value of collaborative R&amp;D. We provide recommendations on the optimal contract structure and timing based on two project characteristics, novelty of the R&amp;D process and market-potential variability.</description><author>Crama, Pascale; De Reyck, Bert; Taneri, Niyazi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stochastic Dominance Analysis Without the Independence Axiom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cerreia-Vioglio, Simone; Maccheroni, Fabio; Marinaccia, Massimo
We characterize the consistency of a large class of nonexpected utility preferences (including mean-variance preferences and prospect theory preferences) with stochastic orders (for example, stochastic dominances of different degrees). Our characterization rests on a novel decision theoretic result that provides a behavioral interpretation of the set of all derivatives of the functional representing the decision maker's preferences. As an illustration, we consider in some detail prospect theory and choice-acclimating preferences, two popular models of reference dependence under risk, and we show the incompatibility of loss aversion with prudence.</description><author>Cerreia-Vioglio, Simone; Maccheroni, Fabio; Marinaccia, Massimo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Bright-Line Earnings Surprises Really Affect Stock Price Reactions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abarbanell, Jeffery; Park, Hyungshin
Several influential studies have concluded that earnings surprises just to the right or to the left of a hypothesized bright line produce distinct price reactions compared with surrounding earnings surprises because they convey special meaning. In this study, we examine whether previous inferences of asymmetric stock price reactions to bright-line surprises are observed when empirical tests are designed to be consistent with a rational expectations equilibrium. Focusing on a small range of earnings surprises around hypothesized bright lines, we find no evidence of asymmetric price reactions once investors' ex ante expectation of bias in earnings surprises is controlled. Results from additional tests yield support for the external validity of the theoretical framework underlying our bright-line pricing tests. Our findings suggest simple refinements to traditional bins-comparison and regression tests for asymmetric price reactions to bright-line earnings surprises, which account for necessary conditions implied by a rational expectations equilibrium.</description><author>Abarbanell, Jeffery; Park, Hyungshin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jumps in Equity Index Returns Before and During the Recent Financial Crisis: A Bayesian Analysis (vol 63, pg 988, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kou, Steven; Yu, Cindy; Zhong, Haowen
nan</description><author>Kou, Steven; Yu, Cindy; Zhong, Haowen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jumps in Equity Index Returns Before and During the Recent Financial Crisis: A Bayesian Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kou, Steven; Yu, Cindy; Zhong, Haowen
We attempt to answer two questions in this paper: (i) How did jumps in equity returns change after the 2008-2009 financial crisis-in particular, were there significant changes in jump rates or in jump sizes, or both? (ii) Can the performance of affine jump-diffusion models be improved if jump sizes are larger, i.e., jumps with tails heavier than those of the normal distribution? To answer the second question, we find that a simple affine jump-diffusion model with both stochastic volatility and double-exponential jumps fits both the S&amp;P 500 and the NASDAQ-100 daily returns from 1980 to 2013 well; the model outperforms existing ones (e.g., models with variance-gamma jumps or jumps in volatility) during the crisis and is at least comparable before the crisis. For the first question, on the basis of the model and the data sets, we observe that during the crisis, negative jump rate increased significantly, although there was little change in the average negative jump size.</description><author>Kou, Steven; Yu, Cindy; Zhong, Haowen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing Risk and Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nanda, Ramana; Rhodes-Kropf, Matthew
We provide a model of investment in new ventures that demonstrates why some places, times, and industries should be associated with a greater degree of experimentation by investors. Investors respond to financing risk, a forecast of limited future funding, by modifying their focus to finance less innovative firms. In equilibrium, financing risk disproportionately impacts innovative ventures with the greatest real option value by creating a trade-off between protecting the firm from financing risk and maximizing its real option value. We propose that extremely novel technologies may need "hot" financial markets to get through the initial period of discovery or diffusion.</description><author>Nanda, Ramana; Rhodes-Kropf, Matthew</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tailored Benders Decomposition for a Long-Term Power Expansion Model with Short-Term Demand Response</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lohmann, Timo; Rebennack, Steffen
We present a long-term power generation expansion planning model that features a long planning horizon, an hourly time resolution, multiperiod investment and retirement decisions, transmission constraints, start-up restrictions, and short-term demand response. Demand response is the capability of power load to react to short-term changes in electricity prices. It plays an increasingly important role in today's electricity markets but has not been taken into consideration in long-term power generation expansion planning problems, which mostly treat demand as perfectly inelastic. Given mild assumptions for the underlying demand function, the resulting model is a large-scale, concave, linearly constrained maximization problem. We exploit the model structure by developing a new approach to generalized Benders decomposition (GBD). In particular, we present two algorithmic ideas: (1) solving the nonlinear Benders subproblem as a linear programming (LP) problem with the aid of dynamic linear overestimation, referred to as the LP-based method, and (2) directly calculating all necessary optimal primal and dual variable values, referred to as the calculation-based method. We consider three special cases of our expansion planning model and show that solving mathematical programming problems can become entirely obsolete in the calculation-based method. We demonstrate the efficiency of all proposed algorithms for the Texas power system, comparing our tailored decomposition methods to a monolithic approach and a state-of-the-art GBD implementation. Our LP-based method is up to 3,822 times faster than the monolithic approach and up to 55 times faster than the GBD. The calculation-based method dramatically improves the solution time, being an average factor of 20 faster than solving LPs and 107,074 times faster than the monolithic approach (for the largest solvable instance by a commercial solver). The overall largest instance we solve, containing more than 79 million variables and constraints, converges in less than one minute using the calculation-based method. The modeling language GAMS and its latest features were used to efficiently implement all algorithms.</description><author>Lohmann, Timo; Rebennack, Steffen</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Demonstrations and Price Competition in New Product Release</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boleslavsky, Raphael; Cotton, Christopher S.; Gurnani, Haresh
We incorporate product demonstrations into a game theoretic model of price competition. Demonstrations may include product samples, trials, return policies, online review platforms, or any other means by which a firm allows consumers to learn about their value for a new product. In our model, demonstrations help individual consumers to learn whether they prefer an innovative product over an established alternative. The innovative firm controls demonstration informativeness. When the innovative firm commits to demonstration policies and there is flexibility in prices, the firm is best off offering fully informative demonstrations that divide the market and dampen price competition. In contrast, when a firm can adjust its demonstration strategy in response to prices, the firm prefers only partially informative demonstrations, designed to maximize its market share. Such a strategy can generate the monopoly profit for the innovative firm. We contrast the strategic role of demonstrations in our framework with the strategic role of capacity limits in models of judo economics, which also allow firms to divide a market and reduce competition.</description><author>Boleslavsky, Raphael; Cotton, Christopher S.; Gurnani, Haresh</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do CMO Incentives Matter? An Empirical Investigation of CMO Compensation and Its Impact on Firm Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bansal, Naresh; Joseph, Kissan; Ma, Minghui; Wintoki, M. Babajide
Despite growing interest in various facets of the position of chief marketing officer (CMO), there is very little research on CMO compensation. Accordingly, we set out to investigate the determinants of CMO compensation and its effect on firm performance. Employing the lens of agency theory, we hypothesize that the CMO's marginal productivity will positively impact the amount of total compensation as well as the extent of performance-based compensation in the CMO's compensation contract. Moreover, we hypothesize that deviations in contracting elements from predicted levels will adversely impact firm performance. Analyzing a sample of 9,230 firm-year observations over the period 1992-2013, we find that CMOs employed at firms with high advertising and R&amp; D intensity, and operating in competitive product markets, command larger amounts of total compensation. Moreover, a greater proportion of their compensation is market based, with heightened sensitivity to movements in the firm's stock price. We also find that deviations in CMO compensation elements have an adverse impact on operating performance (return on assets (ROA)), earnings surprises, and stock returns. Specifically, a 10% deviation in market-based compensation from predicted levels reduces ROAby 0.28%, dampens earnings surprises by 0.19%, and degrades annualized stock returns by 2.4%.</description><author>Bansal, Naresh; Joseph, Kissan; Ma, Minghui; Wintoki, M. Babajide</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Utility-Based Link Recommendation for Online Social Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Zhepeng; Fang, Xiao; Bai, Xue; Sheng, Olivia R. Liu
Link recommendation, which suggests links to connect currently unlinked users, is a key functionality offered by major online social networks. Salient examples of link recommendation include "People You May Know" on Facebook and LinkedIn as well as "You May Know" on Google+. The main stakeholders of an online social network include users (e.g., Facebook users) who use the network to socialize with other users and an operator (e.g., Facebook Inc.) that establishes and operates the network for its own benefit (e.g., revenue). Existing link recommendation methods recommend links that are likely to be established by users but overlook the benefit a recommended link could bring to an operator. To address this gap, we define the utility of recommending a link and formulate a new research problem-the utility-based link recommendation problem. We then propose a novel utility-based link recommendation method that recommends links based on the value, cost, and linkage likelihood of a link, in contrast to existing link recommendation methods that focus solely on linkage likelihood. Specifically, our method models the dependency relationship between the value, cost, linkage likelihood, and utility-based link recommendation decision using a Bayesian network; predicts the probability of recommending a link with the Bayesian network; and recommends links with the highest probabilities. Using data obtained from a major U.S. online social network, we demonstrate significant performance improvement achieved by our method compared with prevalent link recommendation methods from representative prior research.</description><author>Li, Zhepeng; Fang, Xiao; Bai, Xue; Sheng, Olivia R. Liu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>