<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Management Science5</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Jumps in High-Frequency Data: Spurious Detections, Dynamics, and News</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bajgrowicz, Pierre; Scaillet, Olivier; Treccani, Adrien
Applying tests for jumps to financial data sets can lead to an important number of spurious detections. Bursts of volatility are often incorrectly identified as jumps when the sampling is too sparse. At a higher frequency, methods robust to microstructure noise are required. We argue that whatever the jump detection test and the sampling frequency, a large number of spurious detections remain because of multiple testing issues. We propose a formal treatment based on an explicit thresholding on available test statistics. We prove that our method eliminates asymptotically all remaining spurious detections. In Dow Jones stocks between 2006 and 2008, spurious detections can represent up to 90% of the jumps detected initially. For the stocks considered, jumps are rare events, they do not cluster in time, and no cojump affects all stocks simultaneously, suggesting jump risk is diversifiable. We relate the remaining jumps to macroeconomic news, prescheduled company-specific announcements, and stories from news agencies that include a variety of unscheduled and uncategorized events. The vast majority of news does not cause jumps but may generate a market reaction in the form of bursts of volatility.</description><author>Bajgrowicz, Pierre; Scaillet, Olivier; Treccani, Adrien</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Information Value of Credit Rating Action Reports: A Textual Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit; Chen, Vincent Y. S.; Zhang, Weina
We examine whether Standard &amp; Poor's (S&amp;P) credit rating action reports contain new default-related information beyond credit rating actions such as rating changes, credit watch, and outlooks. We find that the net linguistic tone (negative minus positive tone) in the reports is significantly and negatively related to abnormal returns and predicts future rating changes. We discover that the provision of tone does not seem to be inflated by the conventional proxies of conflict of interest faced by S&amp;P, as higher conflict of interest is related to more negative net tone. Moreover, the tone can predict future rating changes even when conflict of interest is high. Overall, our study reveals novel evidence on the information value of credit rating action reports.</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; Chen, Vincent Y. S.; Zhang, Weina</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Determinants of Bank Mergers: A Revealed Preference Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akkus, Oktay; Cookson, J. Anthony; Hortacsu, Ali
We provide new estimates of merger value creation by exploiting revealed preferences of merging banks within a matching market framework. We find that merger value arises from cost efficiencies in overlapping markets, relaxing of regulation, and network effects exhibited by the acquirer-target matching. Beyond our findings, the revealed preference method has notable advantages that warrant its application beyond the bank merger market. Notably, we show that the method outperforms reduced form alternatives out of sample, enables sensible counterfactual experiments, and can be used to evaluate private-to-private mergers, which have been understudied because of lack of stock market data.</description><author>Akkus, Oktay; Cookson, J. Anthony; Hortacsu, Ali</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Empirical Model of Drug Detailing: Dynamic Competition and Policy Implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Qiang; Gupta, Sachin; Venkataraman, Sriram; Liu, Hongju
The practice of detailing in the marketing of prescription drugs is undergoing significant changes. For instance, in September 2013, the Physician Payment Sunshine Act went into full effect. The accompanying transparency requirements have prompted physician practices and hospitals to severely restrict pharmaceutical sales representatives' direct access to their physicians. Despite all the attention in the popular press, scant scholarly research has investigated how these restrictions on physician access impact physician prescription behavior and competitive detailing to physicians. To analyze the impact of these restrictions, we develop a structural model of how pharmaceutical firms compete dynamically to schedule detailing to physicians. Detailing activities are known to have significant carryover effects that are captured in a first-stage model of physicians' demand for prescription drugs. We also specify detailing policy functions that describe each firm's observed detailing actions. In a second stage, we estimate a model that describes costs of detailing, assuming that the observed detailing levels are consistent with a Markov perfect Nash equilibrium. The estimated structural model is used to examine the implications of restrictions on the amount of detailing via counterfactual simulations. We find that restriction policies would increase the market share of a nondrug-treatment-only option but impact firms asymmetrically; firms that are strong in detailing and/or rely more on detailing would be hurt more. Unexpectedly, a policy that imposes a ceiling on detailing frequency could significantly reduce detailing of all firms in the market, including those firms with average detailing levels below the ceiling, and effectively would soften competition between firms and enhance their profits.</description><author>Liu, Qiang; Gupta, Sachin; Venkataraman, Sriram; Liu, Hongju</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competing for Attention in Social Communication Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iyer, Ganesh; Katona, Zsolt
We investigate the incentives for social communication in the new social media technologies. Three features of online social communication are represented in the model. First, new social media platforms allow for increased connectivity; i.e., they enable sending messages to many more receivers, for the same fixed cost, compared to traditional word of mouth. Second, users contribute content because they derive status-or image-based utility from being listened to by their peers. Third, we capture the role of social differentiation, or how social distance between people affects their preferences for messages. In the model, agents endogenously decide whether to be a sender of information and then compete for the attention of receivers. An important point of this paper is that social communication incentives diminish even as the reach or the span of communication increases. As the span of communication increases, competition between senders for receiver attention becomes more intense, resulting in senders competing with greater equilibrium messaging effort. This in turn leads to lower equilibrium payoffs and the entry of fewer senders. This result provides a strategic rationale for the so-called participation inequality phenomenon, which is a characteristic of many social media platforms. We also show that social differentiation may enhance or deter sender entry depending on whether it can be endogenously influenced by senders. Finally, we examine how the underlying network structure (in terms of its density and its degree distribution) affects communication and uncover a nonmonotonic pattern in that increased connectivity first increases and then reduces the entry of senders.</description><author>Iyer, Ganesh; Katona, Zsolt</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric Effects of Favorable and Unfavorable Information on Decision Making Under Ambiguity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peysakhovich, Alexander; Karmarkar, Uma R.
Most daily decisions involve uncertainty about outcome probabilities arising from incomplete knowledge, i.e., ambiguity. We explore how the addition of partial information affects these types of choices using theoretical and empirical methods. Our experiments in both gain and loss domains demonstrate that when such information supports a favorable outcome, it strongly increases valuation of an ambiguous financial prospect. However, when information supports an unfavorable outcome, it has significantly less impact. We find that two mechanisms drive this asymmetry. First, unfavorable information decreases estimates of a good outcome occurring but also reduces aversive uncertainty. These factors act in opposition, minimizing the effects of unfavorable information. Second, when information can be subjectively interpreted, unfavorable information is less likely to be integrated into evaluations. Our findings reveal mechanisms not captured by traditional models of decision making under uncertainty and highlight the importance of increasing the salience of unfavorable information in uncertain contexts to promote unbiased decision making.</description><author>Peysakhovich, Alexander; Karmarkar, Uma R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Sum and Its Parts: Judgmental Hierarchical Forecasting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kremer, Mirko; Siemsen, Enno; Thomas, Douglas J.
Firms require demand forecasts at different levels of aggregation to support a variety of resource allocation decisions. For example, a retailer needs store-level forecasts to manage inventory at the store, but also requires a regionally aggregated forecast for managing inventory at a distribution center. In generating an aggregate forecast, a firm can choose to make the forecast directly based on the aggregated data or indirectly by summing lower-level forecasts (i.e., bottom up). Our study investigates the relative performance of such hierarchical forecasting processes through a behavioral lens. We identify two judgment biases that affect the relative performance of direct and indirect forecasting approaches: a propensity for random judgment errors and a failure to benefit from the informational value that is embedded in the correlation structure between lower-level demands. Based on these biases, we characterize demand environments where one hierarchical process results in more accurate forecasts than the other.</description><author>Kremer, Mirko; Siemsen, Enno; Thomas, Douglas J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is IT Enough? Evidence from a Natural Experiment in India's Agriculture Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parker, Chris; Ramdas, Kamalini; Savva, Nicos
Access to information and communication technologies (ICTs) such as mobile phone networks is widely known to improve market efficiency. In this paper, we examine whether access to timely and accurate information provided through ICT applications has any additional impact. Using a detailed data set from Reuters Market Light (RML), a text message service in India that provides daily price information to market participants, we find that this information reduces the geographic price dispersion of crops in rural communities by an average of 12%, over and above access to mobile phone technology and other means of communication. To identify the effect of information on price dispersion, we exploit a natural experiment where bulk text messages were banned unexpectedly across India for 12 days in 2010. We find that besides reducing geographic price dispersion, RML also increases the rate at which prices converge across India over time. We discuss the implications of this for development organizations and information providers.</description><author>Parker, Chris; Ramdas, Kamalini; Savva, Nicos</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Financial Implications of Supply Chain Changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Houston, Joel F.; Lin, Chen; Zhu, Zhongyan
We examine how a firm's bankruptcy affects the bank financing costs of its key suppliers. We do so by using an extensive, hand-collected data set that captures the supply chain relationships of bankrupt firms over the time period 1990-2009. Looking at a sample of more than 2,000 loan contracts, we compare the average borrowing cost of suppliers in the two years prior to the bankruptcy of a key customer to the average cost in the two years following the announced bankruptcy. We find the average loan spreads increase by roughly 20% following the customer's announced bankruptcy. These effects are even stronger if the bankrupt firm is operating within a distressed industry or when there is a strong supplier-customer relationship. We also find that the structure of lending agreements significantly changes in the aftermath of a client bankruptcy. More specifically, we find that the number of covenants increases and the lead banker(s) take an increasingly important role in the period following the client's bankruptcy. Taken together, the results of this study provide new insights into the financial implications of supply chain changes.</description><author>Houston, Joel F.; Lin, Chen; Zhu, Zhongyan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Design and Moral Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kirchler, Michael; Huber, Juergen; Stefan, Matthias; Sutter, Matthias
In an experiment with 739 subjects, we study whether and how different interventions might have an influence on the degree of moral behavior when subjects make decisions that can generate negative externalities on uninvolved parties. Particularly, subjects can either take money for themselves or donate it to UNICEF for measles vaccines. By considering two fairly different institutional regimes-one with individual decision making, one with a double-auction market-we expose the different interventions to a kind of robustness check. We find that the threat of monetary punishment promotes moral behavior in both regimes. Getting subjects more involved with the traded good has no effect, though, in both regimes. Only the removal of anonymity, thus making subjects identifiable, has different effects across regimes, which we explain by different perceptions of responsibility.</description><author>Kirchler, Michael; Huber, Juergen; Stefan, Matthias; Sutter, Matthias</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When 3+1 &gt; 4: Gift Structure and Reciprocity in the Field</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilchrist, Duncan S.; Luca, Michael; Malhotra, Deepak
Do higher wages elicit reciprocity and lead to increased productivity? In a field experiment with 266 employees, we find that paying higher wages, per se, does not have a discernible effect on productivity in a context with no future employment opportunities. However, structuring a portion of the wage as a clear and unexpected gift-by offering an unconditional raise after the employee has accepted the contract-leads to higher productivity for the duration of the job. Gifts are roughly as efficient as hiring more workers.</description><author>Gilchrist, Duncan S.; Luca, Michael; Malhotra, Deepak</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Behavior-Based Pricing: An Analysis of the Impact of Peer-Induced Fairness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Krista J.; Jain, Sanjay
Firms tracking consumer purchase information often use behavior-based pricing (BBP), i.e., price discriminate between consumers based on preferences revealed from purchase histories. However, behavioral research has shown that such pricing practices can lead to perceptions of unfairness when consumers are charged a higher price than other consumers for the same product. This paper studies the impact of consumers' fairness concerns on firms' behavior-based pricing strategy, profits, consumer surplus, and social welfare. Prior research shows that BBP often yields lower profits than profits without customer recognition or behavior-based price discrimination. By contrast, we find that firms' profits from conducting BBP increase with consumers' fairness concerns. When fairness concerns are sufficiently strong, practicing BBP is more profitable than without customer recognition. However, consumers' fairness concerns decrease consumer surplus. In addition, when consumers' fairness concerns are sufficiently strong, they reduce inefficient switching and improve social welfare.</description><author>Li, Krista J.; Jain, Sanjay</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Opening Up Intellectual Property Strategy: Implications for Open Source Software Entry by Start-up Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wen, Wen; Ceccagnoli, Marco; Forman, Chris
We examine whether a firm's intellectual property (IP) strategy in support of the open source software (OSS) community stimulates new OSS product entry by start-up software firms. In particular, we analyze the impact of strategic decisions taken by IBM around the mid-2000s, such as its announcement that it will not assert its patents against the OSS community and its creation of a patent commons. These decisions formed a coherent IP strategy in support of OSS. We find that IBM's actions stimulated new OSS product introductions by entrepreneurial firms and that their impact is increasing in the cumulativeness of innovation in the market and the extent to which patent ownership in the market is concentrated.</description><author>Wen, Wen; Ceccagnoli, Marco; Forman, Chris</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uncommon Value: The Characteristics and Investment Performance of Contrarian Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wei, Kelsey D.; Wermers, Russ; Yao, Tong
Motivated by extant theories of herding behavior, this paper empirically identifies contrarian mutual funds as those trading most frequently against the crowd. We find that contrarian funds generate superior performance both when they trade against and with the herd, indicating that they possess superior private information. Furthermore, contrarians do not trade in a particularly correlated fashion with each other, consistent with these funds having disparate information. Our fund-level contrarian measure is largely unrelated to existing measures of fund strategy uniqueness, as both contrarian and herding funds score highly on such measures. Building on our finding of superior alphas for contrarian funds, we construct a stock-level contrarian score that reflects the aggregate stock selection information possessed by contrarian managers. This stock-level contrarian score significantly predicts stock returns after controlling for measures of stock-level herding, as well as a battery of return-predictive investment signals documented in prior studies.</description><author>Wei, Kelsey D.; Wermers, Russ; Yao, Tong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading as Gambling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dorn, Anne Jones; Dorn, Daniel; Sengmueller, Paul
This paper offers evidence from three different samples consistent with investors substituting between playing the lottery and gambling in financial markets. In the United States, increases in the jackpots of the multistate lotteries Powerball and Mega Millions are associated with significant reductions in small trade participation in the stock market. California-based discount brokerage clients and German discount brokerage clients are significantly less likely to trade during weeks with larger lottery prizes in the California and German lotteries, respectively. Variation in lottery prizes affects speculative trading in more lottery-like securities such as individual stocks and options, but not trading in bonds and mutual funds. Trading that is likely associated with long-term savings motives, such as trading in retirement accounts, does not respond to lottery jackpots, either. The negative relation between trading activity and jackpots is stronger for individuals who are more likely to play the lottery.</description><author>Dorn, Anne Jones; Dorn, Daniel; Sengmueller, Paul</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Private Money Buy Public Science? Disease Group Lobbying and Federal Funding for Biomedical Research</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hegde, Deepak; Sampat, Bhaven
Private interest groups lobby politicians to influence public policy. However, little is known about how lobbying influences the policy decisions made by federal agencies. We study this through examining lobbying by advocacy groups associated with rare diseases for funding by the National Institutes of Health (NIH), the world's largest funder of biomedical research. Disease group lobbying for NIH funding has been controversial, with critics alleging that it distorts public funding toward research on diseases backed by powerful groups. Our data reveal that lobbying is associated with higher political support, in the form of congressional "soft earmarks" for the diseases. Lobbying increases with disease burden and is more likely to be associated with changes in NIH funding for diseases with higher scientific opportunity, suggesting that it may have a useful informational role. Only special grant mechanisms that steer funding toward particular diseases, which comprise less than a third of the NIH's grants, are related to earmarks. Thus, our results suggest that lobbying by private groups influences federal funding for biomedical research. However, the channels of political influence are subtle, affect a small portion of funding, and may not necessarily have a distortive effect on public science.</description><author>Hegde, Deepak; Sampat, Bhaven</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of Funds of Hedge Funds: Evidence from Their Holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aiken, Adam L.; Clifford, Christopher P.; Ellis, Jesse
We examine the portfolio holdings of funds of hedge funds (FoFs) to identify the channels through which FoFs add value for their clients. FoFs offer access to a diversified portfolio of funds that would be costly for constrained investors to manage on their own. Although we find only limited evidence that FoFs exhibit skill when selecting hedge funds, we find strong evidence that FoFs make skillful termination decisions. After FoFs divest from a hedge fund, those hedge funds subsequently underperform and fail more often. Our evidence indicates that FoFs learn and skillfully process information about their portfolio funds after they become investors, enabling them to forecast poor future performance. Our study suggests that FoFs serve an important role as intermediaries in a market characterized by significant frictions and transactions costs.</description><author>Aiken, Adam L.; Clifford, Christopher P.; Ellis, Jesse</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Stock Analysts Influence Merger Completion? An Examination of Postmerger Announcement Recommendations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becher, David A.; Cohn, Jonathan B.; Juergens, Jennifer L.
This paper investigates the effects of analyst recommendations issued after a merger announcement on deal completion. We find the probability of completion increases (decreases) with the favorability of acquirer (target) recommendations. Results from instrumental variables tests support causality running from recommendations to merger outcomes. Additional tests suggest that these relations are driven by target shareholders reassessing the merger offer in response to movements in acquirer and target valuations. We also find that favorably recommended firms in a proposed merger underperform following deal resolution, suggesting that investors overreact to postmerger announcement recommendations.</description><author>Becher, David A.; Cohn, Jonathan B.; Juergens, Jennifer L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Peers and Network Growth: Evidence from a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hasan, Sharique; Bagde, Surendrakumar
Much research suggests that social networks affect individual and organizational success. However, a strong assumption underlying this research is that network structure is not reducible to the individual attributes of social actors. In this article, we test this assumption by examining whether interacting with random peers causes exogenous growth of a person's network. Using three years of network data for students at an Indian college, we evaluate the effect of peers on network growth. We find strong evidence that interacting with random, but well-connected, roommates causes significant growth of a focal student's network. Further, we find that this growth also implies an increase in how close an actor moves to a network's center and whether that actor is likely to serve as a network bridge. Fundamentally, our results demonstrate that exogenous factors beyond individual agency-i. e., random peers-can shape network structure. Our results also provide a useful model for causally identifying the determinants of network structure and dynamics.</description><author>Hasan, Sharique; Bagde, Surendrakumar</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dynamic Impact of Product-Harm Crises on Brand Preference and Advertising Effectiveness: An Empirical Analysis of the Automobile Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Yan; Shankar, Venkatesh
Product-harm crises (recalls) carry negative product information that adversely affects brand preference and advertising effectiveness. This negative impact of product-harm crises may differ across recall events depending on media coverage of the event, crisis severity, and consumers' prior beliefs about product quality. We develop a state space model to capture the dynamics in brand preference, advertising effectiveness, and consumer response to product recalls; integrate it with a random coefficient demand model; and estimate it using a unique data set containing 35 automobile brands, 193 auto sub-brands, and 359 recalls during 1997-2002. Our results reveal that consumers respond more negatively to product recalls with greater media attention, more severe consequences, and higher perceived product quality. Furthermore, they show that sub-brand advertising effectiveness declines by a greater amount than parent-brand advertising and the decline in effectiveness of the recalled sub-brand's advertising spills over to other sub-brands under the same parent brand.</description><author>Liu, Yan; Shankar, Venkatesh</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Correcting for Misspecification in Parameter Dynamics to Improve Forecast Accuracy with Adaptively Estimated Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kolsarici, Ceren; Vakratsas, Demetrios
Adaptive estimation methods have become a popular tool for capturing and forecasting changing conditions in dynamic environments. Although adaptive models can provide superior one-step-ahead forecasts, their application to multiperiod forecasting is challenging when the underlying parameter variation process is not correctly specified. The authors propose a methodology based on the Chebyshev approximation method (CAM), which provides a parsimonious substitute for the measurement updating process in the forecasting period, to help forecasters improve multiperiod accuracy in the case of parameter variation misspecification. In two empirical applications concerning the sales growth of new brands, CAM exhibits superior forecasting performance compared to a variety of benchmarks. CAM's properties are further explored through extensive simulations, which suggest that the proposed method is more likely to increase forecast accuracy when parameter variation is more systematic but misspecified because of uncertainty regarding its exact functional form.</description><author>Kolsarici, Ceren; Vakratsas, Demetrios</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Increasing Quality Sequence: When Is It an Optimal Product Introduction Strategy?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pedram, Mahmood; Balachander, Subramanian
In this paper, we analyze the optimal introduction timing of a seller's products targeted at segments that differ in their willingness to pay for quality. Past studies suggest that an introduction sequence of a high-quality product followed by a lower-quality version of the product may mitigate the cannibalization effects of the low-quality product on profits from the high-quality product. We show that if customers who value quality more possess an outside option such as a substitute product, as may be the case with replacement buyers, a seller may find it optimal to follow a low-quality product with a higher-quality one, the latter being targeted at replacement buyers. Furthermore, the ability of the seller to commit to future qualities accentuates the sequential increase in quality in the presence of such buyers. Thus, we show that conditions other than uncertainty or technological improvements occurring over time may justify a seller adopting a strategy of sequentially increasing quality.</description><author>Pedram, Mahmood; Balachander, Subramanian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bias Blind Spot: Structure, Measurement, and Consequences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Scopelliti, Irene; Morewedge, Carey K.; McCormick, Erin; Min, H. Lauren; Lebrecht, Sophie; Kassam, Karim S.
People exhibit a bias blind spot: they are less likely to detect bias in themselves than in others. We report the development and validation of an instrument to measure individual differences in the propensity to exhibit the bias blind spot that is unidimensional, internally consistent, has high test-retest reliability, and is discriminated from measures of intelligence, decision-making ability, and personality traits related to self-esteem, self-enhancement, and self-presentation. The scale is predictive of the extent to which people judge their abilities to be better than average for easy tasks and worse than average for difficult tasks, ignore the advice of others, and are responsive to an intervention designed to mitigate a different judgmental bias. These results suggest that the bias blind spot is a distinct metabias resulting from naive realism rather than other forms of egocentric cognition, and has unique effects on judgment and behavior.</description><author>Scopelliti, Irene; Morewedge, Carey K.; McCormick, Erin; Min, H. Lauren; Lebrecht, Sophie; Kassam, Karim S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Goal Setting and Monetary Incentives: When Large Stakes Are Not Enough</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corgnet, Brice; Gomez-Minambres, Joaquin; Hernan-Gonzalez, Roberto
The aim of this paper is to test the effectiveness of wage-irrelevant goal-setting policies in a laboratory environment. In our design, managers can assign a goal to their workers by setting a certain level of performance on the work task. We establish our theoretical conjectures by developing a model in which assigned goals act as reference points to workers' intrinsic motivation. Consistent with our model, we find that managers set goals that are challenging but attainable for a worker of average ability. Workers respond to these goals by increasing effort and performance and by decreasing on-the-job leisure activities with respect to the no-goal-setting baseline. Finally, we study the interaction between goal setting and monetary rewards and find, in line with our theoretical model, that goal setting is most effective when monetary incentives are strong. These results suggest that goal setting may produce intrinsic motivation and increase workers' performance beyond what is achieved by using solely monetary incentives.</description><author>Corgnet, Brice; Gomez-Minambres, Joaquin; Hernan-Gonzalez, Roberto</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political Values, Culture, and Corporate Litigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hutton, Irena; Jiang, Danling; Kumar, Alok
Using one of the largest samples of litigation data available to date, we examine whether the political culture of a firm determines its propensity for corporate misconduct. We measure political culture using the political contributions of top managers, firm political action committees, and local residents. We show that firms with a Republican culture are more likely to be the subject of civil rights, labor, and environmental litigation than are Democratic firms, consistent with the Democratic ideology that emphasizes equal rights, labor rights, and environmental protection. However, firms with a Democratic culture are more likely to be the subject of litigation related to securities fraud and intellectual property rights violations than are Republican firms, whose party ideology stresses self-reliance, property rights, market discipline, and limited government regulation. Upon litigation filing, both types of firms experience similar announcement reaction, which suggests that the observed relationship between political culture and corporate misconduct is unlikely to reflect differences in expected litigation costs.</description><author>Hutton, Irena; Jiang, Danling; Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging with Futures: Does Anything Beat the Naive Hedging Strategy?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Yudong; Wu, Chongfeng; Yang, Li
This paper investigates out-of-sample performance of the naive hedging strategy relative to that of the minimum variance hedging strategy, in which the covariance parameters are estimated from 18 econometric models. Hedging performance is compared across 24 futures markets. Our main findings suggest that it is difficult to find a strategy under the minimum variance framework that outperforms the naive hedging strategy both consistently and significantly. Our findings are robust to different sample periods, estimation windows, and hedging horizons and can be partly explained by the effects of estimation error and model misspecification.</description><author>Wang, Yudong; Wu, Chongfeng; Yang, Li</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Privacy and Marketing Externalities: Evidence from Do Not Call</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goh, Khim-Yong; Hui, Kai-Lung; Png, Ivan P. L.
If not well targeted, advertising and direct marketing inflict nuisance and inconvenience on consumers. Theoretical analyses predict that consumer actions to avoid advertising impose externalities on other consumers. We investigate the extent of such externalities in the context of the U.S. Do Not Call (DNC) registry by exploiting the exogenous timing of the enforcement of the registry. Supported by multiple robustness tests, and validation and falsification exercises, we conclude that consumer DNC registrations imposed externalities on other consumers. An increase in the first wave of registrations by 1% was associated with a 3.1% increase in subsequent registrations. This effect was stronger in larger and more educationally or racially heterogeneous markets. The externality was possibly due to unregistered consumers being more receptive to telemarketing and telemarketers increasing calls to them. Our results suggest that managers should facilitate consumer opt-out, especially in larger and more educationally or racially heterogeneous markets.</description><author>Goh, Khim-Yong; Hui, Kai-Lung; Png, Ivan P. L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Social Interaction on Economic Transactions: Evidence from Changes in Two Retail Formats</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldfarb, Avi; McDevitt, Ryan C.; Samila, Sampsa; Silverman, Brian S.
Examining changes in two different retail formats, we show that consumers alter their purchases depending on the retail environment. In both settings, the change in behavior coincides with a reduction in the interpersonal interaction required to complete a transaction. As such, we contend that the format changes reduced a "social friction" that would otherwise inhibit consumers due to an implicit cost associated with ordering certain items in social settings.</description><author>Goldfarb, Avi; McDevitt, Ryan C.; Samila, Sampsa; Silverman, Brian S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Should Firms Expose Themselves to Risk?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexandrov, Alexei
I analyze a firm making a decision whether to expose itself to risk in an exogenous parameter when the firm can change a choice variable after observing the realization of the exogenous parameter. For example, the firm decides whether to choose an advertising campaign with a less certain outcome (conditional on the same expected outcome) when it can adjust the product's price after seeing the effects of the campaign. I show that in many cases, the firm wants to expose itself to risk, and I outline general conditions that need to be satisfied for this result. I then analyze the strategic version of this setup with two competing firms, provide a general characterization, and show that in many cases both firms want to expose themselves to risk, as long as the risks are not too positively correlated. This is the case for many linear demand and constant marginal cost settings (monopolies, differentiated Bertrand firms, or differentiated Cournot firms selling substitutes) where the exogenous parameter is a demand, or a marginal cost shifter results in the monopoly (or both of the competitors if the risks are not too positively correlated) voluntarily exposing itself to risk.</description><author>Alexandrov, Alexei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prospect Theory Explains Newsvendor Behavior: The Role of Reference Points</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Long, Xiaoyang; Nasiry, Javad
Current understanding in operations management is that prospect theory, as a theory of decision making under uncertainty, cannot systematically explain the ordering behavior observed in experiments on the newsvendor problem. We suggest this is because the newsvendor's reference point is assumed to be the status quo, i.e., zero payoff. We propose an alternative based on newsvendor's salient payoffs and show that prospect theory can, in fact, account for experimental results.</description><author>Long, Xiaoyang; Nasiry, Javad</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Valuation of Delinquent Credit-Card Accounts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chehrazi, Naveed; Weber, Thomas A.
This paper introduces a dynamic model of the stochastic repayment behavior exhibited by delinquent creditcard accounts. Based on this model, we construct a dynamic collectability score (DCS) that estimates the account-specific probability of collecting a given portion of the outstanding debt over any given time horizon. The model integrates a variety of information sources, including historical repayment data, account-specific, and time-varying macroeconomic covariates, as well as scheduled account-treatment actions. Two model-identification methods are examined, based on maximum-likelihood estimation and the generalized method of moments. The latter allows for an operational-statistics approach, combining model estimation and performance optimization by tailoring the estimation error to business-relevant loss functions. The DCS framework is applied to a large set of account-level repayment data. The improvements in classification and prediction performance compared to standard bank-internal scoring methods are found to be significant.</description><author>Chehrazi, Naveed; Weber, Thomas A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relaxations of Approximate Linear Programs for the Real Option Management of Commodity Storage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nadarajah, Selvaprabu; Margot, Francois; Secomandi, Nicola
The real option management of commodity conversion assets gives rise to intractable Markov decision processes (MDPs), in part because of the use of high-dimensional models of commodity forward curve evolution, as commonly done in practice. Focusing on commodity storage, we identify a deficiency of approximate linear programming (ALP), which we address by developing a novel approach to derive relaxations of approximate linear programs. We apply our approach to obtain a class of tractable ALP relaxations, also subsuming an existing method. We provide theoretical support for the use of these ALP relaxations rather than their associated approximate linear programs. Applied to existing natural gas storage instances, our ALP relaxations significantly outperform their corresponding approximate linear programs. Our best ALP relaxation is both near optimal and competitive with, albeit slower than, state-of-the-art methods for computing heuristic policies and lower bounds on the value of commodity storage, but is more directly applicable for dual (upper) bound estimation than these methods. Our approach is potentially relevant for the approximate solution of MDPs that arise in the real option management of other commodity conversion assets, as well as the valuation of real and financial options that depend on forward curve dynamics.</description><author>Nadarajah, Selvaprabu; Margot, Francois; Secomandi, Nicola</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Supply Management in Multiproduct Firms with Fixed Proportions Technology</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyabatli, Onur
This paper studies the supply management of a primary input, where this input gives rise to multiple products in fixed proportions. My objective is twofold. First, I study fixed proportions technology under demand uncertainty in comparison with the flexible and dedicated technologies. I show that fixed proportions technology has a cost-pooling value over dedicated technology, which is larger than the capacity-pooling value of flexible technology over dedicated technology. I identify the critical role that demand correlation plays with the fixed proportions technology: in contrast to the capacity-pooling value, which decreases in demand correlation, the cost-pooling value increases in demand correlation. Second, focusing on the fixed proportions technology, I study supply management in the presence of contract and spot markets. I investigate how the optimal supply management strategy should respond to changing market uncertainties, and the differences in this response based on the contract type. I find that when the exercise price of the contract is high, a higher contract market dependence is the best response to the increasing demand correlation or spot price variability. However, a lower contract market dependence is the best response to the same when the exercise price is low. Managerially, these results are important because they imply that the supply management strategy adopted as a response to a change in the business environment should differ depending on the contract type. My results have implications about the new product strategy and the procurement contract choice of the processors in the agricultural industries.</description><author>Boyabatli, Onur</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Colocation Still Matters: Conformance Quality and the Interdependence of R&amp;D and Manufacturing in the Pharmaceutical Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gray, John V.; Siemsen, Enno; Vasudeva, Gurneeta
This study investigates the conformance quality benefits of colocating manufacturing with research and development (R&amp;D) activities. Findings from a panel data set of U.S.-based pharmaceutical plants over a 13-year period reveal that colocation of manufacturing and R&amp;D relates to better conformance quality, on average, across the entire sample. We find that these benefits of colocation persist throughout the time period we study (1994-2007), which is surprising, given the rapid development of information and communication technologies during that time. These benefits are particularly enhanced for manufacturing plants operating with processes that involve a high level of tacit process knowledge and that belong to large firms. Our findings highlight the importance of matching organizational design with process and firm characteristics in settings involving knowledge interdependence. They also highlight the continued value of physical proximity through geographical colocation between manufacturing and R&amp;D activities to achieve desired quality outcomes.</description><author>Gray, John V.; Siemsen, Enno; Vasudeva, Gurneeta</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance Information, Production Uncertainty, and Subjective Entitlements in Bargaining</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karagozoglu, Emin; Riedl, Arno
We experimentally explore the effect of performance information and production uncertainties on (i) subjective entitlements derived from the production process and (ii) bargaining over the jointly produced surplus. We hypothesize that performance information and details of the production process affect entitlements, which in turn influence bargaining behavior. We find that, without performance information, subjective entitlements are mostly mutually consistent, and bargaining mainly ends with an equal split. In stark contrast, negotiators derive strong, mutually inconsistent, subjective entitlements when there is performance information. These subjective entitlements affect opening proposals, concessions, and bargaining duration and lead to asymmetric agreements. Moreover, given performance information, endogenous variations in entitlements influence bargaining, suggesting an independent role of subjective entitlements. Production uncertainties influence bargaining, especially when performance information is present, but do not substantially mitigate the effect of entitlements. Theoretical bargaining models allowing for reference points or fairness principles can partly account for the empirical results. Yet, important aspects are left unexplained and our results suggest ways for extending these models.</description><author>Karagozoglu, Emin; Riedl, Arno</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Noise Create the Size and Value Effects?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arnott, Robert D.; Hsu, Jason C.; Liu, Jun; Markowitz, Harry
If the price of a stock differs from its intrinsic value by a random noise, then value stocks are more likely to have negative noise; they are thus more likely undervalued and have higher expected return than justified by risk. The same intuition applies to small capitalization stocks. We formally verify and explore this intuition by using a standard noise-in-price model. This intuition is different from the Jensen's inequality effect studied by Blume and Stambaugh [Blume ME, Stambaugh RF (1983) Biases in computed returns: An application to the size effect. J. Financial Econom. 12(3):387-404]. Our model is parsimonious: the value premium as well as size premium are computed in closed form and depend on only four parameters: mean of stock return, volatility of stock return, volatility of the price-to-dividend ratio, and noise volatility. We emphasize that only a moderate volatility of price noise is needed to generate the observed value premium. However, the model cannot generate the observed size premium.</description><author>Arnott, Robert D.; Hsu, Jason C.; Liu, Jun; Markowitz, Harry</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expectations as Reference Points: Field Evidence from Professional Soccer</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartling, Bjoern; Brandes, Leif; Schunk, Daniel
We show that professional soccer players and their coaches exhibit reference-dependent behavior during matches. Controlling for the state of the match and for unobserved heterogeneity, we show on a minute-by-minute basis that players breach the rules of the game, measured by the referee's assignment of cards, significantly more often if their teams are behind the expected match outcome, measured by preplay betting odds of large professional bookmakers. We further show that coaches implement significantly more offensive substitutions if their teams are behind expectations. Both types of behaviors impair the expected ultimate match outcome of the team, which shows that our findings do not simply reflect fully rational responses to reference-dependent incentive schemes of favorite teams to falling behind. We derive these results in a data set that contains more than 8,200 matches from 12 seasons of the German Bundesliga and 12 seasons of the English Premier League.</description><author>Bartling, Bjoern; Brandes, Leif; Schunk, Daniel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Legitimacy, Communication, and Leadership in the Turnaround Game</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brandts, Jordi; Cooper, David J.; Weber, Roberto A.
We study the effectiveness of leaders for inducing coordinated organizational change to a more efficient equilibrium, i.e., a turnaround. We compare communication from leaders to incentive increases and also compare the effectiveness of randomly selected and elected leaders. Although all interventions yield shifts to more efficient equilibria, communication from leaders has a greater effect than incentives. Moreover, leaders who are elected by followers are significantly better at improving their group's outcome than randomly selected leaders. The improved effectiveness of elected leaders results from sending more performance-relevant messages. Our results are evidence that the way in which leaders are selected affects their legitimacy and the degree to which they influence followers. Finally, we observe that a combination of factors-specifically, incentive increases and communication from elected leaders-yields near-universal turnarounds to full efficiency.</description><author>Brandts, Jordi; Cooper, David J.; Weber, Roberto A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Interproduct Competition Model Incorporating Branding Hierarchy and Product Similarities Using Store-Level Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Voleti, Sudhir; Kopalle, Praveen K.; Ghosh, Pulak
We develop and implement a Bayesian semiparametric model of demand under interproduct competition that enables us to assess the respective contributions of brand-SKU (stock keeping unit) hierarchy and interproduct similarity to explaining and predicting demand. To incorporate brand-SKU hierarchy effects, we use Bayesian hierarchical clustering inherent in a nested Dirichlet process to simultaneously partition brands, and SKUs conditional on brands, into groups of "similarity clusters." We examine cluster memberships and postprocess the Markov chain Monte Carlo output to infer cluster properties by accounting for parameter uncertainty. Our proposed approach lends to a spatial competition interpretation in latent attribute space and helps uncover the extent to which competition across SKUs in the latent attribute space is local or global. In a related vein, we discuss the implications of well-defined groups of similar SKUs as subcategory or submarket boundaries in latent attribute space. We empirically test our model using aggregate beer category sales data from a midsize U.S. retail chain. We find that branding hierarchy effects dominate those from product similarity. We find that the model partitions the 15 brands in the data into 4 brand clusters and the 96 SKUs into 25 SKU clusters conditional on brand cluster membership. In estimating a set of models of spatial interproduct competition, we find that SKU competition is more local than global in that only subsets of products compete within groups of comparable products. Finally, we discuss the substantive implications of our results.</description><author>Voleti, Sudhir; Kopalle, Praveen K.; Ghosh, Pulak</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Standardization and the Effectiveness of Online Advertising</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldfarb, Avi; Tucker, Catherine E.
The technological transformation and automation of digital content delivery has revolutionized the media industry. Increased reliance on automation has also led to requirements for standardization of content-delivery formats. This paper examines how the memorability of banner advertising changed with the introduction of new standards regularizing its format. Using data from randomized field tests, we find evidence that for most ads, ad effectiveness falls as the use of standard formats rises. The decline is smaller when a standardized ad appears to be more original (such as ads created by an ad agency). Therefore, a likely explanation is that increased use of a standard format makes it harder for basic ads to distinguish themselves from their competition because the ad format commands less attention.</description><author>Goldfarb, Avi; Tucker, Catherine E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating Venture Technical Competence in Venture Capitalist Investment Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, Rohit; Kryscynski, David; Singh, Harpreet
Although much research emphasizes the importance of venture technical competence for venture success and, therefore, the importance of venture technical competence in venture capitalist (VC) investment decisions, we know little about why some VCs may be better than others at assessing the technical competence of ventures. We gathered unique and proprietary data from 33 VCs and 308 ventures that sought Series A funding from those VCs. We show that VC assessment of ventures predicts VC investment, and venture technical competence predicts subsequent venture failure. This means that VCs that overassess ventures are more likely to invest in firms that are more likely to fail. We then show that higher VC technical competence leads to lower errors in assessment, but that greater similarity between the VC and venture in technical competence leads to higher assessments, ceteris paribus. We thus conclude that VC competence enhances the accuracy of VC assessments, but similarity in technical competence between VCs and ventures may lead to positive assessment bias.</description><author>Aggarwal, Rohit; Kryscynski, David; Singh, Harpreet</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Effectiveness of Patenting Strategies in Innovation Races</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mihm, Juergen; Sting, Fabian J.; Wang, Tan
Which, if any, of a firm's inventions should it patent? Should it patent at all? Many companies engaged in an innovation race seek a patenting strategy that balances protection of their intellectual property against the knowledge spillovers resulting from disclosure requirements. Not much is known about factors that determine the patenting strategy best able to resolve this trade-off. Although scholars in various management, economics, and engineering disciplines have researched patents and patenting regimes, little work has addressed the normative issues that pertain to forming an appropriate firm-level patenting strategy. We develop an inventory of real-life patenting strategies and integrate them into a coherent framework. Our simulation model characterizes the optimal patenting choices for different environmental and firm-level contingencies while capturing the dynamics between competing firms. We identify the firm's research and development strategy as the most salient determinant of its optimal patenting strategy. Our research contributes to establishing a contingency theory of patenting strategies.</description><author>Mihm, Juergen; Sting, Fabian J.; Wang, Tan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aging and Financial Decision Making</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gamble, Keith Jacks; Boyle, Patricia A.; Yu, Lei; Bennett, David A.
This study examines how cognitive changes associated with aging impact the financial decision-making capability of older Americans. We find that a decrease in cognition is associated with a decrease in financial literacy. Decreases in episodic memory and visuospatial ability are associated with a decrease in numeracy, and a decrease in semantic memory is associated with a decrease in financial knowledge. A decrease in cognition also predicts a drop in self-confidence in general, but importantly, it is not associated with a drop in confidence in managing one's own finances. Participants experiencing decreases in cognition do show an increased likelihood of getting help with financial decisions; however, many participants experiencing significant drops in cognition still do not get help.</description><author>Gamble, Keith Jacks; Boyle, Patricia A.; Yu, Lei; Bennett, David A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing Investment: The Choice Between Bonds and Bank Loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morellec, Erwan; Valta, Philip; Zhdanov, Alexei
We build a model of investment and financing decisions to study the choice between bonds and bank loans in a firm's marginal financing decision and its effects on corporate investment. We show that firms with more growth options, with higher bargaining power in default, operating in more competitive product markets, or facing lower credit supply are more likely to issue bonds. We also demonstrate that, by changing the cost of financing, these characteristics affect the timing of investment. We test these predictions using a sample of U.S. firms and present new evidence that supports our theory.</description><author>Morellec, Erwan; Valta, Philip; Zhdanov, Alexei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Corporate Social Responsibility Lead to Superior Financial Performance? A Regression Discontinuity Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Flammer, Caroline
This study examines the effect of shareholder proposals related to corporate social responsibility (CSR) on financial performance. Specifically, I focus on CSR proposals that pass or fail by a small margin of votes. The passage of such "close call" proposals is akin to a random assignment of CSR to companies and hence provides a quasi-experiment to study the effect of CSR on performance. I find that the adoption of close call CSR proposals leads to positive announcement returns and superior accounting performance, implying that these proposals are value enhancing. When I examine the channels through which companies benefit from CSR, I find that labor productivity and sales growth increase after the vote. Finally, I document that close call CSR proposals differ from non-close proposals along several dimensions. Accordingly, although my results imply that adopting close call CSR proposals is beneficial to companies, they do not necessarily imply that CSR proposals are beneficial in general.</description><author>Flammer, Caroline</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Service Quality Variability and Termination Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sriram, S.; Chintagunta, Pradeep K.; Manchanda, Puneet
We investigate the roles of the level and variability in quality in driving customer retention for a new service. We present model-free evidence that whereas high average quality helps in retaining customers, high variability leads to higher termination rates. Apart from these main effects, we use model-free evidence to document the presence of (a) an interaction effect between average service quality and its variability on termination rates, (b) customer learning about service quality over time, and (c) a slower rate of learning among households that experience high variability. We postulate a mechanism involving risk aversion and learning, which can induce this interaction effect, and test this against several alternative explanations. We show that it is important to consider variability in quality while inferring the impact of improvements to average quality-ignoring the interaction effect between average quality and variability leads to an 18%-64% (5%-31%) overestimation (underestimation) of quality improvement elasticities among high-variability (low-variability) households. Given that responsiveness to quality decreases with variability, it is better for the firm to focus quality improvement efforts on customers experiencing low variability; increasing average quality by 1% lowers termination by 1.1% for low-variability households, but only by 0.41% for high-variability households.</description><author>Sriram, S.; Chintagunta, Pradeep K.; Manchanda, Puneet</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Sharing in Supply Chains: An Empirical and Theoretical Valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cui, Ruomeng; Allon, Gad; Bassamboo, Achal; Van Mieghem, Jan A.
We provide an empirical and theoretical assessment of the value of information sharing in a two-stage supply chain. The value of downstream sales information to the upstream firm stems from improving upstream order fulfillment forecast accuracy. Such an improvement can lead to lower safety stock and better service. Based on the data collected from a consumer packaged goods company, we empirically show that, if the company includes the downstream sales data to forecast orders, the improvement in the mean squared forecast error ranges from 7.1% to 81.1% across all studied products. Theoretical models in the literature, however, suggest that the value of information sharing should be zero for over half of our studied products. To reconcile the gap between the literature and the empirical observations, we develop a new theoretical model. Whereas the literature assumes that the decision maker strictly adheres to a given inventory policy, our model allows him to deviate, accounting for private information held by the decision maker, yet unobservable to the econometrician. This turns out to reconcile our empirical findings with the literature. These "decision deviations" lead to information losses in the order process, resulting in a strictly positive value of downstream information sharing. Furthermore, we empirically quantify and show the significance of the value of operations knowledge-the value of knowing the downstream replenishment policy.</description><author>Cui, Ruomeng; Allon, Gad; Bassamboo, Achal; Van Mieghem, Jan A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Propagation of Financial Shocks: The Case of Venture Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Townsend, Richard R.
This paper investigates how venture-backed companies are affected when others sharing the same investor suffer a negative shock. In theory, companies may be helped or hurt in this scenario. To examine the topic empirically, I estimate the impact of the collapse of the technology bubble on non-information-technology (non-IT) companies that were held alongside IInternet companies in venture portfolios. Using a difference-indifferences framework, I find that the end of the bubble was associated with a significantly larger decline in the probability of raising continuation financing for these non-IT companies in comparison to others. This does not appear to be driven by unobservable company characteristics such as company quality or IT relatedness; for the same portfolio company receiving capital from multiple venture firms, investors with greater Internet exposure were significantly less likely to continue to participate in follow-on rounds.</description><author>Townsend, Richard R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Diseconomies of Queue Pooling: An Empirical Investigation of Emergency Department Length of Stay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Song, Hummy; Tucker, Anita L.; Murrell, Karen L.
We conduct an empirical investigation of the impact of queue management on patients' average wait time and length of stay (LOS). Using an emergency department's (ED) patient-level data from 2007 to 2010, we find that patients' average wait time and LOS are longer when physicians are assigned patients under a pooled queuing system with a fairness constraint compared to a dedicated queuing system with the same fairness constraint. Using a difference-in-differences approach, we find the dedicated queuing system is associated with a 17% decrease in average LOS and a 9% decrease in average wait time relative to the control group-a 39-minute reduction in LOS and a four-minute reduction in wait time for an average patient of medium severity in this ED. Interviews and observations of physicians suggest that the improved performance stems from the physicians' increased ownership over patients and resources that is afforded by a dedicated queuing system, which enables physicians to more actively manage the flow of patients into and out of ED beds. Our findings suggest that the benefits from improved flow management in a dedicated queuing system can be large enough to overcome the longer wait time predicted to arise from nonpooled queues. We conduct additional analyses to rule out alternate explanations for the reduced average wait time and LOS in the dedicated system, such as stinting and decreased quality of care. Our paper has implications for healthcare organizations and others seeking to reduce patient wait time and LOS without increasing costs.</description><author>Song, Hummy; Tucker, Anita L.; Murrell, Karen L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entry and Subcontracting in Public Procurement Auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Branzoli, Nicola; Decarolis, Francesco
We empirically study how the interplay between entry and subcontracting choices is affected by the use of different auction formats in public procurement. The difference-in-differences strategy used exploits a data set of auctions for public works run alternately under first price and average bid auctions. We find that the use of first price auctions causes a marked decline in both entry and subcontracting. We also find that the type of firms entering first price auctions changes with firms becoming more likely to bid jointly with other firms in ad hoc joint ventures.</description><author>Branzoli, Nicola; Decarolis, Francesco</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge Funds and Stock Market Efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kokkonen, Joni; Suominen, Matti
We measure misvaluation using the discounted residual income model. As shown in the literature, this measure of stocks' misvaluation significantly explains their future cross-sectional returns. We measure the market-level misvaluation (market inefficiency) by the misvaluation spread: the difference in the misvaluation of the most overvalued and undervalued shares. We show that the misvaluation spread is a strong predictor of a misvaluation-based long-short portfolio's returns, reinforcing the hypothesis that it proxies for the level of mispricing in the stock market. Using data on hedge fund returns, hedge fund industry assets under management, flows, and individual hedge fund holdings, we present evidence that hedge funds' trading reduces market-level misvaluation. Our results are robust across different time periods and are not driven by market liquidity. Moreover, we find that mutual funds do not have the price-correcting effect that hedge funds have.</description><author>Kokkonen, Joni; Suominen, Matti</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which Skills Matter in the Market for CEOs? Evidence from Pay for CEO Credentials</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Falato, Antonio; Li, Dan; Milbourn, Todd
Market-based theories predict that differences in CEO skills lead to potentially large differences in pay, but it is challenging to quantify the CEO skill premium in pay. In a first step toward overcoming this empirical challenge, we code detailed biographical information for a large sample of CEOs for a panel of S&amp;P 1500 firms between 1993 and 2005 to identify specific reputational, career, and educational credentials that are indicative of skills. Newly appointed CEOs earn up to a 5% or $280,000 total pay premium per credential decile, which is concentrated among CEOs with better reputational and career credentials, those with the very best credentials, and those who run large firms. Consistent with the unique economic mechanism of market-based theories, CEO credentials have a positive impact on firm performance. The performance differential for newly appointed CEOs is up to 0.5% per credential decile and is also concentrated among CEOs with better reputational and career credentials and those at large firms. Credentials are positively correlated with unobserved CEO heterogeneity in pay and performance, which further validates our hypothesis that boards use them as publicly observable signals of otherwise hard-to-gauge CEO skills. In all, our results offer direct evidence in support of market-based explanations of the overall rise in CEO pay.</description><author>Falato, Antonio; Li, Dan; Milbourn, Todd</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Structural Model of Employee Behavioral Dynamics in Enterprise Social Media</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Yan; Singh, Param Vir; Ghose, Anindya
We develop and estimate a dynamic structural framework to analyze the social-media content creation and consumption behavior of employees within an enterprise. We focus, in particular, on employees' blogging behavior. The model incorporates two key features that are ubiquitous in blogging forums: users face (1) a trade-off between blog posting and blog reading; and (2) a trade-off between work-related and leisure-related content. We apply the model to a unique data set comprising the complete details of the blog posting and reading behavior of employees over a 15-month period at a Fortune 1000 IT services and consulting firm. Despite getting a higher utility from work-related blogging, employees nevertheless publish a significant number of leisure posts. This is partially because the creation of leisure posts has a significant positive spillover effect on the readership of work posts. Counterfactual experiments demonstrate that leisure-related blogging has positive spillovers for work-related blogging, and hence a policy of abolishing leisure-related content creation can inadvertently have adverse consequences on work-related content creation in an enterprise setting. When organizations restrict leisure blogging, the sharing of online work-related knowledge decreases and this in turn can also reduce employee performance rating. Overall, blogging within enterprises by employees during their work day can have positive long-term benefits for organizations.</description><author>Huang, Yan; Singh, Param Vir; Ghose, Anindya</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interdiction Games on Markovian PERT Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gutin, Eli; Kuhn, Daniel; Wiesemann, Wolfram
In a stochastic interdiction game a proliferator aims to minimize the expected duration of a nuclear weapons development project, and an interdictor endeavors to maximize the project duration by delaying some of the project tasks. We formulate static and dynamic versions of the interdictor's decision problem where the interdiction plan is either precommitted or adapts to new information revealed over time, respectively. The static model gives rise to a stochastic program, whereas the dynamic model is formalized as a multiple optimal stopping problem in continuous time and with decision-dependent information. Under a memoryless probabilistic model for the task durations, we prove that the static model reduces to a mixed-integer linear program, whereas the dynamic model reduces to a finite Markov decision process in discrete time that can be solved via efficient value iteration. We then generalize the dynamic model to account for uncertainty in the outcomes of the interdiction actions. We also discuss a crashing game where the proliferator can use limited resources to expedite tasks so as to counterbalance the interdictor's efforts. The resulting problem can be formulated as a robust Markov decision process.</description><author>Gutin, Eli; Kuhn, Daniel; Wiesemann, Wolfram</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Digital Content Provision and Optimal Copyright Protection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, Liang; Meng, Xiangyi
Advances in digital technologies have led to an increasing concern about piracy for providers of digital content (e.g., e-books, games, music, software, videos). Yet controversies exist over the influence of copyright protection on firm profitability. The objective of this paper is to provide an alternative rationale for the growing anti-protection trend and to investigate optimal copyright enforcement and quality provision in a monopoly setting. The proposed economic mechanism centers on the influence of copyright protection on consumer search when consumers can get to know the firm's actions (e.g., price, quality) only after costly search. We show that more stringent copyright protection can induce the consumers to rationally expect lower ex post surplus, thus exerting a negative strategic effect on the consumers' willingness to search. This strategic effect may outweigh the positive main effect on the relative attractiveness of the authorized versus the pirated product, which can hence explain the optimality of incomplete and even zero copyright protection policies in markets where consumer prepurchase search is important (e.g., information goods, digital products). It is also because of this strategic effect that the firm may provide lower quality as copyright enforcement increases. Interestingly, quality unobservability can moderate this strategic effect and thus lead to an increasing incentive for copyright protection.</description><author>Guo, Liang; Meng, Xiangyi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aggregate Impact of Different Brand Development Strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hariharan, Vijay Ganesh; Bezawada, Ram; Talukdar, Debabrata
Current branding literature investigates the spillover effects and extension effects due to the introduction of product extensions. However, no study so far has evaluated the aggregate market impact of these effects across different brand development strategies or accounted for the strategic decision to introduce the extension. It is important to examine the above given the significant investments and the high failure rates associated with the introduction of new product extensions. In this study, we develop an analytical framework that derives revenue outcome due to an extension introduction as a function of spillover and extension effects. We empirically estimate the above effects through a Bayesian endogenous switching model that jointly models market shares of the extension and its parent brand along with the strategic decision to introduce the extension and the endogeneity in prices. By using a data set that covers 155 extensions introduced across 20 U.S. geographic markets, we obtain several new generalizable empirical insights. Our results show that spillover effects are higher for brand extensions, whereas line extensions benefit through larger extension effects. We find that vertically differentiating a line extension in terms of increased quality mitigates its negative spillover effects. The addition of a new brand name (i.e., sub-branding) lowers spillover effects for line extensions, whereas it increases the market performance for brand extensions. Our findings provide several strategic implications for manufacturers to successfully introduce and manage product extensions.</description><author>Hariharan, Vijay Ganesh; Bezawada, Ram; Talukdar, Debabrata</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bang for the Buck: Gain-Loss Ratio as a Driver of Judgment and Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Langhe, Bart; Puntoni, Stefano
Prominent decision-making theories propose that individuals (should) evaluate alternatives by combining gains and losses in an additive way. Instead, we suggest that individuals seek to maximize the rate of exchange between positive and negative outcomes and thus combine gains and losses in a multiplicative way. Sensitivity to gain-loss ratio provides an alternative account for several existing findings and implies a number of novel predictions. It implies greater sensitivity to losses and risk aversion when expected value is positive, but greater sensitivity to gains and risk seeking when expected value is negative. It also implies more extreme preferences when expected value is positive than when expected value is negative. These predictions are independent of decreasing marginal sensitivity, loss aversion, and probability weighting-three key properties of prospect theory. Five new experiments and reanalyses of two recently published studies support these predictions.</description><author>de Langhe, Bart; Puntoni, Stefano</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sticking with What (Barely) Worked: A Test of Outcome Bias</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lefgren, Lars; Platt, Brennan; Price, Joseph
Outcome bias occurs when an evaluator considers ex post outcomes when judging whether a choice was correct ex ante. We formalize this cognitive bias in a simple model of distorted Bayesian updating. We then examine strategy changes made by professional basketball coaches. We find that they are more likely to revise their strategy after a loss than a win-even for narrow losses, which are uninformative about team effectiveness. This increased strategy revision following a loss occurs even when a loss was expected and even when failure is due to factors beyond the team's control. These results are consistent with our model's predictions.</description><author>Lefgren, Lars; Platt, Brennan; Price, Joseph</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contractual vs. Actual Separation Pay Following CEO Turnover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldman, Eitan Moshe; Huang, Peggy Peiju
Using hand-collected data, we document the details of the ex ante severance contracts and the ex post separation pay given to S&amp;P 500 chief executive officers (CEOs) upon departing from their companies. We analyze what determines whether or not a CEO receives separation pay in excess of the amount specified in the severance contract. We find that discretionary separation pay is given to about 40% of departing CEOs and is, on average, $8 million, which amounts to close to 242% of a CEO's annual compensation. We investigate the determinants of discretionary separation pay and find, for example, that discretionary separation pay positively correlates with weak internal governance in cases of voluntary CEO turnover but not when the CEO is forced out. We also find that discretionary pay is higher when the CEO has a noncompete clause in her ex ante severance contract. Event study analysis suggests that shareholders benefit from discretionary separation pay in forced turnovers but not in voluntary ones. Our overall results help to shed light on the complex role of discretionary separation pay in the bargaining game between boards and departing executives.</description><author>Goldman, Eitan Moshe; Huang, Peggy Peiju</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real Options and American Derivatives: The Double Continuation Region</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Battauz, Anna; De Donno, Marzia; Sbuelz, Alessandro
We study the nonstandard optimal exercise policy associated with relevant capital investment options and with the prepayment option of widespread collateralized-borrowing contracts like the gold loan. Option exercise is optimally postponed not only when moneyness is insufficient, but also when it is excessive. We extend the classical optimal exercise properties for American options. Early exercise of an American call with a negative underlying payout rate can occur if the option is moderately in the money. We fully characterize the existence, the monotonicity, the continuity, the limits, and the asymptotic behavior at maturity of the double free boundary that separates the exercise region from the double continuation region. We find that the finite-maturity nonstandard policy conspicuously differs from the infinite-maturity one.</description><author>Battauz, Anna; De Donno, Marzia; Sbuelz, Alessandro</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Reaction of Stock Returns to News About Fundamentals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cenesizoglu, Tolga
In good times, stock prices react negatively to good news and positively to bad news, whereas in bad times, they react positively to good news and negatively to bad news. To account for this stylized fact, we consider an asset pricing model where the dividend growth rate switches between different values depending on the underlying state of the economy. Investors never observe the true dividend growth rate, but learn about it through not only its realizations but also external signals such as macroeconomic indicators. Under plausible assumptions, the differing precision of external signals across different states of the economy can change the sign of the market reaction to news from external signals in good and bad times.</description><author>Cenesizoglu, Tolga</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Experimental Investigation of Auctions and Bargaining in Procurement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shachat, Jason; Tan, Lijia
In reverse auctions, buyers often retain the right to bargain further concessions from the winners. The optimal form of such procurement is an English auction followed by an auctioneer's option to engage in ultimatum bargaining with the winners. We study behavior and performance in this procurement format using a laboratory experiment. Sellers closely follow the equilibrium strategy of exiting the auction at their costs and then accepting strictly profitable offers. Buyers generally exercise their option to bargain according to their equilibrium strategy, but their take-it-or-leave-it offers vary positively with auction prices when they should be invariant. We explain this deviation by modeling buyers' subjective posteriors regarding the winners' costs as distortions of the Bayesian posteriors, calculated using a formulation similar to a commonly used probability weighting function. We further test the robustness of the experimental results and the subjective posterior explanation with three additional experimental treatments.</description><author>Shachat, Jason; Tan, Lijia</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Advice on Women's and Men's Selection into Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brandts, Jordi; Groenert, Valeska; Rott, Christina
We conduct a laboratory experiment to study how advice by a more experienced and better-informed person affects an individual's entry into a real-effort tournament and the gender gap. Our experiment is motivated by the concerns raised by approaching the gender gap through affirmative action policies. Overall, advice improves the entry decision of subjects, in that forgone earnings due to wrong entry decisions go significantly down. The improvements are mainly driven by increased entry of strong-performing women, who also become more confident, and reduced entry of weak-performing men. We find that the overall gender gap persists even though it disappears among low and strong performers. The persistence is due to an emerging gender gap among intermediate performers driven by women (men) following more the advice to stay out of (enter) the tournament in this performance group.</description><author>Brandts, Jordi; Groenert, Valeska; Rott, Christina</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Comparison of Milestone-Based and Buyout Options Contracts for Coordinating R&amp;D Partnerships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, Shantanu; Gaba, Vibha; Hasija, Sameer
We analyze optimal contractual arrangements in a bilateral research and development (R&amp;D) partnership between a risk-averse provider that conducts early-stage research followed by a regulatory verification stage and a risk-neutral client that performs late-stage development activities, including production, distribution, and marketing. The problem is formulated as a sequential investment game with the client as the principal, where the investments are observable but not verifiable. The model captures the inherent incentive alignment problems of double-sided moral hazard, risk aversion, and holdup. We compare the efficacy of milestone-based options contracts and buyout options contracts from the client's perspective and identify conditions under which they attain the first-best outcome for the client. We find that milestone-based options contracts always attain the first-best outcome for the client when the provider has some bargaining power in renegotiation and identify their applicability to different R&amp;D partnerships.</description><author>Bhattacharya, Shantanu; Gaba, Vibha; Hasija, Sameer</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forward-Looking MD&amp;A Disclosures and the Information Environment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Muslu, Volkan; Radhakrishnan, Suresh; Subramanyam, K. R.; Lim, Dongkuk
We use computer-intensive techniques to study the informational properties of forward-looking disclosures in the management discussion and analysis (MD&amp;A) sections of 10-K filings made with the Securities and Exchange Commission. We find that firms make more forward-looking MD&amp;A disclosures when their stock prices have lower informational efficiency, i.e., when their stock prices poorly reflect future earnings information. The greater levels of forward-looking MD&amp;A disclosures help improve yet are unable to completely mitigate the lower informational efficiency of stock prices for such firms. These findings are stronger for operations-related forward-looking disclosures, disclosures that are made prior to 2000, and disclosures made by loss firms.</description><author>Muslu, Volkan; Radhakrishnan, Suresh; Subramanyam, K. R.; Lim, Dongkuk</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does a Procurement Service Provider Generate Value for the Buyer Through Information About Supply Risks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Zhibin; Babich, Volodymyr
We consider a supply chain with one buyer and two suppliers who are subject to disruptions and whose likelihoods of disruption are their private information. In such a setting, does the buyer benefit from engaging the services of a better-informed procurement service provider (PSP) compared to procuring directly from the suppliers? Intuition might suggest that hiring a PSP is always the right choice because the PSP's knowledge of the supply base improves supplier selection and management. On the other hand, earlier studies prove that using a PSP purely for its superior knowledge about supply costs is always worse for a buyer than contracting with the suppliers directly. Our answer to this research question is more nuanced. Contrary to the findings of earlier studies, we find that the buyer may benefit from using a PSP. We identify, quantify, and explain all of the benefits and the costs of using a PSP, and describe conditions under which the benefits exceed the costs. The benefits of using a PSP are derived when one supplier is of high reliability and the other is of low reliability, from a reduction of informational costs due to implicit supplier collusion facilitated by the PSP and an improvement of supply availability. The costs of using a PSP are derived when both suppliers are of low reliability, from the loss of direct control over the supplier's production actions, which leads to reduced supply availability and increased informational costs, and from the PSP facilitating implicit supplier collusion. Comparative statics analysis indicates that using the PSP is valuable only if the buyer diversifies with some supplier-type combinations but not others, and that hiring a PSP is not a solution to the problem of an unreliable supply base.</description><author>Yang, Zhibin; Babich, Volodymyr</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beating Irrationality: Does Delegating to IT Alleviate the Sunk Cost Effect?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Herrmann, Philipp N.; Kundisch, Dennis O.; Rahman, Mohammad S.
We investigate the impact of delegating decision making to information technology (IT) on an important human decision bias-the sunk cost effect. To address our research question, we use a unique data set containing actual market transaction data for approximately 7,000 pay-per-bid auctions. In contrast with the laboratory experiments of previous related studies, our research presents the unique advantage of investigating the effects of IT-enabled automated bidding agents on the occurrence of a decision bias in real market transactions. We identify normatively irrational decision scenarios and analyze consumer behavior in these situations. Our findings show that participants with a higher behavioral investment are more likely to violate the assumption of normative economic rationality because of the sunk cost effect. More importantly, we observe that the delegation of auction participation, i.e., actual bidding, to IT significantly reduces the occurrence of the sunk cost effect in subsequent decisions made by the same individual. We can attribute this reduction to the comparably lower behavioral investments incurred by auction participants who delegate their bidding to IT. In particular, by mitigating different contributors of behavioral investments, delegating to IT reduces the likelihood of the occurrence of the sunk cost effect by more than 50%.</description><author>Herrmann, Philipp N.; Kundisch, Dennis O.; Rahman, Mohammad S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-Selling Attacks and Creditor Runs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Xuewen
This paper investigates the mechanism through which short selling of a bank's stocks can trigger the failure of the bank. In the model, creditors, who learn information from stock prices, will grow increasingly unsure about the bank's true fundamentals in facing noisier stock prices; thus a run on the bank is more likely because of creditors' concave payoff. Understanding this, speculators conduct short selling beforehand to amplify (il)liquidity and add noise to stock prices, triggering a bank run, and subsequently profit from the bank's failure. We show that short-selling attacks on a bank involve two runs: the aggressive run among speculators and the conservative run among creditors. These two runs interact and reinforce each other, with compound feedback loops that drastically increase the probability of the collapse of the bank. We discuss policy implications of the model.</description><author>Liu, Xuewen</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stress on the Ward: Evidence of Safety Tipping Points in Hospitals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuntz, Ludwig; Mennicken, Roman; Scholtes, Stefan
Do hospitals experience safety tipping points as utilization increases, and if so, what are the implications for hospital operations management? We argue that safety tipping points occur when managerial escalation policies are exhausted and workload variability buffers are depleted. Front-line clinical staff is forced to ration resources and, at the same time, becomes more error prone as a result of elevated stress hormone levels. We confirm the existence of safety tipping points for in-hospital mortality using the discharge records of 82,280 patients across six high-mortality-risk conditions from 256 clinical departments of 83 German hospitals. Focusing on survival during the first seven days following admission, we estimate a mortality tipping point at an occupancy level of 92.5%. Among the 17% of patients in our sample who experienced occupancy above the tipping point during the first seven days of their hospital stay, high occupancy accounted for one in seven deaths. The existence of a safety tipping point has important implications for hospital management. First, flexible capacity expansion is more cost-effective for safety improvement than rigid capacity, because it will only be used when occupancy reaches the tipping point. In the context of our sample, flexible staffing saves more than 40% of the cost of a fully staffed capacity expansion, while achieving the same reduction in mortality. Second, reducing the variability of demand by pooling capacity in hospital clusters can greatly increase safety in a hospital system, because it reduces the likelihood that a patient will experience occupancy levels beyond the tipping point. Pooling the capacity of nearby hospitals in our sample reduces the number of deaths due to high occupancy by 34%.</description><author>Kuntz, Ludwig; Mennicken, Roman; Scholtes, Stefan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Clumped or Piecewise? Evidence on Preferences for Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zimmermann, Florian
In this paper we examine individuals' attitudes toward the timing of information. We test a theoretical prediction that people prefer to get information "clumped together" rather than piecewise. We conduct a controlled lab experiment where subjects participate in a lottery and can choose between different resolutions of uncertainty (clumped or piecewise) and analyze which kind of resolution is preferred. Two additional treatments allow us to get a quantitative measure of subjects' preferences over different information structures. Our data provide little support for a systematic aversion to piecewise information on the aggregate level. In additional treatment conditions, we demonstrate the robustness of our findings and explore potential explanations.</description><author>Zimmermann, Florian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Sourcing and Foreign Knowledge Seeking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berry, Heather; Kaul, Aseem
We develop and test a rigorous theoretical account of firm global sourcing decisions, distinguishing the antecedents of offshore integration from those of offshore outsourcing. Although traditional theories of global sourcing focus on lowering costs, we argue that as high-performing firms seek to develop new capabilities by tapping into foreign knowledge, they will increasingly turn to offshore integration to reap colocation benefits and overcome expropriation challenges. By contrast, offshore outsourcing will be preferred by less profitable firms seeking to tap into low-cost inputs, especially as investments in information technology lower monitoring costs. Empirical analysis of a comprehensive panel of cross-border product transfers by U.S. manufacturing multinational corporations from 1989 to 2004 reveals support for these arguments. Our study thus highlights the effect of foreign knowledge seeking on global sourcing and helps explain recent trends in this increasingly important phenomenon, especially the increasing reliance on offshore integration in technology intensive industries.</description><author>Berry, Heather; Kaul, Aseem</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Hidden Cost of Accommodating Crowdfunder Privacy Preferences: A Randomized Field Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burtch, Gordon; Ghose, Anindya; Wattal, Sunil
Online crowdfunding has received a great deal of attention as a promising avenue to fostering entrepreneurship and innovation. Because online settings bring increased visibility and traceability of transactions, many crowdfunding platforms provide mechanisms that enable a campaign contributor to conceal his or her identity or contribution amount from peers. We study the impact of these information (privacy) control mechanisms on crowdfunder behavior. Employing a randomized experiment at one of the world's largest online crowdfunding platforms, we find evidence of both positive (e.g., comfort) and negative (e.g., privacy priming) causal effects. We find that reducing access to information controls induces a net increase in fund-raising, yet this outcome results from two competing influences-treatment increases willingness to engage with the platform (a 4.9% increase in the probability of contribution) and simultaneously decreases the average contribution (a $5.81 decline). This decline derives from a publicity effect, wherein contributors respond to a lack of privacy by tempering extreme contributions. We unravel the causal mechanisms that drive the results and discuss the implications of our findings for the design of online platforms.</description><author>Burtch, Gordon; Ghose, Anindya; Wattal, Sunil</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Investigation of the Average Bid Mechanism for Procurement Auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Wei-Shiun; Chen, Bo; Salmon, Timothy C.
In a procurement context, it can be quite costly for a buyer when the winning seller underestimates the cost of a project and then defaults on the project midway through completion. The average bid auction is one mechanism intended to help address this problem. This format involves awarding the contract to the bidder who has bid closest to the average of the bids submitted. We compare the performance of this mechanism with the standard low price mechanism to determine how successful the average bid format is in preventing bidder losses as well as its impact on the price paid by the buyer. We find the average bid mechanism to be more successful than expected because, surprisingly, bidding behavior remains similar between the average bid and low price auctions. We provide an explanation for the bidding behavior in the average bid auction that is based on subjects having problems processing signals near the extremes of the distribution.</description><author>Chang, Wei-Shiun; Chen, Bo; Salmon, Timothy C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Market Leaders Lead in Business Process Innovation? The Case(s) of E-business Adoption</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McElheran, Kristina
Are market leaders more likely to be early adopters of business process innovations? Although they tend to enjoy economies of scale in adoption, leaders may find that adjustment costs also increase with scale. Prior work has focused on how misalignment of incumbents' internal capabilities may affect their technology strategy. However, technology-capability misalignment may exist outside the firm boundary as well. In this paper, I build on mainstream product innovation concepts to predict when market leaders will adopt certain business process innovations. I then test these predictions in a large data set on early e-business adoption, leveraging its novel insight into focal firms, their markets, and their customers. I find market leaders were significantly more likely to embrace new information technology-enabled practices-except when customer adjustment costs were a significant concern. These findings highlight the strategic significance of external capabilities in the face of technological change.</description><author>McElheran, Kristina</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sponsored Search Marketing: Dynamic Pricing and Advertising for an Online Retailer</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ye, Shengqi; Aydin, Goker; Hu, Shanshan
Consider a retailer using sponsored search marketing together with dynamic pricing. The retailer's bid on a search keyword affects the retailer's rank among the search results. The higher the rank, the higher the customer traffic and the customers' willingness to pay will be. Thus, the question arises: When a retailer bids higher to attract more customers, should the accompanying price also decrease (to strengthen the bid's effect on demand) or increase (to take advantage of higher willingness to pay)? We find that the answer depends on how fast the retailer increases its bid. In particular, as the end of the season approaches, the optimal bid exhibits smooth increases followed by big jumps. The optimal price increases only when the optimal bid increases sharply, including the instances where the bid jumps up. Such big jumps arise, for example, when the customer traffic is an S-shaped function of the retailer's bid.</description><author>Ye, Shengqi; Aydin, Goker; Hu, Shanshan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interpersonal Bundling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yongmin; Zhang, Tianle
This paper studies a model of interpersonal bundling, in which a monopolist offers a good for sale under a regular price and a group purchase discount if the number of consumers in a group-the bundle size-belongs to some menu of intervals. We find that this is often a profitable selling strategy in response to demand uncertainty, and it can achieve the highest profit among all possible selling mechanisms. We explain how the profitability of interpersonal bundling with a minimum or maximum group size may depend on the nature of uncertainty and on parameters of the market environment, and we discuss strategic issues related to the optimal design and implementation of these bundling schemes. Our analysis sheds light on popular marketing practices such as group purchase discounts, and it offers insights on potential new marketing innovation.</description><author>Chen, Yongmin; Zhang, Tianle</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Risk Preferences of US Executives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brenner, Steffen
In this paper, I elicit risk attitudes of U.S. executives by calibrating a subjective option valuation model for option exercising data (1996 to 2008), yielding approximately 65,000 values of relative risk aversion (RRA) for almost 7,000 executives. The observed behavior is generally consistent with moderate risk aversion and a median (mean) RRA close to one (three). Values are validated for chief executive officers (CEOs) by testing theory-based predictions on the influence of individual characteristics on risk preferences such as gender, marital status, religiosity, and intelligence. Senior managers such as CEOs, presidents, and chairpersons of the boards of directors are significantly less risk averse than non-senior executives. RRA heterogeneity is strongly correlated with sector membership and firm-level variables such as size, performance, and capital structure. Alternative factors influencing option exercises are tested for their influence on RRA values.</description><author>Brenner, Steffen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Equity, Royalty, and Fixed Fees in Technology Licensing to University Spin-Offs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Savva, Nicos; Taneri, Niyazi
We develop a model based on asymmetric information (adverse selection) that provides a rational explanation for the persistent use of royalties alongside equity in university technology transfer. The model shows how royalties, through their value-destroying distortions, can act as a screening tool that allows a less-informed principal, such as the university's Technology Transfer Office (TTO), to elicit private information from the more informed spin-off. We also show that equity-royalty contracts outperform fixed-fee-royalty contracts because they cause fewer value-destroying distortions. Furthermore, we show that our main result is robust to problems of moral hazard. Beside the coexistence result, the model also offers explanations for the empirical findings that equity generates higher returns than royalty and that TTOs willing to take equity in lieu of fixed fees are more successful in creating spin-offs.</description><author>Savva, Nicos; Taneri, Niyazi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pay What You Want as a Marketing Strategy in Monopolistic and Competitive Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schmidt, Klaus M.; Spann, Martin; Zeithammer, Robert
Pay what you want (PWYW) can be an attractive marketing strategy to price discriminate between fair-minded and selfish customers, to fully penetrate a market without giving away the product for free, and to undercut competitors that use posted prices. We report on laboratory experiments that identify causal factors determining the willingness of buyers to pay voluntarily under PWYW. Furthermore, to see how competition affects the viability of PWYW, we implement markets in which a PWYW seller competes with a traditional seller. Finally, we endogenize the market structure and let sellers choose their pricing strategy. The experimental results show that outcome-based social preferences and strategic considerations to keep the seller in the market can explain why and how much buyers pay voluntarily to a PWYW seller. We find that PWYW can be viable on a monopolistic market, but it is less successful as a competitive strategy because it does not drive traditional posted-price sellers out of the market. Instead, the existence of a posted-price competitor reduces buyers' payments and prevents the PWYW seller from fully penetrating the market. When given the choice, most sellers opt for setting a posted price rather than a PWYW pricing strategy. We discuss the implications of these results for the use of PWYW as a marketing strategy. Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2014.1946.</description><author>Schmidt, Klaus M.; Spann, Martin; Zeithammer, Robert</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Fixed Charge Transportation Problem: An Exact Algorithm Based on a New Integer Programming Formulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roberti, Roberto; Bartolini, Enrico; Mingozzi, Aristide
The fixed charge transportation problem generalizes the well-known transportation problem where the cost of sending goods from a source to a sink is composed of a fixed cost and a continuous cost proportional to the amount of goods sent. In this paper, we describe a new integer programming formulation with exponentially many variables corresponding to all possible flow patterns to sinks. We show that the linear relaxation of the new formulation is tighter than that of the standard mixed integer programming formulation. We describe different classes of valid inequalities for the new formulation and a column generation method to compute a valid lower bound embedded into an exact branch-and-price algorithm. Computational results on test problems from the literature show that the new algorithm outperforms the state-of-the-art exact methods from the literature and can solve instances with up to 70 sources and 70 sinks. Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2014.1947.</description><author>Roberti, Roberto; Bartolini, Enrico; Mingozzi, Aristide</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Brand Licensing Increase a Licensor's Shareholder Value?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Robinson, Adina Barbulescu; Tuli, Kapil R.; Kohli, Ajay K.
This study examines 171 brand licensing announcements and subsequent changes in the licensor firms' shareholder values using the event study method. We find that although brand licensing announcements lead to positive abnormal returns on average, nearly 44% of the announcements in our sample are followed by negative abnormal returns. We argue that investors react more favorably to a brand licensing announcement when they believe (i) the brand has greater ability to stimulate licensee product sales (and thus generate higher royalties for the licensor) and (ii) the licensor firm has greater ability to limit licensee opportunism (and thus limit brand dilution and its adverse effect on sales of other products marketed under the brand name). In line with our hypotheses related to a brand's ability to stimulate licensee product sales, the study's findings suggest that investors react more favorably to announcements involving brands with greater brand fit and greater brand breadth. However, investors appear to react less favorably to announcements involving brands with higher advertising investments. In line with our hypotheses related to a licensor firm's ability to limit licensee opportunism, the study's findings suggest that investors react more favorably to announcements involving larger licensors; however, investors' reactions do not appear to be influenced by licensor firms' licensing experience.</description><author>Robinson, Adina Barbulescu; Tuli, Kapil R.; Kohli, Ajay K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Smart People Ask for (My) Advice: Seeking Advice Boosts Perceptions of Competence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brooks, Alison Wood; Gino, Francesca; Schweitzer, Maurice E.
Although individuals can derive substantial benefits from exchanging information and ideas, many individuals are reluctant to seek advice from others. We find that people are reticent to seek advice for fear of appearing incompetent. This fear, however, is misplaced. We demonstrate that individuals perceive those who seek advice as more competent than those who do not. This effect is moderated by task difficulty, advisor egocentrism, and advisor expertise. Individuals perceive those who seek advice as more competent when the task is difficult rather than when it is easy, when people seek advice from them personally rather than when they seek advice from others and when people seek advice from experts rather than from nonexperts or not at all.</description><author>Brooks, Alison Wood; Gino, Francesca; Schweitzer, Maurice E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Reduced Search Costs and the Distribution of Bidder Participation Affect Auction Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Overby, Eric; Kannan, Karthik
Electronic commerce allows bidders to find and participate in auctions regardless of location. This reduction in bidders' search costs has important effects on bidders' participation patterns and sellers' revenue. The "demand expansion" effect occurs when reduced search costs allow bidders to participate in more auctions. The "demand distribution" effect occurs when reduced search costs allow bidders to distribute themselves more evenly across auctions. We focus on the latter effect by modeling when a more even distribution of bidder participation across auctions increases seller revenue. We apply our analytical insights to 65,718 sequential auctions (comprising over 10 million vehicles) in the wholesale used vehicle market. We show that reduced search costs can increase seller revenue by smoothing the distribution of bidder participation across auctions, even if the aggregate amount of bidder participation remains constant. This contributes new results to the auction theory literature and generates novel insights for sellers seeking increased revenue.</description><author>Overby, Eric; Kannan, Karthik</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Attitude, Beliefs Updating, and the Information Content of Trades: An Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bisiere, Christophe; Decamps, Jean-Paul; Lovo, Stefano
We conduct a series of experiments that simulate trading in financial markets. We find that the information content of the order flow varies with the strength of subjects' prior beliefs about fundamentals. The presence of intrinsic uncertainty about the asset's fundamentals reduces informational efficiency. This originates from subjects' risk attitudes and biases in the way some subjects update their beliefs. The behavior of approximately 63% of the subjects is consistent with the expected utility maximization. These subjects are either risk averse (52%) or risk loving (11%). About 22% of the subjects display non-Bayesian updating of beliefs: underconfidence emerges for weak prior beliefs, and confirmation bias occurs for strong prior beliefs. Non-Bayesian belief updating reduces market efficiency when subjects' prior beliefs are weak and increases it when the prior beliefs are strong. Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2013.1886.</description><author>Bisiere, Christophe; Decamps, Jean-Paul; Lovo, Stefano</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Changes in the Composition of Publicly Traded Firms: Implications for the Dividend-Price Ratio and Return Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jank, Stephan
This paper documents how the changing composition of U.S. publicly traded firms has prompted a decline in the long-run mean of the aggregate dividend-price ratio, most notably since the 1970s. Adjusting the dividend-price ratio for such changes resolves several issues with respect to the predictability of stock market returns: the adjusted dividend-price ratio is less persistent, in-sample evidence for predictability is more pronounced, there is greater parameter stability in the predictive regression (particularly during the 1990s), and there is evidence of out-of-sample predictability. Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2013.1883.</description><author>Jank, Stephan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Experiments on Compound Risk in Relation to Simple Risk and to Ambiguity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abdellaoui, Mohammed; Klibanoff, Peter; Placido, Laetitia
We conduct experiments measuring individual behavior under compound risk, simple risk, and ambiguity. We focus on (1) treatment of compound risks relative to simple risks and (2) the relationship between compound risk attitudes and ambiguity attitudes. We find that compound risks are valued differently than corresponding reduced simple risks. These differences measure compound risk attitudes. These attitudes display more aversion as the reduced probability of the winning event increases. Like Halevy [Halevy Y (2007) Ellsberg revisited: An experimental study. Econometrica 75:503-536], we find an association between compound risk reduction and ambiguity neutrality. However, in contrast to the almost perfect identification in Halevy's data, we find a substantially weaker relation in both directions. First, a majority of our ambiguity-neutral subjects fail to reduce compound risk. Second, almost a quarter of our subjects who reduce compound risk are nonneutral to ambiguity. All of the latter come from the more quantitatively sophisticated part of our subject pool. Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2014.1953.</description><author>Abdellaoui, Mohammed; Klibanoff, Peter; Placido, Laetitia</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disclosure Policy and Industry Fluctuations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertomeu, Jeremy; Liang, Pierre Jinghong
This paper examines voluntary disclosures in a repeated oligopoly and their association with price-setting behavior and industry profits along industrial fluctuations. The analysis focuses on the collectively optimal equilibrium among oligopoly firms. We show that, in industries that are highly concentrated or feature low cost of capital, nondisclosure is prevalent and results in stable product prices and high profit margins. Otherwise, firms may selectively disclose to soften competition in the product market. Under partial disclosure, firms withhold information during sharp industry expansions or declines. Consequently, the disclosure policy dampens the dissemination of shocks to the industry.</description><author>Bertomeu, Jeremy; Liang, Pierre Jinghong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Repeated Auctions with Budgets in Ad Exchanges: Approximations and Design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balseiro, Santiago R.; Besbes, Omar; Weintraub, Gabriel Y.
Ad exchanges are emerging Internet markets where advertisers may purchase display ad placements, in real time and based on specific viewer information, directly from publishers via a simple auction mechanism. Advertisers join these markets with a prespecified budget and participate in multiple second-price auctions over the length of a campaign. This paper studies the competitive landscape that arises in ad exchanges and the implications for publishers' decisions. The presence of budgets introduces dynamic interactions among advertisers that need to be taken into account when attempting to characterize the bidding landscape or the impact of changes in the auction design. To this end, we introduce the notion of a fluid mean-field equilibrium (FMFE) that is behaviorally appealing and computationally tractable, and in some important cases, it yields a closed-form characterization. We establish that an FMFE approximates well the rational behavior of advertisers in these markets. We then show how this framework may be used to provide sharp prescriptions for key auction design decisions that publishers face in these markets. In particular, we show that ignoring budgets, a common practice in this literature, can result in significant profit losses for the publisher when setting the reserve price.</description><author>Balseiro, Santiago R.; Besbes, Omar; Weintraub, Gabriel Y.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Attribute-Level Heterogeneity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ebbes, Peter; Liechty, John C.; Grewal, Rajdeep
Modeling consumer heterogeneity helps practitioners understand market structures and devise effective marketing strategies. In this research we study finite mixture specifications for modeling consumer heterogeneity where each regression coefficient has its own finite mixture-that is, an attribute finite mixture model. An important challenge of such an approach to modeling heterogeneity lies in its estimation. A proposed Bayesian estimation approach, based on recent advances in reversible-jump Markov chain Monte Carlo methods, can estimate parameters for the attribute-based finite mixture model, assuming that the number of components for each finite mixture is a discrete random variable. An attribute specification has several advantages over traditional, vector-based, finite mixture specifications; specifically, the attribute mixture model offers a more appropriate aggregation of information than does the vector specification facilitating estimation. In an extensive simulation study and an empirical application, we show that the attribute model can recover complex heterogeneity structures, making it dominant over traditional (vector) finite mixture regression models and a strong contender compared to mixture-of-normals models for modeling heterogeneity.</description><author>Ebbes, Peter; Liechty, John C.; Grewal, Rajdeep</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Differentiation with User-Generated Content</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Kaifu; Sarvary, Miklos
This paper studies competition between firms whose "products" (content) are generated by their customers (users). Video sharing sites, social networks, online games, etc. all rely heavily on user-generated content and have been growing significantly in the last decade. We model a Hotelling style market in which consumers have heterogeneous tastes along a circular city. In a first step, we consider two ex ante identical firms whose offerings entirely depend on user-generated content. Consumers contribute content to the firm they join and benefit from the content provided by the others, their valuation being higher the closer the content contributor is to the content consumer (i.e., there are local network effects). In such a setting, we show that ex ante identical firms can acquire differentiated market positions that spontaneously emerge from user-generated content. Moreover, such differentiation may take interesting patterns, wherein a firm simultaneously attracts multiple distinct consumer segments that are isolated from each other. Greater segregation, measured by the number of disjoint segments in each platform, reduces consumer valuation for content, but interestingly, it intensifies firm competition. We show that this insight can help us refine the set of possible equilibria. In a second step, we consider firms that explicitly differentiate their offerings by generating some content on their own. We show that user-generated content may strengthen or defeat firms' intended positioning (i.e., firms attract consumers located opposite to their chosen positions) and consumer surplus may be higher in the latter case. Finally, we allow multihoming by consumers and show that the previous equilibrium patterns remain valid, but in most equilibria, a subset of consumers (located between rival firms' core clienteles) are multihomers. More multihoming consumers imply reduced differentiation and higher degree of platform competition. We relate these findings to anecdotal evidence and explore their strategic implications for competing firms relying on user-generated content.</description><author>Zhang, Kaifu; Sarvary, Miklos</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Vertical Scope, Turbulence, and the Benefits of Commitment and Flexibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Claussen, Jorg; Kretschmer, Tobias; Stieglitz, Nils
We address the contested state of theory and the mixed empirical evidence on the relationship between turbulence and vertical scope by studying how turbulence affects the benefits of commitment from integrated development of components and the benefits of flexibility from sourcing components externally. We show that increasing turbulence first increases but then decreases the relative value of vertical integration. Moderate turbulence reduces the value of flexibility by making supplier selection more difficult and increases the value of commitment by mitigating the status quo bias of integrated structures. Both effects improve the value of integration. Higher levels of turbulence undermine the adaptive benefits of commitment, but have a less adverse effect on flexibility, making nonintegration more attractive. We also show how complexity and uneven rates of turbulence moderate the nonmonotonic relationship between turbulence and integration.</description><author>Claussen, Jorg; Kretschmer, Tobias; Stieglitz, Nils</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Preferences Around the World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rieger, Marc Oliver; Wang, Mei; Hens, Thorsten
We present results from a large-scale international survey on risk preferences conducted in 53 countries. In all countries, we find, on average, an attitude of risk aversion in gains and of risk seeking in losses. The degree of risk aversion shows significant cross-country differences. Moreover, risk attitudes in our sample depend not only on economic conditions but also on cultural factors, as measured by the Hofstede dimensions individualism and uncertainty avoidance. The data may also serve as an interesting starting point for further research on cultural differences in behavioral economics.</description><author>Rieger, Marc Oliver; Wang, Mei; Hens, Thorsten</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Origin of Utility, Weighting, and Discounting Functions: How They Get Their Shapes and How to Change Their Shapes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stewart, Neil; Reimers, Stian; Harris, Adam J. L.
We present a theoretical account of the origin of the shapes of utility, probability weighting, and temporal discounting functions. In an experimental test of the theory, we systematically change the shape of revealed utility, weighting, and discounting functions by manipulating the distribution of monies, probabilities, and delays in the choices used to elicit them. The data demonstrate that there is no stable mapping between attribute values and their subjective equivalents. Expected and discounted utility theories, and also their descendants such as prospect theory and hyperbolic discounting theory, simply assert stable mappings to describe choice data and offer no account of the instability we find. We explain where the shape of the mapping comes from and, in describing the mechanism by which people choose, explain why the shape depends on the distribution of gains, losses, risks, and delays in the environment.</description><author>Stewart, Neil; Reimers, Stian; Harris, Adam J. L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are People Risk Vulnerable?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beaud, Mickael; Willinger, Marc
We report on a within-subject experiment, with substantial monetary incentives, designed to test whether or not people are risk vulnerable. In the experiment, subjects face the standard portfolio choice problem in which the investor has to allocate part of his wealth between one safe asset and one risky asset. We elicit risk vulnerability by observing each subject's portfolio choice in two different contexts that differ only by the presence or absence of an actuarially neutral background risk. Our main result is that most of the subjects are risk vulnerable: 81% chose a less risky portfolio when exposed to background risk. More precisely, 47% invested a strictly smaller amount in the risky asset, whereas 34% were indifferent. Furthermore, contrasting the predictions provided by competing decision-theoretic models, we conclude that expected utility theory best fits our experimental data.</description><author>Beaud, Mickael; Willinger, Marc</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decentralized Procurement in Light of Strategic Inventories</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arya, Anil; Frimor, Hans; Mittendorf, Brian
The centralization versus decentralization choice is perhaps the quintessential organizational structure decision. In the operations realm, this choice is particularly critical when it comes to the procurement function. Why firms may opt to decentralize procurement has been often studied and confirmed to be a multifaceted choice. This paper complements existing studies by detailing the trade-offs in the centralization versus decentralization decision in light of firms' strategic use of inventories to influence supplier pricing. In particular, we demonstrate that a firm's decision to cede procurement choices to its individual divisions can help moderate inventory levels and provide a natural salve on supply chain frictions.</description><author>Arya, Anil; Frimor, Hans; Mittendorf, Brian</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Content on Global Internet Adoption and the Global "Digital Divide"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Viard, V. Brian; Economides, Nicholas
A country's human capital and economic productivity increasingly depend on the Internet as a result of its expanding role in providing information and communications. This has prompted a search for ways to increase Internet adoption and narrow its disparity across countries-the global "digital divide." Previous work has focused on demographic, economic, and infrastructure determinants of Internet access that are difficult to change in the short run. Internet content increases adoption and can be changed more quickly; however, the magnitude of its impact, and therefore its effectiveness as a policy and strategy tool, has until now been unknown. Quantifying the role of content is challenging because of feedback (network effects) between content and adoption: more content stimulates adoption, which in turn increases the incentive to create content. We develop a methodology to overcome this endogeneity problem. We find a statistically and economically significant effect, implying that policies promoting content creation can substantially increase adoption. Because it is ubiquitous, Internet content is also useful to effect social change across countries. Content has a greater effect on adoption in countries with more disparate languages, making it a useful tool to overcome linguistic isolation. Our results offer guidance for policymakers on country characteristics that influence adoption's responsiveness to content and for Internet firms on where to expand internationally and how to quantify content investments.</description><author>Viard, V. Brian; Economides, Nicholas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Speculation Spillovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Yu-Jane; Zhang, Zheng; Zhao, Longkai
This paper demonstrates that speculative activities can be contagious and spill over across markets. Specifically, we test the hypothesis that during China's warrants bubble period, speculative activities in the warrants market grabbed investors' attention and caused them to trade more speculatively in the underlying stocks. Consistent with this hypothesis, we find that turnover and return volatility of the underlying stocks are positively associated with the warrants' unexpected turnover and price deviation from their fundamental values during the previous day, controlling for information-driven trading and hedging motives, and that such a spillover effect is more pronounced when warrants attract more investor attention.</description><author>Liu, Yu-Jane; Zhang, Zheng; Zhao, Longkai</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Accounting Quality in the M&amp;A Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marquardt, Carol; Zur, Emanuel
We examine the role of target firms' accounting quality in the merger and acquisition process. We predict that target firm accounting quality will be positively associated with (1) the likelihood that the deal will be structured as a negotiation rather than as an auction, (2) the speed with which the deal reaches final resolution, and (3) the likelihood that the proposed deal is ultimately completed. Our empirical evidence is consistent with these predictions. These results complement and extend existing findings on target firm accounting quality and provide new evidence that financial accounting quality relates positively to the efficient allocation of the economy's capital resources.</description><author>Marquardt, Carol; Zur, Emanuel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prioritization via Stochastic Optimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koc, Ali; Morton, David P.
We take a novel approach to decision problems involving binary activity-selection decisions competing for scarce resources. The literature approaches such problems by forming an optimal portfolio of activities. However, often practitioners instead form a rank-ordered list of activities and select those with the highest priority. We account for both viewpoints. We rank activities considering both the uncertainty in the problem parameters and the optimal portfolio that will be obtained once the uncertainty is revealed. We use stochastic integer programming as a modeling framework, and we apply our approach to a facility location problem and a multidimensional knapsack problem. We develop two sets of cutting planes to improve computation.</description><author>Koc, Ali; Morton, David P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rationing Capacity in Advance Selling to Signal Quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yu, Man; Ahn, Hyun-Soo; Kapuscinski, Roman
We consider a seller who can sell her product over two periods, advance and spot. The seller has private information about the product quality, which is unknown to customers in advance and publicly revealed in spot. The question we consider is whether the seller has an incentive to signal quality in advance and, if so, how she can convey a credible signal of product quality. We characterize the seller's signaling strategy and find that rationing of capacity in the advance period is an effective tool of signaling product quality. We find that the high-quality seller can distinguish herself by allocating less capacity than the low-quality seller in the advance period. We show that this signaling mechanism exists whenever advance selling would be optimal for both the high-quality and low-quality sellers if quality were known by the consumers. Interestingly, the seller's ability to ration (rationing flexibility) sometimes disadvantages the seller; this effect is independent of product quality.</description><author>Yu, Man; Ahn, Hyun-Soo; Kapuscinski, Roman</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bargaining for an Assortment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aydin, Goker; Heese, H. Sebastian
A retailer's assortment decision results from a process of give-and-take, during which the retailer may bid manufacturers against one another, and the terms of trade offer plenty of flexibility for allocating the profit among the retailer and manufacturers. We adopt a bargaining framework to capture such an assortment selection process. We investigate the properties of the profit allocations that could emerge in a decentralized supply chain. In our model, the retailer engages in simultaneous bilateral negotiations with all manufacturers. Our model and analysis produce managerial insights that could not be obtained in the absence of a bargaining perspective on assortment planning. For example, we find that when a manufacturer improves its product, such improvements not only benefit the retailer but might even benefit competing manufacturers. In fact, even improvements to out-of-assortment products can increase the profits of the retailer and certain in-assortment manufacturers. Hence, our results suggest that a manufacturer can benefit from collaborating with judiciously chosen competitors.</description><author>Aydin, Goker; Heese, H. Sebastian</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Drive More Effective Data-Based Innovations: Enhancing the Utility of Secure Databases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qian, Yi; Xie, Hui
Databases play a central role in evidence-based innovations in business, economics, social, and health sciences. In modern business and society, there are rapidly growing demands for constructing analytically valid databases that also are secure and protect sensitive information to meet customer and public expectations, to minimize financial losses, and to comply with privacy regulations and laws. We propose new data perturbation and shuffling (DPS) procedures, named MORE, for this purpose. As compared with existing DPS methods, MORE can substantially increase the utility of secure databases without increasing disclosure risk. MORE is capable of preserving important nonmonotonic relationships among attributes, such as the inverted-U relationship between competition and innovation. Maintaining such relationships is often the key to determining optimal levels of policy and managerial interventions. MORE does not require data to be of particular types or have particular distributional shapes. Instead, it provides unified, flexible, and robust algorithms to mask general types of confidential variables with arbitrary distributions, thereby making it suitable for general-purpose data masking. Since MORE nests the commonly used generalized linear models as special cases, a much wider range of statistical analyses can be conducted by using the secure databases with results similar to those achieved by using the original databases. Unlike existing DPS approaches that typically require a joint model for all variables, MORE requires no modeling of nonconfidential variables and thus further increases the robustness of secure databases. Evaluation of MORE through Monte Carlo simulation studies and empirical applications demonstrates that it performs better than existing data-masking methods.</description><author>Qian, Yi; Xie, Hui</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Keyword Search Advertising and First-Page Bid Estimates: A Strategic Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amaldoss, Wilfred; Desai, Preyas S.; Shin, Woochoel
In using the generalized second-price (GSP) auction to sell advertising slots, a search engine faces several challenges. Advertisers do not truthfully bid their valuations, and the valuations are uncertain. Furthermore, advertisers are budget constrained. In this paper we analyze a stylized model of the first-page bid estimate (FPBE) mechanism first developed by Google and demonstrate its advantages in dealing with these challenges. We show why and when the FPBE mechanism yields higher profits for the search engine compared with the traditional GSP auction and the GSP auction with advertiser-specific minimum bid. In the event that a high-valuation advertiser is budget constrained, the search engine can use the FPBE mechanism to alter the listing order with the intent of keeping the high-valuation advertiser in the auction for a longer time. The resulting increase in the search engine's profits is not necessarily at the expense of the advertisers because the combined profits of the advertisers and the search engine increase.</description><author>Amaldoss, Wilfred; Desai, Preyas S.; Shin, Woochoel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spinoffs and the Mobility of US Merchant Semiconductor Inventors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheyre, Cristobal; Klepper, Steven; Veloso, Francisco
Data on inventors and assignees of patents are used to analyze the mobility of semiconductor inventors. Exploiting data on the origins of semiconductor producers with larger sales, we argue that the higher mobility of semiconductor inventors in Silicon Valley is in great part due to the entry of spinoffs there. Our empirical evidence suggests that spinoff entry promoted mobility in Silicon Valley even before the industry was clustered there. Agglomeration economies and the ban on noncompete covenants may influence spinoff entry, but spinoffs promote mobility even in the absence of those conditions. Because most of the greater inventor mobility in Silicon Valley corresponds to inventors moving from incumbents to recent entrants, the benefits that arise from greater mobility rates will be disproportionately reaped by new firms.</description><author>Cheyre, Cristobal; Klepper, Steven; Veloso, Francisco</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bias in Spatial Risk Assessment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mishra, Himanshu; Mishra, Arul; Moreno, Oscar
In instances of decision making under uncertainty with a visual component, we propose that individuals show a bias and estimate a higher probability of a threat affecting them if the threat is located in their left visual field compared to their right visual field. Across four studies we demonstrate the bias in naturalistic settings such as pedestrians assessing the risk of crossing the street, individuals estimating the risk posed from an unsavory person, and people assessing the contamination risk of an object. Moreover, we discuss four potential mechanisms that could cause the proposed effect. Finally, we discuss theoretical, managerial, and policy implications.</description><author>Mishra, Himanshu; Mishra, Arul; Moreno, Oscar</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are All Independent Directors Equally Informed? Evidence Based on Their Trading Returns and Social Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Ying; Dhaliwal, Dan; Li, Zengquan; Yang, Yong George
We study the impact of social networks on the ability of independent directors to obtain private information from their firms' executives. We find that independent directors socially connected to their firms' senior executives earn significantly higher returns than unconnected independent directors in stock sales transactions. The network effect on independent directors' trading profitability is stronger in firms with higher information asymmetry and with more powerful executives. In addition, the trading returns of independent directors previously unconnected with firm executives increase after the arrival of a connected executive and drop after the connected executive leaves the firm. Moreover, the net stock sales by connected directors predict future negative news for up to three quarters. As a comparison, the trading returns of connected and unconnected independent directors do not differ significantly in stock purchases. Taken together, our results suggest that social connections help independent directors gain access to private bad news information from firms' senior executives.</description><author>Cao, Ying; Dhaliwal, Dan; Li, Zengquan; Yang, Yong George</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Electric Vehicles with a Battery Switching Station: Adoption and Environmental Impact</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avci, Buket; Girotra, Karan; Netessine, Serguei
The transportation sector's carbon footprint and dependence on oil are of deep concern to policy makers in many countries. Use of all-electric drive trains is arguably the most realistic medium-term solution to address these concerns. However, motorist anxiety induced by an electric vehicle's limited range and high battery cost have constrained consumer adoption. A novel switching-station-based solution is touted as a promising remedy. Vehicles use standardized batteries that, when depleted, can be switched for fully charged batteries at switching stations, and motorists only pay for battery use. We build a model that highlights the key mechanisms driving adoption and use of electric vehicles in this new switching-station-based electric vehicle system and contrast it with conventional electric vehicles. Our model employs results from repairable item inventory theory to capture switching-station operation; we embed this model in a behavioral model of motorist use and adoption. Switching-station systems effectively transfer range risk from motorists to the station operator, who, through statistical economies of scale, can better manage it. We find that this transfer of risk can lead to higher electric vehicle adoption than in a conventional system, but it also encourages more driving than a conventional system does. We calibrate our models with motorist behavior data, electric vehicle technology data, operation costs, and emissions data to estimate the relative effectiveness of the two systems under the status quo and other plausible future scenarios. We find that the system that is more effective at reducing emissions is often less effective at reducing oil dependence, and the misalignment between the two objectives is most severe when the energy mix is coal heavy and has advanced battery technology. Increases in gasoline prices (by imposition of taxes, for instance) are much more effective in reducing carbon emissions, whereas battery-price-reducing policy interventions are more effective for reducing oil dependence. Taken together, our results help a policy maker identify the superior system for achieving the desired objectives. They also highlight that policy makers should not conflate the dual objectives of oil dependence and emissions reductions as the preferred system, and the policy interventions that further that system may be different for the two objectives.</description><author>Avci, Buket; Girotra, Karan; Netessine, Serguei</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the (Surprising) Sufficiency of Linear Models for Dynamic Pricing with Demand Learning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Besbes, Omar; Zeevi, Assaf
We consider a multiperiod single product pricing problem with an unknown demand curve. The seller's objective is to adjust prices in each period so as to maximize cumulative expected revenues over a given finite time horizon; in doing so, the seller needs to resolve the tension between learning the unknown demand curve and maximizing earned revenues. The main question that we investigate is the following: How large of a revenue loss is incurred if the seller uses a simple parametric model that differs significantly (i.e., is misspecified) relative to the underlying demand curve? We measure performance by analyzing the price trajectory induced by this misspecified model and quantifying the magnitude of revenue losses (as a function of the time horizon) relative to an oracle that knows the true underlying demand curve. The "price of misspecification" is expected to be significant if the parametric model is overly restrictive. Somewhat surprisingly, we show (under reasonably general conditions) that this need not be the case.</description><author>Besbes, Omar; Zeevi, Assaf</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Human and Financial Capital for Microenterprise Development: Evidence from a Field and Lab Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berge, Lars Ivar Oppedal; Bjorvatn, Kjetil; Tungodden, Bertil
Microenterprises constitute an important source of employment, and developing such enterprises is a key policy concern in most countries. But what is the most efficient tool for microenterprise development? We study this question in a developing country context (Tanzania), where microenterprises are the source of employment for more than half of the labor force, and we report from a field experiment that jointly investigated the importance of a human capital intervention (business training) and a financial capital intervention (business grant). Using data from three survey rounds, a lab experiment, and administrative records of the microfinance institution, we present evidence on business performance, management practices, happiness, business knowledge, and noncognitive abilities. Our study demonstrates strong effects of the combination of the two interventions on male entrepreneurs, while the effects on female entrepreneurs are much more muted. The results suggest that long-term finance is an important constraint for microfinance entrepreneurs, but that business training is essential to transform financial capital into productive investments. Our study also points to the need for more comprehensive measures to promote the businesses of female entrepreneurs.</description><author>Berge, Lars Ivar Oppedal; Bjorvatn, Kjetil; Tungodden, Bertil</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Pricing in a Monetary Economy with Heterogeneous Beliefs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Croitoru, Benjamin; Lu, Lei
In this paper, we shed new light on the role of monetary policy in asset pricing by examining the case in which investors have heterogeneous expectations about future monetary policy. This case is realistic because central banks are typically less than perfectly open about their intentions. Accordingly, surveys of economists reveal that they frequently disagree in their expectations. Under heterogeneity in beliefs, investors place speculative bets against each other on the evolution of the money supply, and as a result the sharing of wealth in the economy evolves stochastically. Employing a continuous-time equilibrium model, we show that these fluctuations majorly affect the prices of all assets, as well as inflation. Our model could help explain some empirical puzzles. In particular, we find that the volatility of bond yields and stock market volatility could be significantly increased by the heterogeneity in beliefs, a conclusion supported by our empirical analyses.</description><author>Croitoru, Benjamin; Lu, Lei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Self-Control on the Construction of Risk Perceptions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jia, Jayson S.; Khan, Uzma; Litt, Ab
We show that the way decision makers construct risk perceptions is systematically influenced by their level of self-control: low self-control results in greater weighting of probability and reduced weighting of consequences of negative outcomes in formulating overall threat perceptions. Seven studies demonstrate such distorted risk construction in wide-ranging risk domains. The effects hold for both chronic and manipulated levels of perceived self-control and are observed only for risks involving high personal agency (e.g., overeating, smoking, drinking). As an important implication of our results, we also demonstrate that those lower (higher) in self-control show relatively less (more) interest in products and lifestyle changes reducing consequences (e.g., a pill that heals liver damage from drinking) than those reducing likelihood of risks (e.g., a pill that prevents liver damage from drinking). We also explore several possible underlying processes for the observed effect and discuss the theoretical and managerial relevance of our findings.</description><author>Jia, Jayson S.; Khan, Uzma; Litt, Ab</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do I Follow My Friends or the Crowd? Information Cascades in Online Movie Ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Young-Jin; Hosanagar, Kartik; Tan, Yong
Online product ratings are widely available on the Internet and are known to influence prospective buyers. An emerging literature has started to look at how ratings are generated and, in particular, how they are influenced by prior ratings. We study the social influence of prior ratings and, in particular, investigate any differential impact of prior ratings by strangers ("crowd") versus friends. We find evidence of both herding and differentiation behavior in crowd ratings wherein users' ratings are influenced positively or negatively by prior ratings depending on movie popularity. In contrast, friends' ratings always induce herding. Further, the presence of social networking reduces the likelihood of herding on prior ratings by the crowd. Finally, we find that an increase in the number of friends who can potentially observe a user's rating ("audience size") has a positive impact on ratings. These findings raise questions about the reliability of ratings as unbiased indicators of quality and advocate the need for techniques to de-bias rating systems.</description><author>Lee, Young-Jin; Hosanagar, Kartik; Tan, Yong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateral Valuation and Borrower Financial Constraints: Evidence from the Residential Real Estate Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit; Ben-David, Itzhak; Yao, Vincent
Financially constrained borrowers have the incentive to influence the appraisal process in order to increase borrowing or reduce the interest rate. We document that the average valuation bias for residential refinance transactions is above 5%. The bias is larger for highly leveraged transactions, around critical leverage thresholds, and for transactions mediated through a broker. Mortgages with inflated valuations default more often. Lenders account for 60%-90% of the bias through pricing.</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; Ben-David, Itzhak; Yao, Vincent</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-Term Strategic Asset Allocation: An Out-of-Sample Evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diris, Bart; Palm, Franz; Schotman, Peter
We evaluate the out-of-sample performance of a long-term investor who follows an optimized dynamic trading strategy. Although the dynamic strategy is able to benefit from predictability out-of-sample, a short-term investor using a single-period market timing strategy would have realized an almost identical performance. The value of intertemporal hedge demands in strategic asset allocation appears negligible. The result is caused by the estimation error in predicting the predictors. A myopic investor only needs to predict one-period-ahead expected returns, but hedge demands also require accurate predictions of the predictor variables. To reduce the problem of errors in optimized portfolio weights, we consider Bayesian procedures. Myopic and dynamic portfolios are similarly affected by such modifications, and differences in performance become even smaller.</description><author>Diris, Bart; Palm, Franz; Schotman, Peter</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Founder or Joiner? The Role of Preferences and Context in Shaping Different Entrepreneurial Interests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roach, Michael; Sauermann, Henry
Entrepreneurial ventures rely not only on founders but also on "joiners"-start-up employees who are attracted to entrepreneurship, but who do not want to be founders themselves. Drawing on both preference and contextual theories of entrepreneurship, we examine how individuals' interest in being a founder, a joiner, or neither forms prior to the first career transition. We find that although individuals with founder and joiner interests share similar preferences for entrepreneurial job attributes such as autonomy and risk, their preferences for these attributes also differ in significantly meaningful ways. Contextual factors such as norms, role models, and opportunities exhibit very different relationships with founder and joiner interests. Most interestingly, our results suggest that preferences and context interrelate in unique ways to shape different entrepreneurial interests. In particular, an interest in being a founder is most strongly associated with individuals' preferences for entrepreneurial job attributes, whereas contextual factors do little to shape a founder interest in individuals who lack these preferences. An interest in being a joiner, on the other hand, is associated with both preferences and context, and this relationship is most pronounced for individuals with preferences that predispose them toward entrepreneurship. This study highlights joiners as a distinct type of entrepreneurial actor and demonstrates the importance of considering the interplay between preferences and context in the study of entrepreneurship.</description><author>Roach, Michael; Sauermann, Henry</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Empirical Investigation of Dynamic Ordering Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Larson, Chad R.; Turcic, Danko; Zhang, Fuqiang
Adaptive base stock policy is a well-known tool for managing inventories in nonstationary demand environments. This paper presents empirical tests of this policy using aggregate, firm-level data. First, we extend a single-item adaptive base stock policy in previous literature to a multi-item case. Second, we transform the policy derived for the multi-item case to a regression model that relates firm-level inventory purchases to firm-level sales and changes in sales forecasts. We focus on two research questions: Can the adaptive base stock policy explain cross-sectional ordering behaviors under sales growth? To the extent that the adaptive base stock policy fails to explain ordering behaviors under sales growth, are there frictions that explain such a finding? Our empirical results demonstrate disparities in ordering behaviors between firms experiencing high and moderate sales growth. Contrary to theoretical prediction, this implies that inventory purchases are a function of not only current sales and changes in sales forecast but also past sales growth. As potential explanations for this departure from theoretical prediction, we show that both future demand dynamics and inventory holding risks depend on past sales growth. In addition, we find that firms' inventory holding risks may also be affected by purchasing constraints imposed by supply chain contracts. Our results provide managerial implications for practitioners and inform future theoretical research.</description><author>Larson, Chad R.; Turcic, Danko; Zhang, Fuqiang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Advance Selling: Effects of Interdependent Consumer Valuations and Seller's Capacity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yu, Man; Kapuscinski, Roman; Ahn, Hyun-Soo
We examine the impact of consumer valuation interdependence and capacity on a firm's optimal selling strategies. We consider a seller who can offer a single product to consumers twice, in advance and in spot. Consumers choose whether and when to buy, but if they buy in advance, they are uncertain about their own valuations. Whether they buy in advance or in spot, consumers' valuations are realized in the spot period and they may range from fully independent to perfectly correlated, creating markets with different characteristics of aggregate demand for the seller. Facing these consumers, the seller chooses a portion of the total capacity to offer in advance and prices in both periods. We describe how the optimal strategy and benefits of advance selling depend on the interdependence of consumer valuation, as well as capacity level and other market parameters. We find that a change in valuation interdependence can lead to dramatically different policies for the seller. For example, when individual valuations are highly diverse and the consumer population is large, the seller must offer a discount during advance selling but may limit the advance sales. On the other hand, when valuations are highly correlated, the seller can charge a premium price during advance selling. For the same valuation interdependence, the qualitative nature of the optimal strategy changes with available capacity.</description><author>Yu, Man; Kapuscinski, Roman; Ahn, Hyun-Soo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Dual Sourcing and Order Smoothing: The Impact of Capacity and Lead Times</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boute, Robert N.; Van Mieghem, Jan A.
After decades of offshoring production across the world, companies are rethinking their global networks. Local sourcing is receiving more attention, but it remains challenging to balance the offshore sourcing cost advantage against the increased inventories, because of its longer lead time, and against the cost and (volume) flexibility of each source's capacity. To guide strategic allocation in this global network decision, this paper establishes reasonably simple prescriptions that capture the key drivers. We adopt a conventional discrete-time inventory model with a linear control rule that smoothes orders and allows an exact and analytically tractable analysis of single-and dual-sourcing policies under normal demand. Distinguishing features of our model are that it captures each source's lead time, capacity cost, and flexibility to work overtime. We use Lagrange's inversion theorem to provide exact and simple square-root bound formulae for the strategic sourcing allocations and the value of dual sourcing. The formulae provide structural insight on the impact of financial, operational, and demand parameters, and a starting point for quantitative decision making. We investigate the robustness of our results by comparing the smoothing policy with existing single-and dual-sourcing models in a simulation study that relaxes model assumptions.</description><author>Boute, Robert N.; Van Mieghem, Jan A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Branding Conspicuous Goods: An Analysis of the Effects of Social Influence and Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amaldoss, Wilfred; Jain, Sanjay
Branding decisions are critical for the success of new products. Prior research on branding and brand extension has primarily focused on how branding influences consumers' perceptions of product quality. However, consumers of conspicuous goods care not only about product quality but also about the profile of its users. For example, high-end consumers prefer an exclusive brand. On the other hand, low-end consumers may find a brand more attractive if high-end consumers use it. In this paper, we analyze how social effects and market structure can influence the branding of conspicuous goods. Consistent with intuition, our theoretical analysis shows that a monopolist would prefer not to use umbrella branding when consumers' desire for uniqueness is high. By contrast, in a competitive market, umbrella branding is more profitable than individual branding when consumers have a high level of desire for uniqueness. We also identify conditions in which it is optimal for marketers of conspicuous goods to adopt either an individual branding strategy or asymmetric branding strategies. Furthermore, competing firms may offer umbrella branding even when both firms may be better off if they could commit to using individual branding. Finally, we extend the model to consider a market where consumers' product preference is not related to social status. Again, if consumers are sufficiently snobbish, competing firms earn more profits by adopting an umbrella branding strategy instead of an individual branding strategy.</description><author>Amaldoss, Wilfred; Jain, Sanjay</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Dollar for Your Thoughts: Feedback-Conditional Rebates on eBay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cabral, Luis; Li, Lingfang
We run a series of controlled field experiments on eBay where buyers are rewarded for providing feedback. Our results provide little support for the hypothesis of buyers' rational economic behavior: the likelihood of feedback barely increases as we increase feedback rebate values; also, the speed of feedback, bid levels, and the number of bids are all insensitive to rebate values. By contrast, we find evidence consistent with reciprocal buyer behavior. Lower transaction quality leads to a higher probability of negative feedback as well as a speeding up of such negative feedback. However, when transaction quality is low (as measured by slow shipping), offering a rebate significantly decreases the likelihood of negative feedback. All in all, our results are consistent with the hypothesis that buyers reciprocate the sellers' "good deeds" (feedback rebate, high transaction quality) with more frequent and more favorable feedback. As a result, sellers can "buy" feedback, but such feedback is likely to be biased.</description><author>Cabral, Luis; Li, Lingfang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Tips Increase Workers' Income?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shy, Oz
This paper constructs a model of service providers who compete in service and labor markets simultaneously to analyze the effects of tipping on hourly wages and total tip-inclusive hourly worker compensation. An increase in the tipping rate reduces hourly wages. Total worker compensation increases at different rates depending on the market structure, market coverage, and employment level, with the exception of price-taking (competitive) service providers, where the tip-inclusive hourly income declines with the tipping rate. The paper develops an index of "effective tipping" that measures the net percentage change in total hourly worker compensation associated with each tipping rate.</description><author>Shy, Oz</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Threshold Effects in Online Group Buying</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Jiahua; Shi, Mengze; Hu, Ming
This paper studies two types of threshold-induced effects: a surge of new sign-ups around the time when the thresholds of group-buying deals are reached, and a stronger positive relation between the number of new sign-ups and the cumulative number of sign-ups before the thresholds are reached than afterward. This empirical study uses a data set that records the intertemporal cumulative number of sign-ups for group-buying deals in 86 city markets covered by Groupon, during a period of 71 days when Groupon predominantly used "a deal a day" format for each local market and posted the number of sign-ups in real time. We find that the first type of threshold effect is significant in all product categories and in all markets. The second type of threshold effect varies across product categories and markets. Our results underscore the importance of considering product and market characteristics in threshold design decisions for online group buying.</description><author>Wu, Jiahua; Shi, Mengze; Hu, Ming</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Women Avoid Salary Negotiations? Evidence from a Large-Scale Natural Field Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leibbrandt, Andreas; List, John A.
One explanation advanced for the persistent gender pay differences in labor markets is that women avoid salary negotiations. By using a natural field experiment that randomizes nearly 2,500 job seekers into jobs that vary important details of the labor contract, we are able to observe both the extent of salary negotiations and the nature of sorting. We find that when there is no explicit statement that wages are negotiable, men are more likely to negotiate for a higher wage, whereas women are more likely to signal their willingness to work for a lower wage. However, when we explicitly mention the possibility that wages are negotiable, these differences disappear completely. In terms of sorting, we find that men, in contrast to women, prefer job environments where the "rules of wage determination" are ambiguous. This leads to the gender gap being much more pronounced in jobs that leave negotiation of wage ambiguous.</description><author>Leibbrandt, Andreas; List, John A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Product-Level Uncertainty and Online Purchase Behavior: An Empirical Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Youngsoo; Krishnan, Ramayya
Online consumers are uncertain about subjective product quality (e.g., fit and feel of clothing and texture of materials) because of the absence of experiential information. In this paper, we examine the dynamic change of the products purchased online over time in the presence of this type of uncertainty. Using individual-level transaction data, we find that consumers purchase products with a high degree of product uncertainty as their online shopping experiences help them better estimate product quality. Our results also show that the average and highest prices of market baskets decrease (around 1%) when online shopping experience increases (10%). This implies that online consumers are reluctant to buy expensive products with only digitally transferred information, whereas they tend to purchase more of the cheaper products online along with their accumulated online shopping experience. We also verify the interaction effects of product uncertainty and product price on online consumers' purchase decision. When online consumers buy products priced under $50, they readily buy products with a high degree of product uncertainty regardless of their online shopping experience. But consumers are unlikely to buy expensive products online if there is a high degree of product uncertainty, even when they have accumulated much online shopping experience. In addition, we find that online vendors can effectively overcome product-level uncertainty by taking advantage of retailer reputation in the physical world and through the use of digitized video commercials. Our study on the dynamics in the set of products purchased online expands the understanding of consumer purchase behavior under uncertainty.</description><author>Kim, Youngsoo; Krishnan, Ramayya</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Of Age, Sex, and Money: Insights from Corporate Officer Compensation on the Wage Inequality Between Genders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Newton, David; Simutin, Mikhail
This paper shows that the gender and age of the wage setter are crucial determinants of the disparity in wages between sexes. We document our findings using a data set on compensation of corporate officers that is uniquely suited for this analysis because officer wages are set by chief executive officers (CEOs). We show that CEOs pay officers of the opposite gender less than officers of their own gender, even when controlling for job characteristics. Older and male CEOs exhibit the greatest propensity to differentiate on the basis of sex. Female officers receive smaller raises if the firm is headed by a man. Our results suggest that CEO gender and age are economically more important determinants of officer compensation than are firm stock performance, stock volatility, or return on assets.</description><author>Newton, David; Simutin, Mikhail</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gender Differences in the Willingness to Compete Emerge Early in Life and Persist</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sutter, Matthias; Glaetzle-Ruetzler, Daniela
Gender differences in the willingness to compete have been identified as one important factor in explaining gender differences in labor markets and within organizations. We present three experiments with a total of 1,570 subjects, ages three to 18 years, to investigate the origins of this gender gap. In a between-subjects design we find that boys are more likely to compete than girls as early as kindergarten and that this gap prevails throughout adolescence. Re-examining the behavior of 316 subjects in a within-subjects design two years later, we show that these gender differences also largely persist over a longer time period and can thus be considered stable. Controlling for subjects' abilities in the different tasks, their risk attitudes, and expected performance, the gender gap in the willingness to compete is estimated in the range of 10-20 percentage points. We discuss the implications of our findings for policy interventions and organizational management. Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2014.1981.</description><author>Sutter, Matthias; Glaetzle-Ruetzler, Daniela</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Supply Chain Effects of Bankruptcy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, S. Alex; Birge, John R.; Parker, Rodney P.
This paper examines how a firm's financial distress and the legal environment regarding the ease of bankruptcy reorganization can alter product market competition and supplier-buyer relationships. We identify three effects-predation, bail-out, and abetment-that can change firms' behavior from their actions in the absence of financial distress. The predation effect increases competition before potential bankruptcy as the nondistressed competitor behaves as if it has some first-mover advantage that could benefit a supplier with price control. The bail-out effect reflects the supplier's incentive to grant the distressed firm concessions to preserve competition, improving supply chain efficiency and providing support for the exclusivity rule in Chapter 11 of the United States Bankruptcy Code when the supplier and the distressed firm are financially linked. The abetment effect is that the supplier may deliberately abet the competitor's predation, leading to increased operational disadvantages for the distressed firm before bankruptcy. Together these effects stress that a firm's bankruptcy potential can hurt its competitors and benefit its suppliers/customers. They also provide guidelines for firms' operational decisions in such situations, a rationale for observed firm actions surrounding bankruptcies, and motivation for policies supporting reorganization and relaxing broad enforcement of nondiscriminatory pricing regulations.</description><author>Yang, S. Alex; Birge, John R.; Parker, Rodney P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cleaning House: The Impact of Information Technology Monitoring on Employee Theft and Productivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pierce, Lamar; Snow, Daniel C.; McAfee, Andrew
This paper examines how firm investments in technology-based employee monitoring impact both misconduct and productivity. We use unique and detailed theft and sales data from 392 restaurant locations from five firms that adopt a theft monitoring information technology (IT) product. We use difference-in-differences models with staggered adoption dates to estimate the treatment effect of IT monitoring on theft and productivity. We find significant treatment effects in reduced theft and improved productivity that appear to be primarily driven by changed worker behavior rather than worker turnover. We examine four mechanisms that may drive this productivity result: economic and cognitive multitasking, fairness-based motivation, and perceived increases of general oversight. The observed productivity results represent substantial financial benefits to both firms and the legitimate tip-based earnings of workers. Our results suggest that employee misconduct is not solely a function of individual differences in ethics or morality, but can also be influenced by managerial policies that can benefit both firms and employees.</description><author>Pierce, Lamar; Snow, Daniel C.; McAfee, Andrew</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Resource Allocation Decisions Under Imperfect Evaluation and Organizational Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schlapp, Jochen; Oraiopoulos, Nektarios; Mak, Vincent
Research and development (R&amp;D) projects face significant organizational challenges, especially when the different units who run these projects compete among each other for resources. In such cases, information sharing among the different units is critical, but it cannot be taken for granted. Instead, individual units need to be incentivized to not only exert effort in evaluating their projects, but also to truthfully reveal their findings. The former requires an emphasis on individual performance, whereas the latter relies on the existence of a common goal across the organization. Motivated by this commonly observed tension, we address the following question: How should a firm balance individual and shared incentives, so that vital information is both acquired, and equally importantly, disseminated to the entire organization? Our model captures two key characteristics of R&amp;D experimentation: information is imperfect and it is also costly. Our analysis yields several important implications for the design of such incentive schemes and the management of R&amp;D portfolios.</description><author>Schlapp, Jochen; Oraiopoulos, Nektarios; Mak, Vincent</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Linear Tests for Decreasing Absolute Risk Aversion Stochastic Dominance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Post, Thierry; Fang, Yi; Kopa, Milos
We develop and implement linear formulations of convex stochastic dominance relations based on decreasing absolute risk aversion (DARA) for discrete and polyhedral choice sets. Our approach is based on a piecewise-exponential representation of utility and a local linear approximation to the exponentiation of log marginal utility. An empirical application to historical stock market data suggests that a passive stock market portfolio is DARA stochastic dominance inefficient relative to concentrated portfolios of small-cap stocks. The mean-variance rule and Nth-order stochastic dominance rules substantially underestimate the degree of market portfolio inefficiency because they do not penalize the unfavorable skewness of diversified portfolios, in violation of DARA.</description><author>Post, Thierry; Fang, Yi; Kopa, Milos</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of Field Experiments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Jimmy Q.; Rusmevichientong, Paat; Simester, Duncan; Tsitsiklis, John N.; Zoumpoulis, Spyros I.
The feasibility of using field experiments to optimize marketing decisions remains relatively unstudied. We investigate category pricing decisions that require estimating a large matrix of cross-product demand elasticities and ask the following question: How many experiments are required as the number of products in the category grows? Our main result demonstrates that if the categories have a favorable structure, we can learn faster and reduce the number of experiments that are required: the number of experiments required may grow just logarithmically with the number of products. These findings potentially have important implications for the application of field experiments. Firms may be able to obtain meaningful estimates using a practically feasible number of experiments, even in categories with a large number of products. We also provide a relatively simple mechanism that firms can use to evaluate whether a category has a structure that makes it feasible to use field experiments to set prices. We illustrate how to accomplish this using either a sample of historical data or a pilot set of experiments. We also discuss how to evaluate whether field experiments can help optimize other marketing decisions, such as selecting which products to advertise or promote.</description><author>Li, Jimmy Q.; Rusmevichientong, Paat; Simester, Duncan; Tsitsiklis, John N.; Zoumpoulis, Spyros I.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Compact Bid Languages and Core Pricing in Large Multi-item Auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goetzendorff, Andor; Bichler, Martin; Shabalin, Pasha; Day, Robert W.
We introduce an auction design framework for large markets with hundreds of items and complex bidder preferences. Such markets typically lead to computationally hard allocation problems. Our new framework consists of compact bid languages for sealed-bid auctions and methods to compute second-price rules such as the Vickrey-Clarke-Groves or bidder-optimal, core-selecting payment rules when the optimality of the allocation problem cannot be guaranteed. To demonstrate the efficacy of the approach for a specific, complex market, we introduce a compact bidding language for TV advertising markets and investigate the resulting winner-determination problem and the computation of core payments. For realistic instances of the respective winner-determination problems, very good solutions with a small integrality gap can be found quickly, although closing the integrality gap to find marginally better solutions or prove optimality can take a prohibitively large amount of time. Our subsequent adaptation of a constraint-generation technique for the computation of bidder-optimal core payments to this environment is a practically viable paradigm by which core-selecting auction designs can be applied to large markets with potentially hundreds of items. Such auction designs allow bidders to express their preferences with a low number of parameters, while at the same time providing incentives for truthful bidding. We complement our computational experiments in the context of TV advertising markets with additional results for volume discount auctions in procurement to illustrate the applicability of the approach in different types of large markets.</description><author>Goetzendorff, Andor; Bichler, Martin; Shabalin, Pasha; Day, Robert W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Management Earnings Forecasts and Value of Analyst Forecast Revisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Yongtae; Song, Minsup
This study examines the stock-price reactions to analyst forecast revisions around earnings announcements to test whether preannouncement forecasts reflect analysts' private information or piggybacking on confounding events and news. We find that management earnings forecasts influence the timing and precision of analyst forecasts. More importantly, evidence suggests that prior studies' finding of weaker (stronger) stock-price responses to forecast revisions in the period immediately after (before) the prior-quarter earnings announcement disappears once management earnings forecasts are controlled for. To the extent that management earnings forecasts are public disclosures, our results suggest that the importance of analysts' information discovery role documented in prior studies is likely to be overstated.</description><author>Kim, Yongtae; Song, Minsup</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Repurchasing Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mao, Lei; Tserlukevich, Yuri
In this paper we build a theoretical model of a firm repurchasing its corporate debt. We find that firm creditors as a group sell debt to the firm only at face value. However, because of the cross-creditor externalities, buying back debt is cheaper and easier when there are many creditors, e.g., when debt is traded on the open market. We further show that repurchases contribute to flexibility in firms' capital structure and can increase ex ante firm value. The value of repurchases to the shareholders increases with the firm's ability to save cash and delay the repurchase.</description><author>Mao, Lei; Tserlukevich, Yuri</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Transparency and the Impact of Investor Sentiment on Stock Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Firth, Michael; Wang, Kailong; Wong, Sonia M. L.
Using China's stock market as the testing venue, this study examines how corporate transparency helps explain the sensitivity of stock prices to general investor sentiment. We find that firms with low corporate transparency, measured by a battery of proxies including state ownership, the prevalence of related party transactions, accrual-based earnings management, audit opinions, and the quality of audit firms, are more affected by investor sentiment than are firms with high corporate transparency. Overall, our findings highlight the importance of corporate transparency in mitigating the effects of investor sentiment on stock prices.</description><author>Firth, Michael; Wang, Kailong; Wong, Sonia M. L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Theory of Market Pioneers, Dynamic Capabilities, and Industry Evolution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mitchell, Matthew; Skrzypacz, Andrzej
We analyze a model of industry evolution where the number of active submarkets is endogenously determined by pioneering innovation from incumbents and entrants. Incumbent pioneers enjoy an advantage of additional pioneering innovation via a dynamic capability that takes the form of an improved technology for innovation in young submarkets. Entrants are motivated in part by a desire to acquire the dynamic capability. We show that dynamic capabilities increase total innovation, but whether the capability confers an advantage in terms of marginal or average cost is important in determining how the impact of dynamic capabilities is distributed across incumbent and entrant innovation rates. We complement the existing literature-that focuses on exogenous arrival of submarkets or the steady state of a model with constant submarkets-by describing how competition, free entry, and the dynamic capability of incumbents drive the evolution of an industry. The shift from immature to mature submarkets can lead to a shakeout in firm numbers, and it eventually leads to a reduction in total dynamic capabilities in an industry.</description><author>Mitchell, Matthew; Skrzypacz, Andrzej</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Advance Scheduling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Truong, Van-Anh
The dynamic assignment of patients to exam days in order to manage daily variations in demand and capacity is a long-standing open research area in appointment scheduling. In particular, the dynamic assignment of advance appointments has been considered to be especially challenging because of its high dimensionality. We consider a canonical model of dynamic advance scheduling with two patient classes: an urgent demand class, which must be served on the day of arrival, and a regular demand class, which can be served at a future date. Patients take the earliest appointments offered and do not differentiate among providers. We derive a surprising characterization of an optimal policy and an algorithm to compute the policy exactly and efficiently. These are, to our knowledge, the first analytical results for the dynamic advance assignment of patients to exam days. We introduce the property of successive refinability, which allows advance schedules to be easily computable and under which there is no cost to the system to making advance commitments to patients. We allow multiple types of capacity to be considered and both demand and capacity to be nonstationary and stochastic.</description><author>Truong, Van-Anh</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analysis of Tailored Base-Surge Policies in Dual Sourcing Inventory Systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Janakiraman, Ganesh; Seshadri, Sridhar; Sheopuri, Anshul
We study a model of a firm managing its inventory of a single product by sourcing supplies from two supply sources, a regular supplier who offers a lower unit cost and a longer lead time than a second, emergency, supplier. A practically implementable policy for such a firm is a tailored base-surge (TBS) policy [Allon G, Van Mieghem JA (2010) Global dual sourcing: Tailored base-surge allocation to near-and offshore production. Management Sci. 56(1):110-124] to manage its inventory. Under this policy, the firm procures a constant quantity from the regular supplier in every period and dynamically makes procurement decisions for the emergency supplier. Allon and Van Mieghem describe this practice as using the regular supplier to meet a base level of demand and the emergency supplier to manage demand surges, and they conjecture that this practice is most effective when the lead time difference between the two suppliers is large. We confirm these statements in two ways. First, we show the following analytical result: when demand is composed of a base demand random component plus a surge demand random component, which occurs with a certain small probability, the best TBS policy is close to optimal (over all policies) in a well-defined sense. Second, we also numerically investigate the cost effectiveness of the best TBS policy on a test bed of problem instances. The emphasis of this investigation is the study of the effect of the lead time difference between the two suppliers. Our study reveals that the cost difference between the best TBS policy and the optimal policy decreases dramatically as the lead time of the regular supplier increases. On our test bed, this cost difference decreases from an average (over the test bed) of 21% when the lead time from the regular supplier is two periods (the emergency supplier offers instant delivery) to 3.5% when that lead time is seven periods.</description><author>Janakiraman, Ganesh; Seshadri, Sridhar; Sheopuri, Anshul</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inducing Social Norms in Laboratory Allocation Choices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schram, Arthur; Charness, Gary
Social norms involve observation by others and external sanctions for violations, whereas moral norms involve introspection and internal sanctions. To study such norms and their effects, we design a laboratory experiment. We examine dictator choices, where we create a shared understanding by providing advice from peers with no financial payoff at stake. We vary whether advice is given, as well as whether choices are made public. This design allows us to explicitly separate the effects of moral and social norms. We find that choices are in fact affected by a combination of observability and shared understanding.</description><author>Schram, Arthur; Charness, Gary</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A New Solution for the Moral Hazard Problem in Team Production</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guillen, Pablo; Merrett, Danielle; Slonim, Robert
We propose an intergroup competition scheme (ICS) to theoretically solve free riding in team production and provide experimental evidence from a voluntary contribution mechanism public goods game. The ICS includes an internal transfer payment from the lowest to highest contributing team proportional to the difference in group contributions. The ICS requires minimal information, makes the efficient contribution a dominant strategy, and is budget balanced. These features make the ICS ideally suited to solve the moral hazard problem in team production. Our experiment demonstrates that the ICS raises contributions to almost reach optimality with the appropriate parameters. We also show experimentally that the success of the ICS can be primarily attributed to the effect of higher returns and to the introduction of competition, and it is not due to the introduction of potential losses or information regarding other groups.</description><author>Guillen, Pablo; Merrett, Danielle; Slonim, Robert</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bonus Payments and Reference Point Violations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ockenfels, Axel; Sliwka, Dirk; Werner, Peter
We investigate how bonus payments affect the satisfaction and performance of managers in a large multinational company. We find that falling behind a natural reference standard for a fair bonus payment (a "reference point violation") reduces satisfaction and subsequent performance. The effects are mitigated if information about one's relative standing toward the reference point is withheld. A model and a laboratory experiment provide complementary insights and additional robustness checks.</description><author>Ockenfels, Axel; Sliwka, Dirk; Werner, Peter</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exploring Trade-offs in the Organization of Scientific Work: Collaboration and Scientific Reward</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bikard, Michael; Murray, Fiona; Gans, Joshua S.
When do scientists and other innovators organize into collaborative teams, and why do they do so for some projects and not others? At the core of this important organizational choice is, we argue, a trade-off scientists make between the productive efficiency of collaboration and the credit allocation that arises after the completion of collaborative work. In this paper, we explore this trade-off by developing a model to structure our understanding of the factors shaping researcher collaborative choices, in particular the implicit allocation of credit among participants in scientific projects. We then use the annual research activity of 661 faculty scientists at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology over a 31-year period to explore the trade-off between collaboration and reward at the individual faculty level and to infer critical parameters in the collaborative organization of scientific work.</description><author>Bikard, Michael; Murray, Fiona; Gans, Joshua S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Counterfactual Decomposition of Movie Star Effects with Star Selection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Angela; Mazumdar, Tridib; Li, Bo
We investigate the effects of a movie star on the movie's opening week theater allocations and box office revenue. Because the pairing of a star and a movie involves a bilateral matching process between the studio and the star, the star (hence the nonstar) movie samples are nonrandom and the star variable is potentially endogenous. To assess the star as well as movie characteristics effects, we utilize a switching model to account for endogenous assignment of stars and nonstars into respective movie samples. In addition to controlling for selection biases, the endogenous switching model generates managerially relevant insights into the factors that influence a star's assignment to a movie. Additionally, because the star and nonstar movie characteristics (e.g., movie budget, distribution, genre, etc.) are often systematically different, we counterfactually estimate the theater allocations and revenues that nonstars (stars) would have generated had they acted in movies endowed with the same characteristics as the star (nonstar) movies. The decomposition analysis, conducted at different quantiles of theater and revenue distributions, shows that the presence of a star has a much stronger effect on theater allocations than the movie characteristics have. However, the revenue difference is entirely contributed by the differences in the characteristics of the star and nonstar movies. Thus, the star effects on revenue come indirectly through the theater allocations as well as from the characteristics of the movies in which they participate.</description><author>Liu, Angela; Mazumdar, Tridib; Li, Bo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Empirical Investigation on the Appointments of Supply Chain and Operations Management Executives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hendricks, Kevin B.; Hora, Manpreet; Singhal, Vinod R.
This paper provides empirical evidence on the performance effects and choice of appointments of supply chain and operations management executives (SCOMEs). The analysis is based on a sample of 681 SCOME appointments that were publicly announced during the 2000-2011 period. We find that the stock market reaction is positive on the day of the announcement. Categorizing the SCOME appointments as new or old and insider or outsider, we find that the market reaction for newly created SCOME positions is positive. The market also reacts more positively when a SCOME is an outsider rather than an insider. The strongest positive reaction is observed when outsiders are hired for newly created SCOME positions. We find evidence of both poor stock price performance and poor operating performance in the period preceding the appointment of new SCOMEs. New SCOME appointments are not followed by an immediate improvement in stock price and operating performance. However, there is no further decline in performance, suggesting that the decline observed in the preappointment period does not continue after the new SCOME is appointed. We also find that the likelihood of a SCOME being an outsider is greater for firms that are smaller, operate in more concentrated industries, and have experienced poor prior performance.</description><author>Hendricks, Kevin B.; Hora, Manpreet; Singhal, Vinod R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Signaling New Product Reliability with After-Sales Service Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, Nitin; Kim, Sang-Hyun; Savva, Nicos
Prior studies on performance-based contracting (PBC) for after-sales services have highlighted its advantages over traditional resource-based contracting (RBC), when products are established and their reliability is known to all parties. We develop a game theoretic model to investigate how these insights are affected when the vendor is privately informed about the reliability of a newly developed product. A novel feature of our model is the interaction between reliability signaling (private information) and the vendor's discretionary investment in spares inventory (private action), which arises naturally in the setting we consider. We find that this interaction leads to contrasting equilibrium outcomes under the two contracts: RBC induces the vendor to focus on inventory savings, leading to underinvestment in spares, whereas PBC induces the vendor to focus on reliability signaling, achieved through overinvestment in inventory. As a result, neither contract is efficient. We investigate two means to mitigate this inefficiency, but either approach has caveats: (a) making inventory verifiable removes the trade-off between reliability signaling and inventory investment, but results in diverging contract preferences between the vendor and the buyer; (b) pooling inventories across multiple buyers saves inventory costs but it also hinders reliability signaling, potentially exacerbating inefficiency.</description><author>Bakshi, Nitin; Kim, Sang-Hyun; Savva, Nicos</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Probabilistic Selling in Quality-Differentiated Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Zelin; Joseph, Kissan; Subramaniam, Ramanathan
Probabilistic selling-the sale of synthetic products consisting of a lottery between two distinct goods-has been extensively analyzed in horizontal markets. In this research, we investigate probabilistic selling in quality-differentiated markets. This is an important new dimension of inquiry because of the widespread prevalence of quality-differentiated markets as well as significant differences in the preference structure across these markets. In fact, this latter consideration casts doubt as to whether probabilistic selling will even emerge in quality-differentiated markets. We find that probabilistic selling emerges in quality-differentiated markets as a way to profitably dispose excess capacity; moreover, probabilistic selling remains viable even under endogenous quality choice. In addition, in markets where sellers employ "strong" quality differentiation, the introduction of an intermediate probabilistic good actually causes closer quality levels in a product line and enhances consumer welfare. In contrast, in markets where sellers employ "weak" quality differentiation, the introduction of an intermediate probabilistic good increases quality separation and degrades consumer welfare. Overall, we view our contribution as one of characterizing the optimality, implementation, and policy implications of probabilistic selling in quality-differentiated markets.</description><author>Zhang, Zelin; Joseph, Kissan; Subramaniam, Ramanathan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Failure of Hindsight-Biased Principals to Delegate Optimally</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Danz, David; Kuebler, Dorothea; Mechtenberg, Lydia; Schmid, Julia
With the help of a simple model, we show that the hindsight bias can lead to inefficient delegation decisions. This prediction is tested experimentally. In an online experiment that was conducted during the FIFA World Cup 2010, participants were asked to predict a number of outcomes of the ongoing World Cup and had to recall their assessments after the outcomes had been realized. Their answers were used to construct individual measures of the hindsight bias. The participants also had to make choices in a delegation game. Our data confirm that hindsight-biased subjects more frequently fail to delegate optimally than subjects whom we have classified as not hindsight biased.</description><author>Danz, David; Kuebler, Dorothea; Mechtenberg, Lydia; Schmid, Julia</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Demand Effects of Joint Product Advertising in Online Videos</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Anuj; Tan, Yinliang
Joint product display in videos may help customers to not only evaluate the attributes of products that can influence their individual demands (direct effect) but also learn about the complementarity between them that may cause additional correlation in their demands (spillover effect). To estimate the demand effects, we introduced videos displaying apparel with matching accessories for a few randomly selected apparel on a fashion retailer's website. We found that introducing a video resulted in a 14.5% increase in apparel sales and a 28.3% increase in accessories sales. The estimated increase in accessories sales was largely attributed to the spillover effect of videos. Moreover, introducing videos with other product promotions resulted in a significantly higher effect of videos on product demands. Overall, we show how video display of related products can increase their demands in an online product network.</description><author>Kumar, Anuj; Tan, Yinliang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational Speculators, Contrarians, and Excess Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lof, Matthijs
The vector autoregressive approach for testing present value models is applied to a heterogeneous-agent asset pricing model using historical observations of the S&amp;P 500 index. Besides fundamentalists, who value assets according to expected dividends, the model features rational and contrarian speculators. Agents choose their strategy based on evolutionary considerations. Supplementing the standard present value model with speculative agents dramatically improves the model's ability to replicate observed market dynamics. In particular, the existence of contrarians can explain some of the most volatile episodes including the 1990s bubble, suggesting this was not a rational bubble.</description><author>Lof, Matthijs</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition in Portfolio Management: Theory and Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asparouhova, Elena; Bossaerts, Peter; Copic, Jernej; Cornell, Brad; Cvitanic, Jaksa; Meloso, Debrah
We explore theoretically and experimentally the general equilibrium price and allocation implications of delegated portfolio management when the investor-manager relationship is nonexclusive. Our theory predicts that competition forces managers to promise portfolios that mimic Arrow-Debreu (AD) securities, which investors then combine to fit their preferences. A weak version of the capital asset pricing model (CAPM) obtains, where state prices (relative to state probabilities) implicit in prices of traded securities will be inversely ranked to aggregate wealth across states. Our experiment broadly corroborates the price and choice predictions of the theory. However, price quality deteriorates when only a few managers attract most of the available wealth. Wealth concentration increases because funds flow toward managers who offer portfolios closer to replicating AD securities (as in the theory), but also because funds flow to managers who had better performance in the immediate past (an observation unrelated to the theory).</description><author>Asparouhova, Elena; Bossaerts, Peter; Copic, Jernej; Cornell, Brad; Cvitanic, Jaksa; Meloso, Debrah</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Market Competition and the Financing of New Ventures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Bettignies, Jean-Etienne; Duchene, Anne
This paper examines the interaction between venture risk, product market competition, and the entrepreneur's choice between bank financing and venture capital (VC) financing. Under bank financing, a debt-type contract emerges as optimal, which allows the entrepreneur to retain full control of the venture and thus yields strong effort incentives, as long as the entrepreneur can service the debt repayment; however, this leads to liquidation in the case of default, making the venture's success quite sensitive to exogenous, even temporary, shocks that may hinder debt repayment. Under VC financing, an equity-type contract emerges as optimal. Although it is not sensitive to exogenous shocks, this contract requires the entrepreneur to share a fraction of the rents with the financier, thus yielding lower effort incentives for the entrepreneur. There exists a threshold level of venture risk such that bank financing is optimal if and only if venture risk is below that threshold. Product market competition increases the value of stronger entrepreneurial incentives and thus increases the maximum level of risk the entrepreneur is willing to take before switching from bank financing to VC financing. This is a robust result that is shown to hold in various models of competition, including the Hotelling, Salop, Dixit-Stiglitz, and Cournot-to-Bertrand switch.</description><author>de Bettignies, Jean-Etienne; Duchene, Anne</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Good-Looking People More Employable?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ruffle, Bradley J.; Shtudiner, Ze'ev
We investigate the role of physical attractiveness in the hiring process. We sent 5,312 curricula vitae (CVs) in pairs to 2,656 advertised job openings. In each pair, one CV was without a picture, whereas the second, otherwise almost identical CV contained a picture of either an attractive male or female or a plain-looking male or female. Employer callbacks to attractive men are significantly higher than to men with no picture and to plain-looking men, nearly doubling the latter group. Strikingly, attractive women do not enjoy the same beauty premium. In fact, women with no picture have a significantly higher rate of callback than attractive or plain-looking women. We explore a number of explanations for this discrimination against attractive women and provide evidence that female jealousy and envy are likely reasons.</description><author>Ruffle, Bradley J.; Shtudiner, Ze'ev</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effectiveness of Field Price Discretion: Empirical Evidence from Auto Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phillips, Robert; Simsek, A. Serdar; van Ryzin, Garrett
In many markets, it is common for headquarters to create a price list but grant local salespeople discretion to negotiate prices for individual transactions. How much (if any) pricing discretion headquarters should grant is a topic of debate within many firms. We investigate this issue using a unique data set from an indirect lender with local pricing discretion. We estimate that the local sales force adjusted prices in a way that improved profits by approximately 11% on average. A counterfactual analysis shows that using a centralized, data-driven pricing optimization system could improve profits even further, up to 20% over those actually realized. This suggests that centralized pricing-if appropriately optimized-can be more effective than field price discretion. We discuss the implications of these findings for auto lending and other industries with similar pricing processes.</description><author>Phillips, Robert; Simsek, A. Serdar; van Ryzin, Garrett</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gaining Access by Doing Good: The Effect of Sociopolitical Reputation on Firm Participation in Public Policy Making</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Werner, Timothy
This paper examines the role of firms' sociopolitical reputations, as proxied by their perceived engagement in socially responsible practices, in public policy makers' decisions to grant access in the policy-making process. I argue that policy makers' dependencies, motivations, and decision-making processes lead them to evaluate firms by using sociopolitical reputation as a differentiating heuristic. I hypothesize that firms that construct stronger sociopolitical reputations will be granted greater access and that firms' existing political activity and policy makers' partisanship will moderate this relationship. I test these hypotheses using an 11-year panel on congressional testimony, reputation, and political and financial characteristics for the S&amp;P 500 and find support for all three. These findings support the existence of a sociopolitical dimension to firms' reputations that affects how public policy makers evaluate firms, demonstrating that corporate social responsibility pays political benefits.</description><author>Werner, Timothy</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why and When Consumers Prefer Products of User-Driven Firms: A Social Identification Account</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahl, Darren W.; Fuchs, Christoph; Schreier, Martin
B Companies are increasingly drawing on their user communities to generate promising ideas for new products, which are then marketed as "user-designed" products to the broader consumer market. We demonstrate that nonparticipating, observing consumers prefer to buy from user-rather than designer-driven firms because of an enhanced identification with the firm that has adopted this user-driven philosophy. Three experimental studies validate a newly proposed social identification account underlying this effect. Because consumers are also users, their social identities connect to the user-designers, and they feel empowerment by vicariously being involved in the design process. This formed connection leads to preference for the firm's products. Importantly, this social identification account also effectively predicts when the effect does not materialize. First, we find that if consumers feel dissimilar to participating users, the effects are attenuated. We demonstrate that this happens when the community differs from consumers along important demographics (i.e., gender) or when consumers are nonexperts in the focal domain (i.e., they feel that they do not belong to the social group of participating users). Second, the effects are attenuated if the user-driven firm is only selectively rather than fully open to participation from all users (observing consumers do not feel socially included). These findings advance the emerging theory on user involvement and offer practical implications for firms interested in pursuing a user-driven philosophy.</description><author>Dahl, Darren W.; Fuchs, Christoph; Schreier, Martin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Your Online Friends Make You Pay? A Randomized Field Experiment on Peer Influence in Online Social Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bapna, Ravi; Umyarov, Akhmed
Demonstrating compelling causal evidence of the existence and strength of peer-to-peer influence has become the holy grail of modern research in online social networks. In these networks, it has been consistently demonstrated that user characteristics and behavior tend to cluster both in space and in time. There are multiple well-known rival mechanisms that compete to be the explanation for this observed clustering. These range from peer influence to homophily to other unobservable external stimuli. These multiple mechanisms lead to similar observational data, yet have vastly different policy implications. In this paper, we present a novel randomized experiment that tests the existence of causal peer influence in the general population-one that did not involve subject recruitment for experimentation-of a particular large-scale online social network. We utilize a unique social feature to exogenously induce adoption of a paid service among a group of randomly selected users, and in the process develop a clean exogenous randomization of treatment and control groups. A variety of nonparametric, semiparametric, and parametric approaches, ranging from resampling-based inference to ego-level random effects to logistic regression to survival models, yield close to identical, statistically and economically significant estimates of peer influence in the general population of a freemium social network. Our estimates show that peer influence causes more than a 60% increase in odds of buying the service due to the influence coming from an adopting friend. In addition, we find that users with a smaller number of friends experience stronger relative increase in the adoption likelihood due to influence from their peers as compared to the users with a larger number of friends. Our nonparametric resampling procedure-based estimates are helpful in situations of networked data that violate independence assumptions. We establish that peer influence is a powerful force in getting users from free to premium levels, a known challenge in freemium communities.</description><author>Bapna, Ravi; Umyarov, Akhmed</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Organizational Structure and Product Choice in Knowledge-Intensive Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Yanhui
This paper formulates a model in which a firm simultaneously chooses its organizational structure and product position. The firm's production is knowledge intensive, requiring employees to solve problems. A vertical hierarchy, in which workers refer unsolved problems to managers facilitates the acquisition and leveraging of managers' superior knowledge. I show that a larger span of control is complementary to the provision of high-value products. Moreover, this complementarity is sustained when employees acquire sufficient knowledge and is further strengthened when the firm enhances its capability of communicating knowledge. The model yields testable implications concerning (1) the fit between a firm's product position and span of control, (2) the effect of information technology on product innovations and skill-biased organizational changes, and (3) the heterogeneity in hierarchical structure and human resource management in professional service firms.</description><author>Wu, Yanhui</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Philanthropy and Productivity: Evidence from an Online Real Effort Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tonin, Mirco; Vlassopoulos, Michael
Contributing to a social cause can be an important driver for workers in the public and nonprofit sectors as well as in firms that engage in corporate philanthropy or other corporate social responsibility policies. This paper compares the effectiveness of a social incentive that takes the form of a donation received by a charity of the subject's choice to a financial incentive. We find that social incentives lead to a 13% rise in productivity, regardless of their form (lump sum or related to performance) or strength. The response is strong for subjects with low initial productivity (30%), whereas high-productivity subjects do not respond. When subjects can choose the mix of incentives, half sacrifice some of their private compensation to increase social compensation, with women more likely to do so than men. Furthermore, offering subjects some discretion in choosing their own payment schemes leads to a substantial improvement in performance. Comparing social incentives to equally costly increases in private compensation for low-productivity subjects reveals that the former are less effective in increasing productivity, but the difference is small and not statistically significant.</description><author>Tonin, Mirco; Vlassopoulos, Michael</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fair Wages and Effort Provision: Combining Evidence from a Choice Experiment and a Field Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohn, Alain; Fehr, Ernst; Goette, Lorenz
The presence of workers who reciprocate higher wages with greater effort can have important consequences for firms and labor markets. Knowledge about the extent and determinants of reciprocal effort choices is, however, incomplete. We investigate the role of fairness perceptions and social preferences in a field experiment in which workers were hired for a one-time job. We show that workers who perceive being underpaid at the base wage increase their performance if the hourly wage increases, whereas those who feel adequately paid or overpaid at the base wage do not change their performance. Moreover, we find that only the workers who display reciprocity in a choice experiment show reciprocal effort responses in the field. The workers who lack reciprocity in the choice experiment do not respond to the wage increase, even if they feel underpaid at the base wage. Our findings suggest that fairness perceptions and social preferences are key in workers' performance response to wage increases. In our study, the wage increase affects effort mainly through the removal of perceived unfairness, i.e., the elimination of negative reciprocity toward the firm, rather than positive reciprocity. These results are the first direct evidence of the fair-wage effort hypothesis in the field and also help interpret previous contradictory findings in the literature.</description><author>Cohn, Alain; Fehr, Ernst; Goette, Lorenz</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate General Counsel and Financial Reporting Quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hopkins, Justin J.; Maydew, Edward L.; Venkatachalam, Mohan
We examine the role of general counsel (GC) in firms' financial reporting quality. GCs have a broad oversight role within the firm, including keeping the firm in compliance with laws and regulations and dealing with potential violations with respect to financial reporting. Several high-profile U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) investigations have resulted in lawsuits or indictments against GCs for perpetrating financial fraud and caused many to ask: where were the gatekeepers? As such, we examine the conditions under which GCs may stray from their primary role as gatekeepers. Mainly, we empirically investigate claims that compensation can impair the independence or compromise the professional judgment of a GC. We measure the level of compensation using the GC's presence or absence in the top five officers of the firm by compensation. Results are consistent with GCs straying from their role as gatekeepers, to some extent, when highly compensated in a manner similar to the CEO and CFO. In particular, firms with highly compensated GCs have lower financial reporting quality and more aggressive accounting practices, including management of the litigation reserve. However, the results also show that highly compensated GCs play an important gatekeeping role in keeping the firm in compliance with generally accepted accounting principles. Thus, highly compensated GCs appear to tolerate moderately aggressive behavior but constrain it such that it would not result in violation of securities laws and jeopardize their standing within the firm.</description><author>Hopkins, Justin J.; Maydew, Edward L.; Venkatachalam, Mohan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decision Making Under Uncertainty When Preference Information Is Incomplete</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Armbruster, Benjamin; Delage, Erick
We consider the problem of optimal decision making under uncertainty but assume that the decision maker's utility function is not completely known. Instead, we consider all the utilities that meet some criteria, such as preferring certain lotteries over other lotteries and being risk averse, S-shaped, or prudent. These criteria extend the ones used in the first- and second-order stochastic dominance framework. We then give tractable formulations for such decision-making problems. We formulate them as robust utility maximization problems, as optimization problems with stochastic dominance constraints, and as robust certainty equivalent maximization problems. We use a portfolio allocation problem to illustrate our results.</description><author>Armbruster, Benjamin; Delage, Erick</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Logarithmic Safety Staffing Rule for Contact Centers with Call Blending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pang, Guodong; Perry, Ohad
We consider large contact centers that handle two types of jobs-inbound and outbound-simultaneously, a process commonly referred to as call blending. Inbound work arrives to the system according to an exogenous arrival process, whereas outbound work is generated by the contact center. We assume that there is an infinite supply of outbound work to process, and that inbound calls are prioritized over the outbound calls. We propose a logarithmic safety staffing rule, combined with a threshold control policy, ensuring that agents' utilization is very close to one at all times, but that there are practically always idle agents present. Specifically, we prove that it is possible to have almost all inbound calls answered immediately upon their arrival, in addition to satisfying a target long-run throughput rate of outbound calls, with at most a negligible proportion of those calls dropped. Simulation experiments demonstrate the effectiveness and accuracy of our analysis.</description><author>Pang, Guodong; Perry, Ohad</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Waiting Patiently: An Empirical Study of Queue Abandonment in an Emergency Department</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Batt, Robert J.; Terwiesch, Christian
We study queue abandonment from a hospital emergency department. We show that abandonment is influenced by the queue length and the observable queue flows during the waiting exposure, even after controlling for wait time. For example, observing an additional person in the queue or an additional arrival to the queue leads to an increase in abandonment probability equivalent to a 25-minute or 5-minute increase in wait time, respectively. We also show that patients are sensitive to being "jumped" in the line and that patients respond differently to people more sick and less sick moving through the system. This customer response to visual queue elements is not currently accounted for in most queuing models. Additionally, to the extent the visual queue information is misleading or does not lead to the desired behavior, managers have an opportunity to intervene by altering what information is available to waiting customers.</description><author>Batt, Robert J.; Terwiesch, Christian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Vision for Increasing Our Impact</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ho, Teck-Hua
nan</description><author>Ho, Teck-Hua</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Naivete, Projection Bias, and Habit Formation in Gym Attendance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acland, Dan; Levy, Matthew R.
We implement a gym-attendance incentive intervention and elicit subjects' predictions of their postintervention attendance. We find that subjects greatly overpredict future attendance, which we interpret as evidence of partial naivete with respect to present bias. We find a significant postintervention attendance increase, which we interpret as habit formation, and which subjects appear not to predict ex ante. These results are consistent with a model of projection bias with respect to habit formation. Neither the intervention incentives, nor the small posttreatment incentives involved in our elicitation mechanism, appear to crowd out existing intrinsic motivation. The combination of naivete and projection bias in gym attendance can help to explain limited take-up of commitment devices by dynamically inconsistent agents, and points to new forms of contracts. Alternative explanations of our results are discussed.</description><author>Acland, Dan; Levy, Matthew R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Marketplace or Reseller?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hagiu, Andrei; Wright, Julian
Intermediaries can choose between functioning as a marketplace (in which suppliers sell their products directly to buyers) or as a reseller (by purchasing products from suppliers and selling them to buyers). We model this as a decision between whether control rights over a noncontractible decision variable (the choice of some marketing activity) are better held by suppliers (the marketplace mode) or by the intermediary (the reseller mode). Whether the marketplace or the reseller mode is preferred depends on whether independent suppliers or the intermediary have more important information relevant to the optimal tailoring of marketing activities for each specific product. We show that this trade-off is shifted toward the reseller mode when marketing activities create spillovers across products and when network effects lead to unfavorable expectations about supplier participation. If the reseller has a variable cost advantage (respectively, disadvantage) relative to the marketplace, then the trade-off is shifted toward the marketplace for long-tail (respectively, short-tail) products. We thus provide a theory of which products an intermediary should offer in each mode. We also provide some empirical evidence that supports our main results.</description><author>Hagiu, Andrei; Wright, Julian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Vice-Virtue Bundles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Peggy J.; Haws, Kelly L.; Lamberton, Cait; Campbell, Troy H.; Fitzsimons, Gavan J.
We introduce a simple solution to help consumers manage choices between healthy and unhealthy food options: vice-virtue bundles. Vice-virtue bundles are item aggregates with varying proportions of both vice and virtue, holding overall quantity constant. Four studies compare choice and perceptions of differently composed vice-virtue bundles relative to one another and to pure vice and pure virtue options. Although multiple consumer segments can be identified, results suggest that people overall tend to prefer vice-virtue bundles with small (1 4) to medium (12) proportions of vice rather than large (3 4) proportions of vice. Moreover, people generally rate vice-virtue bundles with small vice proportions as healthier but similarly tasty as bundles with larger vice proportions. For most individuals, choice patterns are different from those predicted by variety-seeking accounts alone. Instead, these findings provide evidence of asymmetric effectiveness of small vice and virtue proportions at addressing taste and health goals, respectively.</description><author>Liu, Peggy J.; Haws, Kelly L.; Lamberton, Cait; Campbell, Troy H.; Fitzsimons, Gavan J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competing with Privacy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Casadesus-Masanell, Ramon; Hervas-Drane, Andres
We analyze the implications of consumer privacy for competition in the marketplace. Firms compete for consumer information and derive revenues both from consumer purchases as well as from disclosing consumer information in a secondary market. Consumers choose which firm to patronize and how much personal information to provide it with. We show that firms maximize profits by focusing on a single revenue source and competing at the extensive rather than the intensive margin, outperforming competitors by attracting a larger customer base. We also show that competition drives the provision of services with a low level of consumer information disclosure (high level of privacy), but higher competition intensity in the marketplace need not improve privacy when consumers exhibit low willingness to pay. Our findings are relevant to the business models of Internet firms and contribute to inform the regulatory debate on consumer privacy.</description><author>Casadesus-Masanell, Ramon; Hervas-Drane, Andres</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shopping for Information? Diversification and the Network of Industries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anjos, Fernando; Fracassi, Cesare
We propose and test a view of corporate diversification as a strategy that exploits internal information markets, by bringing together information that is scattered across the economy. First, we construct an interindustry network using input-output data, to proxy for the economy's information structure. Second, we introduce a new measure of conglomerate informational advantage, named "excess centrality," which captures how much more central conglomerates are relative to specialized firms operating in the same industries. We find that high-excess-centrality conglomerates have greater value, and produce more and better patents. Consistent with the internal-information-markets view, we also show that excess centrality has a greater effect in industries covered by fewer analysts and in industries where soft information is important.</description><author>Anjos, Fernando; Fracassi, Cesare</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intertemporal Price Discrimination: Structure and Computation of Optimal Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Besbes, Omar; Lobel, Ilan
We study a firm's optimal pricing policy under commitment. The firm's objective is to maximize its long-term average revenue given a steady arrival of strategic customers. In particular, customers arrive over time, are strategic in timing their purchases, and are heterogeneous along two dimensions: their valuation for the firm's product and their willingness to wait before purchasing or leaving. The customers' patience and valuation may be correlated in an arbitrary fashion. For this general formulation, we prove that the firm may restrict attention to cyclic pricing policies, which have length, at most, twice the maximum willingness to wait of the customer population. To efficiently compute optimal policies, we develop a dynamic programming approach that uses a novel state space that is general, capable of handling arbitrary problem primitives, and that generalizes to finite horizon problems with nonstationary parameters. We analyze the class of monotone pricing policies and establish their suboptimality in general. Optimal policies are, in a typical scenario, characterized by nested sales, where the firm offers partial discounts throughout each cycle, offers a significant discount halfway through the cycle, and holds its largest discount at the end of the cycle. We further establish a form of equivalence between the problem of pricing for a stream of heterogeneous strategic customers and pricing for a pool of heterogeneous customers who may stockpile units of the product.</description><author>Besbes, Omar; Lobel, Ilan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Remanufacturing, Third-Party Competition, and Consumers' Perceived Value of New Products</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agrawal, Vishal V.; Atasu, Atalay; van Ittersum, Koert
In this paper, we investigate whether and how the presence of remanufactured products and the identity of the remanufacturer influence the perceived value of new products through a series of behavioral experiments. Our results demonstrate that the presence of products remanufactured and sold by the original equipment manufacturer (OEM) can reduce the perceived value of new products by up to 8%. However, the presence of thirdparty-remanufactured products can increase the perceived value of new products by up to 7%. These results suggest that deterring third-party competition via preemptive remanufacturing may reduce profits, whereas the presence of third-party competition may actually be beneficial for an OEM.</description><author>Agrawal, Vishal V.; Atasu, Atalay; van Ittersum, Koert</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>ICU Admission Control: An Empirical Study of Capacity Allocation and Its Implication for Patient Outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Song-Hee; Chan, Carri W.; Olivares, Marcelo; Escobar, Gabriel
This work examines the process of admission to a hospital's intensive care unit (ICU). ICUs currently lack systematic admission criteria, largely because the impact of ICU admission on patient outcomes has not been well quantified. This makes evaluating the performance of candidate admission strategies difficult. Using a large patient-level data set of more than 190,000 hospitalizations across 15 hospitals, we first quantify the cost of denied ICU admission for a number of patient outcomes. We use hospital operational factors as instrumental variables to handle the endogeneity of the admission decisions and identify important specification issues that are required for this approach to be valid. Using the quantified cost estimates, we then provide a simulation framework for evaluating various admission strategies' performance. By simulating a hospital with 21 ICU beds, we find that we could save about $1.9 million per year by using an optimal policy based on observables designed to reduce readmissions and hospital length of stay. We also discuss the role of unobserved patient factors, which physicians may discretionarily account for when making admission decisions, and show that including these unobservables could result in a more than threefold increase in benefits compared to just optimizing the policy over the observable patient factors.</description><author>Kim, Song-Hee; Chan, Carri W.; Olivares, Marcelo; Escobar, Gabriel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Asset-Pricing Implications of Government Economic Policy Uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brogaard, Jonathan; Detzel, Andrew
Using the news-based measure of Baker et al. [Baker SR, Bloom N, Davis SJ (2013) Measuring economic policy uncertainty. Working paper, Stanford University, Stanford, CA] to capture economic policy uncertainty (EPU) in the United States, we find that EPU positively forecasts log excess market returns. An increase of one standard deviation in EPU is associated with a 1.5% increase in forecasted three-month abnormal returns (6.1% annualized). Furthermore, innovations in EPU earn a significant negative risk premium in the Fama-French 25 size-momentum portfolios. Among the Fama-French 25 portfolios formed on size and momentum returns, the portfolio with the greatest EPU beta underperforms the portfolio with the lowest EPU beta by 5.53% per annum, controlling for exposure to the Carhart four factors as well as implied and realized volatility. These findings suggest that EPU is an economically important risk factor for equities.</description><author>Brogaard, Jonathan; Detzel, Andrew</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic Volatilities and Long-Run Risks of Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhou, Guofu; Zhu, Yingzi
In this paper, motivated by existing and growing evidence on multiple macroeconomic volatilities, we extend the long-run risks model by allowing both a long-and a short-run volatility components in the evolution of economic fundamentals. With this extension, the new model not only is consistent with the volatility literature that the stock market is driven by two, rather than one, volatility factors, but also provides significant improvements in fitting various patterns, such as the size of market risk premium, the level of interest rate, degree of dividend yield predictability, and the term structure of variance risk premiums, of both the equity and option data.</description><author>Zhou, Guofu; Zhu, Yingzi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Timing of Product Allocation: Using Probabilistic Selling to Enhance Inventory Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fay, Scott; Xie, Jinhong
This paper examines probabilistic selling (PS) as an inventory-management mechanism, paying special attention to the impact of the timing of product assignment to buyers of probabilistic goods. In practice, sellers tend to offer probabilistic products only after major demand uncertainty has been resolved. By deferring product assignments, a firm is able to obtain more information about demand for each specific product before deciding which product to assign to consumers. However, our analysis demonstrates that PS can be an effective inventory-management mechanism even if the firm allocates products before knowing which product will be more popular and, thus, scarcer. Interestingly, we show that it can be more profitable for the firm to allocate products to consumers before, rather than after, learning the true demand for a product because, although early allocation imposes higher inventory costs (as a result of larger required inventory levels), it also enables the firm to charge higher prices. Our results also reveal that, when introducing probabilistic goods, the firm should order less inventory (relative to the case where probabilistic goods are not offered) if costs are very low but more inventory otherwise. Finally, we show that PS, as an inventory-management mechanism, can create a win-win situation, both improving profit and increasing social welfare.</description><author>Fay, Scott; Xie, Jinhong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Latent Homophily or Social Influence? An Empirical Analysis of Purchase Within a Social Network</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ma, Liye; Krishnan, Ramayya; Montgomery, Alan L.
Consumers who are close to one another in a social network often make similar purchase decisions. This similarity can result from latent homophily or social influence, as well as common exogenous factors. Latent homophily means consumers who are connected to one another are likely to have similar characteristics and product preferences. Social influence refers to the ability of one consumer to directly influence another consumer's decision based upon their communication. We present an empirical study of purchases of caller ring-back tones using data from an Asian mobile network that predicts consumers' purchase timing and choice decisions. We simultaneously measure latent homophily and social influence, while also accounting for exogenous factors. Identification is achieved due to our dynamic, panel data structure and the availability of detailed communication data. We find strong influence effects and latent homophily effects in both the purchase timing and product choice decisions of consumers.</description><author>Ma, Liye; Krishnan, Ramayya; Montgomery, Alan L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Electronic Commerce on Geographic Purchasing Patterns and Price Dispersion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Overby, Eric; Forman, Chris
The "law of one price" states that if prices for the same or highly similar goods vary across geographic locations by more than the cost of transport, then traders will shift supply and demand to exploit the price differences. However, several frictions prevent traders from doing this, including lack of information about prices and difficulty trading across locations. Electronic commerce has the potential to reduce these frictions by increasing price visibility and lowering transaction costs. We analyze this by studying how the diffusion of an electronic channel affected geographic trading patterns and price dispersion in the wholesale used vehicle market from 2003 to 2008. We find that buyers used the channel to shift their demand geographically to exploit price differences, which reduced geographic price dispersion. We find that the electronic channel also influenced how sellers distributed supply, but we find little evidence that this led to reduced geographic price dispersion.</description><author>Overby, Eric; Forman, Chris</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Resource Allocation: Top-Down, Bottom-Up, and the Value of Strategic Buckets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hutchison-Krupat, Jeremy; Kavadias, Stylianos
When senior managers make the critical decision of whether to assign resources to a strategic initiative, they have less precise initiative-specific information than project managers who execute such initiatives. Senior management chooses between a decision process that dictates the resource level ( top-down) and one that delegates the resource decision and gives up control in favor of more precise information ( bottom-up). We investigate this choice and vary the amount of information asymmetry between stakeholders, the "penalty for failure" imposed upon project managers, and how challenging the initiative is for the firm. We find that no single decision process is the "best." Bottom-up processes are beneficial for more challenging initiatives. Increased organizational penalties may prompt the firm to choose a narrower scope and deter the approval of profitable initiatives. Such penalties, however, enable an effective decision process known as "strategic buckets" that holds the potential to achieve first-best resource allocation levels.</description><author>Hutchison-Krupat, Jeremy; Kavadias, Stylianos</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Appointment Scheduling with Limited Distributional Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mak, Ho-Yin; Rong, Ying; Zhang, Jiawei
In this paper, we develop distribution-free models that solve the appointment sequencing and scheduling problem by assuming only moments information of job durations. We show that our min-max appointment scheduling models, which minimize the worst-case expected waiting and overtime costs out of all probability distributions with the given marginal moments, can be exactly formulated as tractable conic programs. These formulations are obtained by exploiting hidden convexity of the problem. In the special case where only the first two marginal moments are given, the problem can be reformulated as a second-order cone program. Based on the structural properties of this formulation, under a mild condition, we derive the optimal time allowances in closed form and prove that it is optimal to sequence jobs in increasing order of job duration variance. We also prove similar results regarding the optimal time allowances and sequence for the case where only means and supports of job durations are known.</description><author>Mak, Ho-Yin; Rong, Ying; Zhang, Jiawei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Market Discovery Algorithm to Estimate a General Class of Nonparametric Choice Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Ryzin, Garrett; Vulcano, Gustavo
We propose an approach for estimating customer preferences for a set of substitutable products using only sales transactions and product availability data. The underlying demand framework combines a general, nonparametric discrete choice model with a Bernoulli process of arrivals over time. The choice model is defined by a discrete probability mass function (pmf) on a set of possible preference rankings of alternatives, and it is compatible with any random utility model. An arriving customer is assumed to purchase the available option that ranks highest in her preference list. The problem we address is how to jointly estimate the arrival rate and the pmf of the rank-based choice model under a maximum likelihood criterion. Since the potential number of customer types is factorial, we propose a market discovery algorithm that starts with a parsimonious set of types and enlarge it by automatically generating new types that increase the likelihood value. Numerical experiments confirm the potential of our proposal. For a realistic data set in the hospitality industry, our approach improves the root mean square errors between predicted and observed purchases computed under independent demand model estimates by 67%-93%.</description><author>van Ryzin, Garrett; Vulcano, Gustavo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identifying Expertise to Extract the Wisdom of Crowds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Budescu, David V.; Chen, Eva
Statistical aggregation is often used to combine multiple opinions within a group. Such aggregates outperform individuals, including experts, in various prediction and estimation tasks. This result is attributed to the "wisdom of crowds." We seek to improve the quality of such aggregates by eliminating poorly performing individuals from the crowd. We propose a new measure of contribution to assess the judges' performance relative to the group and use positive contributors to build a weighting model for aggregating forecasts. In Study 1, we analyze 1,233 judges forecasting almost 200 current events to illustrate the superiority of our model over unweighted models and models weighted by measures of absolute performance. In Study 2, we replicate our findings by using economic forecasts from the European Central Bank and show how the method can be used to identify smaller crowds of the top positive contributors. We show that the model derives its power from identifying experts who consistently outperform the crowd.</description><author>Budescu, David V.; Chen, Eva</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sex Hormones and Competitive Bidding</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schipper, Burkhard C.
We correlate competitive bidding and profits in symmetric independent private value first-price auctions with salivary testosterone, estradiol, progesterone, and cortisol in more than 200 subjects. Bids are significantly positively correlated and profits are significantly negatively correlated with basal salivary progesterone, but only for females who do not use hormonal contraceptives. Surprisingly, we have null findings for basal testosterone, estradiol, and cortisol for both males and females. We show that our finding for progesterone is not mediated by risk aversion or bidding mistakes. No hormone responds to total profits in the auctions except for a small positive response of the stress hormone cortisol in males.</description><author>Schipper, Burkhard C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Management Insights</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorman, Michael F.
nan</description><author>Gorman, Michael F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sorting Effects of Performance Pay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldmanis, Maris; Ray, Korok
Compensation not only provides incentives to an existing manager but also affects the type of manager attracted to the firm. This paper examines the dual incentive and sorting effects of performance pay in a simple contracting model of endogenous participation. Unless the manager is highly risk averse, sorting dampens optimal pay-performance sensitivity (PPS) because PPS beyond a nominal amount transfers unnecessary (information) rent to the manager. This helps explain why empirical estimates of PPS are much lower than predictions from models of moral hazard alone. The model also predicts that sorting under asymmetric information causes the firm to turn away more candidates than would be efficient; PPS increases in the cost of hiring the manager and in the manager's outside option, but decreases in output risk, information risk, and managerial risk aversion; and the firm becomes more selective in hiring as either the manager's outside option, the cost of hiring, risk aversion, output risk, or information risk increases.</description><author>Goldmanis, Maris; Ray, Korok</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Incumbents Improve Service Quality in Response to Entry? Evidence from Airlines' On-Time Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Prince, Jeffrey T.; Simon, Daniel H.
We examine if and how incumbent firms respond to entry and entry threats using nonprice modes of competition. Our analysis focuses on airline service quality. We find that incumbent on-time performance (OTP) actually worsens in response to entry, and even entry threats, by Southwest Airlines. Since Southwest is both a top-performing airline in OTP and a low-cost carrier (LCC), we conjecture that this response by incumbents may be due to a cost-cutting strategy that allows for intense postentry price competition along with preentry deterrence, or it may be due to a postentry differentiation strategy along with preentry accommodation. Further analysis of entry and entry threats by other airlines is inconclusive, providing evidence that is partially consistent with both hypotheses. Nonetheless, the phenomenon of worsening OTP can only be observed when the (potential) entrant is a LCC (Southwest, Jet Blue, and AirTran).</description><author>Prince, Jeffrey T.; Simon, Daniel H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Temporary Increases in Information Asymmetry Affect the Cost of Equity?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levi, Shai; Zhang, Xiao-Jun
Prior literature finds that long-lasting changes in firms' disclosure policies and information environment affect the cost of equity. Information asymmetry, however, also changes during the fiscal quarter. Firms disclose information periodically, and in between disclosure dates, traders can obtain private information, and adverse-selection risk increases. Such temporary increases in information asymmetry are usually considered to be diversifiable or too small to impact expected stock returns. In addition, investors may postpone trades or sell other assets in their portfolio on high information asymmetry days. We, however, find that returns increase significantly on days during the fiscal quarter when adverse-selection risk is high and liquidity low. Consistent with theory, we show that temporary asymmetry affects returns when investors demand liquidity and market makers bear risk for carrying capacity and providing it.</description><author>Levi, Shai; Zhang, Xiao-Jun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Bargaining in a Supply Chain with Asymmetric Demand Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feng, Qi; Lai, Guoming; Lu, Lauren Xiaoyuan
We analyze a dynamic bargaining game in which a seller and a buyer negotiate over quantity and payment to trade for a product. Both firms are impatient, and they make alternating offers until an agreement is reached. The buyer is privately informed about his type, which can be high or low: the high type's demand is stochastically larger than the low type's. In the dynamic negotiation process, the seller can screen, whereas the buyer can signal information through their offers, and the buyer has an endogenous and type-dependent reservation profit. With rational assumptions on the seller's belief structure, we characterize the perfect Bayesian equilibrium of the bargaining game. Interestingly, we find that both quantity distortion and information rent may be avoided depending on the firms' relative patience, and the seller may reach an agreement with either the high type or the low type first, or with both simultaneously. Furthermore, we explore our model to characterize the effect of demand forecasting accuracy on firm profitability. We find that improved demand forecast benefits the buyer but hurts the seller when the buyer's forecasting accuracy is low. However, once the buyer's forecasting accuracy exceeds a threshold, both firms will benefit from further improvement of the forecast. This observation makes an interesting contrast to previous findings based on the one-shot principal-agent model, in which improvement of forecasting accuracy mostly leads to a win-lose outcome for the two firms, and the buyer has an incentive to improve his forecasting accuracy only when it is extremely low.</description><author>Feng, Qi; Lai, Guoming; Lu, Lauren Xiaoyuan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Outsourcing Information Security: Contracting Issues and Security Implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cezar, Asunur; Cavusoglu, Huseyin; Raghunathan, Srinivasan
A unique challenge in information security outsourcing is that neither the outsourcing firm nor the managed security service provider (MSSP) perfectly observes the outcome, the occurrence of a security breach, of prevention effort. Detection of security breaches often requires specialized effort. The current practice is to outsource both prevention and detection to the same MSSP. Some security experts have advocated outsourcing prevention and detection to different MSSPs. We show that the former outsourcing contract leads to a significant disincentive to provide detection effort. The latter contract alleviates this problem but introduces misalignment of incentives between the firm and the MSSPs and eliminates the advantages offered by complementarity between prevention and detection functions, which may lead to a worse outcome than the current contract. We propose a new contract that is superior to these two on various dimensions.</description><author>Cezar, Asunur; Cavusoglu, Huseyin; Raghunathan, Srinivasan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tie Strength, Embeddedness, and Social Influence: A Large-Scale Networked Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aral, Sinan; Walker, Dylan
We leverage the newly emerging business analytical capability to rapidly deploy and iterate large-scale, microlevel, in vivo randomized experiments to understand how social influence in networks impacts consumer demand. Understanding peer influence is critical to estimating product demand and diffusion, creating effective viral marketing, and designing "network interventions" to promote positive social change. But several statistical challenges make it difficult to econometrically identify peer influence in networks. Though some recent studies use experiments to identify influence, they have not investigated the social or structural conditions under which influence is strongest. By randomly manipulating messages sent by adopters of a Facebook application to their 1.3 million peers, we identify the moderating effect of tie strength and structural embeddedness on the strength of peer influence. We find that both embeddedness and tie strength increase influence. However, the amount of physical interaction between friends, measured by coappearance in photos, does not have an effect. This work presents some of the first large-scale in vivo experimental evidence investigating the social and structural moderators of peer influence in networks. The methods and results could enable more effective marketing strategies and social policy built around a new understanding of how social structure and peer influence spread behaviors in society.</description><author>Aral, Sinan; Walker, Dylan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Path to Purchase: A Mutually Exciting Point Process Model for Online Advertising and Conversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xu, Lizhen; Duan, Jason A.; Whinston, Andrew
This paper studies the effects of various types of online advertisements on purchase conversion by capturing the dynamic interactions among advertisement clicks themselves. It is motivated by the observation that certain advertisement clicks may not result in immediate purchases, but they stimulate subsequent clicks on other advertisements, which then lead to purchases. We develop a novel model based on mutually exciting point processes, which consider advertisement clicks and purchases as dependent random events in continuous time. We incorporate individual random effects to account for consumer heterogeneity and cast the model in the Bayesian hierarchical framework. We construct conversion probability to properly evaluate the conversion effects of online advertisements. We develop simulation algorithms for mutually exciting point processes to compute the conversion probability and for out-of-sample prediction. Model comparison results show the proposed model outperforms the benchmark models that ignore exciting effects among advertisement clicks. Using a proprietary data set, we find that display advertisements have relatively low direct effect on purchase conversion, but they are more likely to stimulate subsequent visits through other advertisement formats. We show that the commonly used measure of conversion rate is biased in favor of search advertisements and underestimates the conversion effect of display advertisements the most. Our model also furnishes a useful tool to predict future purchases and advertisement clicks for the purpose of targeted marketing and customer relationship management.</description><author>Xu, Lizhen; Duan, Jason A.; Whinston, Andrew</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Introduction to the Special Issue on Business Analytics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertsimas, Dimitris; Bradlow, Eric; Gans, Noah; Gupta, Alok
nan</description><author>Bertsimas, Dimitris; Bradlow, Eric; Gans, Noah; Gupta, Alok</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Simultaneously Discovering and Quantifying Risk Types from Textual Risk Disclosures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bao, Yang; Datta, Anindya
Managers and researchers alike have long recognized the importance of corporate textual risk disclosures. Yet it is a nontrivial task to discover and quantify variables of interest from unstructured text. In this paper, we develop a variation of the latent Dirichlet allocation topic model and its learning algorithm for simultaneously discovering and quantifying risk types from textual risk disclosures. We conduct comprehensive evaluations in terms of both conventional statistical fit and substantive fit with respect to the quality of discovered information. Experimental results show that our proposed method outperforms all competing methods, and could find more meaningful topics (risk types). By taking advantage of our proposed method for measuring risk types from textual data, we study how risk disclosures in 10-K forms affect the risk perceptions of investors. Different from prior studies, our results provide support for all three competing arguments regarding whether and how risk disclosures affect the risk perceptions of investors, depending on the specific risk types disclosed. We find that around two-thirds of risk types lack informativeness and have no significant influence. Moreover, we find that the informative risk types do not necessarily increase the risk perceptions of investors-the disclosure of three types of systematic and liquidity risks will increase the risk perceptions of investors, whereas the other five types of unsystematic risks will decrease them. Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2014.1930.</description><author>Bao, Yang; Datta, Anindya</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Empirical Analysis of Digital Music Bundling Strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Danaher, Brett; Huang, Yan; Smith, Michael D.; Telang, Rahul
We use panel data on digital song and album sales coupled with a quasi-random price experiment to determine own- and cross-price elasticities for songs and albums. We then develop a structural model of consumer demand to estimate welfare under various policy relevant counterfactual scenarios. This approach represents an early application of the "big data" management paradigm within the media industries and provides managers with detailed guidance on optimal pricing and marketing strategies for digital music. Our results show that tiered pricing coupled with reduced album pricing increases revenue to the labels by 18% relative to uniform pricing policies traditionally preferred by digital marketplaces while also increasing consumer surplus by 23%. Thus, optimal tiered pricing can yield a Pareto improvement over the prior status quo. Additionally, our results indicate that even without tiered pricing, unbundling albums outperforms "album-only" pricing policies that dominated the era of physical CD/cassette sales.</description><author>Danaher, Brett; Huang, Yan; Smith, Michael D.; Telang, Rahul</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A General Multiple Distributed Lag Framework for Estimating the Dynamic Effects of Promotions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kappe, Eelco; Blank, Ashley Stadler; DeSarbo, Wayne S.
Game attendance resulting from ticket sales is the single largest revenue stream for Major League Baseball (MLB) teams. We propose a general multiple distributed lag framework following the Koyck family of models for estimating MLB attendance drivers and focus specifically on the differential direct and carryover effects of in-game promotions. By setting various model constraints, the proposed framework incorporates different forms of serial correlation and promotion-specific dynamic effects. Using information model-selection heuristics, we select an optimal model of attendance drivers for the Pittsburgh Pirates' 2010-2012 MLB seasons. We demonstrate that our newly proposed model with an unrestricted serial correlation structure performs best. We find that although kids promotions have the highest direct effect on attendance, giveaway and entertainment promotions have substantial carryover effects and the largest total effects. We use our results to optimize the Pirates' promotional schedule and find that a reallocation of resources across promotional categories can increase profits between 39% and 88%. Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2013.1856.</description><author>Kappe, Eelco; Blank, Ashley Stadler; DeSarbo, Wayne S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Theoretical and Empirical Aspects of Marginal Distribution Choice Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mishra, Vinit Kumar; Natarajan, Karthik; Padmanabhan, Dhanesh; Teo, Chung-Piaw; Li, Xiaobo
In this paper, we study the properties of a recently proposed class of semiparametric discrete choice models (referred to as the marginal distribution model (MDM)), by optimizing over a family of joint error distributions with prescribed marginal distributions. Surprisingly, the choice probabilities arising from the family of generalized extreme value models of which the multinomial logit model is a special case can be obtained from this approach, despite the difference in assumptions on the underlying probability distributions. We use this connection to develop flexible and general choice models to incorporate consumer and product level heterogeneity in both partworths and scale parameters in the choice model. Furthermore, the extremal distributions obtained from the MDM can be used to approximate the Fisher's information matrix to obtain reliable standard error estimates of the partworth parameters, without having to bootstrap the method. We use simulated and empirical data sets to test the performance of this approach. We evaluate the performance against the classical multinomial logit, mixed logit, and a machine learning approach that accounts for partworth heterogeneity. Our numerical results indicate that MDM provides a practical semiparametric alternative to choice modeling.</description><author>Mishra, Vinit Kumar; Natarajan, Karthik; Padmanabhan, Dhanesh; Teo, Chung-Piaw; Li, Xiaobo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real-Time Optimization of Personalized Assortments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golrezaei, Negin; Nazerzadeh, Hamid; Rusmevichientong, Paat
Motivated by the availability of real-time data on customer characteristics, we consider the problem of personalizing the assortment of products for each arriving customer. Using actual sales data from an online retailer, we demonstrate that personalization based on each customer's location can lead to over 10% improvements in revenue compared to a policy that treats all customers the same. We propose a family of index-based policies that effectively coordinate the real-time assortment decisions with the back-end supply chain constraints. We allow the demand process to be arbitrary and prove that our algorithms achieve an optimal competitive ratio. In addition, we show that our algorithms perform even better if the demand is known to be stationary. Our approach is also flexible and can be combined with existing methods in the literature, resulting in a hybrid algorithm that brings out the advantages of other methods while maintaining the worst-case performance guarantees.</description><author>Golrezaei, Negin; Nazerzadeh, Hamid; Rusmevichientong, Paat</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Business Analytics for Flexible Resource Allocation Under Random Emergencies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Angalakudati, Mallik; Balwani, Siddharth; Calzada, Jorge; Chatterjee, Bikram; Perakis, Georgia; Raad, Nicolas; Uichanco, Joline
In this paper, we describe both applied and analytical work in collaboration with a large multistate gas utility. The project addressed a major operational resource allocation challenge that is typical to the industry. We study the resource allocation problem in which some of the tasks are scheduled and known in advance, and some are unpredictable and have to be addressed as they appear. The utility has maintenance crews that perform both standard jobs (each must be done before a specified deadline) as well as respond to emergency gas leaks (that occur randomly throughout the day and could disrupt the schedule and lead to significant overtime). The goal is to perform all the standard jobs by their respective deadlines, to address all emergency jobs in a timely manner, and to minimize maintenance crew overtime. We employ a novel decomposition approach that solves the problem in two phases. The first is a job scheduling phase, where standard jobs are scheduled over a time horizon. The second is a crew assignment phase, which solves a stochastic mixed integer program to assign jobs to maintenance crews under a stochastic number of future emergencies. For the first phase, we propose a heuristic based on the rounding of a linear programming relaxation formulation and prove an analytical worst-case performance guarantee. For the second phase, we propose an algorithm for assigning crews that is motivated by the structure of an optimal solution. We used our models and heuristics to develop a decision support tool that is being piloted in one of the utility's sites. Using the utility's data, we project that the tool will result in a 55% reduction in overtime hours.</description><author>Angalakudati, Mallik; Balwani, Siddharth; Calzada, Jorge; Chatterjee, Bikram; Perakis, Georgia; Raad, Nicolas; Uichanco, Joline</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Website Morphing 2.0: Switching Costs, Partial Exposure, Random Exit, and When to Morph</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hauser, John R.; Liberali, Guilherme; Urban, Glen L.
Website morphing infers latent customer segments from clickstreams and then changes websites' look and feel to maximize revenue. The established algorithm infers latent segments from a preset number of clicks and then selects the best "morph" using expected Gittins indices. Switching costs, potential website exit, and all clicks prior to morphing are ignored. We model switching costs, potential website exit, and the (potentially differential) impact of all clicks to determine when to morph for each customer. Morphing earlier means more customer clicks are based on the optimal morph; morphing later reveals more about the customer's latent segment. We couple this within-customer optimization to between-customer expected Gittins index optimization to determine which website "look and feel" to give to each customer at each click. We evaluate the improved algorithm with synthetic data and with a proof-of-feasibility application to Japanese bank card loans. The proposed algorithm generalizes the established algorithm, is feasible in real time, performs substantially better when tuning parameters are identified from calibration data, and is reasonably robust to misspecification. Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2014.1961.</description><author>Hauser, John R.; Liberali, Guilherme; Urban, Glen L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Integration of Online and Offline Channels in Retail: The Impact of Sharing Reliable Inventory Availability Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gallino, Santiago; Moreno, Antonio
Using a proprietary data set, we analyze the impact of the implementation of a "buy-online, pick-up-in-store" (BOPS) project. The implementation of this project is associated with a reduction in online sales and an increase in store sales and traffic. These results can be explained by two simultaneous phenomena: (1) additional store sales from customers who use the BOPS functionality and buy additional products in the stores (cross-selling effect) and (2) the shift of some customers from the online to the brick-and-mortar channel and the conversion of noncustomers into store customers (channel-shift effect). We explain these channel-shift patterns as an increase in "research online, purchase offline" behavior enabled by BOPS implementation, and we validate this explanation with evidence from the change of cart abandonment and conversion rates of the brick-and-mortar and online channels. We interpret these results in light of recent operations management literature that analyzes the impact of sharing inventory availability information. Our analysis illustrates the limitations of drawing conclusions about complex interventions using single-channel data.</description><author>Gallino, Santiago; Moreno, Antonio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Big Data Investment, Skills, and Firm Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tambe, Prasanna
This paper analyzes how labor market factors have shaped early returns on big data investment using a new data source-the LinkedIn skills database. The data source enables firm-level measurement of the employment of workers with technical skills such as Hadoop, MapReduce, and Apache Pig. From 2006 to 2011, Hadoop investments were associated with 3% faster productivity growth, but only for firms (a) with significant data assets and (b) in labor markets where similar investments by other firms helped to facilitate the development of a cadre of workers with complementary technical skills. The benefits of labor market concentration decline for investments in mature data technologies, such as Structured Query Language-based databases, for which the complementary skills can be acquired by workers through universities or other channels. These findings underscore the importance of geography, corporate investment, and skill acquisition channels for explaining productivity growth differences during the spread of new information technology innovations.</description><author>Tambe, Prasanna</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>