<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>MS8</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>A Global Equilibrium Asset Pricing Model with Home Preference</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Solnik, Bruno; Zuo, Luo
We develop a global equilibrium asset pricing model assuming that investors suffer from foreign aversion, a preference for home assets based on familiarity. Using a utility formulation inspired by regret theory, we derive closed-form solutions. When the degree of foreign aversion is high in a given country, investors place a high valuation on domestic equity, which results in a low expected return. Thus, the model generates the simple prediction that a country's degree of home bias and the expected return of its domestic assets should be inversely related. Our predicted relation between the degree of home bias and a country's expected return has the opposite sign predicted by models that assume some form of market segmentation. Using International Monetary Fund portfolio data, we find that expected returns are negatively related to home bias.</description><author>Solnik, Bruno; Zuo, Luo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local Religious Beliefs and Mutual Fund Risk-Taking Behaviors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shu, Tao; Sulaeman, Johan; Yeung, P. Eric
We study the effects of local religious beliefs on mutual fund risk-taking behaviors. Funds located in low-Protestant or high-Catholic areas exhibit significantly higher fund return volatilities. Similar differences persist when we use the religiosity ratios at fund managers' college locations. Risk-taking associated with local religious beliefs manifests in higher portfolio concentrations, higher,portfolio turnover, more aggressive interim trading, and more "tournament" risk-shifting behaviors, but not over-weighting risky individual stocks. Overall, our results suggest that local religious beliefs have significant influences on mutual fund behaviors.</description><author>Shu, Tao; Sulaeman, Johan; Yeung, P. Eric</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Strategy, Analyst Coverage, and the Uniqueness Paradox</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Litov, Lubomir P.; Moreton, Patrick; Zenger, Todd R.
In this paper, we argue that managers confront a paradox in selecting strategy. On one hand, capital markets systematically discount uniqueness in the strategy choices of firms. Uniqueness in strategy heightens the cost of collecting and analyzing information to evaluate a firm's future value. These greater costs in strategy evaluation discourage the collection and analysis of information regarding the firm, and result in a valuation discount. On the other hand, uniqueness in strategy is a necessary condition for creating economic ::ents and should, except for this information cost, be positively associated with firm value. We find empirical support for both propositions using a novel measure of strategy uniqueness in a firm panel data set between 1985 and 2007.</description><author>Litov, Lubomir P.; Moreton, Patrick; Zenger, Todd R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contingent Capital with a Capital-Ratio Trigger</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glasserman, Paul; Nouri, Behzad
Contingent capital in the form of debt that converts to equity when a bank faces financial distress has been proposed as a mechanism to enhance financial stability and avoid costly government rescues. Specific proposals vary in their choice of conversion trigger and conversion mechanism. We analyze the case of contingent capital with a capital-ratio trigger and partial and ongoing conversion. The capital ratio we use is based on accounting or book values to approximate the regulatory ratios that determine capital requirements for banks. The conversion process is partial and ongoing in the sense that each time a bank's capital ratio reaches the minimum threshold, just enough debt is converted to equity to meet the capital requirement, so long as the contingent capital has not been depleted. We derive closed-form expressions for the market value of such securities when the firm's asset value is modeled as geometric Brownian motion, and from these we get formulas for the fair yield spread on the convertible debt. A key step in the analysis is an explicit expression for the fraction of equity held by the original shareholders and the fraction held by converted investors in the contingent capital.</description><author>Glasserman, Paul; Nouri, Behzad</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Large-Scale Service Marketplaces: The Role of the Moderating Firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allon, Gad; Bassamboo, Achal; Cil, Eren B.
Recently, large-scale, Web-based service marketplaces, where many small service providers compete among themselves in catering to customers with diverse needs, have emerged. Customers who frequent these marketplaces seek quick resolutions and thus are usually willing to trade prices with waiting times. The main goal of this paper is to discuss the role of the moderating firm in facilitating information gathering, operational efficiency, and communication among agents in service marketplaces. Surprisingly, we show that operational efficiency may be detrimental to the overall efficiency of the marketplace. Furthermore, we establish that to reap the "expected" gains of operational efficiency, the moderating firm may need to complement the operational efficiency by enabling communication among its agents. The study emphasizes the scale of such marketplaces and the impact it has on the outcomes.</description><author>Allon, Gad; Bassamboo, Achal; Cil, Eren B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hierarchies and the Survival of Prisoners of War During World War II</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holderness, Clifford G.; Pontiff, Jeffrey
Using a comprehensive database of American prisoners of war during World War IT, we find that survival from captivity generally declines as the hierarchy of a prisoner's group becomes steeper or more closely matches the military's established hierarchy. There is no evidence that survival is enhanced by being held in more hierarchical groups. One interpretation of these findings that is consistent with survivors' accounts is that the military's hierarchy was too inflexible to adapt from the battlefield to captivity and this inflexibility impeded trading among the prisoners.</description><author>Holderness, Clifford G.; Pontiff, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Generalized Norton-Bass Model for Multigeneration Diffusion.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Zhengrui; Jain, Dipak C.
The Norton-Bass (NB) model is often credited as the pioneering multigeneration diffusion model in marketing. However, as acknowledged by the authors, when counting the number of adopters who substitute an old product generation with a new generation, the NB model does not differentiate those who have already adopted the old generation from those who have not. In this study, we develop a generalized Norton-Bass (GNB) model that separates the two different types of substitutions. The GNB model provides closed-form expressions for both the number of units in use and the adoption rate, and offers greater flexibility in parameter estimation, forecasting, and revenue projection. An appealing aspect of the GNB model is that it us,uses exactly the same set of parameters as the NB model and is mathematically consistent with the later. Empirical results show that the GNB model delivers better overall performance than previous models both in terms of model fit and forecasting performance. The analyses also show that differentiating leapfrogging and switching adoptions based on the GNB model can help gain additional insights into the process of multigeneration diffusion. Furthermore, we demonstrate that the GNB model can incorporate the effect of marketing mix variables on the speed of diffusion for all product generations.</description><author>Jiang, Zhengrui; Jain, Dipak C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing Disruption Risk: The Interplay Between Operations and Insurance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dong, Lingxiu; Tomlin, Brian
s Disruptive events that halt production can have severe business consequences if not appropriately managed. Business interruption (BI) insurance offers firms a financial mechanism for managing their exposure to disruption risk. Firms can also avail of operational measures to manage the risk. In this paper, we explore the relationship between BI insurance and operational measures. We model a manufacturing firm that can purchase BI insurance, invest in inventory, and avail of emergency sourcing. Allowing the insurance premium to depend on the firm's insurance and operational decisions, we characterize the optimal insurance deductible and coverage limit as well as the optimal inventory level. We prove that insurance and operational measures Are not always substitutes, and we establish conditions under which they can be complements; that is, insurance can increase the marginal value of inventory and can increase the overall value of emergency sourcing. We also find that the value of insurance is higher for those firms less able to absorb financially significant disruptions. As disruptions become longer but rarer, the value of emergency sourcing increases, and the value of inventory and the value of insurance increase before eventually decreasing.</description><author>Dong, Lingxiu; Tomlin, Brian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Pricing Restrictions on Predictability: Frictions Matter</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Roon, Frans; Szymanowska, Marta
U.S. stock portfolios sorted on size; momentum; transaction costs; market-to-book, investment-to-assets, and return-on-assets (ROA) ratios; and industry classification show considerable levels and variation of return predictability, inconsistent with asset pricing models. This means that a predictable risk premium is not equal to compensation for systematic risk as implied by asset pricing theory. We show that introducing market frictions relaxes these asset pricing moments from a strict equality to a range. Empirically, it is not short sales constraints but transaction costs (below 35 basis points) that help to reconcile the observed predictability with linear portfolio return-based factor models, and partly with the durable consumption model. Across the sorts, predictability in industry returns can be reconciled with all models considered with only a 25 basis point transaction cost, whereas for momentum and ROA portfolios, up to 115 basis points are needed.</description><author>de Roon, Frans; Szymanowska, Marta</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Supply Chain Performance Under Market Valuation: An Operational Approach to Restore Efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lai, Guoming; Xiao, Wenqiang; Yang, Jun
Based on a supply chain framework, we study the stocking decision of a downstream buyer who receives private demand information and has the incentive to influence her capital market valuation. We first characterize a market equilibrium under a general, single buyback contract. We show that the buyer's stocking decision can be distorted in equilibrium. Such a downstream stocking distortion hurts the buyer firm's own performance, and it also influences the performances of the supplier and the supply chain. We further reveal scenarios where full supply chain efficiency cannot be reached under any single buyback contract. Then, focusing on contract design, we characterize conditions under which a menu of buyback contracts can prevent downstream stocking distortion and restore full efficiency in the supply chain. Our study demonstrates that in a supply chain context, a firm's incentive to undertake real economic activities to influence capital market valuation can potentially be resolved through operational means.</description><author>Lai, Guoming; Xiao, Wenqiang; Yang, Jun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling Bounded Rationality in Capacity Allocation Games with the Quantal Response Equilibrium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yefen; Su, Xuanming; Zhao, Xiaobo
We consider a supply chain with a single supplier and two retailers. The retailers choose their orders strategically, and if their orders exceed the supplier's capacity, quantities are allocated proportionally to the orders. We experimentally study the capacity allocation game using subjects motivated by financial incentives. We find that the Nash equilibrium, which assumes that players are perfectly rational, substantially exaggerates retailers' tendency to strategically order more than they need. We propose a model of bounded rationality based on the quantal response equilibrium, in which players are not perfect optimizers and they face uncertainty in their opponents' actions. We structurally estimate model parameters using the maximum-likelihood method. Our results confirm that retailers exhibit bounded rationality, become more rational through repeated game play, but may not converge to perfect rationality as assumed by the Nash equilibrium. Finally, we consider several alternative behavioral theories and show that they do not explain our experimental data as well as our bounded rationality model.</description><author>Chen, Yefen; Su, Xuanming; Zhao, Xiaobo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend Smoothing and Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Long; Da, Zhi; Priestley, Richard
The relative predictability of returns and dividends is a central issue because it forms the paradigm to interpret asset price variation. A little studied question is how dividend smoothing, as a choice of corporate policy, affects predictability. We show that even if dividends are supposed to be predictable without smoothing, dividend smoothing can bury this predictability. Because aggregate dividends are dramatically more smoothed in the postwar period than before, the lack of dividend growth predictability in the postwar period does not necessarily mean that there is no cash flow news in stock price variations; rather, a more plausible interpretation is that dividends are smoothed. Using two alternative measures that are less subject to dividend smoothing-net payout and earnings-we reach the consistent conclusion that cash flow news plays a more important role than discount rate news in price variations in the postwar period.</description><author>Chen, Long; Da, Zhi; Priestley, Richard</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Behavioralist Visits the Factory: Increasing Productivity Using Simple Framing Manipulations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hossain, Tanjim; List, John A.
Recent discoveries in behavioral economics have led to important new insights concerning what can happen in markets. Such gains in knowledge have come primarily via laboratory experiments a missing piece of the puzzle in many cases is parallel evidence drawn from naturally occurring field counterparts. We provide a small movement in this direction by taking advantage of a unique opportunity to work with a Chinese high-tech manufacturing facility. Our study revolves around using insights gained from one of the most influential lines of behavioral research framing manipulations in an attempt to increase worker productivity in the facility. Using a natural field experiment, we report several insights. For example, conditional incentives framed as both "losses" and "gains" increase productivity for both individuals and teams. In addition, teams more acutely respond to bonuses posed as losses than as comparable bonuses posed as gains. The magnitude of this framing effect is roughly 1%: that is, total team productivity is enhanced by 1% purely due to the framing manipulation. Importantly, we find that neither the framing nor the incentive effect lose their significance over time; rather, the effects are observed over the entire sample period. Moreover, we learn that repeated interaction with workers and conditionality of the bonus contract are substitutes for sustenance of incentive effects in the long run.</description><author>Hossain, Tanjim; List, John A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reflected Knowledge and Trust in Global Collaboration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mortensen, Mark; Neeley, Tsedal B.
Scholars argue that direct knowledge about distant colleagues is crucial for fostering trust in global collaboration. However, their arguments focus mainly on how trust accrues from knowledge about distant collaborators' personal characteristics, relationships, and behavioral norms. We suggest that an equally important trust mechanism is "reflected knowledge," knowledge that workers gain about the personal characteristics, relationships, and behavioral norms of their own site through the lens of their distant collaborators. Based on surveys gathered from 140 employees in a division of a global chemical company, we found that direct knowledge and reflected knowledge enhanced trust in distinct ways. Although both enhanced feelings of closeness with others, results indicate that direct knowledge increased focal actors' understanding of their distant colleagues, whereas reflected knowledge promoted feelings of being understood. We discuss implications of reflected knowledge to theories of trust and interpersonal dynamics in globally distributed collaboration.</description><author>Mortensen, Mark; Neeley, Tsedal B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Selling to Conspicuous Consumers: Pricing, Production, and Sourcing Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tereyagoglu, Necati; Veeraraghavan, Senthil
Consumers often purchase goods that are "hard to find" to conspicuously display their exclusivity and social status. Firms that produce such conspicuously consumed goods such as designer apparel, fashion goods, jewelry, etc., often face challenges in making optimal pricing and production decisions. Such firms are confronted with precipitous trade-off between high sales volume and high margins, because of the highly uncertain market demand, strategic consumer behavior, and the display of conspicuous consumption. In this paper, we propose a model that addresses pricing and production decisions for a firm, using the rational expectations framework. We show that, in equilibrium, firms may offer high availability of goods despite the presence of conspicuous consumption. We show that scarcity strategies are harder to adopt as demand variability increases, and we provide conditions under which scarcity strategies could be successfully adopted to improve profits. Finally, to credibly commit to scarcity strategy, we show that firms can adopt sourcing strategies, such as sourcing from an expensive production location/supplier or using expensive raw materials.</description><author>Tereyagoglu, Necati; Veeraraghavan, Senthil</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Efficiency-Fairness Trade-off</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertsimas, Dimitris; Farias, Vivek F.; Trichakis, Nikolaos
This paper deals with a basic issue: How does one approach the problem of designing the "right" objective for a given resource allocation problem? The notion of what is right can be fairly nebulous; we consider two issues that we see as key: efficiency and fairness. We approach the problem of designing objectives that account for the natural tension between efficiency and fairness in the context of a framework that captures a number of resource allocation problems of interest to managers. More precisely, we consider a rich family of objectives that have been well studied in the literature for their fairness properties. We deal with the problem of selecting the appropriate objective from this family. We characterize the trade-off achieved between efficiency and fairness as one selects different objectives and develop several concrete managerial prescriptions for the selection problem based on this trade-off. Finally, we demonstrate the value of our framework in a case study that considers air traffic management.</description><author>Bertsimas, Dimitris; Farias, Vivek F.; Trichakis, Nikolaos</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Royalty Contract Revision in a Multistage Strategic R&amp;D Alliance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xiao, Wenqiang; Xu, Yi
This paper investigates the impact of royalty revision on incentives and profits in a two-stage (research and development (R&amp;D) stage and marketing stage) alliance with a marketer and an innovator. The marketer offers royalty contracts to the innovator. We find that the potential for royalty revision leads to more severe distortions in the optimal initial royalty contracts offered by the marketer. We show that if the innovator plays a significant role in the marketing stage, the marketer should offer a low royalty rate initially and then revise the royalty rate up later. Otherwise, she should do the opposite. We identify two major effects of royalty revision. First, royalty revision provides the marketer with a flexibility to dynamically adjust royalty rates across the two stages of the alliance to better align the innovator's incentives. This incentive-realigning effect improves the marketer's profit. Second, royalty revision makes it harder for the marketer to obtain private information from the innovator, because the innovator worries that the marketer Will take advantage of the information to revise the initial contract to a more favorable one to herself later. This information-revealing effect hurts the marketer's profit. We characterize in what kind of alliances marketers would benefit the most from royalty revision so that managers should clearly establish the expectation for royalty revision, and in what kind of alliances markerters would not benefit from royalty revision so that managers should commit not to revise the initial royalty contract. With royalty contracts that are contingent on the R&amp;D outcome of the R&amp;D stage, we find that contingent contract structure could be either substitutable (by fully capturing the incentive re-aligning effect) or complementary (by weakening the information revealing effect) to royalty revision, depending on whether the innovator plays a significant role in the marketing stage. Managers may need to use a contingent contract (if possible) either to replace or with royalty revision accordingly to improve profits.</description><author>Xiao, Wenqiang; Xu, Yi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Investment Banks' Relationships with Investors Impact Pricing? The Case of Convertible Bond Issues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henderson, Brian J.; Tookes, Heather
This study examines the role of repeat interactions between placement agents (investment banks) and investors in the initial pricing of convertible bonds. Under the assumption that attracting repeat investors can reduce search frictions in primary issue markets, we test the hypothesis that banks' relationships with investors actually allow more favorable pricing for issuing firms (in contrast to the "favoritism" hypothesis, under which banks use underpricing to reward favored clients). In the empirical analysis we also allow for a potentially important alternative channel through which search frictions might impact initial pricing: expected after-market liquidity. Using a sample of 601 Rule 144A issues for the years 1997-2007, we document robust negative relationships between at-issue discounts and both types of frictions. Our findings suggest that search frictions play a meaningful role in initial convertible bond pricing and, specifically, that intermediaries can add substantial value through repeated interactions with investors.</description><author>Henderson, Brian J.; Tookes, Heather</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pathwise Optimization for Optimal Stopping Problems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desai, Vijay V.; Farias, Vivek F.; Moallemi, Ciamac C.
We introduce the pathwise optimization (PO) method, a new convex optimization procedure to produce upper and lower bounds on the optimal value (the "price") of a high-dimensional optimal stopping problem. The PO method builds on a dual characterization of optimal stopping problems as optimization problems over the space of martingales, which we dub the martingale duality approach. We demonstrate via numerical experiments that the PO method produces upper bounds of a quality comparable with state-of-the-art approaches, but in a fraction of the time required for those approaches. As a by-product, it yields lower bounds (and suboptimal exercise policies) that are substantially superior to those produced by state-of-the-art methods. The PO method thus constitutes a practical and desirable approach to high-dimensional pricing problems. Furthermore, we develop an approximation theory relevant to martingale duality approaches in general and the PO method in particular. Our analysis provides a guarantee on the quality of upper bounds resulting from these approaches and identifies three key determinants of their performance: the quality of an input value function approximation, the square root of the effective time horizon of the problem, and a certain spectral measure of "predictability" of the underlying Markov chain. As a corollary to this analysis we develop approximation guarantees specific to the PO method. Finally, we view the PO method and several approximate dynamic programming methods for high-dimensional pricing problems through a common lens and in doing so show that the PO method dominates those alternatives.</description><author>Desai, Vijay V.; Farias, Vivek F.; Moallemi, Ciamac C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust Simulation of Global Warming Policies Using the DICE Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Zhaolin; Cao, Jing; Hong, L. Jeff
Integrated assessment models that combine geophysics and economics features are often used to evaluate compare global warming,policies. Because there are typically profound uncertainties in these models, a simulation approach is often used. This approach requires the distribution of the uncertain parameters clearly specified. However, this is typically impossible because there is often a significant amount of ambiguity (e.g., estimation error) in specifying the distribution. In this paper, we adopt the widely used multivariate normal distribution to model the uncertain parameters. However, we assume that the mean vector and covariance matrix of the distribution are within some ambiguity sets. We then show how to find the worst-case performance of a given policy for all distributions constrained by the ambiguity sets. This worst-case performance provides a robust evaluation of the policy. We test our algorithm on a famous integrated model of climate change, known as the Dynamic Integrated Model of Climate and the Economy (DICE model). We find that the DICE model is sensitive to the means and covariance of the parameters. Furthermore, we find that, based on the DICE model, moderately tight environmental policies robustly outperform the no controls policy and the famous aggressive policies proposed by Stern and Gore.</description><author>Hu, Zhaolin; Cao, Jing; Hong, L. Jeff</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managers and Students as Newsvendors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Gary E.; Ockenfels, Axel; Thonemann, Ulrich W.
We compare how experienced procurement managers and students solve the newsvendor problem. We find that managers broadly exhibit the same kind of pull-to-center bias as students do. Also, managers use information and task training no better than students. The performance of managers is positively affected by the level of their education and their level in the organizational hierarchy. We discuss implications for theory and for how ordering might be improved in practice.</description><author>Bolton, Gary E.; Ockenfels, Axel; Thonemann, Ulrich W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Visible Hand? Demand Effects of Recommendation Networks in Electronic Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oestreicher-Singer, Gal; Sundararajan, Arun
Online commercial interactions have increased dramatically over the last decade, leading to the emergence of networks that link the electronic commerce landing pages of related products to one another. Our paper conjectures that the explicit visibility of such "product networks" can alter demand spillovers across their constituent items. We test this conjecture empirically using data about the copurchase networks and demand levels associated with more than 250,000 interconnected books offered on Amazon.com over the period of one year while controlling for alternative explanations of demand correlation using a variety of approaches. Our findings suggest that on average the explicit visibility of a copurchase relationship can lead to up to an average threefold amplification of the influence that complementary products have on each others' demand levels. We also find that newer and more popular products "use" the attention they garner from their network position more efficiently and that diversity in the sources of spillover further amplifies the demand effects of the recommendation network. Our paper presents new evidence quantifying the role of network position in electronic markets and highlights the power of basing (virtual) shelf position on consumer preferences that are explicitly revealed through shared purchasing patterns.</description><author>Oestreicher-Singer, Gal; Sundararajan, Arun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Men Too Sometimes Shy Away from Competition: The Case of Team Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dargnies, Marie-Pierre
Recent results in experimental and personnel economics indicate that women do not like competitive environments as much as men. This paper presents an experimental design that gives participants the opportunity to enter a tournament as part of a team rather than alone. Although a large and significant gender gap in entry in the individual tournament is found, in line with the literature, no gender gap is found in entry in the team tournament. Women do not enter the tournament significantly more often when it is team based, but men enter significantly less when they are part of a team than when alone. The main reason for men's disaffection with team competition appears to be linked to the uncertainty of their teammate's performance in a team tournament. More precisely, high-performing men fear being the victims of the free-riding behavior of their teammate. Women, especially low-performing women, tend to enter the team tournament more often than the individual one when they know they will be matched to a teammate of the same level as their own.</description><author>Dargnies, Marie-Pierre</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical Investigation of Retail Expansion and Cannibalization in a Dynamic Environment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pancras, Joseph; Sriram, S.; Kumar, V.
Managers of retail chains who seek to add new stores or close existing ones need to know the net impact of a store's opening/closure on the overall chain performance. This requires inferring the extent to which each store generates incremental sales as opposed to competing with other stores belonging to the chain for the same set of customers. However, when the chain is experiencing a growth or a decline in sales, not accounting for these dynamics in goodwill is likely to yield misleading estimates of incremental sales versus cannibalization. Moreover, firms might have been strategic in opening outlets in locations with favorable characteristics. We need to control for this location endogeneity while inferring the marginal effect of store opening/closure. In this paper, we develop a demand model that accounts for dynamics in goodwill, location endogeneity, and spatial competition between geographically proximate retail outlets. We calibrate the model parameters on both attitudinal and behavioral data for a fast food chain in a large U. S. city. The results imply that consumers perceive a travel cost of $0.60 per mile. As regards the composition of sales at individual stores, on average, 86.7% of sales constitute incremental purchases with the rest derived from cannibalized sales from nearby stores belonging to the chain. We also find significant decay in cannibalization with distance such that when the distance between stores increases by one mile, the sales lost due to cannibalization decreases by 28.1%; there is virtually no cannibalization at a distance of 10 miles. In terms of managerial applications, we discuss how managers can use the model presented in this paper to make two key decisions: (a) isolating locations that can be closed by identifying stores that yield the lowest marginal benefit to the chain and (b) dealing with franchisees' potential concerns about cannibalization.</description><author>Pancras, Joseph; Sriram, S.; Kumar, V.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Market Efficiency: The Bright Side of Myopic, Uninformed, and Passive External Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Noe, Thomas H.; Rebello, Michael J.; Rietz, Thomas A.
We model the effect of external financing on a firm's ability to maintain a reputation for high-quality production. Producing high quality is first best. Defecting to low quality is tempting because it lowers current costs while revenue remains unchanged because consumers and outside investors cannot immediately observe the defection. However, defection to low quality impairs the firm's reputation, which lowers cash flows and inhibits production over the long term. Financing via short-term claims discourages defection to low quality because the gains from defection are mostly captured by outside investors through an increase in the value of their claims. Therefore, if the firm relies on short-term external financing, it is more likely to produce over the long run, produce high-quality goods, and enjoy high profitability. The aggregate results from a laboratory experiment generally accord with these predictions.</description><author>Noe, Thomas H.; Rebello, Michael J.; Rietz, Thomas A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Search for Product Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Branco, Fernando; Sun, Monic; Villas-Boas, J. Miguel
Consumers often need to search for product information before making purchase decisions. We consider a tractable (continuous-time) model of gradual learning, in which consumers incur search costs to learn further product information, and update their expected utility of the product at each search occasion. We characterize the optimal stopping rules for either purchase, or no purchase, as a function of search costs and of the importance/informativeness of each attribute. This paper also characterizes how the likelihood of purchase changes with the ex ante expected utility, search costs, and the importance/informativeness of each attribute. We discuss optimal pricing, the impact of consumer search on profits and social welfare, and how the seller chooses its price to strategically affect the extent of the consumers' search behavior. We show that lower search costs can hurt the consumer because the seller may then choose to charge higher prices. Discounting creates asymmetry in the purchase and no-purchase search thresholds, and may lead to lower prices if search occurs in equilibrium, or higher prices if there is no search in equilibrium. This paper also considers searching for signals of the value of the product, heterogeneous importance of attributes, endogenous intensity of search, and social learning.</description><author>Branco, Fernando; Sun, Monic; Villas-Boas, J. Miguel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Does It Pay to Delay Supplier Qualification? Theory and Experiments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wan, Zhixi; Beil, Damian R.; Katok, Elena
We study a procurement setting in which the buyer seeks a low price but will not allocate the contract to a supplier who has not passed qualification screening. Qualification screening is costly for the buyer, involving product tests, site visits, and interviews. In addition to a qualified incumbent supplier, the buyer has an entrant of unknown qualification. The buyer wishes to run a price-only, open-descending reverse auction between the incumbent and the entrant, and faces a strategic choice about whether to perform qualification screening on the entrant before or after the auction. We analytically study the buyer's optimal strategy, accounting for the fact that under postauction qualification, the incumbent knows he could lose the auction but still win the contract. In our analysis, we derive the incumbent's optimal bidding strategy under postauction qualification and find that he follows a threshold structure in which high-cost incumbents hold back on bidding-or even boycott the auction-to preserve their profit margin, and only lower-cost incumbents bid to win. These results are strikingly different from the usual open-descending auction analysis where all bidders are fully qualified and bidding to win is always a dominant strategy. We test our analytical results in the laboratory, with human subjects. We find that qualitatively our theoretical predictions hold up quite well, although incumbent suppliers bid somewhat more aggressively than the theory predicts, making buyers more inclined to use postauction qualification.</description><author>Wan, Zhixi; Beil, Damian R.; Katok, Elena</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Coordination of Price Promotions in Complementary Categories</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sinitsyn, Maxim
In this paper, I investigate the outcome of a price competition between two firms, each producing two complementary products. Specifically, I study each firm's decision to coordinate price promotions of its products. Consumers are divided into loyals, who purchase both products from their preferred firm, and heterogeneous switchers, who choose between four possible bundles or buy a product in a single category. The switchers are willing to pay some price premium in order to purchase two complementary products that share the same brand name and are produced by the same firm, because they believe that these products are a better match than two complementary products with different brand names. I find that each firm predominantly promotes its complementary products together. This finding is correlationally supported by data in the shampoo and conditioner and in the cake mix and cake frosting categories.</description><author>Sinitsyn, Maxim</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aspirational Preferences and Their Representation by Risk Measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, David B.; De Giorgi, Enrico; Sim, Melvyn
We consider choice over uncertain, monetary payoffs and study a general class of preferences. These preferences favor diversification, except perhaps on a subset of sufficiently disliked acts over which concentration is instead preferred. This structure encompasses a number of known models (e.g., expected utility and several variants under a concave utility function). We show that such preferences share a representation in terms of a family of measures of risk and targets. Specifically, the choice function is equivalent to selection of a maximum index level such that the risk of beating the target at that level is acceptable. This representation may help to uncover new models of choice. One that we explore in detail is the special case when the targets are bounded. This case corresponds to a type of satisficing and has descriptive relevance. Moreover, the model is amenable to large-scale optimization.</description><author>Brown, David B.; De Giorgi, Enrico; Sim, Melvyn</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust Storage Assignment in Unit-Load Warehouses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Marcus; Lim, Yun Fong; Sim, Melvyn
Assigning products to and retrieving them from proper storage locations are crucial decisions in minimizing the operating cost of a unit-load warehouse. The problem becomes intractable when the warehouse faces variable supply and uncertain demand in a multiperiod setting. We assume a factor-based demand model in which demand for each product in each period is affinely dependent on some uncertain factors. The distributions of these factors are only partially characterized. We introduce a robust optimization model that minimizes the worst-case expected total travel in the warehouse with distributional ambiguity of demand. Under a linear decision rule, we obtain a storage and retrieval policy by solving a moderate-size linear optimization problem. Surprisingly, despite imprecise specification of demand distributions, our computational studies suggest that the linear policy achieves close to the expected value given perfect information and significantly outperforms existing heuristics in the literature.</description><author>Ang, Marcus; Lim, Yun Fong; Sim, Melvyn</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Execution Risk in High-Frequency Arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kozhan, Roman; Tham, Wing Wah
In this paper, we investigate the role of execution risk in high-frequency trading through arbitrage strategies. We show that if rational agents face uncertainty about completing their arbitrage portfolios, then arbitrage is limited even in markets with perfect substitutes and convertibility. Using a simple model, we demonstrate that this risk arises from the crowding effect of competing arbitrageurs entering the same trade and inflicting negative externalities on each other. Our empirical results provide evidence that support the relevance of execution risk in high-frequency arbitrage.</description><author>Kozhan, Roman; Tham, Wing Wah</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficient Cost Allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ray, Korok; Goldmanis, Maris
Firms routinely allocate the costs of common corporate resources down to divisions. The main insight of this paper is that any efficient allocation rule must reflect the firm's underlying cost structure. We propose a new allocation rule (the polynomial rule), which achieves efficiency and approximate budget balance. Welfare losses due to linear allocation rules increase with firm size, so polynomial allocation rules dominate linear rules for larger firms.</description><author>Ray, Korok; Goldmanis, Maris</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring the Informative and Persuasive Roles of Detailing on Prescribing Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ching, Andrew T.; Ishihara, Masakazu
In the pharmaceutical industry, measuring the importance of informative and persuasive roles of detailing is crucial for both drug manufacturers and policy makers. However, little progress has been made in disentangling these two roles of detailing in empirical research. In this paper, we provide a new identification strategy to address this problem. Our key identification assumptions are that the informative component of detailing is chemical specific and the persuasive component is brand specific. Our strategy is to focus on markets where some drug manufacturers engage in a comarketing agreement, under which two or more companies market the same chemical using their own brand names. With our identification assumptions, the variation in the relative market shares of these two brands, together with their brand specific detailing efforts, would allow us to measure the persuasive component of detailing. The variation in the market shares of chemicals, and the detailing efforts summed across brands made of the same chemical, would allow us to measure the informative component of detailing. Using the data for angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitor with diuretic in Canada, we find evidence that our identification strategy can help disentangle these two effects. Although both effects are statistically significant, we find that the persuasive function of detailing plays a very minor role in determining the demand at the chemical level-the informative role of detailing is mainly responsible for the diffusion patterns of chemicals. In contrast, the persuasive role of detailing plays a crucial role in determining the demand for brands that comarket the same chemical.</description><author>Ching, Andrew T.; Ishihara, Masakazu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contractual Flexibility, Rent Seeking, and Renegotiation Design: An Empirical Analysis of Information Technology Outsourcing Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Susarla, Anjana
This paper examines renegotiation design in contracts for outsourced information technology (IT) services. Whereas prior literature in information systems has highlighted the likelihood of ex post rent seeking engendered by renegotiation, we build upon literature on incomplete contracts to posit that renegotiation can be Pareto improving by incorporating contingencies revealed ex post. Research on contract renegotiation has been hampered by two sets of challenges: the lack of appropriate data and empirical challenges in identification. We circumvent this problem both by appropriate data collection and by employing an identification strategy to address alternate causal explanations. We propose a measure, Pareto improving amendments, to assess renegotiation outcomes that enhance the value from outsourcing by hazard equilibration and by incorporating learning. Using a unique sample of 141 IT outsourcing contracts, we examine the role of decision rights delineated ex ante in enabling Pareto improving amendments and in resolving the trade-off between adaptation and rent seeking. We find that flexibility provisions, termination for convenience rights, and contractual rights whereby vendors are granted rights to reuse know-how are associated with Pareto improving amendments. The results are robust to potential endogeneity of contractual provisions when parties have feasible foresight and to the possibility of adverse selection in the sample. We also examine alternate explanations from the literature on contractual breach. Implications for practitioners and researchers are discussed.</description><author>Susarla, Anjana</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Environment and Equity Risk Premium Volatility Around the World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lau, Sie Ting; Ng, Lilian; Zhang, Bohui
This paper examines whether and how differences in investors' information environments (measured by a country's information disclosure, accounting standards, and financial transparency) are related to cross-country differences in the market risk premium volatility. We use the vector-autoregressive and implied cost of capital methods to extract time variation in risk premiums for 41 developed and emerging markets worldwide. Consistent with theoretical predictions, countries with better information environments tend to experience a lower risk premium volatility, even after controlling for various country variables that are potentially associated with variation in risk premiums. Our analysis of two exogenous events, specifically the 1997 Asian financial crisis and 2008 global financial crisis, further corroborates our key finding that information environments play an important role in explaining market risk premium variability.</description><author>Lau, Sie Ting; Ng, Lilian; Zhang, Bohui</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Network Progeny? Prefounding Social Ties and the Success of New Entrants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roberts, Peter W.; Sterling, Adina D.
Entrepreneurs that were employed by successful industry incumbents prior to founding tend to confer advantages on their new organizations. We propose and then demonstrate a similar "network progeny" effect rooted in the social relationships that form among entrepreneurs. Our analysis of new entrants into the Ontario wine industry shows that prefounding friendship ties of the founders of one especially prominent entrepreneurial firm led to significantly higher ice wine prices. This attests to the promise of a network progeny extension of the parent-progeny account of new firm success. Follow-on analysis indicates that this effect is not attributable to an entrant's ability to make ice wines of superior quality or to it having access to better distribution knowledge. We therefore conclude that having a social tie to this prominent entrepreneurial firm generated reflected prominence that enhanced the valuations and therefore prices of wines made by connected market entrants.</description><author>Roberts, Peter W.; Sterling, Adina D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Fair Routing from Emergency Departments to Hospital Wards: QED Queues with Heterogeneous Servers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mandelbaum, Avishai; Momcilovic, Petar; Tseytlin, Yulia
The interface between an emergency department and internal wards is often a hospital's bottleneck. Motivated by this interaction in an anonymous hospital, we analyze queueing systems with heterogeneous server pools, where the pools represent the wards, and the servers are beds. Our queueing system, with a single centralized queue and several server pools, forms an inverted-V model. We introduce the randomized most-idle (RMI) routing policy and analyze it in the quality- and efficiency-driven regime, which is natural in our setting. The RMI policy results in the same server fairness (measured by idleness ratios) as the longest-idle-server-first (LISF) policy, which is commonly used in call centers and considered fair. However, the RMI policy utilizes only the information on the number of idle servers in different pools, whereas the LISF policy requires information that is unavailable in hospitals on a real-time basis.</description><author>Mandelbaum, Avishai; Momcilovic, Petar; Tseytlin, Yulia</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Combinatorial Auctions for Procurement: An Empirical Study of the Chilean School Meals Auction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Olivares, Marcelo; Weintraub, Gabriel Y.; Epstein, Rafael; Yung, Daniel
In this paper we conduct an empirical investigation of a large-scale combinatorial auction (CA)-the Chilean auction for school meals in which the government procures half a billion dollars worth of meal services every year. Our empirical study is motivated by two fundamental aspects in the design of CAs: (1) which packages should bidders be allowed to bid on and (2) diversifying the supplier base to promote competition. We use bidding data to uncover important aspects of the firms' cost structure and their strategic behavior, both of which are not directly observed by the auctioneer; these estimates inform the auction design. Our results indicate that package bidding that allows firms to express their cost synergies due to economies of scale and density seems appropriate. However, we also found evidence that firms can take advantage of this flexibility by discounting package bids for strategic reasons and not driven by cost synergies. Because this behavior can lead to inefficiencies, it may be worth evaluating whether to prohibit certain specific combinations in the bidding process. Our results also suggest that market share restrictions and running sequential auctions seem to promote competition in the long run, without significantly increasing the short-run cost for the government due to unrealized cost synergies. Our results highlight that the simultaneous consideration of the firms' operational cost structure and their strategic behavior is key to the successful design of a CA. More broadly, our paper is the first to provide an econometric study of a large-scale CA, providing novel and substantive insights regarding bidding behavior in this type of auction.</description><author>Olivares, Marcelo; Weintraub, Gabriel Y.; Epstein, Rafael; Yung, Daniel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Psychological Pressure in Competitive Environments: New Evidence from Randomized Natural Experiments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kocher, Martin G.; Lenz, Marc V.; Sutter, Matthias
Dynamic competitive settings may create psychological pressure when feedback about the performance of competitors is provided before the end of the competition. Such psychological pressure could produce a first-mover advantage, despite a priori equal winning probabilities. Using data from a randomized natural experiment-penalty shootouts in soccer-we reexamine evidence by Apesteguia and Palacios-Huerta [Apesteguia J, Palacios-Huerta 1 (2010) Psychological pressure in competitive environments: Evidence from a randomized natural experiment. Amer. Econom. Rev. 100(5):2548-2564]. They report a 21-percentage-point advantage for first movers over second movers in terms of winning probabilities. Extending their sample of 129 shootouts to 540, we fail to detect any significant first-mover advantage. Our results are fully consistent with recent evidence from other sports contests.</description><author>Kocher, Martin G.; Lenz, Marc V.; Sutter, Matthias</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public Opinion and Executive Compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuhnen, Camelia M.; Niessen, Alexandra
We investigate whether public opinion influences the level and structure of executive compensation. During 1992-2008, the negativity of press coverage of chief executive officer (CEO) pay varied significantly, with stock options being the most criticized pay component. We find that after more negative press coverage of CEO pay, firms reduce option grants and increase less contentious types of pay such as salary, although overall compensation does not change. The reduction in option pay after increased press negativity is more pronounced when firms, CEOs, and boards have stronger reputation concerns. Our within-firm, within-year identification shows the results cannot be explained by annual changes in accounting rules regarding executive compensation, stock market conditions, or pay mean reversion.</description><author>Kuhnen, Camelia M.; Niessen, Alexandra</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantifying Managerial Ability: A New Measure and Validity Tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demerjian, Peter; Lev, Baruch; McVay, Sarah
We propose a measure of managerial ability, based on managers' efficiency in generating revenues, which is available for a large sample of firms and outperforms existing ability measures. We find that our measure is strongly associated with manager fixed effects and that the stock price reactions to chief executive officer (CEO) turnovers are positive (negative) when we assess the outgoing CEO as low (high) ability. We also find that replacing CEOs with more (less) able CEOs is associated with improvements (declines) in subsequent firm performance. We conclude with a demonstration of the potential of the measure. We find that the negative relation between equity financing and future abnormal returns documented in prior research is mitigated by managerial ability. Specifically, more able managers appear to utilize equity issuance proceeds more effectively, illustrating that our more precise measure of managerial ability will allow researchers to pursue studies that were previously difficult to conduct.</description><author>Demerjian, Peter; Lev, Baruch; McVay, Sarah</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Streaks in Earnings Surprises and the Cross-Section of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loh, Roger K.; Warachka, Mitch
The gambler's fallacy [Rabin, M. 2002. Inference by believers in the law of small numbers. Quart. J. Econom. 117(3) 775-816] predicts that trends bias investor expectations. Consistent with this prediction, we find that investors underreact to streaks of consecutive earnings surprises with the same sign. When the most recent earnings surprise extends a streak, post-earnings-announcement drift is strong and significant. In contrast, the drift is negligible following the termination of a streak. Indeed, streaks explain about half of the post-earnings-announcement drift in our sample. Our results are robust to more general definitions of trends than streaks and a battery of control variables including the magnitude of earnings surprises and their autocorrelation. Overall, post-earnings-announcement drift has a significant time-series component that is consistent with the gambler's fallacy.</description><author>Loh, Roger K.; Warachka, Mitch</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Power of Diversity over Large Solution Spaces</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>LiCalzi, Marco; Surucu, Oktay
We consider a team of agents with limited problem-solving ability facing a disjunctive task over a large solution space. We provide sufficient conditions for the following four statements. First, two heads are better than one: a team of two agents will solve the problem even if neither agent alone would be able to. Second, teaming up does not guarantee success: if the agents are not sufficiently creative, even a team of arbitrary size may fail to solve the problem. Third, defendit numerus: when the agent's problem-solving ability is adversely affected by the complexity of the solution space, the solution of the problem requires only a mild increase in the size of the team. Fourth, groupthink impairs the power of diversity: if agents' abilities are positively correlated, a larger team is necessary to solve the problem.</description><author>LiCalzi, Marco; Surucu, Oktay</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product and Price Competition with Satiation Effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caro, Felipe; Martinez-de-Albeniz, Victor
Consumers become satiated with a product when purchasing too much too quickly. How much is too much and how quickly is too quickly depends on the characteristics of the product relative to the time interval between consumption periods. Knowing that, consumers allocate their budget to products that generate less satiation effects. Retailers should then choose to sell products that induce minimal satiation, but usually this is operationally more costly. To study this trade-off, we provide an analytical model based on utility theory that relates customer consumption to price and satiation, in the context of multiple competing retailers. We determine the purchasing pattern over time and provide an explicit expression to determine the consumption level in steady state. We derive market shares and show that they take the form of an attraction model in which the attractiveness depends on price and product satiation. We use this to analyze the competition between firms that maximize long-term average profit. We characterize the equilibrium under three scenarios: (i) price-only competition, (ii) product-only competition, and (iii) price and product competition. The results reveal the interplay between a key marketing lever (price) and the firm's ability to offer products that generate less satiation. In particular, we show that when a firm becomes more efficient at reducing satiation, its competitor may benefit if competition is on product only, but not if it is on price and product. We also find that when satiation effects are not managed, a firm's profit may be significantly reduced while a strategic competitor can largely benefit.</description><author>Caro, Felipe; Martinez-de-Albeniz, Victor</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Near-Miss Events Amplify or Attenuate Risky Decision Making</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tinsley, Catherine H.; Dillon, Robin L.; Cronin, Matthew A.
In the aftermath of many natural and man-made disasters, people often wonder why those affected were underprepared, especially when the disaster was the result of known or regularly occurring hazards (e.g., hurricanes). We study one contributing factor: prior near-miss experiences. Near misses are events that have some nontrivial expectation of ending in disaster but, by chance, do not. We demonstrate that when near misses are interpreted as disasters that did not occur, people illegitimately underestimate the danger of subsequent hazardous situations and make riskier decisions (e.g., choosing not to engage in mitigation activities for the potential hazard). On the other hand, if near misses can be recognized and interpreted as disasters that almost happened, this will counter the basic "near-miss" effect and encourage more mitigation. We illustrate the robustness of this pattern across populations with varying levels of real expertise with hazards and different hazard contexts (household evacuation for a hurricane, Caribbean cruises during hurricane season, and deep-water oil drilling). We conclude with ideas to help people manage and communicate about risk.</description><author>Tinsley, Catherine H.; Dillon, Robin L.; Cronin, Matthew A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Combining Equity and Utilitarianism in a Mathematical Programming Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hooker, J. N.; Williams, H. P.
We discuss the problem of combining the conflicting objectives of equity and utilitarianism, for social policy making, in a single mathematical programming model. The definition of equity we use is the Rawlsian one of maximizing the minimum utility over individuals or classes of individuals. However, when the disparity of utility becomes too great, the objective becomes progressively utilitarian. Such a model is particularly applicable not only to health provision but to other areas as well. Building a mixed-integer/linear programming (MILP) formulation of the problem raises technical issues, because the objective function is nonconvex and the hypograph is not MILP representable in its initial form. We present a succinct formulation and show that it is "sharp" in the sense that its linear programming relaxation describes the convex hull of the feasible set (before extra resource allocation or policy constraints are added). We apply the formulation to a healthcare planning problem and show that instances of realistic size are easily solved by standard MILP software.</description><author>Hooker, J. N.; Williams, H. P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust Portfolio Choice with Learning in the Framework of Regret: Single-Period Case</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lim, Andrew E. B.; Shanthikumar, J. George; Vahn, Gah-Yi
In this paper, we formulate a single-period portfolio choice problem with parameter uncertainty in the framework of relative regret. Relative regret evaluates a portfolio by comparing its return to a family of benchmarks, where the benchmarks are the wealths of fictitious investors who invest optimally given knowledge of the model parameters, and is a natural objective when there is concern about parameter uncertainty or model ambiguity. The optimal relative regret portfolio is the one that performs well in relation to all the benchmarks over the family of possible parameter values. We analyze this problem using convex duality and show that it is equivalent to a Bayesian problem, where the Lagrange multipliers play the role of the prior distribution, and the learning model involves Bayesian updating of these Lagrange multipliers/prior. This Bayesian problem is unusual in that the prior distribution is endogenously chosen by solving the dual optimization problem for the Lagrange multipliers, and the objective function involves the family of benchmarks from the relative regret problem. These results show that regret is a natural means by which robust decision making and learning can be combined.</description><author>Lim, Andrew E. B.; Shanthikumar, J. George; Vahn, Gah-Yi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Relational Advantages of Intermediation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Belavina, Elena; Girotra, Karan
This paper provides a novel explanation for the use of supply chain intermediaries. We find that even in the absence of the well-known transactional and informational advantages of mediation, intermediaries improve supply chain performance. In particular, intermediaries facilitate responsive adaptation of the buyers' supplier base to their changing needs while simultaneously ensuring that suppliers behave as if they had long-term sourcing commitments from buying firms. In the face of changing buyer needs, an intermediary that sources on behalf of multiple buyers can responsively change the composition of future business committed to a supplier such that a sufficient level of business comes from the buyer(s) that most prefer this supplier. On the other hand, direct buyers that source only for themselves must provide all their committed business to a supplier from their own sourcing needs, even if they no longer prefer this supplier. Unlike existing theories of intermediation, our theory better explains the observed phenomenon that although transactional barriers and information asymmetries have steadily decreased, the use of intermediaries has soared, even among large companies such as Walmart.</description><author>Belavina, Elena; Girotra, Karan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm Survival and Industry Evolution in Vertically Related Populations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Figueiredo, John M.; Silverman, Brian S.
This paper examines how the density and governance of vertically related populations affect the life chances of organizations. We integrate the literatures on organizational ecology and vertical integration to develop a theory of how (1) specialized upstream industries affect downstream survival rates, (2) the prevalence of different governance forms among upstream and downstream organizations moderates this relationship, and (3) different forms of governance exert differential competitive pressures on focal organizations. We find evidence supporting our hypotheses in an empirical examination of the downstream laser printer industry and upstream laser engine industry.</description><author>de Figueiredo, John M.; Silverman, Brian S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Link to Success: How Blogs Build an Audience by Promoting Rivals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mayzlin, Dina; Yoganarasimhan, Hema
Empirically, we find that Web logs (or "blogs") often link to other blogs in the same category. We present an analytical model that explains why a rational blogger may choose to link to another blog. We allow bloggers to differ along two dimensions: (1) the ability to post news-breaking content, and (2) the ability to find news in other blogs. By linking, a blog signals to the reader that it will be able to direct her to news in other blogs in the future. The downside of a link is that it is a positive signal on the rival's news-breaking ability. We show that linking will be in equilibrium when the heterogeneity on the ability to break news is low relative to the heterogeneity on the ability to find news in other blogs. One implication of the linking mechanism is that blogs that are high on the news-breaking ability are more likely to gain readers. Hence, despite the fact that bloggers link for purely selfish reasons, the macro effects of this activity is that readers' learning is enhanced.</description><author>Mayzlin, Dina; Yoganarasimhan, Hema</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comparing Business and Household Sector Innovation in Consumer Products: Findings from a Representative Study in the United Kingdom</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>von Hippel, Eric; de Jong, Jeroen P. J.; Flowers, Stephen
In a first survey of its type, we measure development and modification of consumer products by product users in a representative sample of 1,173 UK consumers age 18 and older. We estimate this previously unmeasured type of household sector innovation to be quite large: 6.1% of UK consumers-nearly 2.9 million individuals-have engaged in consumer product innovation during the prior three years. In aggregate, consumers' annual product development expenditures are more than 1.4 times larger than the annual consumer product R&amp;D expenditures of all firms in the United Kingdom combined. Consumers engage in many small projects that seem complementary to the innovation efforts of incumbent producers. Consumer innovators very seldom protect their innovations via intellectual property, and 17% diffuse to others. These results imply that, at the country level, productivity studies yield inflated effect sizes for producer innovation in consumer goods. They also imply that existing companies should reconfigure their product development systems to find and build on prototypes developed by consumers.</description><author>von Hippel, Eric; de Jong, Jeroen P. J.; Flowers, Stephen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Supply-Side Story: Risks, Guarantees, Competition, and Information Asymmetry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gumus, Mehmet; Ray, Saibal; Gurnani, Haresh
The risk of supply disruption increases as firms seek to procure from cheaper, but unproven, suppliers. We model a supply chain consisting of a single buyer and two suppliers, both of which compete for the buyer's order and face risk of supply disruption. One supplier is comparatively more reliable but also more expensive, whereas the other one is less reliable but cheaper and faces higher risk of disruption. Moreover, the risk level of the unreliable supplier may be private information, and this lack of visibility increases the buyer's purchasing risk. In such settings, the unreliable supplier often provides a price and quantity (P&amp;Q) guarantee to the buyer. Our objective is to study the underlying motivation for the guarantee offer and its effects on the competitive intensity and the performance of the chain partners. Our model also includes a spot market that can be utilized by any party to buy or to sell. The spot market price is random, partially depends on the available capacity of the two suppliers, and has a positive spread between buying and selling prices. We analytically characterize the equilibrium contracts for the two suppliers and the buyer's optimal procurement strategy. First, our analysis shows that P&amp;Q guarantee allows the unreliable supplier to better compete against the more reliable one by providing supply assurance to the buyer. More importantly, when information asymmetry risk is high, use of a guarantee may enable the unreliable supplier to credibly signal her true risk, thereby improving visibility into the chain. This signal can also be used by the buyer to infer the expected spot market price. In spite of these benefits, a guarantee offer in an asymmetric setting may not always be desirable for the buyer. Rather, it can reduce competition between the suppliers, resulting in higher costs for the buyer.</description><author>Gumus, Mehmet; Ray, Saibal; Gurnani, Haresh</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intermediated Blind Portfolio Auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Padilla, Michael; Van Roy, Benjamin
As much as 12% of the daily volume on the New York Stock Exchange, and similar volumes on other major world exchanges, involves sales by institutional investors to brokers through blind portfolio auctions. Such transactions typically take the form of a first-price sealed-bid auction in which the seller engages a few potential brokers and provides limited information about the portfolio being sold. Uncertainty about the portfolio contents reduces bids, effectively increasing the transaction cost paid by the seller. We consider the use of a trusted intermediary or equivalent cryptographic protocol to reduce transaction costs. In particular, we propose a mechanism through which each party provides relevant private information to an intermediary who ultimately reveals only the portfolio contents and price paid, and only to the seller and winning broker. Through analysis of a game-theoretic model, we demonstrate substantial potential benefits to sellers.</description><author>Padilla, Michael; Van Roy, Benjamin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer Valuation of Modularly Upgradeable Products</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Uelkue, Sezer; Dimofte, Claudiu V.; Schmidt, Glen M.
Although product modularity is often advocated as a design strategy in the operations management literature, little is known about how consumers respond to modular products. In this research we undertake several experiments to explore consumer response to modularly upgradeable products in settings featuring technological change. We consider both the initial product choice (between a modularly upgradeable product and an integral one) and the subsequent upgrade decision (replacement of a module versus full product replacement). First, we show that consumers tend to discount the cost savings associated with modular upgrades excessively (insufficiently) when the time between the initial purchase and the upgrade is short (long). This suggests that modular upgradability as a product feature has higher profit potential for slowly rather than rapidly improving products. Second, we observe a preference reversal between the initial purchase and the point of upgrade: At the point of initial purchase, people foresee making a full product replacement in the future, yet, when faced with the actual upgrade decision, they are more likely to revert to modular upgrades. Finally, we discuss and test several pricing and product design strategies that the firm can use to respond to these cognitive biases.</description><author>Uelkue, Sezer; Dimofte, Claudiu V.; Schmidt, Glen M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Pricing with Financial Milestones: Feedback-Form Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Besbes, Omar; Maglaras, Costis
We study a seller that starts with an initial inventory of goods, has a target horizon over which to sell the goods, and is subject to a set of financial milestone constraints on the revenues and sales that need to be achieved at different time points along the sales horizon. We characterize the revenue maximizing dynamic pricing policy for the seller and highlight the effect of revenue and sales milestones on its structure. The optimal policy can be written in feedback form, where the price at each point in time is selected so as to track the most stringent among all future milestones. Building on that observation, we propose a discrete-review policy that aims to dynamically track the appropriate milestone constraint and show that this simple and practical policy is near optimal in settings with large initial capacity and long sales horizons even in settings with no advance demand model information. One motivating application comes from the sales of new multiunit, residential real estate developments, where intermediate milestone constraints play an important role in their financing and construction.</description><author>Besbes, Omar; Maglaras, Costis</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Learning Through Endogenous Information Acquisition: An Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Celen, Bogachan; Hyndman, Kyle
This paper provides a test of a theory of social learning through endogenous information acquisition. A group of subjects face a decision problem under uncertainty. Subjects are endowed with private information about the fundamentals of the problem and make decisions sequentially. The key feature of the experiment is that subjects can observe the decisions of predecessors by forming links at a cost. The model predicts that the average welfare is enhanced in the presence of a small cost. Our experimental results support this prediction. When the informativeness of signals changes across treatments, behavior changes in accordance with the theory. However, within treatments, there are important deviations from rationality such as a tendency to conform and excessive link formation. Given these biases, our results indicate that subjects would, except when faced with a small cost, have been better off not forming any links.</description><author>Celen, Bogachan; Hyndman, Kyle</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Outsourcing a Two-Level Service Process</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Hsiao-Hui; Pinker, Edieal J.; Shumsky, Robert A.
This paper studies outsourcing decisions for a two-level service process in which the first level serves as a 1 gatekeeper for a second level of experts. The objective of the system operator (the client) is to minimize the sum of staffing costs, customer waiting costs, and mistreatment costs due to unsuccessful attempts by a gatekeeper to solve the customer's problem. The client may outsource all or part of the process to a vendor, and first-best contracts exist when the client outsources only gatekeepers or experts. When the client outsources the entire system as a two-level process, a client-optimal contract may not exist unless the exogenous system parameters satisfy a particular (and unlikely) coordination condition. In addition, optimal incentive-compatible contracts exist when the vendor's structure choice (one level or two levels) can deviate from the client's preference. Finally, we numerically examine how vendor structure choice and labor cost advantages influence the client's optimal outsourcing option.</description><author>Lee, Hsiao-Hui; Pinker, Edieal J.; Shumsky, Robert A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From Wires to Partners: How the Internet Has Fostered R&amp;D Collaborations Within Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Forman, Chris; van Zeebroeck, Nicolas
How did the diffusion of the Internet influence research collaborations within firms? We examine the relationship between business use of basic Internet technology and the size and geographic composition of industrial research teams between 1992 and 1998. We find robust empirical evidence that basic Internet adoption is associated with an increased likelihood of collaborative patents from geographically dispersed teams. On the contrary, we find no evidence of such a link between Internet adoption and within-location collaborative patents, nor do we find any evidence of a relationship between basic Internet and single-inventor patents. We interpret these results as evidence that adoption of basic Internet significantly reduced the coordination costs of research teams, but find little evidence that a drop in the costs of shared resource access significantly improved research productivity.</description><author>Forman, Chris; van Zeebroeck, Nicolas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Money-Back Guarantees: Helping the Low-Quality Retailer</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McWilliams, Bruce
Existing literature, based on signaling theory, suggests that money-back guarantees (MBGs) will be utilized by high-quality firms, where high quality is defined as a low likelihood of product return. However, in today's world, MBGs are ubiquitous among major retailers, even when the likelihood of product return varies greatly between them. To understand this phenomenon, we explore a competitive environment between high- and low-quality retailers where consumers are fully informed and risk neutral, and retailers realize a salvage value for returned products. When MBGs are profitable, under continuous demand it is Nash equilibrium for both retailers to offer MBGs, and the low-quality retailer gains while the high-quality retailer loses relative to when MBGs are not offered. In contrast, if demand is lumpy, retailers can act monopolistically over their respective market segments, allowing both retailers to gain from MBGs, although the low-quality retailer still gains more.</description><author>McWilliams, Bruce</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Conditional Risk and Performance of Financially Distressed Stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O'Doherty, Michael S.
Several recent articles find that stocks with high probabilities of bankruptcy or default earn anomalously low returns and negative unconditional capital asset pricing model (CAPM) alphas in the post-1980 period. I show that the conditional CAPM resolves the performance difference between high- and low-distress stocks. In particular, financially distressed stocks have relatively low exposure to market risk during bad economic times. I help to explain these findings through a theoretical model in which a levered firm's equity beta is negatively related to uncertainty about the unobserved value of its underlying assets.</description><author>O'Doherty, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Working When No One Is Watching: Motivation, Test Scores, and Economic Success</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Segal, Carmit
This paper provides evidence that scores on simple, low-stakes tests are associated with future economic 1 success because the scores also reflect test takers' personality traits associated with their level of intrinsic motivation. To establish this, I use the coding speed test that was administered without incentives to participants in the National Longitudinal Survey of Youth (NLSY). I show that, controlling for cognitive ability, the coding speed scores are correlated with future earnings of male NLSY participants. I provide evidence that the coding speed scores relate to intrinsic motivation. I show that the scores of the highly motivated, though less educated, group (potential recruits to the U.S. military), are higher than the NLSY participants' scores. I use controlled experiments to show directly that intrinsic motivation is an important component of the unincentivized coding speed scores and that it relates to test takers' personality traits.</description><author>Segal, Carmit</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Examination of the Efficiency, Foreclosure, and Collusion Rationales for Vertical Takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shenoy, Jaideep
We investigate the efficiency, foreclosure, and collusion rationales for vertical integration in a large sample of vertically related takeovers. The efficiency rationale, as discussed under the transaction cost economics and property rights theories, posits that vertical integration mitigates contractual inefficiencies between suppliers and customers (termed as holdup) and provides incentives to undertake relationship-specific investments. In contrast, the foreclosure and collusion rationales suggest that vertical integration is anticompetitive in nature. Specifically, the foreclosure argument suggests that vertical integration is used to raise costs of rival firms, and the collusion argument suggests that vertical integration facilitates coordination between the integrated firm and its rivals. To distinguish between the three hypotheses, we examine (1) the announcement period wealth effects to the merging firms, rival firms, and customer firms; and (2) the operating performance changes to the merging firms in vertical takeovers. We find that firms expand their vertical boundaries consistent with an efficiency enhancing rationale.</description><author>Shenoy, Jaideep</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Market-Based Measure of Credit Portfolio Quality and Banks' Performance During the Subprime Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Knaup, Martin; Wagner, Wolf
We propose a new method for measuring the quality of banks' credit portfolios. This method makes use of information embedded in bank share prices by exploiting differences in their sensitivity to credit default swap spreads of borrowers of varying quality. The method allows us to derive a credit risk indicator (CRI). This indicator represents the perceived share of high-risk exposures in a bank's portfolio and can be used as a risk weight for computing regulatory capital requirements. We estimate CRIs for the 150 largest U.S. bank holding companies. We find that their CRIs are able to forecast bank failures and share price performances during the crisis of 2007-2009, even after controlling for a variety of traditional asset quality and general risk proxies.</description><author>Knaup, Martin; Wagner, Wolf</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ranking Intervals and Dominance Relations for Ratio-Based Efficiency Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Salo, Ahti; Punkka, Antti
We develop comparative results for ratio-based efficiency analysis (REA) based on the decision-making units' (DMUs') relative efficiencies over sets of feasible weights that characterize preferences for input and output variables. Specifically, we determine (i) ranking intervals, which indicate the best and worst efficiency rankings that a DMU can attain relative to other DMUs; (ii) dominance relations, which show what other DMUs a given DMU dominates in pairwise efficiency comparisons; and (iii) efficiency bounds, which show how much more efficient a given DMU can be relative to some other DMU or a subset of other DMUs. Unlike conventional efficiency scores, these results are insensitive to outlier DMUs. They also show how the DMUs' efficiency ratios relate to each other for all feasible weights, rather than for those weights only for which the data envelopment analysis (DEA) efficiency score of some DMU is maximized. We illustrate the usefulness of these results by revisiting reported DEA studies and by describing a recent case study on the efficiency comparison of university departments.</description><author>Salo, Ahti; Punkka, Antti</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the Two Components of Risk Attitudes: An Experimental Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qiu, Jianying; Steiger, Eva-Maria
Cumulative prospect theory introduced the weighting of probabilities as an additional component to capture risk attitudes. However, this addition would be a less significant challenge to expected utility theory (EU) if utility curvature and probability weighting showed strong positive correlation. In that case the utility curvature in EU alone, although not properly describing risky behavior in general, would still capture most of the variance of individual risk aversion. This study provides experimental evidence that such a strong and positive correlation does not exist. Although most individuals exhibit concave utility and convex probability weighting, the two components show no strong positive correlation.</description><author>Qiu, Jianying; Steiger, Eva-Maria</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Auctioneers Pick Optimal Reserve Prices?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davis, Andrew M.; Katok, Elena; Kwasnica, Anthony M.
We investigate how auctioneers set reserve prices in auctions. A well-established theoretical result, assuming risk neutrality of the seller, is that the optimal reserve price should not depend on the number of participating bidders. In a set of controlled laboratory experiments, we find that seller behavior often deviates from the theoretical benchmarks. We extend the existing theory to explore three alternative explanations for our results: risk aversion, anticipated regret, and probability weighting. After fitting our data to each of these models through parameter estimation techniques on both an aggregate and individual level, we find that all three models are consistent with some of the characteristics of our data, but that the regret model provides a slightly more favorable fit overall.</description><author>Davis, Andrew M.; Katok, Elena; Kwasnica, Anthony M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the Operational Impact of Container Inspections at International Ports</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, Nitin; Flynn, Stephen E.; Gans, Noah
A U.S. law mandating nonintrusive imaging and radiation detection for 100% of U. S.-bound containers at international ports has provoked widespread concern that the resulting congestion would hinder trade significantly. Using detailed data on container movements, gathered from two large international terminals, we simulate the impact of the two most important inspection policies that are being considered. We find that the current inspection regime being advanced by the U. S. Department of Homeland Security can only handle a small percentage of the total load. An alternate inspection protocol that emphasizes screening-a rapid primary scan of all containers, followed by a more careful secondary scan of only a few containers that fail the primary test-holds promise as a feasible solution for meeting the 100% scanning requirement.</description><author>Bakshi, Nitin; Flynn, Stephen E.; Gans, Noah</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competing to Be Certain (But Wrong): Market Dynamics and Excessive Confidence in Judgment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Radzevick, Joseph R.; Moore, Don A.
In this paper, we investigate how market competition contributes to the expression of overconfidence among those competing for influence. We find evidence that market competition exacerbates the tendency to express excessive confidence. This evidence comes from experiments in which advisors attempt to sell their advice. In the first, advisors must compete with other advice sellers. In the second, advisors and their customers are paired. Advisors are overconfident in both studies and it helps advisors sell their advice. However, competition between advisors in the market further exacerbates overconfidence. In a third study, we demonstrate that the market competition drives overconfidence even when advisors vary in quality. We also investigate the strategic expressions and interpretations of confidence by both sides in the exchange.</description><author>Radzevick, Joseph R.; Moore, Don A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Grammar-Based Integer Programming Models for Multiactivity Shift Scheduling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cote, Marie-Claude; Gendron, Bernard; Rousseau, Louis-Martin
This paper presents a new implicit formulation for shift scheduling problems, using context-free grammars to model the rules for the composition of shifts. From the grammar, we generate an integer programming (IP) model having a linear programming relaxation equivalent to that of the classical set covering model. When solved by a state-of-the-art IP solver on problem instances with a small number of shifts, our model, the set covering formulation, and a typical implicit model from the literature yield comparable solution times. On instances with a large number of shifts, our formulation shows superior performance and can model a wider variety of constraints. In particular, multiactivity cases, which cannot be modeled by existing implicit formulations, can easily be handled with grammars. We present comparative experimental results on a large set of instances involving one work activity, as well as on problems dealing with up to 10 work activities.</description><author>Cote, Marie-Claude; Gendron, Bernard; Rousseau, Louis-Martin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Opportunity Spaces in Innovation: Empirical Analysis of Large Samples of Ideas</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kornish, Laura J.; Ulrich, Karl T.
A common approach to innovation, parallel search, is to identify a large number of opportunities and then to select a subset for further development, with just a few coming to fruition. One potential weakness with parallel search is that it permits repetition. The same, or a similar, idea might be generated multiple times, because parallel exploration processes typically operate without information about the ideas that have already been identified. In this paper we analyze repetition in five data sets comprising 1,368 opportunities and use that analysis to address three questions: (1) When a large number of efforts to generate ideas are conducted in parallel, how likely are the resulting ideas to be redundant? (2) How large are the opportunity spaces? (3) Are the unique ideas more valuable than those similar to many others? The answer to the first question is that although there is clearly some redundancy in the ideas generated by aggregating parallel efforts, this redundancy is quite small in absolute terms in our data, even for a narrowly defined domain. For the second question, we propose a method to extrapolate how many unique ideas would result from an unbounded effort by an unlimited number of comparable idea generators. Applying that method, and for the settings we study, the estimated total number of unique ideas is about one thousand for the most narrowly defined domain and greater than two thousand for the more broadly defined domains. On the third question, we find a positive relationship between the number of similar ideas and idea value: the ideas that are least similar to others are not generally the most valuable ones.</description><author>Kornish, Laura J.; Ulrich, Karl T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Investigation of Earnings Management Through Marketing Actions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chapman, Craig J.; Steenburgh, Thomas J.
Prior research hypothesizes managers use "real actions," including the reduction of discretionary expenditures, to manage earnings to meet or beat key benchmarks. This paper examines this hypothesis by testing how different types of marketing expenditures are used to boost earnings for a durable commodity consumer product that can be easily stockpiled by end consumers. Combining supermarket scanner data with firm-level financial data, we find evidence that differs from prior literature. Instead of reducing expenditures to boost earnings, soup manufacturers roughly double the frequency and change the mix of marketing promotions (price discounts, feature advertisements, and aisle displays) at the fiscal quarter-end when they have greater incentive to boost earnings. Our results confirm managers' stated willingness to sacrifice long-term value in order to smooth earnings and their stated preference to use real actions to boost earnings to meet different types of earnings benchmarks. We estimate that marketing actions can be used to boost quarterly net income by up to 5% depending on the depth and duration of promotion. However, there is a price to pay, with the cost in the following period being approximately 7.5% of quarterly net income. Finally, a unique aspect of the research setting allows tests of who is responsible for the earnings management. Although firms appear unable to increase the frequency of aisle display promotions in the short run, they can reallocate these promotions within their portfolio of brands. Results show firms shifting display promotions away from smaller revenue brands toward larger ones following periods of poor financial performance. This indicates the behavior is determined by parties above brand managers in the firm. These findings are consistent with firms engaging in real earnings management and suggest that effects on subsequent reporting periods and competitor behavior are greater than previously documented.</description><author>Chapman, Craig J.; Steenburgh, Thomas J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Carbon Capture by Fossil Fuel Power Plants: An Economic Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Islegen, Oezge; Reichelstein, Stefan
For fossil fuel power plants to be built in the future, carbon capture and storage (CCS) technologies offer the potential for significant reductions in carbon dioxide (CO(2)) emissions. We examine the break-even value for CCS adoptions, that is, the critical value in the charge for CO(2) emissions that would justify investment in CCS capabilities. Our analysis takes explicitly into account that the supply of electricity at the wholesale level (generation) is organized competitively in some U. S. jurisdictions, whereas in others a regulated utility provides integrated generation and distribution services. For either market structure, we find that emissions charges near $30 per tonne of CO(2) would be the break-even value for adopting CCS capabilities at new coal-fired power plants. The corresponding break-even values for natural gas plants are substantially higher, near $60 per tonne. Our break-even estimates serve as a basis for projecting the change in electricity prices once carbon emissions become costly. CCS capabilities effectively put an upper bound on the increase in electricity prices resulting from carbon regulations, and we estimate this bound to be near 30% at the retail level for both coal and natural gas plants. In contrast to the competitive power supply scenario, however, these price increases materialize only gradually for a regulated utility. The delay in price adjustments reflects that for regulated firms the basis for setting product prices is historical cost, rather than current cost.</description><author>Islegen, Oezge; Reichelstein, Stefan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Management Insights</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorman, Michael F.
nan</description><author>Gorman, Michael F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the Operational Impact of Container Inspections at International Ports (vol 57, pg 1, 2010)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, Nitin; Flynn, Stephen E.; Gans, Noah
nan</description><author>Bakshi, Nitin; Flynn, Stephen E.; Gans, Noah</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Founders' Professional-Education Background on the Adoption of Open Science by For-Profit Biotechnology Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ding, Waverly W.
This paper investigates the effect of founders' professional-education background on the adoption of an open-science technology strategy, using a sample of 512 young biotechnology firms. After controlling for founders' prior work experience and other organizational and environmental factors, I find that firms with proportionally more Ph.D.-holding entrepreneurs on the founding team have a higher probability of adopting open science. In addition, founders' educational background can mitigate the constraint of organizational environments on strategy. A crowded technological niche provides a more challenging environment for firms to implement open science, due to higher scooping risks. The deterrent effect, however, of such a high-risk environment is smaller among firms founded by proportionally more Ph.D.-holding entrepreneurs. There is also some evidence of a stronger effect of founders' educational background on open science in an institutional environment in which open science has yet to become the industry norm. This finding is consistent with and complements the growing body of research that emphasizes the importance of entrepreneurial background in developing knowledge about new-venture strategy and structure.</description><author>Ding, Waverly W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Interpretation of Probabilities Estimated by Maximum Likelihood or Score</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnstone, D. J.
The conventional method of estimating a probability prediction model by maximum likelihood (MLE) is a form of maximum score estimation with economic meaning. Of all the probabilities that a given model might have produced, those obtained by MLE yield maximum in-sample betting return to a log utility investor. Recognition of this affinity between MLE and log utility begs the wider methodological question of whether different decision makers benefit in different degrees from different probabilities. Probabilities produced by MLE can be either too conservative or too bold relative to those found by maximizing utility under more risk-tolerant or risk-averse score functions. A very (not very) risk-averse user, who bets characteristically small (large) fractions of wealth based on a conservative forecast, is bound to make a rapidly (slowly) increasing bet as the forecast probability becomes progressively bolder or more distant from the market probability. The effect of this interaction between risk aversion and forecast is that a highly risk-averse user may need a much bolder forecast to obtain the same certainty equivalent as a more risk-tolerant investor. It follows more broadly that professional forecasters should anticipate how a client with given risk aversion expects to gain from any given forecast, or forecast revision, before committing resources toward making a better informed (but still honest) forecast.</description><author>Johnstone, D. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Choice Under Cumulative Prospect Theory: An Analytical Treatment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Xue Dong; Zhou, Xun Yu
We formulate and carry out an analytical treatment of a single-period portfolio choice model featuring a reference point in wealth, S-shaped utility (value) functions with loss aversion, and probability weighting under Kahneman and Tversky's cumulative prospect theory (CPT). We introduce a new measure of loss aversion for large payoffs, called the large-loss aversion degree (LLAD), and show that it is a critical determinant of the well-posedness of the model. The sensitivity of the CPT value function with respect to the stock allocation is then investigated, which, as a by-product, demonstrates that this function is neither concave nor convex. We finally derive optimal solutions explicitly for the cases in which the reference point is the risk-free return and those in which it is not (while the utility function is piecewise linear), and we employ these results to investigate comparative statics of optimal risky exposures with respect to the reference point, the LLAD, and the curvature of the probability weighting.</description><author>He, Xue Dong; Zhou, Xun Yu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing Consumer Returns in a Competitive Environment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shulman, Jeffrey D.; Coughlan, Anne T.; Savaskan, R. Canan
This paper investigates the pricing and restocking fee decisions of two competing firms selling horizontally differentiated products. We model a duopoly facing consumers who have heterogeneous tastes for the products and who must experience a product before knowing how well it matches with their preferences. The analysis yields several key insights. Restocking fees not only can be sustained in a competitive environment, but also are more severe when consumers are less informed about product fit and when consumers place a greater importance on how well products' attributes fit with their preferences. We compare the competitive equilibrium prices to a scenario in which consumers are certain about their preferences and find conditions defining when consumer uncertainty results in higher equilibrium prices. Comparison to a monopoly setting yields a surprising result: Equilibrium restocking fees in a competitive environment can be higher than those charged by a monopolist.</description><author>Shulman, Jeffrey D.; Coughlan, Anne T.; Savaskan, R. Canan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"I Think You Think I Think You're Lying": The Interactive Epistemology of Trust in Social Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moldoveanu, Mihnea C.; Baum, Joel A. C.
We investigate the epistemology of trust in social networks. We posit trust as a special epistemic state that depends on actors' beliefs about each others' beliefs as well as about states of the world. It offers new ideas and tools for representing the core elements of trust both within dyads and larger groups and presents an approach that makes trust measurable in a noncircular and predictive, rather than merely postdictive, fashion. After advancing arguments for the importance of interactive belief systems to the successful coordination of behavior, we tune our investigation of trust by focusing on beliefs that are important to mobilization and coordination and show how trust functions to influence social capital arising from network structure. We present empirical evidence corroborating the importance of higher-order beliefs to understanding trust and the interactive analysis of trust to the likelihood of successful coordination.</description><author>Moldoveanu, Mihnea C.; Baum, Joel A. C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quality-Speed Conundrum: Trade-offs in Customer-Intensive Services</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anand, Krishnan S.; Pac, M. Fazil; Veeraraghavan, Senthil
In many services, the quality or value provided by the service increases with the time the service provider spends with the customer. However, longer service times also result in longer waits for customers. We term such services, in which the interaction between quality and speed is critical, as customer-intensive services. In a queueing framework, we parameterize the degree of customer intensity of the service. The service speed chosen by the service provider affects the quality of the service through its customer intensity. Customers queue for the service based on service quality, delay costs, and price. We study how a service provider facing such customers makes the optimal "quality-speed trade-off." Our results demonstrate that the customer intensity of the service is a critical driver of equilibrium price, service speed, demand, congestion in queues, and service provider revenues. Customer intensity leads to outcomes very different from those of traditional models of service rate competition. For instance, as the number of competing servers increases, the price increases, and the servers become slower.</description><author>Anand, Krishnan S.; Pac, M. Fazil; Veeraraghavan, Senthil</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Privacy Regulation and Online Advertising</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldfarb, Avi; Tucker, Catherine E.
Advertisers use online customer data to target their marketing appeals. This has heightened consumers' privacy concerns, leading governments to pass laws designed to protect consumer privacy by restricting the use of data and by restricting online tracking techniques used by websites. We use the responses of 3.3 million survey takers who had been randomly exposed to 9,596 online display (banner) advertising campaigns to explore how privacy regulation in the European Union (EU) has influenced advertising effectiveness. This privacy regulation restricted advertisers' ability to collect data on Web users in order to target ad campaigns. We find that, on average, display advertising became far less effective at changing stated purchase intent after the EU laws were enacted, relative to display advertising in other countries. The loss in effectiveness was more pronounced for websites that had general content (such as news sites), where non-data-driven targeting is particularly hard to do. The loss of effectiveness was also more pronounced for ads with a smaller presence on the webpage and for ads that did not have additional interactive, video, or audio features.</description><author>Goldfarb, Avi; Tucker, Catherine E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recruiting for Ideas: How Firms Exploit the Prior Inventions of New Hires</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Singh, Jasjit; Agrawal, Ajay
When firms recruit inventors, they acquire not only the use of their skills but also enhanced access to their stock of ideas. But do hiring firms actually increase their use of new recruits' prior inventions? Our estimates suggest they do, quite significantly in fact, by approximately 219% on average. However, this does not necessarily reflect widespread "learning by hiring." In fact, we estimate that a recruit's exploitation of her own prior ideas accounts for almost half of the above effect, with much of the diffusion to others being limited to the recruit's immediate collaborative network. Furthermore, although one might expect the recruit's role to diminish rapidly as her tacit knowledge diffuses across her new firm, our estimates indicate that her importance is surprisingly persistent over time. We base these findings on an empirical strategy that exploits the variation over time in hiring firms' citations to the recruits' premove patents. Specifically, we employ a difference-indifferences approach to compare premove versus postmove citation rates for the recruits' prior patents and corresponding matched-pair control patents. Our methodology has three benefits compared to previous studies that also examine the link between labor mobility and knowledge flow: (1) it does not suffer from the upward bias inherent in the conventional cross-sectional comparison, (2) it generates results that are robust to a more stringently matched control sample, and (3) it enables a temporal examination of knowledge flow patterns.</description><author>Singh, Jasjit; Agrawal, Ajay</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Goods vs. Industrial Goods: Cost Structure and Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, Roy; Mendelson, Haim
We study markets for information goods and find that they differ significantly from markets for traditional industrial goods. Markets for information goods in which products are vertically differentiated lack the segmentation inherent in markets for industrial goods. As a result, a monopoly will offer only a single product. Competition leads to highly concentrated information-good markets, with the leading firm behaving almost like a monopoly even with free entry and without network effects. We study how the structure of the firms' cost functions drives our results.</description><author>Jones, Roy; Mendelson, Haim</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sabotage in Tournaments: Evidence from a Laboratory Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harbring, Christine; Irlenbusch, Bernd
Although relative performance schemes are pervasive in organizations, reliable empirical data on induced sabotage behavior are almost nonexistent. We study sabotage in repeated tournaments in a controlled laboratory experiment and observe that effort and sabotage are higher for higher wage spreads. Additionally, we find that also in the presence of tournament incentives, agents react reciprocally to higher wages by exerting higher effort. Destructive activities are reduced by explicitly calling them by their name "sabotage." Communication among principal and agents can curb sabotage when they agree on flat prize structures and increased output. If sabotage is not possible, the principals choose tournament incentives more often.</description><author>Harbring, Christine; Irlenbusch, Bernd</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contract Complexity and Performance Under Asymmetric Demand Information: An Experimental Evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalkanci, Basak; Chen, Kay-Yut; Erhun, Feryal
Exploring the tension between theory and practice regarding complexity and performance in contract design is especially relevant. The goal of this paper is to understand why simpler contracts may commonly be preferred in practice despite being theoretically suboptimal. We study a two-tier supply chain with a single supplier and a single buyer to characterize the impact of contract complexity and asymmetric information on performance and to compare theoretical predictions to actual behavior in human subject experiments. In the experiments, the computerized buyer faces a newsvendor setting and has better information on end-consumer demand than the human supplier. The supplier offers either a quantity discount contract (with two or three price blocks) or a price-only contract, contracts that are commonplace in practice, yet different in complexity. Results show that, contrary to theoretical predictions, quantity discounts do not necessarily increase the supplier's profits. We also observe a more equitable distribution of profits between the supplier and the buyer than what theory predicts. These observations can be described with three decision biases (the probabilistic choice bias, the reinforcement bias, and the memory bias) and can be modeled using the experience-weighted attraction learning model. Our results demonstrate that simpler contracts, such as a price-only contract or a quantity discount contract with a low number of price blocks, are sufficient for a supplier designing contracts under asymmetric demand information.</description><author>Kalkanci, Basak; Chen, Kay-Yut; Erhun, Feryal</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Buying from the Babbling Retailer? The Impact of Availability Information on Customer Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allon, Gad; Bassamboo, Achal
Provision of real-time information by a firm to its customers has become prevalent in recent years in both the service and retail sectors. In this paper, we study a retail operations model where customers are strategic in both their actions and in the way they interpret information, whereas the retailer is strategic in the way it provides information. This paper focuses on the ability (or the lack thereof) to communicate unverifiable information and influence customers' actions. We develop a game-theoretic framework to study this type of communication and discuss the equilibrium language emerging between the retailer and its customers. We show that for a single retailer and homogeneous customer population setting, the equilibrium language that emerges carries no information. In this sense, a single retailer providing information on its own cannot create any credibility with the customers. We study how the results are impacted due to the heterogeneity of the customers. We provide conditions under which the firm may be able to influence the customer behavior. In particular, we show that the customers' willingness to pay and willingness to wait cannot be ranked in an opposite manner. However, even when the firm can influence each customer class separately, the effective demand is not impacted.</description><author>Allon, Gad; Bassamboo, Achal</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capacity Investment Timing by Start-ups and Established Firms in New Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Swinney, Robert; Cachon, Gerard P.; Netessine, Serguei
We analyze the competitive capacity investment timing decisions of both established firms and start-ups entering new markets, which have a high degree of demand uncertainty. Firms may invest in capacity early (when uncertainty is high) or late (when uncertainty has been resolved), possibly at different costs. Established firms choose an investment timing and capacity level to maximize expected profits, whereas start-ups make those choices to maximize the probability of survival. When a start-up competes against an established firm, we find that when demand uncertainty is high and costs do not decline too severely over time, the start-up takes a leadership role and invests first in capacity, whereas the established firm follows; by contrast, when two established firms compete in an otherwise identical game, both firms invest late. We conclude that the threat of firm failure significantly impacts the dynamics of competition involving start-ups.</description><author>Swinney, Robert; Cachon, Gerard P.; Netessine, Serguei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of Fast Fashion: Quick Response, Enhanced Design, and Strategic Consumer Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cachon, Gerard P.; Swinney, Robert
A fast fashion system combines quick response production capabilities with enhanced product design capabilities to both design "hot" products that capture the latest consumer trends and exploit minimal production lead times to match supply with uncertain demand. We develop a model of such a system and compare its performance to three alternative systems: quick-response-only systems, enhanced-design-only systems, and traditional systems (which lack both enhanced design and quick response capabilities). In particular, we focus on the impact of each of the four systems on "strategic" or forward-looking consumer purchasing behavior, i.e., the intentional delay in purchasing an item at the full price to obtain it during an end-of-season clearance. We find that enhanced design helps to mitigate strategic behavior by offering consumers a product they value more, making them less willing to risk waiting for a clearance sale and possibly experiencing a stockout. Quick response mitigates strategic behavior through a different mechanism: by better matching supply to demand, it reduces the chance of a clearance sale. Most importantly, we find that although it is possible for quick response and enhanced design to be either complements or substitutes, the complementarity effect tends to dominate. Hence, when both quick response and enhanced design are combined in a fast fashion system, the firm typically enjoys a greater incremental increase in profit than the sum of the increases resulting from employing either system in isolation. Furthermore, complementarity is strongest when customers are very strategic. We conclude that fast fashion systems can be of significant value, particularly when consumers exhibit strategic behavior.</description><author>Cachon, Gerard P.; Swinney, Robert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Organizing Contests for Status: The Matthew Effect vs. the Mark Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bothner, Matthew S.; Podolny, Joel M.; Smith, Edward Bishop
What is the best way to design tournaments for status, in which individuals labor primarily for the esteem of their peers? What process, in other words, should organizers of status-based contests impose upon those who covet peer recognition? We propose a formal model of status-based competition that contrasts two competing alternatives. The first, following Merton, is the "Matthew Effect," according to which a tournament's architect directs slack resources to elite actors and thus widens the distribution of rewards by favoring cumulative advantage. The second is the " Mark Effect," under which a tournament's designer instead pushes slack resources to marginal actors and thus tightens the distribution of rewards. Our results suggest that although the Mark Effect is better for the social welfare of most tournaments, the Matthew Effect is preferable in two distinct contexts: in small tournaments where variation in underlying ability translates into acute advantages for the most capable contestants; and in large tournaments whose contestants face constant, rather than rising, marginal costs-a condition we relate to contestants' perception of their work as intrinsically valuable. Our contributions are twofold: We find, counter to the thrust of Merton's work, that cumulative advantage is not invariably optimal for the functioning of status contests; and we identify circumstances in which the production of superstars is likely to make contests for status better off in aggregate. Implications for future research on status and management are discussed.</description><author>Bothner, Matthew S.; Podolny, Joel M.; Smith, Edward Bishop</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Search Engine Advertising: Channel Substitution When Pricing Ads to Context</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldfarb, Avi; Tucker, Catherine E.
We explore substitution patterns across advertising platforms. Using data on the advertising prices paid by lawyers for 139 Google search terms in 195 locations, we exploit a natural experiment in "ambulance-chaser" regulations across states. When lawyers cannot contact clients by mail, advertising prices per click for search engine advertisements are 5%-7% higher. Therefore, online advertising substitutes for offline advertising. This substitution toward online advertising is strongest in markets with fewer customers, suggesting that the relationship between the online and offline media is mediated by the marketers' need to target their communications.</description><author>Goldfarb, Avi; Tucker, Catherine E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Dynamics for Customers of a Multiservice Provider</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schweidel, David A.; Bradlow, Eric T.; Fader, Peter S.
Multiservice providers, such as telecommunication and financial service companies, can benefit from understanding how customers' service portfolios evolve over the course of their relationships. This can provide guidance for managerial issues such as customer valuation and predicting customers' future behavior, whether it is acquiring additional services, selectively dropping current services, or ending the relationship entirely. In this research, we develop a dynamic hidden Markov model to identify latent states that govern customers' affinity for the available services through which customers evolve. In addition, we incorporate and demonstrate the importance of separating two other sources of dynamics: portfolio inertia and service stickiness. We then examine the relationship between state membership and managerially relevant metrics, including customers' propensities for acquiring additional services or terminating the relationship, and customer lifetime value. Through a series of illustrative vignettes, we show that customers who have discarded a particular service may have an increased risk of canceling all services in the near future (as intuition would suggest) but also may be more prone to acquire more services, a provocative finding of interest to service providers. Our findings also emphasize the need to look beyond the previous period, as in much current research, and consider how customers have evolved over their entire relationship in order to predict their future actions.</description><author>Schweidel, David A.; Bradlow, Eric T.; Fader, Peter S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A New Goodness-of-Fit Test for Event Forecasting and Its Application to Credit Defaults</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bloechlinger, Andreas; Leippold, Markus
We develop a new goodness-of-fit test for validating the performance of probability forecasts. Our test statistic is particularly powerful under sparseness and dependence in the observed data. To build our test statistic, we start from a formal definition of calibrated forecasts, which we operationalize by introducing two components. The first component tests the level of the estimated probabilities; the second validates the shape, measuring the differentiation between high and low probability events. After constructing test statistics for both level and shape, we provide a global goodness-of-fit statistic, which is asymptotically chi(2) distributed. In a simulation exercise, we find that our approach is correctly sized and more powerful than alternative statistics. In particular, our shape statistic is significantly more powerful than the Kolmogorov-Smirnov test. Under independence, our global test has significantly greater power than the popular Hosmer-Lemeshow's chi(2) test. Moreover, even under dependence, our global test remains correctly sized and consistent. As a timely and important empirical application of our method, we study the validation of a forecasting model for credit default events.</description><author>Bloechlinger, Andreas; Leippold, Markus</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating Heuristics Used When Designing Product Costing Systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balakrishnan, Ramji; Hansen, Stephen; Labro, Eva
The academic and practitioner literature justifies firms' use of product costs in product pricing and capacity planning decisions as heuristics to address an otherwise intractable problem. However, product costs are the output of a cost reporting system, which itself is the outcome of heuristic design choices. In particular, because of informational limitations, when designing cost systems firms use simple rules of thumb to group resources into cost pools and to select drivers used to allocate the pooled costs to products. Using simulations, we examine how popular choices in costing system design influence the error in reported costs. Taking information needs into account, we offer alternative ways to translate the vague guidance in the literature to implementable methods. Specifically, we compare size-based rules for forming cost pools with more informationally demanding correlation-based rules and develop a blended method that performs well in terms of accuracy. In addition, our analysis suggests that significant gains can be made from using a composite driver rather than selecting a driver based on the consumption pattern for the largest resource only, especially when combined with correlation-based rules to group resources. We vary properties of the underlying cost structure (such as the skewness in resource costs, the traceability of resources to products, the sharing of resources across products, and the variance in resource consumption patterns) to address the generalizability of our findings and to show when different heuristics might be preferred.</description><author>Balakrishnan, Ramji; Hansen, Stephen; Labro, Eva</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Plant Venture Performance Differences Among Incumbent, Diversifying, and Entrepreneurial Firms: The Impact of Industry Learning Intensity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balasubramanian, Natarajan
Prior firm experience, firm capabilities, and the industry environment are known to be important determinants of new-venture performance. We hypothesize that firm experience prior to setting up a new venture influences the ability to learn from experience after start-up (which is a key capability), and that this relationship is moderated by the importance of learning by doing within the new venture's industry (which is a critical aspect of the industry environment). We argue that together, these relationships influence performance differences among new plant ventures of incumbents, diversifying entrants, and entrepreneurial (de novo) entrants. Using data on 47,915 new plant ventures in U.S. manufacturing, we find that incumbents and diversifying entrants establish significantly more productive new plants than de novo entrants, and that this advantage significantly increases with the importance of learning by doing in an industry (industry learning intensity). These productivity differences appear to be driven more by learning subsequent to plant start-up than by initial disparities in productivity. Together, these findings strongly suggest that pre-start-up experience adds to the process of post-start-up learning, and that the industry learning environment plays an important role in whether entrepreneurial firms can achieve a competitive advantage over existing firms.</description><author>Balasubramanian, Natarajan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sharing Demand Information in Competing Supply Chains with Production Diseconomies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ha, Albert Y.; Tong, Shilu; Zhang, Hongtao
This paper studies the incentive for vertical information sharing in competing supply chains with production technologies that exhibit diseconomies of scale. We consider a model of two supply chains each consisting of one manufacturer selling to one retailer, with the retailers engaging in Cournot or Bertrand competition. For Cournot retail competition, we show that information sharing benefits a supply chain when (1) the production diseconomy is large and (2) either competition is less intense or at least one retailer's information is less accurate. A supply chain may become worse off when making its information more accurate or production diseconomy smaller, if such an improvement induces the firms in the rival supply chain to cease sharing information. For Bertrand retail competition, we show that information sharing benefits a supply chain when (1) the production diseconomy is large and (2) either competition is less intense or information is more accurate. Under Bertrand competition a manufacturer may be worse off by receiving information, which is never the case under Cournot competition. Information sharing in one supply chain triggers a competitive reaction from the other supply chain and this reaction is damaging to the first supply chain under Cournot competition but may be beneficial under Bertrand competition.</description><author>Ha, Albert Y.; Tong, Shilu; Zhang, Hongtao</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Midweight Method to Measure Attitudes Toward Risk and Ambiguity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van de Kuilen, Gijs; Wakker, Peter P.
This paper introduces a parameter-free method for measuring the weighting functions of prospect theory and rank-dependent utility. These weighting functions capture risk attitudes, subjective beliefs, and ambiguity attitudes. Our method, called the midweight method, is based on a convenient way to obtain midpoints in the weighting function scale. It can be used both for risk (known probabilities) and for uncertainty (unknown probabilities). The resulting integrated treatment of risk and uncertainty is particularly useful for measuring ambiguity, i.e., the difference between uncertainty and risk. Compared to existing methods to measure weighting functions and attitudes toward uncertainty and ambiguity, our method is more efficient and can accommodate violations of expected utility under risk. An experiment demonstrates the tractability of our method, yielding plausible results such as ambiguity aversion for moderate and high likelihoods but ambiguity seeking for low likelihoods, as predicted by Ellsberg.</description><author>van de Kuilen, Gijs; Wakker, Peter P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Promised Delivery Time and Capacity Games in Time-Based Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shang, Weixin; Liu, Liming
We investigate firms' competitive behaviors in industries where customers are sensitive to both promised delivery time (PDT) and quality of service (QoS) measured by the on-time delivery rate. To study the competition in PDT at the marketing level, we construct an oligopoly game with an external QoS requirement. We show that there exists a unique Nash equilibrium, and the equilibrium QoS exhibits a switching surface structure with respect to capacities. To study the competition in capacity at the strategic level, we construct a two-stage game in which the firms compete in terms of their capacities in stage 1 and in terms of PDT in stage 2. We show the existence of two different types of pure strategy equilibria and characterize them. This study provides the following insights: an index of time-based competitive advantage (ITCA) and the first-mover advantage determine the positions of the firms in time-based competition; either the well-known prisoner's dilemma or off-equilibrium behaviors due to different preferences for equilibria (when multiple equilibria exist) may lead the firms to overinvest in capacity, but no one may gain a competitive advantage; a uniform improvement in internal efficiency (i.e., a uniform capacity cost reduction) may harm everyone; quality differentiation (i.e., going beyond the QoS benchmark) plays a dual role in time-based competition, either helping a firm with a larger ITCA to compete more effectively, or helping a firm possibly with a smaller ITCA to preempt competitors and protect its market advantage.</description><author>Shang, Weixin; Liu, Liming</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Organizational Change and Employee Stress</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahl, Michael S.
This article analyzes the relationship between organizational change and employee health. It illuminates the potentially negative outcomes of change at the level of the employee. In addition, it relates to the ongoing debate over how employees react to and respond to organizational change. I hypothesize that change increases the risk of negative stress, and I test this hypothesis using a comprehensive panel data set of all stress-related medicine prescriptions for 92,860 employees working in 1,517 of the largest Danish organizations. The findings suggest that the risk of receiving stress-related medication increases significantly for employees at organizations that change, especially those that undergo broad simultaneous changes along several dimensions. Thus, organizational changes are associated with significant risks of employee health problems. These effects are further explored with respect to employees at different hierarchical levels as well as at firms of different sizes and from different sectors.</description><author>Dahl, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Status, Quality, and Attention: What's in a (Missing) Name?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Simcoe, Timothy S.; Waguespack, Dave M.
How much are we influenced by an author's identity when evaluating his or her work? This paper exploits a natural experiment to measure the impact of status signals in the context of open standards development. For a period of time, e-mails announcing new submissions to the Internet Engineering Task Force would replace individual author names with "et al." if submission volumes were unusually high. We measure the impact of status signals by comparing the effect of obscuring high-versus low-status author names. Our results show that name-based signals can explain up to three-quarters of the difference in publication rates between high- and low-status authors. The signaling effect disappears for a set of prescreened proposals that receive more scrutiny than a typical submission, suggesting that status signals are more important when attention is scarce (or search costs high). We also show that submissions from high-status authors receive more attention on electronic discussion boards, which may help high-status authors to develop their ideas and bring them forward to publication.</description><author>Simcoe, Timothy S.; Waguespack, Dave M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants and Outcomes of Internet Banking Adoption</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xue, Mei; Hitt, Lorin M.; Chen, Pei-yu
This paper examines the drivers of adoption of Internet banking and the linkages among adoption drivers and outcomes (product acquisition, service activity, profitability, loyalty). We relate Internet banking adoption to customer demand for banking services, the availability of alternative channels, customers' efficiency in service coproduction ("customer efficiency"), and local Internet banking penetration. We find that customers who have greater transaction demand and higher efficiency, and reside in areas with a greater density of online banking adopters, are faster to adopt online banking after controlling for time, regional, and individual characteristics. Consistent with prior work, we find that customers significantly increase their banking activity, acquire more products, and perform more transactions. These changes in behavior are not associated with short-run increases in customer profitability, but customers who adopt online banking have a lower propensity to leave the bank. Building on these observations we also find that the adoption drivers are linked to the postadoption changes in behavior or profitability. Customers who live in areas with a high branch density or high Internet banking penetration increase their product acquisition and transaction activity more than Internet banking adopters in other regions. Efficient customers and those with high service demand show greater postadoption profitability.</description><author>Xue, Mei; Hitt, Lorin M.; Chen, Pei-yu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Channel Stuffing with Short-Term Interest in Market Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lai, Guoming; Debo, Laurens; Nan, Lin
We study how a manager's short-term interest in the firm's market value may motivate channel stuffing: shipping excess inventory to the downstream channel. Channel stuffing allows a manager to report sales in excess of demand in order to influence investors' valuation of the firm. We apply an inventory model that highlights the potential role of inventory in the manager's channel stuffing and the investors' valuation strategies. Sales in our model are constrained by available inventory. Our model yields a semiseparating and semipooling equilibrium contingent on the initial inventory level: When the demand is lower than a threshold that depends on and is below the initial inventory level, the manager pads sales by a part of the excess inventory and releases the inflated sales report. The investors "correct" the reported sales and are able to infer perfectly the firm's value. When the demand reaches or exceeds this threshold, the manager pads any excess inventory to the sales and reports the initial inventory is sold out, which censors large demand realizations. Then the investors only infer the real demand is no less than the threshold and value the firm accordingly by expectation. Channel stuffing can influence the inventory decision, too. We find both over- and underinvestment in the initial inventory can arise in our model. We discuss empirical and managerial implications of our findings.</description><author>Lai, Guoming; Debo, Laurens; Nan, Lin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cooperation in Games with Forgetfulness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thomadsen, Raphael; Bhardwaj, Pradeep
Companies and managers are apt to forget information, yet classic game theory analysis assumes that all players have perfect recall. This paper expands the literature by examining how introducing forgetfulness into a multiplayer game-theoretic framework can help or hinder cooperative behavior. We find that forgetfulness impacts the ability of firms to cooperate in countervailing directions. On one hand, forgetfulness can diminish the ability to punish deviators, making cooperation more difficult. On the other hand, under some conditions forgetfulness can make meting out severe punishments-even below-(stage) minimax punishments-credible and decrease the ability for players to effectively deviate, facilitating cooperation even in circumstances where cooperation cannot be sustained under perfect recall. We apply our model to a number of strategic games that commonly appear in the literature.</description><author>Thomadsen, Raphael; Bhardwaj, Pradeep</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Recalls in the Medical Device Industry: An Empirical Exploration of the Sources and Financial Consequences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thirumalai, Sriram; Sinha, Kingshuk K.
Medical devices play an increasingly significant role in the delivery of health care today. However, persistent quality problems with medical devices and the associated recalls present potential health risks to patients and personnel using these devices. This study addresses three key issues in this regard. First, it empirically assesses the financial implications of medical device recalls to understand if these consequences are severe enough to deter firms from introducing potentially hazardous medical devices into the market, as can be inferred from the literature. Second, the study considers a cross section of medical device manufacturers to examine the effect of firm characteristics on the costs of poor quality. Third, in an attempt to explore the sources of recalls, this study investigates firm characteristics that are likely to be associated with device recalls. The econometric analyses in the study are based on data from manufacturers in the medical device industry over a four-year period (2002-2005). Contrary to our expectations, the findings of the study indicate that at an aggregate level, the market penalties for medical device recalls are not significant, i.e., at the aggregate level, the costs of poor quality are not severe. Furthermore, we find that the magnitude of financial consequences of device recalls is affected by the product scope, sales, growth prospects, and the capital structure of a firm. In our analyses exploring the sources of device recalls, we find that firms with a research and development focus, developing broader product portfolios, have a higher likelihood of device recalls. Also, we find that the likelihood of recalls decreases with prior recall experience, indicating the presence of learning. Implications of the study findings, limitations, and directions for future research are identified.</description><author>Thirumalai, Sriram; Sinha, Kingshuk K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Accelerated Learning of User Profiles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atahan, Pelin; Sarkar, Sumit
Websites typically provide several links on each page visited by a user. Whereas some of these links help users easily navigate the site, others are typically used to provide targeted recommendations based on the available user profile. When the user profile is not available ( or is inadequate), the site cannot effectively target products, promotions, and advertisements. In those situations, the site can learn the profile of a user as the user traverses the site. Naturally, the faster the site can learn a user's profile, the sooner the site can benefit from personalization. We develop a technique that sites can use to learn the profile as quickly as possible. The technique identifies links for sites to make available that will lead to a more informative profile when the user chooses one of the offered links. Experiments conducted using our approach demonstrate that it enables learning the profiles markedly better after very few user interactions as compared to benchmark approaches. The approach effectively learns multiple attributes simultaneously, can learn well classes that have highly skewed priors, and remains quite effective even when the distribution of link profiles at a site is relatively homogeneous. The approach works particularly well when a user's traversal is influenced by the most recently visited pages on a site. Finally, we show that the approach is robust to noise in the estimates for the probability parameters needed for its implementation.</description><author>Atahan, Pelin; Sarkar, Sumit</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Noncompete Covenants: Incentives to Innovate or Impediments to Growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Samila, Sampsa; Sorenson, Olav
We find that the enforcement of noncompete clauses significantly impedes entrepreneurship and employment growth. Based on a panel of metropolitan areas in the United States from 1993 to 2002, our results indicate that, relative to states that enforce noncompete covenants, an increase in the local supply of venture capital in states that restrict the scope of these agreements has significantly stronger positive effects on (i) the number of patents, (ii) the number of firm starts, and (iii) employment. We address potential endogeneity in the supply of venture capital by using endowment returns as an instrumental variable. Our results point to a strong interaction between financial intermediation and the legal regime in promoting entrepreneurship and economic growth.</description><author>Samila, Sampsa; Sorenson, Olav</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reference-Point Formation and Updating</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baucells, Manel; Weber, Martin; Welfens, Frank
Reference-dependent preferences have been well accepted in decision sciences, experimental economics, behavioral finance, and marketing. However, we still know very little about how decision makers form and update their reference points given a sequence of information. Our paper provides some novel experiments in a financial context to advance the understanding of reference-point formation over time. Our subjects' reference price is best described as a combination of the first and the last price of the time series, with intermediate prices receiving smaller and nondecaying weights. Hence, reference prices are not recursive. We provide a parsimonious formula to predict the reference points, which we test out-of-sample. The fit of the model is reasonably good.</description><author>Baucells, Manel; Weber, Martin; Welfens, Frank</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Model of Probabilistic Choice Satisfying First-Order Stochastic Dominance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blavatskyy, Pavlo R.
This paper presents a new model of probabilistic binary choice under risk. In this model, a decision maker always satisfies first-order stochastic dominance. If neither lottery stochastically dominates the other alternative, a decision maker chooses in a probabilistic manner. The proposed model is derived from four standard axioms (completeness, weak stochastic transitivity, continuity, and common consequence independence) and two relatively new axioms. The proposed model provides a better fit to experimental data than do existing models. The baseline model can be extended to other domains such as modeling variable consumer demand.</description><author>Blavatskyy, Pavlo R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cyclical Bid Adjustments in Search-Engine Advertising</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Xiaoquan; Feng, Juan
Keyword advertising, or sponsored search, is one of the most successful advertising models on the Internet. One distinctive feature of keyword auctions is that they enable advertisers to adjust their bids and rankings dynamically, and the payoffs are realized in real time. We capture this unique feature with a dynamic model and identify an equilibrium bidding strategy. We find that under certain conditions, advertisers may engage in cyclical bid adjustments, and equilibrium bidding prices may follow a cyclical pattern: price-escalating phases interrupted by price-collapsing phases, similar to an "Edgeworth cycle" in the context of dynamic price competitions. Such cyclical bidding patterns can take place in both first-and second-price auctions. We obtain two data sets containing detailed bidding records of all advertisers for a sample of keywords in two leading search engines. Our empirical framework, based on a Markov switching regression model, suggests the existence of such cyclical bidding strategies. The cyclical bid-updating behavior we find cannot be easily explained with static models. This paper emphasizes the importance of adopting a dynamic perspective in studying equilibrium outcomes of keyword auctions.</description><author>Zhang, Xiaoquan; Feng, Juan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pooling, Access, and Countervailing Power in Channel Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hendrikse, George
Fruit and vegetable marketing organization the Greenery has experienced various governance structure changes, like horizontal merger, forward integration, and the emergence of grower associations. A multilateral incomplete contracting model is presented to account for these changes by analysing the interactions between pooling, access, and countervailing power. This model does not only explain the changes at the Greenery, but it contributes also to the design of efficient channel governance.</description><author>Hendrikse, George</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Empirical Analysis of User Content Generation and Usage Behavior on the Mobile Internet</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghose, Anindya; Han, Sang Pil
We quantify how user mobile Internet usage relates to unique characteristics of the mobile Internet. In particular, we focus on examining how the mobile-phone-based content generation behavior of users relates to content usage behavior. The key objective is to analyze whether there is a positive or negative interdependence between the two activities. We use a unique panel data set that consists of individual-level mobile Internet usage data that encompass individual multimedia content generation and usage behavior. We combine this knowledge with data on user calling patterns, such as duration, frequency, and locations from where calls are placed, to construct their social network and to compute their geographical mobility. We build an individual-level simultaneous equation panel data model that controls for the different sources of endogeneity of the social network. We find that there is a negative and statistically significant temporal interdependence between content generation and usage. This finding implies that an increase in content usage in the previous period has a negative impact on content generation in the current period and vice versa. The marginal effect of this interdependence is stronger on content usage (up to 8.7%) than on content generation (up to 4.3%). The extent of geographical mobility of users has a positive effect on their mobile Internet activities. Users more frequently engage in content usage compared to content generation when they are traveling. In addition, the variance of user mobility has a stronger impact on their mobile Internet activities than does the mean. We also find that the social network has a strong positive effect on user behavior in the mobile Internet. These analyses unpack the mechanisms that stimulate user behavior on the mobile Internet. Implications for shaping user mobile Internet usage behavior are discussed.</description><author>Ghose, Anindya; Han, Sang Pil</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Durable Products, Time Inconsistency, and Lock-in</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilbert, Stephen M.; Jonnalagedda, Sreelata
Many durable products cannot be used without a contingent consumable product, e. g., printers require ink, iPods require songs, razors require blades, etc. For such products, manufacturers may be able to lock in consumers by making their products incompatible with consumables that are produced by other firms. We examine the effectiveness of such a strategy in the presence of strategic consumers who anticipate the future prices of both the durable product and the contingent consumable. Under a lock-in strategy, the manufacturer has pricing power over the contingent consumable, which she can use to extract additional rents from higher valuation consumers, but such pricing power may also reduce consumers' willingness to pay for the durable because it subjects them to being held up with higher consumables prices in the future. Restricting our attention to linear pricing policies, we find that if the manufacturer can commit to shutting down production of her durable after an initial one-time sale, then competition from another consumable of an appropriately degraded level of quality can benefit the manufacturer by mitigating consumers' fears of being held up. On the other hand, when the manufacturer cannot commit to shutting down production of her durable, then her own output of additional durables gives her an incentive to keep consumables prices low, and competition in the consumables market is less beneficial.</description><author>Gilbert, Stephen M.; Jonnalagedda, Sreelata</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Newspaper Reports and Consumer Choice: Evidence from the Do Not Call Registry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goh, Khim-Yong; Hui, Kai-Lung; Png, Ivan P. L.
Despite annual expenditures on public relations exceeding $19.42 billion, U.S. businesses lack practical guidance about the effectiveness of publicity in mass media. Here, we assemble a rich and novel data set to gauge the impact of news reports on consumer sign-ups with the U.S. Do Not Call (DNC) Registry. Using multiple identification strategies, we found robust evidence that news reports increased consumer registrations. Specifically, a 1% increase in the number of news reports increased DNC registrations by 0.018%. The impact increased with mention of the toll-free telephone number and URL, but decreased with the length of the headline and main text. Furthermore, we found evidence that reports affect behavior through persuasion as well as information-the impact on registration was higher for reports that mentioned the number of other people registering. Finally, the impact of news reports on consumer registration was stronger in national than local newspapers and in politically neutral and Democrat than Republican newspapers.</description><author>Goh, Khim-Yong; Hui, Kai-Lung; Png, Ivan P. L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dark Side of Rapport: Agent Misbehavior Face-to-Face and Online</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jap, Sandy; Robertson, Diana C.; Hamilton, Ryan
A considerable body of research has extolled the virtues of establishing rapport in negotiations. Negotiators who are high in rapport tend to be more likely to reach an agreement and more satisfied with the outcome. Although rapport generally has been found to have positive effects in standard negotiation settings, we investigate the effects of rapport in impasse settings, where conflict between negotiators' core needs means that a successful deal can only be reached when one or both parties acts unethically or "misbehaves," for example, by lying to the negotiation partner. In a series of three experiments, we find that negotiators who have a high level of rapport are more likely to behave unethically than are negotiators who have a low level of rapport. We find this effect holds both when high rapport results from the way in which negotiations are conducted (face-to-face versus computer mediated) and also when rapport is established through a brief rapport-building exercise before negotiations begin. Finally, we find that the negative effects (unethical behavior)-but not the positive effects (satisfaction with the negotiation, trust, and willingness to work in the future with the negotiation partner)-of high rapport are reduced when negotiators are given a simple reminder before negotiations begin that one's actions can have long-term repercussions for one's reputation. Taken together, this research supports the idea that, despite its several advantages, in certain situations rapport has a dark side, of which negotiators must be wary.</description><author>Jap, Sandy; Robertson, Diana C.; Hamilton, Ryan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Stock Market in the Driver's Seat! Implications for R&amp;D and Marketing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chakravarty, Anindita; Grewal, Rajdeep
The budgets for research and development (R&amp;D) and marketing should be determined by managers to attain product market advantages. However, in response to investor expectations for short-term stock returns, managers may modify these budgets myopically to avoid unexpected short-term earnings shortfalls, at the cost of long-term profitability. We propose that the past behavior of firm stock returns and volatility may create investor expectations of short-term financial performance, which drives managers to modify either R&amp;D or marketing budgets or both. In the context of high-technology firms, a Bayesian vector autoregression model, supported by content analysis, shows that few firms exhibit high levels of managerial myopia by simultaneously cutting both R&amp;D and marketing budgets; instead, firms display moderate myopic reactions, in the form of unanticipated decreases in R&amp;D budgets but increased budgets for marketing functions. The tendency to manage myopically in response to past stock returns and volatility increases as firm size or industry concentration decrease.</description><author>Chakravarty, Anindita; Grewal, Rajdeep</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Threat from Within: Account Managers' Concern About Opportunism by Their Own Team Members</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Murtha, Brian R.; Challagalla, Goutam; Kohli, Ajay K.
It is well known that transaction-specific investments (TSIs) made in customers by account managers makes them vulnerable to opportunism by customers (i.e., the targets of the investments). The present research shows that TSIs made in customers by account managers can also lead them to be concerned about internal opportunism by nontargets of the investments (e.g., information technology or finance specialists in their own teams). Furthermore, it shows that concern about internal opportunism leads account managers to engage in internal blocking of their own team members (i.e., restricting their access to customers and to customer information) 1 which results in lower performance with customers. This phenomenon is a conundrum in that account managers interested in stronger performance with customers appear to block the very functional specialists who can help them attain better performance. This research also identifies two types of continuities (account manager-customer continuity and specialist-customer continuity) that moderate the relationship between TSIs and concern about internal opportunism. Building on the literature in economics and organization theory, our research suggests that cross-functional teams that are designed to bring different functional areas together are more complex to manage than previously believed.</description><author>Murtha, Brian R.; Challagalla, Goutam; Kohli, Ajay K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal and Competitive Assortments with Endogenous Pricing Under Hierarchical Consumer Choice Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koek, A. Guerhan; Xu, Yi
This paper studies assortment planning and pricing for a product category with heterogeneous product types from two brands. We model consumer choice using the nested multinomial logit framework with two different hierarchical structures: a brand-primary model in which consumers choose a brand first, then a product type in the chosen brand, and a type-primary model in which consumers choose a product type first, then a brand within that product type. We consider a centralized regime that finds the optimal solution for the whole category and a decentralized regime that finds a competitive equilibrium between two brands. We find that optimal and competitive assortments and prices have quite distinctive properties across different models. Specifically, with the brand-primary model, both the optimal and the competitive assortments for each brand consist of the most popular product types from the brand. With the type-primary choice model, the optimal and the competitive assortments for each brand may not always consist of the most popular product types of the brand. Instead, the overall assortment in the category consists of a set of most popular product types. The price of a product under the centralized regime can be characterized by a sum of a markup that is constant across all products and brands, its procurement cost, and its marginal operational cost, implying a lower price for more popular products. The markup may be different for each brand and product type under the decentralized regime, implying a higher price for brands with a larger market share. These properties of the assortments and prices can be used as effective guidelines for managers to identify and price the best assortments and to rule out nonoptimal assortments. Our results suggest that to offer the right set of products and prices, category and/or brand managers should create an assortment planning process that is aligned with the hierarchical choice process consumers commonly follow to make purchasing decisions.</description><author>Koek, A. Guerhan; Xu, Yi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Social Responsibility and Competitive Advantage: Overcoming the Trust Barrier</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Du, Shuili; Bhattacharya, C. B.; Sen, Sankar
This research builds on the complementary corporate social responsibility (CSR) literatures in strategy and marketing to provide insight into the efficacy of CSR as a challenger's competitive weapon against a market leader. Through an investigation of a real-world CSR initiative, we show that the challenger can reap superior business returns (i. e., more positive attitudinal and behavioral outcomes) among consumers who had participated in its CSR initiative, relative to those who were merely aware of the initiative. Specifically, participant consumers demonstrate the desired attitudinal and behavioral changes in favor of the challenger, regardless of their affective trust in the leader, whereas aware consumers' reactions become less favorable as their affective trust in the leader increases. Furthermore, participant consumers, but not aware ones, form a communal, trust-based bond with the challenger.</description><author>Du, Shuili; Bhattacharya, C. B.; Sen, Sankar</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Introduction to the Special Issue on Marketing Within the Enterprise and Beyond</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chintagunta, Pradeep K.; Desai, Preyas S.
nan</description><author>Chintagunta, Pradeep K.; Desai, Preyas S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk-Neutral Models for Emission Allowance Prices and Option Valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carmona, Rene; Hinz, Juri
The existence of mandatory emission trading schemes in Europe and the United States, and the increased liquidity of trading on futures contracts on CO2 emissions allowances, led naturally to the next step in the development of these markets: These futures contracts are now used as underliers for a vibrant derivative market. In this paper, we give a rigorous analysis of a simple risk-neutral reduced-form model for allowance futures prices, demonstrate its calibration to historical data, and show how to price European call options written on these contracts.</description><author>Carmona, Rene; Hinz, Juri</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging and Vertical Integration in Electricity Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aid, Rene; Chemla, Gilles; Porchet, Arnaud; Touzi, Nizar
This paper analyzes the interactions between competitive (wholesale) spot, retail, and forward markets and vertical integration in electricity markets. We develop an equilibrium model with producers, retailers, and traders to study and quantify the impact of forward markets and vertical integration on prices, risk premia, and retail market shares. We point out that forward hedging and vertical integration are two separate mechanisms for demand and spot price risk diversification that both reduce the retail price and increase retail market shares. We show that they differ in their impact on prices and firms' utility because of the asymmetry between production and retail segments. Vertical integration restores the symmetry between producers' and retailers' exposure to demand risk, whereas linear forward contracts do not. Vertical integration is superior to forward hedging when retailers are highly risk averse. We illustrate our analysis with data from the French electricity market.</description><author>Aid, Rene; Chemla, Gilles; Porchet, Arnaud; Touzi, Nizar</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Benefits of Aggregate Performance Metrics in the Presence of Career Concerns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arya, Anil; Mittendorf, Brian
This paper considers the desirability of aggregate performance measures in light of the fact that many individuals' performance incentives are driven by a desire to shape external perceptions (and thus future pay). In contrast to the case of explicit incentive contracts, we find that when individuals' actions are driven by career incentives, an aggregate measure (e.g., group or team output) can sometimes alleviate moral hazard concerns and improve efficiency. Aggregation intermingles performance measures that may be differentially affected by skill and effort of many agents. When such entanglement increases the prospect that the external market will attribute an employee's effort-driven contribution to transferable skills, the employee exerts higher effort as a means of posturing to the market. The incentive benefit of aggregation is weighed against the incentive cost because of information loss. Information loss from aggregation can reduce the market's reliance on the measure and thus diminish agents' desire to undertake effort to influence the measure.</description><author>Arya, Anil; Mittendorf, Brian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Generalized Measure of Riskiness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Cakici, Nusret; Chabi-Yo, Fousseni
This paper proposes a generalized measure of riskiness that nests the original measures pioneered by Aumann and Serrano (Aumann, R. J., R. Serrano. 2008. An economic index of riskiness. J. Political Econom. 116(5) 810-836) and Foster and Hart (Foster, D. P., S. Hart. 2009. An operational measure of riskiness. J. Political Econom. 117(5) 785-814). The paper introduces the generalized options' implied measure of riskiness based on the risk-neutral return distribution of financial securities. It also provides asset allocation implications and shows that the forward-looking measures of riskiness successfully predict the cross section of 1-, 3-, 6-, and 12-month-ahead risk-adjusted returns of individual stocks. The empirical results indicate that the generalized measure of riskiness is able to rank equity portfolios based on their expected returns per unit of risk and hence yields a more efficient strategy for maximizing expected return of the portfolio while minimizing its risk.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Cakici, Nusret; Chabi-Yo, Fousseni</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deriving the Pricing Power of Product Features by Mining Consumer Reviews</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Archak, Nikolay; Ghose, Anindya; Ipeirotis, Panagiotis G.
Increasingly, user-generated product reviews serve as a valuable source of information for customers making product choices online. The existing literature typically incorporates the impact of product reviews on sales based on numeric variables representing the valence and volume of reviews. In this paper, we posit that the information embedded in product reviews cannot be captured by a single scalar value. Rather, we argue that product reviews are multifaceted, and hence the textual content of product reviews is an important determinant of consumers' choices, over and above the valence and volume of reviews. To demonstrate this, we use text mining to incorporate review text in a consumer choice model by decomposing textual reviews into segments describing different product features. We estimate our model based on a unique data set from Amazon containing sales data and consumer review data for two different groups of products (digital cameras and camcorders) over a 15-month period. We alleviate the problems of data sparsity and of omitted variables by providing two experimental techniques: clustering rare textual opinions based on pointwise mutual information and using externally imposed review semantics. This paper demonstrates how textual data can be used to learn consumers' relative preferences for different product features and also how text can be used for predictive modeling of future changes in sales.</description><author>Archak, Nikolay; Ghose, Anindya; Ipeirotis, Panagiotis G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Overconfidence and Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Galasso, Alberto; Simcoe, Timothy S.
Are the attitudes and beliefs of chief executive officers (CEOs) linked to their firms' innovative performance? This paper uses a measure of overconfidence, based on CEO stock-option exercise, to study the relationship between a CEO's "revealed beliefs" about future performance and standard measures of corporate innovation. We begin by developing a career concern model where CEOs innovate to provide evidence of their ability. The model predicts that overconfident CEOs, who underestimate the probability of failure, are more likely to pursue innovation, and that this effect is larger in more competitive industries. We test these predictions on a panel of large publicly traded firms for the years from 1980 to 1994. We find a robust positive association between overconfidence and citation-weighted patent counts in both cross-sectional and fixed-effect models. This effect is larger in more competitive industries. Our results suggest that overconfident CEOs are more likely to take their firms in a new technological direction.</description><author>Galasso, Alberto; Simcoe, Timothy S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic Risk: What Defaults Are Telling Us</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giesecke, Kay; Kim, Baeho
This paper develops dynamic measures of the systemic risk of the financial sector as a whole. It defines systemic risk as the conditional probability of failure of a sufficiently large fraction of the total population of financial institutions. This definition recognizes that the cause of systemic distress is the correlated failure of institutions to meet obligations to creditors, customers, and trading partners. The likelihood estimators of the failure probability are based on a dynamic hazard model of correlated failure timing that captures the influence on failure timing of time-varying macroeconomic and sector-specific risk factors, and of spillover effects. Tests indicate that our measures provide accurate out-of-sample forecasts of the term structure of systemic risk in the United States for the period from 1998 to 2009.</description><author>Giesecke, Kay; Kim, Baeho</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Goodbye Pareto Principle, Hello Long Tail: The Effect of Search Costs on the Concentration of Product Sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brynjolfsson, Erik; Hu, Yu; Simester, Duncan
Many markets have historically been dominated by a small number of best-selling products. The Pareto principle, also known as the 80/20 rule, describes this common pattern of sales concentration. However, information technology in general and Internet markets in particular have the potential to substantially increase the collective share of niche products, thereby creating a longer tail in the distribution of sales. This paper investigates the Internet's "long tail" phenomenon. By analyzing data collected from a multichannel retailer, it provides empirical evidence that the Internet channel exhibits a significantly less concentrated sales distribution when compared with traditional channels. Previous explanations for this result have focused on differences in product availability between channels. However, we demonstrate that the result survives even when the Internet and traditional channels share exactly the same product availability and prices. Instead, we find that consumers' usage of Internet search and discovery tools, such as recommendation engines, are associated with an increase the share of niche products. We conclude that the Internet's long tail is not solely due to the increase in product selection but may also partly reflect lower search costs on the Internet. If the relationships we uncover persist, the underlying trends in technology portend an ongoing shift in the distribution of product sales.</description><author>Brynjolfsson, Erik; Hu, Yu; Simester, Duncan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Group Buying: A New Mechanism for Selling Through Social Interactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jing, Xiaoqing; Xie, Jinhong
This paper examines a unique selling strategy, Group Buying, under which consumers enjoy a discounted group price if they are willing and able to achieve a required group size and coordinate their transaction time. We argue that Group Buying allows a seller to gain from facilitating consumer social interaction, i.e., using a group discount to motivate informed customers to work as "sales agents" to acquire less-informed customers through interpersonal information/knowledge sharing. We formally model such an information-sharing effect and examine if and when Group Buying is more profitable than (1) traditional individual-selling strategies, and (2) another popular social interaction scheme, Referral Rewards programs. We show that Group Buying dominates traditional individual-selling strategies when the information/knowledge gap between expert and novice consumers is neither too high nor too low (e.g., for products in the midstage of their life cycle) and when interpersonal information sharing is very efficient (e.g., in cultures that emphasize trust and group conformity, or when implemented through existing online social networks). We also show that, unlike Referral Rewards programs, Group Buying requires information sharing before any transaction takes place, thereby increasing the scale of social interaction but also incurring a higher cost. As a result, Group Buying is optimal when interpersonal communication is very efficient or when the product valuation of the less-informed consumer segment is high.</description><author>Jing, Xiaoqing; Xie, Jinhong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creating Social Contagion Through Viral Product Design: A Randomized Trial of Peer Influence in Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aral, Sinan; Walker, Dylan
We examine how firms can create word-of-mouth peer influence and social contagion by designing viral features into their products and marketing campaigns. To econometrically identify the effectiveness of different viral features in creating social contagion, we designed and conducted a randomized field experiment involving the 1.4 million friends of 9,687 experimental users on Facebook.com. We find that viral features generate econometrically identifiable peer influence and social contagion effects. More surprisingly, we find that passive-broadcast viral features generate a 246% increase in peer influence and social contagion, whereas adding active-personalized viral features generate only an additional 98% increase. Although active-personalized viral messages are more effective in encouraging adoption per message and are correlated with more user engagement and sustained product use, passive-broadcast messaging is used more often, generating more total peer adoption in the network. Our work provides a model for how randomized trials can identify peer influence in social networks.</description><author>Aral, Sinan; Walker, Dylan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Labor Illusion: How Operational Transparency Increases Perceived Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buell, Ryan W.; Norton, Michael I.
A ubiquitous feature of even the fastest self-service technology transactions is the wait. Conventional wisdom and operations theory suggest that the longer people wait, the less satisfied they become; we demonstrate that because of what we term the labor illusion, when websites engage in operational transparency by signaling that they are exerting effort, people can actually prefer websites with longer waits to those that return instantaneous results-even when those results are identical. In five experiments that simulate service experiences in the domains of online travel and online dating, we demonstrate the impact of the labor illusion on service value perceptions, demonstrate that perceptions of service provider effort induce feelings of reciprocity that together mediate the link between operational transparency and increased valuation, and explore boundary conditions and alternative explanations.</description><author>Buell, Ryan W.; Norton, Michael I.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Label Confusion: The Groucho Effect of Uncertain Standards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harbaugh, Rick; Maxwell, John W.; Roussillon, Beatrice
abels certify that a product meets some standard for quality, but often consumers are unsure of the exact standard that the label represents. Focusing on the case of ecolabels for environmental quality, we show how even small amounts of uncertainty can create consumer confusion that reduces or eliminates the value to firms of adopting voluntary labels. First, consumers are most suspicious of a label when a product with a bad reputation has it, so labels are often unpersuasive at showing that a seemingly bad product is actually good. Second, label proliferation aggravates the effect of uncertainty, causing the informativeness of labels to decrease rather than increase. Third, uncertainty makes labeling and nonlabeling equilibria more likely to coexist as the number of labels increases, so consumers face greater strategic uncertainty over how to interpret the presence or absence of a label. Finally, a label can be legitimitized or spoiled for other products when a product with a good or bad reputation displays it, so firms may adopt labels strategically to manipulate such information spillovers, which further exacerbates label confusion. Managers can reduce label confusion by supporting mandatory labeling or by undertaking investments to make certain labels "focal."</description><author>Harbaugh, Rick; Maxwell, John W.; Roussillon, Beatrice</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monte Carlo Algorithms for Default Timing Problems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giesecke, Kay; Kim, Baeho; Zhu, Shilin
Dynamic, intensity-based point process models are widely used to measure and price the correlated default risk in portfolios of credit-sensitive assets such as loans and corporate bonds. Monte Carlo simulation is an important tool for performing computations in these models. This paper develops, analyzes, and evaluates two simulation algorithms for intensity-based point process models. The algorithms extend the conventional thinning scheme to the case where the event intensity is unbounded, a feature common to many standard model formulations. Numerical results illustrate the performance of the algorithms for a familiar top-down model and a novel bottom-up model of correlated default risk.</description><author>Giesecke, Kay; Kim, Baeho; Zhu, Shilin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance, Debt, and Investment Policy During the Great Depression</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, John R.; Hazarika, Sonali; Narasimhan, Krishnamoorthy
We study a period of severe disequilibrium to investigate whether board characteristics are related to corporate investment, debt usage, and firm value. During the 1930-1938 Depression era, when the corporate sector was shocked by an unprecedented downturn, we document a relation between board characteristics and firm performance that varies in economically sensible ways: Complex firms (that would benefit more from board advice) exhibit a positive relation between board size and firm value, and simple firms exhibit a negative relation between board size and firm value. Moreover, simple firms with large boards do not downsize adequately in response to the severe economic contraction: they invest more (or shrink less) and use more debt during the 1930s. We document similar effects for the number of outside directors on the board. Finally, we also find that companies with properly aligned governance structures are more likely to replace the company president following poor performance.</description><author>Graham, John R.; Hazarika, Sonali; Narasimhan, Krishnamoorthy</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating Value-at-Risk Models with Desk-Level Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkowitz, Jeremy; Christoffersen, Peter; Pelletier, Denis
We present new evidence on disaggregated profit and loss (P/L) and value-at-risk (VaR) forecasts obtained from a large international commercial bank. Our data set includes the actual daily P/L generated by four separate business lines within the bank. All four business lines are involved in securities trading and each is observed daily for a period of at least two years. Given this unique data set, we provide an integrated, unifying framework for assessing the accuracy of VaR forecasts. We use a comprehensive Monte Carlo study to assess which of these many tests have the best finite-sample size and power properties. Our desk-level data set provides importance guidance for choosing realistic P/L-generating processes in the Monte Carlo comparison of the various tests. The conditional autoregressive value-at-risk test of Engle and Manganelli (2004) performs best overall, but duration-based tests also perform well in many cases.</description><author>Berkowitz, Jeremy; Christoffersen, Peter; Pelletier, Denis</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Financial Firms Manage Risk? Unraveling the Interaction of Financial and Operational Hedging</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hankins, Kristine Watson
This paper investigates how firms manage risk by examining the relationship between financial and operational hedging using a sample of bank holding companies. Risk management theory holds that capital market imperfections make cash flow volatility costly. I investigate whether financial firms consider this cost or focus exclusively on managing tradable exposures. After documenting that acquisitions provide operational hedging by reducing potentially costly volatility, I find that postacquisition financial hedging declines even after controlling for the specific underlying risks. In addition, the decrease in financial hedging is related to the acquisition's level of operational hedging. Larger increases in operational hedging are followed by larger declines in financial hedging. These results indicate that firms in this sample manage aggregate risk, not just tradable exposures, and that operational hedging can substitute for financial hedging.</description><author>Hankins, Kristine Watson</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization and Real Investment in Incomplete Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gaur, Vishal; Seshadri, Sridhar; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.
We study the impact of financial innovations on real investment decisions within the framework of an incomplete market economy comprised of firms, investors, and an intermediary. The firms face unique investment opportunities that arise in their business operations and can be undertaken at given reservation prices. The cash flows thus generated are not spanned by the securities traded in the financial market and cannot be valued uniquely. The intermediary purchases claims against these cash flows, pools them together, and sells tranches of primary or secondary securities to the investors. We derive necessary and sufficient conditions under which projects are undertaken due to the intermediary's actions, and firms are amenable to the pool proposed by the intermediary, compared to the no-investment option or the option of forming alternative pools. We also determine the structure of the new securities created by the intermediary and identify how it exploits the arbitrage opportunities available in the market. Our results have implications for valuation of real investments, synergies among them, and their financing mechanisms. We illustrate these implications using an example of inventory decisions under random demand.</description><author>Gaur, Vishal; Seshadri, Sridhar; Subrahmanyam, Marti G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stochastic Capacity Investment and Flexible vs. Dedicated Technology Choice in Imperfect Capital Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyabatli, Onur; Toktay, L. Beril
This paper analyzes the impact of endogenous credit terms under capital market imperfections in a capacity investment setting. We model a monopolist firm that decides on its technology choice (flexible versus dedicated) and capacity level under demand uncertainty. Differing from the majority of the stochastic capacity investment literature, we assume that the firm is budget constrained and can relax its budget constraint by borrowing from a creditor. The creditor offers technology-specific loan contracts to the firm, after which the firm makes its technology choice and subsequent decisions. Capital market imperfections impose financing frictions on the firm. Our analysis contributes to the capacity investment literature by extending the theory of stochastic capacity investment and flexible versus dedicated technology choice to understand the impact of capital market imperfections, and by analyzing the impact of demand uncertainty (variability and correlation) on the operational decisions and the performance of the firm under different capital market conditions. We demonstrate that the endogenous nature of credit terms in imperfect capital markets may modify or reverse conclusions concerning capacity investment and technology choice obtained under the perfect market assumption and we explain why. The theory developed in this paper suggests some rules of thumb for the strategic management of the capacity and technology choice in imperfect capital markets.</description><author>Boyabatli, Onur; Toktay, L. Beril</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Multiechelon Inventory Problem with Secondary Market Sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Angelus, Alexandar
We consider a finite-horizon, multiechelon inventory system in which the surplus of stock can be sold (i.e., disposed) in the secondary markets at each stage in the system. What are called nested echelon order-up-to policies are shown to be optimal for jointly managing inventory replenishments and secondary market sales. Under a general restriction on model parameters, we establish that it is optimal not to both sell off excess stock and replenish inventory. Secondary market sales complicate the structure of the system, so that the classical Clark and Scarf echelon reformulation no longer allows for the decomposition of the objective function under the optimal policy. We introduce a novel class of policies, referred to as the disposal saturation policies, and show that there exists a disposal saturation policy, determined recursively by a single base-stock level at each echelon, that achieves the decomposition of this problem. The resulting optimal replenishment policy is shown to be the echelon base-stock policy. We demonstrate the heuristic performance of this disposal saturation policy through a series of numerical studies: except at extreme ranges of model parameters, the policy provides a very good approximation to the optimal policy while avoiding the curse of dimensionality. We also conduct numerical studies to determine the value of the secondary markets for multistage supply chains and assess its sensitivity to model parameters. The results provide potentially useful insights for companies seeking to enter or develop secondary markets for supply chains.</description><author>Angelus, Alexandar</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficient Two-Dimensional Packing Algorithms for Mobile WiMAX</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lodi, Andrea; Martello, Silvano; Monaci, Michele; Cicconetti, Claudio; Lenzini, Luciano; Mingozzi, Enzo; Eklund, Carl; Moilanen, Jani
We present the result of research, developed within Nokia Siemens Networks, to solve the downlink subframe allocation problem in Mobile WiMAX (IEEE 802.16) technology in its full complexity, while simultaneously fulfilling real-life constraints on processing power and delay. We describe the IEEE 802.16 standard, and introduce two system models. A theoretical analysis of the two-dimensional packing problems originated by such models shows that they are both NP-hard in the strong sense. From a practical point of view, the processing budget for scheduling in the base station was estimated to be 1 ms on a state-of-the-art PC. Thus, we introduce two highly efficient heuristics that were developed to handle the system practically. A thorough computational analysis of their optimization characteristics and a system-level evaluation in realistic scenarios proved that the algorithms offer significant capacity gain in Mobile WiMAX systems that translate to increased operator revenues.</description><author>Lodi, Andrea; Martello, Silvano; Monaci, Michele; Cicconetti, Claudio; Lenzini, Luciano; Mingozzi, Enzo; Eklund, Carl; Moilanen, Jani</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Acquirers Retain Successful Target CEOs? The Role of Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wulf, Julie; Singh, Harbir
The resource-based view argues that acquisitions can build competitive advantage partially through retention of valuable human capital of the target firm. However, making commitments to retain and motivate successful top managers is a challenge when contracts are not enforceable. Investigating the conditions under which target chief executive officers (CEOs) are retained in a sample of mergers in the 1990s, we find greater retention of better-performing and higher-paid CEOs-both measures of valuable human capital. We also show that the performance-retention link is stronger when the acquirer's governance provisions support managers and when the acquirer's CEO owns more equity. Although it is not common for acquirers to retain target CEOs, we argue that they are more likely to do so when their governance environment maintains managerial discretion. Based on a joint analysis of retention and governance, our findings are largely consistent with a managerial human capital explanation of retention.</description><author>Wulf, Julie; Singh, Harbir</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multiechelon Procurement and Distribution Policies for Traded Commodities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goel, Ankur; Gutierrez, Genaro J.
We consider a firm that procures and distributes a commodity from spot and forward markets under randomly fluctuating prices; the commodity is distributed downstream to a set of nonhomogeneous retailers to satisfy random demand. We formulate a model that allows one to compute approximate, but near optimal, procurement and distribution policies for this system, and we explore the value of the commodity's market in providing managers with (a) additional flexibility in procurement and (b) information on price dynamics generated through the trading of futures contracts. Our results indicate that the presence of the commodity market and the information that it conveys may lead to significant reductions in inventory-related costs; however, to obtain these benefits, both the spot procurement flexibility and the term structure of prices generated by the commodity market must be incorporated in the formulation of the operating policy. Managerial insights on the procurement strategy as a function of variability in prices and demand are also discussed.</description><author>Goel, Ankur; Gutierrez, Genaro J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Focus on Performance: Evidence from California Hospitals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Singh, Diwas K. C.; Terwiesch, Christian
We use hospital-level discharge data from cardiac patients in California to estimate the effects of focus on operational performance. We examine focus at three distinct levels of the organization-at the firm level, at the operating unit level, and at the process flow level. We find that focus at each of these levels is associated with improved outcomes, namely, faster services at higher levels of quality, as indicated by lower lengths of stay (LOS) and reduced mortality rates. We then analyze the extent to which the superior operational outcome is driven by focused hospitals truly excelling in their operations or by focused hospitals simply "cherry-picking" easy-to-treat patients. To do this, we use an instrumental variables estimation strategy that effectively randomizes the assignment of patients to hospitals. After controlling for selective patient admissions, the previously observed benefits of firm level focus disappear; focused hospitals no longer demonstrate a statistically significant reduction in LOS or mortality rate. However, at more granular measures of focus within the hospital (e.g., operating unit level), we find that more focus leads to a shorter LOS, even after controlling for selective admission effects.</description><author>Singh, Diwas K. C.; Terwiesch, Christian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extracting Business Value from IT: A Sensemaking Perspective of Post-Adoptive Use</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hsieh, J. J. Po-An; Rai, Arun; Xu, Sean Xin
How can firms extract value from already-implemented information technologies (IT) that support the work processes of employees? One approach is to stimulate employees to engage in post-adoptive extended use, i.e., to learn and apply more of the available functions of the implemented technologies to support their work. Such learning behavior of extending functions in use is ingrained in a process by which users make sense of the technologies in the context of their work system. This study draws on sensemaking theory to develop a model to understand the antecedents, contingencies, and consequences of customer service employees' extended use of customer relationship management (CRM) technologies. The model is tested using multisource longitudinal data collected through a field study of one of the world's largest telecommunications service providers. Our results suggest that employees engage in post-adoptive sensemaking at two levels: technology and work system. We found that sensemaking at both of these levels impacts the extended use of CRM technologies. Employees' sensemaking at the technology level is influenced by employees' assessment of technology quality, whereas employees' sensemaking at the work system level is influenced by customers' assessment of service quality. Moreover, in the case of low technology quality and low service quality, specific mechanisms for employee feedback should be conceptualized and aligned at two levels: through employee participation at the technology level and through work system coordination at the work system level. Such alignment can mitigate the undesirable effect of low technology quality and low service quality, thereby facilitating extended use. Importantly, we found that extended use amplifies employees' service capacity, leading to better objective performance. Put together, our findings highlight the critical role of employees' sensemaking about the implemented technologies in promoting their extended use of IT and improving their work performance.</description><author>Hsieh, J. J. Po-An; Rai, Arun; Xu, Sean Xin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stars and Misfits: Self-Employment and Labor Market Frictions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Astebro, Thomas; Chen, Jing; Thompson, Peter
Recent evidence has shown that entrants into self-employment are disproportionately drawn from the tails of the earnings and ability distributions. This observation is explained by a multitask model of occupational choice in which frictions in the labor market induce mismatches between firms and workers, and misassignment of workers to tasks. The model also yields distinctive predictions relating prior work histories to earnings and to the probability of entry into self-employment. These predictions are tested with the Korean Labor and Income Panel Study, from which we find considerable support for the model.</description><author>Astebro, Thomas; Chen, Jing; Thompson, Peter</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cooperation Without Enforcement? A Comparative Analysis of Litigation and Online Reputation as Quality Assurance Mechanisms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakos, Yannis; Dellarocas, Chrysanthos
Commerce depends on buyers and sellers fulfilling their contractual obligations; mechanisms inducing such performance are essential to well-functioning markets. Internet-enabled reputation mechanisms that collect and disseminate consumer feedback have emerged as prominent means for inducing seller performance in online and offline markets. This paper compares the ability of reputation and more traditional litigation-like mechanisms for dispute resolution to induce efficient economic outcomes. We use a game-theoretic formulation and derive results for their relative efficiency and effectiveness individually or as complements. We find that the popular view of reputation as an efficient and relatively costless way to induce seller effort under all circumstances is incorrect; reputation is less efficient than litigation in inducing any given level of effort. Thus, reputation improves efficiency only in settings where the high cost of litigation, insufficient damage levels, or low court accuracy induce suboptimal effort or cause market failure. When adverse selection is important, reputation helps reveal the true types of market participants, which may offset its higher cost of inducing effort. Finally, adding reputation to existing litigation mechanisms increases seller effort and may require adjusting damage awards to avoid inducing excessive effort that reduces economic efficiency.</description><author>Bakos, Yannis; Dellarocas, Chrysanthos</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competing Matchmakers: An Experimental Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hossain, Tanjim; Minor, Dylan; Morgan, John
Platform competition is ubiquitous, yet platform market structure is little understood. Theory models typically suffer from equilibrium multiplicity-platforms might coexist or the market might tip to either platform. We use laboratory experiments to study the outcomes of platform competition. When platforms are primarily vertically differentiated, we find that even when platform coexistence is theoretically possible, markets inevitably tip to the more efficient platform. When platforms are primarily horizontally differentiated, so there is no single efficient platform, we find strong evidence of equilibrium coexistence.</description><author>Hossain, Tanjim; Minor, Dylan; Morgan, John</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Experienced vs. Described Uncertainty: Do We Need Two Prospect Theory Specifications?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abdellaoui, Mohammed; L'Haridon, Olivier; Paraschiv, Corina
This paper reports on the results of an experimental elicitation at the individual level of all prospect theory components (i.e., utility, loss aversion, and weighting functions) in two decision contexts: situations where alternatives are described as probability distributions and situations where the decision maker must experience unknown probability distributions through sampling before choice. For description-based decisions, our results are fully consistent with prospect theory's empirical findings under risk. Furthermore, no significant differences are detected across contexts as regards utility and loss aversion. Whereas decision weights exhibit similar qualitative properties across contexts typically found under prospect theory, our data suggest that, for gains at least, the subjective treatment of uncertainty in experience-based and description-based decisions is significantly different. More specifically, we observe a less pronounced overweighting of small probabilities and a more pronounced underweighting of moderate and high probabilities for experience-based decisions. On the contrary, for losses, no significant differences were observed in the evaluation of prospects across contexts.</description><author>Abdellaoui, Mohammed; L'Haridon, Olivier; Paraschiv, Corina</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intellectual Capital and Financing Decisions: Evidence from the US Patent Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Qiao; Wong, Kit Pong
This paper develops a real options model to understand two distinct roles played by intellectual capital in corporate financing decisions. Whereas limiting a firm's debt capacity because of its low liquidation value, intellectual capital enhances a firm's debt capacity through its positive impact on earnings. Our model shows that the former dominates or is dominated by the latter, depending on whether the rate of dissipation of intellectual capital upon default is larger or smaller than a critical level, respectively. Using patent-based and research-and-development-based variables as proxies for intellectual capital, we find robust evidence that the relation between intellectual capital and leverage is positive. Specifically, a one-standard-deviation increase in the level of a firm's intellectual capital is associated with an increase of 6.6% to 21.1% in its market leverage. We further find this positive relation to be stronger for biotechnology firms.</description><author>Liu, Qiao; Wong, Kit Pong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash-Out or Flameout! Opportunity Cost and Entrepreneurial Strategy: Theory, and Evidence from the Information Security Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arora, Ashish; Nandkumar, Anand
We analyze how entrepreneurial opportunity cost conditions performance. Departing from the common practice of using survival as a measure of entrepreneurial performance, we model both failure and cashout (liquidity event) as conditioned by the same underlying process. High-opportunity-cost entrepreneurs prefer a shorter time to success, even if this also implies failing more quickly, whereas entrepreneurs with fewer outside alternatives will choose less aggressive strategies and, consequently, linger on longer. We formalize this intuition with a simple model. Using a novel data set of information security start-ups, we find that entrepreneurs with high opportunity costs are not only more likely to cash out more quickly but are also more likely to fail faster. Not only is survival a poor indicator of performance, but its use as one obscures the relationship between entrepreneurial characteristics, entrepreneurial strategies, and outcomes.</description><author>Arora, Ashish; Nandkumar, Anand</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Demand Forecasting Behavior: System Neglect and Change Detection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kremer, Mirko; Moritz, Brent; Siemsen, Enno
We analyze how individuals make forecasts based on time-series data. Using a controlled laboratory experiment, we find that forecasting behavior systematically deviates from normative predictions: Forecasters overreact to forecast errors in relatively stable environments, but underreact to errors in relatively unstable environments. The performance loss that is due to such systematic judgment biases is larger in stable than in unstable environments.</description><author>Kremer, Mirko; Moritz, Brent; Siemsen, Enno</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Circulation of Ideas in Firms and Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hellmann, Thomas; Perotti, Enrico
This paper models the generation, circulation, and completion of new ideas, showing how markets and innovative firms complement each other in a symbiotic relationship. Novel ideas are initially incomplete and require further insight before yielding a valuable innovation. Finding the complementary piece requires ideas to circulate, which creates appropriation risks. Circulation of ideas in markets ensures efficient completion, but because ideas can be appropriated, market entrepreneurs underinvest in idea generation. Firms can establish boundaries that guarantee safe circulation of internal ideas, but because firms need to limit idea circulation, they may fail to achieve completion. Spin-offs allow firms to benefit from the market's strength at idea completion, whereas markets benefit from firms' strength at generating new ideas. The model predicts diverse organizational forms (internal ventures, spin-offs, and start-ups) coexisting and mutually reinforcing each other. The analysis provides new insights into the structure of innovation-driven clusters such as Silicon Valley.</description><author>Hellmann, Thomas; Perotti, Enrico</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Note: A Reply to "New Product Diffusion Decisions Under Supply Constraints"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ho, Teck-Hua; Savin, Sergei; Terwiesch, Christian
In our prior work on product diffusions in presence of a capacity constraint, we postulated that a firm operating in such an environment should always attempt to fulfill as much of the present demand as is possible with the capacity constraint. In other words, the firm would never have demand backlogged while accumulating inventory. In this note, we derive a sufficient condition for the optimality of such fulfillment policy.</description><author>Ho, Teck-Hua; Savin, Sergei; Terwiesch, Christian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Product Diffusion Decisions Under Supply Constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shen, Wenjing; Duenyas, Izak; Kapuscinski, Roman
Two recent papers on managing new product diffusion decisions under production constraints reach somewhat contradictory conclusions. Ho et al. (Ho, T.-H., S. Savin, C. Terwiesch. 2002. Managing demand and sales dynamics in new product diffusion under supply constraint. Management Sci. 48(2) 187-206) show that it is never optimal to refuse to satisfy any customers when the firm has inventory of the product. On the other hand, in a very similar model, Kumar and Swaminathan (Kumar, S., J. M. Swaminathan. 2003. Diffusion of innovations under supply constraints. Oper. Res. 51(6) 866-879) show that production constraints may in fact lead a firm to reject customers' orders even when the firm has the inventory to satisfy them (to slow down new product diffusion). We provide a counterexample to the results of Ho et al. (2002) and show that in their and Kumar and Swaminathan's (2003) models, it may be optimal to deny customers a product in inventory. We provide a generalization of both models that includes the ability to dynamically price the product (and also allows capacity and production costs to vary over time). We show that the unintuitive but optimal behavior of denying customers products that are in inventory disappears when the firm can dynamically set prices.</description><author>Shen, Wenjing; Duenyas, Izak; Kapuscinski, Roman</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exogenous Learning, Seller-Induced Learning, and Marketing of Durable Goods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jing, Bing
W hen learning of product characteristics takes some time, a firm introducing a new durable faces the trade-off between releasing early to an uninformed market and deferring release to a better-informed market. In a two-period monopoly, we examine the strategic interaction between exogenous learning (EL) and seller-induced learning (SIL) and the firm's product release and pricing strategies. The familiar, direct effect of strong learning is to facilitate a higher price for informed customers. We point out its indirect effect of inducing a higher period 1 price for uninformed customers (by lowering their expected utility from learning). These two effects underlie three major results. First, a strong learning intensity does not always imply deferred release. Surprisingly, for medium unit costs, the firm releases late (early) when learning intensity is weak (strong). Second, SIL facilitates different product release strategies, depending on the unit cost level. Potential SIL investment facilitates early release for low or medium unit costs, but may facilitate deferred release for high unit costs. Lastly, when customers have heterogeneous prior valuation, the high-end customers may buy early at a lower price and the low-end customers may buy later at a higher price, contrary to the usual skim pricing with informed customers.</description><author>Jing, Bing</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Integrating Long-Term and Short-Term Contracting in Beef Supply Chains</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyabatli, Onur; Kleindorfer, Paul R.; Koontz, Stephen R.
T his paper analyzes the optimal procurement, processing, and production decisions of a meat-processing company (hereafter, a "packer") in a beef supply chain. The packer processes fed cattle to produce two beef products, program (premium) boxed beef and commodity boxed beef, in fixed proportions, but with downward substitution of the premium product for the commodity product. The packer can source input (fed cattle) from a contract market, where long-term contracts are signed in advance of the required delivery time, and from a spot market on the spot day. Contract prices are taken to be of a general window form, linear in the spot price but capped by upper and lower limits on realized contract price. Our analysis provides managerial insights on the interaction of window contract terms with processing options. We show that the packer benefits from a low correlation between the spot price and product market uncertainties, and this is independent of the form of the window contract. Although the expected revenues from processing increase in spot price variability, the overall impact on profitability depends on the parameters of the window contract. Using a calibration based on the report by the GIPSA (Grain Inspection, Packers and Stockyards Administration. 2007. GIPSA livestock and meat marketing study, vol. 3: Fed cattle and beef industries. Report, U. S. Department of Agriculture, Washington, DC), this paper elucidates for the first time the value of long-term contracting as a complement to spot sourcing in the beef supply chain. Our comparative statics results provide some rules of thumb for the packer for the strategic management of the procurement portfolio. In particular, we show that higher variability (higher spot price variability, product market variability, and correlation) increases the profits of the packer, but decreases the reliance on the contract market relative to the spot market.</description><author>Boyabatli, Onur; Kleindorfer, Paul R.; Koontz, Stephen R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Portfolio Optimization with Transaction Costs: Heuristics and Dual Bounds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, David B.; Smith, James E.
W e consider the problem of dynamic portfolio optimization in a discrete-time, finite-horizon setting. Our general model considers risk aversion, portfolio constraints (e. g., no short positions), return predictability, and transaction costs. This problem is naturally formulated as a stochastic dynamic program. Unfortunately, with nonzero transaction costs, the dimension of the state space is at least as large as the number of assets, and the problem is very difficult to solve with more than one or two assets. In this paper, we consider several easy-to-compute heuristic trading strategies that are based on optimizing simpler models. We complement these heuristics with upper bounds on the performance with an optimal trading strategy. These bounds are based on the dual approach developed in Brown et al. (Brown, D. B., J. E. Smith, P. Sun. 2009. Information relaxations and duality in stochastic dynamic programs. Oper. Res. 58(4) 785-801). In this context, these bounds are given by considering an investor who has access to perfect information about future returns but is penalized for using this advance information. These heuristic strategies and bounds can be evaluated using Monte Carlo simulation. We evaluate these heuristics and bounds in numerical experiments with a risk-free asset and 3 or 10 risky assets. In many cases, the performance of the heuristic strategy is very close to the upper bound, indicating that the heuristic strategies are very nearly optimal.</description><author>Brown, David B.; Smith, James E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Selling to Strategic Consumers When Product Value Is Uncertain: The Value of Matching Supply and Demand</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Swinney, Robert
W e address the value of quick response production practices when selling to a forward-looking consumer population with uncertain, heterogeneous valuations for a product. Consumers have the option of purchasing the product early, before its value has been learned, or delaying the purchase decision until a time at which valuation uncertainty has been resolved. Whereas individual consumer valuations are uncertain ex ante, the market size is uncertain to the firm. The firm may either commit to a single production run at a low unit cost prior to learning demand, or commit to a quick response strategy that allows additional production after learning additional demand information. We find that the value of quick response is generally lower with strategic (forward-looking) customers than with nonstrategic (myopic) customers in this setting. Indeed, it is possible for a quick response strategy to decrease the profit of the firm, though whether this occurs depends on various characteristics of the market; specifically, we identify conditions under which quick response increases profit (when prices are increasing, when dissatisfied consumers can return the product at a cost to the firm) and conditions under which quick response may decrease profit (when prices are constant or when consumer returns are not allowed).</description><author>Swinney, Robert</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tournaments Without Prizes: Evidence from Personnel Records</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blanes i Vidal, Jordi; Nossol, Mareike
W e use a quasi-experimental research design to study the effect of giving workers feedback on their relative performance. The setting is a firm in which workers are paid piece rates and where, for exogenous reasons, management begins to reveal to workers their relative position in the distribution of pay and productivity. We find that merely providing this information leads to a large and long-lasting increase in productivity that is costless to the firm. Our findings are consistent with the interpretation that workers' incipient concerns about their relative standing are activated by information about how they are performing relative to others.</description><author>Blanes i Vidal, Jordi; Nossol, Mareike</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option Pricing Under a Mixed-Exponential Jump Diffusion Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cai, Ning; Kou, S. G.
This paper aims to extend the analytical tractability of the Black-Scholes model to alternative models with arbitrary jump size distributions. More precisely, we propose a jump diffusion model for asset prices whose jump sizes have a mixed-exponential distribution, which is a weighted average of exponential distributions but with possibly negative weights. The new model extends existing models, such as hyperexponential and double-exponential jump diffusion models, because the mixed-exponential distribution can approximate any distribution as closely as possible, including the normal distribution and various heavy-tailed distributions. The mixed-exponential jump diffusion model can lead to analytical solutions for Laplace transforms of prices and sensitivity parameters for path-dependent options such as lookback and barrier options. The Laplace transforms can be inverted via the Euler inversion algorithm. Numerical experiments indicate that the formulae are easy to implement and accurate. The analytical solutions are made possible mainly because we solve a high-order integro-differential equation explicitly. A calibration example for SPY options shows that the model can provide a reasonable fit even for options with very short maturity, such as one day.</description><author>Cai, Ning; Kou, S. G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Preference Reversals Under Ambiguity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maafi, Hela
Preference reversals have been widely studied using risky or riskless gambles. However, little is known about preference reversals under ambiguity (unknown probabilities). Subjects were asked to make a binary choice between ambiguous P-bets (big likelihood of giving small prize) and ambiguous $-bets (small likelihood of giving large prize) and their willingness to accept was elicited. Subjects then performed the same two tasks with risky bets, where the probability of winning for a given risky bet is the center of the probability interval of the corresponding ambiguous bet. Preference reversals are not only replicated under ambiguity but are even stronger than are those under risk. This is due to higher elicited prices for the $-bet and lower elicited prices for the P-bet under ambiguity than under risk. This result can be explained by the shape of the weighting function for different levels of uncertainty and for different elicitation modes.</description><author>Maafi, Hela</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Integrated Product Architecture and Pricing for Managing Sequential Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krishnan, Vish; Ramachandran, Karthik
Science and technology advances drive firms to continually enhance their product's performance and launch sequentially improving offerings. Firms face challenges in marketing such improving products to well-informed, forward-looking consumers who anticipate product improvements and seek to delay their purchase timing. Product design, specifically a modular upgradable architecture in which improving and stable subsystems of a product are separated and selectively upgraded, can be a valuable approach for marketers to alleviate consumer concerns about product obsolescence. However, such an architecture-based approach can present new challenges as well, and dealing with them requires carefully coordinated cross-functional decision making by the firm. In this paper, we identify and formalize the notion of design inconsistency, which refers to the monopolist firm's inability to commit to future product design architectures. We find that firms experience design inconsistency even when they are able to commit to future prices, and design inconsistency lowers firm profits as well as consumer surplus. We then derive a joint product architecture and pricing approach to solve this problem; this enables an innovating firm to optimally and in a time-consistent manner launch modular upgradable products. The modeling and analysis in the paper lends insight into types of markets and products for which modular upgradability is most appropriate and offers guidelines on making pricing and product design decisions jointly for managing sequential innovation.</description><author>Krishnan, Vish; Ramachandran, Karthik</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Simple Economics of the Price-Setting Newsvendor Problem</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Salinger, Michael; Ampudia, Miguel
The Lerner relationship linking the profit-maximizing price to marginal cost and the elasticity of demand generalizes to the price-setting newsvendor, and the result resolves the puzzle over the different effects of additive and multiplicative uncertainty on the solution. Multiplicative uncertainty increases the optimal price because it increases the marginal cost of a unit sold and does not affect the markup factor. Additive uncertainty has no effect on the marginal cost of a unit sold and lowers the markup factor because it increases the elasticity of the average quantity sold with respect to price.</description><author>Salinger, Michael; Ampudia, Miguel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling Security-Check Queues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Zhe George; Luh, Hsing Paul; Wang, Chia-Hung
Motivated by the waiting lines between the U.S.-Canadian border crossings, we investigate a security-check system with both security and customer service goals. In such a system, every customer has to be inspected by the first-stage inspector, but only a proportion of customers need to go through the second stage for further inspection. This "further inspection proportion," affecting both security screening and the system congestion, becomes a key decision variable for the security-check system. Using a stylized two-stage queueing model, we established the convexity of the expected waiting cost function. With such a property, the optimal further inspection proportion can be determined to achieve the balance of the two goals and the service capacities can be classified into "security-favorable," "security-unfavorable," or "security-infeasible" categories. A specific capacity category implies if the security and customer service goals are consistent or in conflict. In addition, we have verified that the properties discovered in the stylized model also hold approximately in a more general multiserver setting. Numerical results are presented to demonstrate the accuracy and robustness of the approximations and the practical value of the model.</description><author>Zhang, Zhe George; Luh, Hsing Paul; Wang, Chia-Hung</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Skill, Luck, and the Multiproduct Firm: Evidence from Hedge Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Figueiredo, Rui J. P.; Rawley, Evan
We formalize the idea that when managers require external investment to expand, higher-skilled firms will be more likely to diversify in equilibrium, even though managers can exploit asymmetric information about their ability to raise capital from investors. We exploit the timing of new fund launches in the hedge fund industry to distinguish between agency and capability effects in firm product diversification decisions, using a large survivor-bias-free panel data set on the hedge fund industry from 1994 to 2006. Empirically we show that diversifying firms' excess returns are high relative to those of other firms prior to diversification and fall within firm following diversification, but are six basis points higher per month per unit of risk ex post compared to a matched sample of focused firms. The evidence suggests that managers exploit asymmetric information about their own ability to time diversification decisions; yet, the discipline of markets ensures that better firms diversify, on average. The results provide large-sample empirical evidence that agency effects and firm capabilities jointly influence diversification decisions.</description><author>de Figueiredo, Rui J. P.; Rawley, Evan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Covenants in Venture Capital Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bengtsson, Ola
This paper studies how covenants are included in contracts between venture capitalists (VCs) and entrepreneurs. I show that VCs hold covenanted veto rights even though they are shareholders who have access to other powerful governance solutions. Unlike bank loans and bonds, venture capital (VC) contracts exhibit considerable variation in their contractual designs. I exploit this variation to confirm the argument that covenants are in place to overcome a conflict of interest that arises from debt-like contractual features of a venture capitalist's preferred stock. In particular, I find that contracts with higher fixed payoffs include 1.6 more covenants than do contracts with lower fixed payoffs. Similarly, VC contracts with no VC board majority requirement include 0.6 more covenants than do contracts that require a VC board majority. Covenants are also more common with older companies and when fewer VCs invest in a round. My findings contribute to both the debt covenant literature and the entrepreneurial finance literature.</description><author>Bengtsson, Ola</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing Product Variety and Collocation in a Competitive Environment: An Empirical Investigation of Consumer Electronics Retailing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ren, Charlotte R.; Hu, Ye; Hu, Yu; Hausman, Jerry
Product variety is an important strategic tool that firms can use to attract customers and respond to competition. This study focuses on the retail industry and investigates how stores manage their product variety, contingent on the presence of competition and their actual distance from rivals. Using a unique data set that contains all Best Buy and Circuit City stores in the United States, the authors find that a store's product variety (i.e., number of stock-keeping units) increases if a rival store exists in its market but, in the presence of such competition, decreases when the rival store is collocated (within one mile of the focal store). Moreover, collocated rival stores tend to differentiate themselves by overlapping less in product range than do noncollocated rivals. This smaller and more differentiated product variety may be because of coordinated interactions between collocated stores. In summary, this paper presents evidence of both coordination and competition in retailers' use of product variety.</description><author>Ren, Charlotte R.; Hu, Ye; Hu, Yu; Hausman, Jerry</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Housing, Consumption, and Investment Decisions over the Life Cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kraft, Holger; Munk, Claus
W e derive explicit solutions to life-cycle utility maximization problems involving stock and bond investment, perishable consumption, and the rental and ownership of residential real estate. Prices of houses, stocks and bonds, and labor income are correlated. Because of a positive correlation between house prices and labor income, young individuals want little exposure to house price risk and tend to rent their home. Later in life the desired housing investment increases and will eventually reach and exceed the desired consumption, suggesting that the individual should buy his home-and either additional housing units (for renting out) or house price-linked financial assets. In the final years, preferences shift back to home rental. The derived strategies are still useful if housing positions are only reset infrequently. Our results suggest that markets for real estate investment trusts or other house price-linked contracts lead to nonnegligible welfare gains.</description><author>Kraft, Holger; Munk, Claus</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Genius Leads to Adversity: Experimental Evidence on the Reputational Effects of Task Difficulty Choices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Katok, Elena; Siemsen, Enno
We use a behavioral laboratory experiment to study how agents with reputation concerns select the difficulty of their tasks. Drawing upon existing theory, we subjected participants in our study to a context in which they had to convince a principal of their capability to reap financial benefits. Our results show that participants tended to increase the difficulty of their task to enhance their reputation. In addition, we provide evidence that performance rewards reduce a less capable agent's tendency to choose a more difficult task, whereas a highly capable agent's pattern of choices is unaffected by performance rewards. Although the productivity of agents in our experiment therefore decreased if they had to convince a principal of their capability, we show that these detrimental performance implications can to some degree be overcome for less capable agents through performance rewards or by ensuring that the principal can interpret the agent's choice.</description><author>Katok, Elena; Siemsen, Enno</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Preorder Strategy with Endogenous Information Control</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chu, Leon Yang; Zhang, Hao
In this paper, we investigate the integrated information and pricing strategy for a seller who can take customer preorders before the release of a product. The preorder option enables the seller to sell a product at an early stage when consumers are less certain about their valuations. We find that the optimal pricing strategy may be highly dependent on the amount of information available at preorder and that a small change in the latter may cause a dramatic change in the proportion of consumers who preorder under optimal pricing. Furthermore, the seller's optimal information strategy depends on a key measure, the normalized margin, which is the ratio between the expected profit margin and the standard deviation of consumer valuation. Although the seller may want to release some information or none, she should never release all information. Finally, under the optimal information and pricing strategy, the benefit of preorder is most pronounced when the normalized margin is in a medium range.</description><author>Chu, Leon Yang; Zhang, Hao</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loss Aversion with a State-Dependent Reference Point</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Giorgi, Enrico G.; Post, Thierry
This study investigates reference-dependent choice with a stochastic, state-dependent reference point. The optimal reference-dependent solution equals the optimal consumption solution ( no loss aversion) if the reference point is selected fully endogenously. Given that loss aversion is widespread, we conclude that the reference point generally includes an important exogenously fixed component. We develop a choice model in which adjustment costs can cause stickiness relative to an initial, exogenous reference point. Using historical U. S. investment benchmark data, we show that this model is consistent with diversification across bonds and stocks for a wide range of evaluation horizons, despite the historically high-risk premium of stocks compared to bonds.</description><author>De Giorgi, Enrico G.; Post, Thierry</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficient Risk Estimation via Nested Sequential Simulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Broadie, Mark; Du, Yiping; Moallemi, Ciamac C.
We analyze the computational problem of estimating financial risk in a nested simulation. In this approach, an outer simulation is used to generate financial scenarios, and an inner simulation is used to estimate future portfolio values in each scenario. We focus on one risk measure, the probability of a large loss, and we propose a new algorithm to estimate this risk. Our algorithm sequentially allocates computational effort in the inner simulation based on marginal changes in the risk estimator in each scenario. Theoretical results are given to show that the risk estimator has a faster convergence order compared to the conventional uniform inner sampling approach. Numerical results consistent with the theory are presented.</description><author>Broadie, Mark; Du, Yiping; Moallemi, Ciamac C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Demand Aggregation Through Delayed Component Allocation in an Assemble-to-Order System</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Fernando; DeCroix, Gregory A.; Wang, Yulan
We consider an assemble-to-order system in which multiple products are assembled from a common component and a set of product-dedicated components. Component capacities are chosen prior to a finite-horizon selling season, and the common component is allocated to the products based on observed demands. We propose a collection of allocation mechanisms involving varying degrees of demand aggregation, ranging from a scheme under which all demands are observed prior to making the allocation decision to allocations made for each arriving demand. In this context, we explore the impact of the allocation scheme on sales, profits, and capacity decisions, including the degree of capacity imbalance. We find that the benefit from increased demand aggregation is closely linked to the degree of capacity imbalance: profit gains from delayed allocation tend to be higher in systems in which the optimal capacity portfolio is highly unbalanced when the allocation decision is made after observing all demands. We develop insights into what detailed system parameters lead to the largest gains from demand aggregation and also explore the trade-offs associated with the choice of an allocation scheme when customers exhibit impatience if the allocation scheme forces them to wait to be served.</description><author>Bernstein, Fernando; DeCroix, Gregory A.; Wang, Yulan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mandatory Fair Value Accounting and Information Asymmetry: Evidence from the European Real Estate Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Muller, Karl A.; Riedl, Edward J.; Sellhorn, Thorsten
We examine the effects of mandating the provision of fair value information for long-lived tangible assets on firms' information asymmetry. Specifically, we investigate whether European real estate firms' compulsory adoption of International Accounting Standard 40 (IAS 40; Investment Property), which mandated the provision of investment property fair values in 2005, resulted in reduced information asymmetry across market participants. Using as a control group firms that voluntarily provided these fair values prior to the mandatory adoption of IAS 40, we find that mandatory adoption firms exhibit a larger decline in information asymmetry, as reflected in lower bid-ask spreads. However, we also find that mandatory adoption firms continue to have higher information asymmetry than voluntary adoption firms, which appears partially attributable to the lower reliability of fair values reported by the mandatory adoption firms. Together, this evidence adds to the debate on fair value accounting by demonstrating that common adoption of fair value, even for long-lived tangible assets, under a mandatory reporting regime can reduce, but not necessarily eliminate, information asymmetry differences across firms.</description><author>Muller, Karl A.; Riedl, Edward J.; Sellhorn, Thorsten</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trust in Forecast Information Sharing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oezer, Oezalp; Zheng, Yanchong; Chen, Kay-Yut
This paper investigates the capacity investment decision of a supplier who solicits private forecast information from a manufacturer. To ensure abundant supply, the manufacturer has an incentive to inflate her forecast in a costless, nonbinding, and nonverifiable type of communication known as "cheap talk." According to standard game theory, parties do not cooperate and the only equilibrium is uninformative-the manufacturer's report is independent of her forecast and the supplier does not use the report to determine capacity. However, we observe in controlled laboratory experiments that parties cooperate even in the absence of reputation-building mechanisms and complex contracts. We argue that the underlying reason for cooperation is trust and trustworthiness. The extant literature on forecast sharing and supply chain coordination implicitly assumes that supply chain members either absolutely trust each other and cooperate when sharing forecast information, or do not trust each other at all. Contrary to this all-or-nothing view, we determine that a continuum exists between these two extremes. In addition, we determine (i) when trust is important in forecast information sharing, (ii) how trust is affected by changes in the supply chain environment, and (iii) how trust affects related operational decisions. To explain and better understand the observed behavioral regularities, we also develop an analytical model of trust to incorporate both pecuniary and nonpecuniary incentives in the game-theoretic analysis of cheap-talk forecast communication. The model identifies and quantifies how trust and trustworthiness induce effective cheap-talk forecast sharing under the wholesale price contract. We also determine the impact of repeated interactions and information feedback on trust and cooperation in forecast sharing. We conclude with a discussion on the implications of our results for developing effective forecast management policies.</description><author>Oezer, Oezalp; Zheng, Yanchong; Chen, Kay-Yut</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing for Prudence and Skewness Seeking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ebert, Sebastian; Wiesen, Daniel
Numerous theoretical predictions such as precautionary saving or preventive behavior have been derived for prudent decision makers. Further, prudence can be characterized as downside risk aversion and plays a key role in preference for skewness. We use a simple experimental method to test for prudence and skewness preference in the laboratory and compare the two. To this end, we introduce a novel graphical representation of compound lotteries that is easily accessible to subjects and test it for robustness, using a factorial design. Prudence is observed on the aggregate and individual level. We find that prudence does not boil down to skewness seeking. We further provide some theoretical explanations for this result.</description><author>Ebert, Sebastian; Wiesen, Daniel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Preference Reversals for Ambiguity Aversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Trautmann, Stefan T.; Vieider, Ferdinand M.; Wakker, Peter P.
T his paper finds preference reversals in measurements of ambiguity aversion, even if psychological and informational circumstances are kept constant. The reversals are of a fundamentally different nature than the reversals found before because they cannot be explained by context-dependent weightings of attributes. We offer an explanation based on Sugden's random-reference theory, with different elicitation methods generating different random reference points. Then measurements of ambiguity aversion that use willingness to pay are confounded by loss aversion and hence overestimate ambiguity aversion.</description><author>Trautmann, Stefan T.; Vieider, Ferdinand M.; Wakker, Peter P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Centralized vs. Decentralized Ambulance Diversion: A Network Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deo, Sarang; Gurvich, Itai
One of the most important operational challenges faced by emergency departments (EDs) in the United States is patient overcrowding. In periods of overcrowding, an ED can request the emergency medical services (EMS) agency to divert incoming ambulances to neighboring hospitals, a phenomenon known as "ambulance diversion." The EMS agency may accept this request provided that at least one of the neighboring EDs is not on diversion. From an operations perspective, properly executed ambulance diversion should result in resource pooling and reduce the overcrowding and delays in a network of EDs. Recent evidence indicates, however, that this potential benefit is not always realized. In this paper, we provide one potential explanation for this discrepancy and suggest potential remedies. Using a queueing game between two EDs that aim to minimize their own waiting time, we find that decentralized decisions regarding diversion explain the lack of pooling benefits. Specifically, we find the existence of a defensive equilibrium, wherein each ED does not accept diverted ambulances from the other ED. This defensiveness results in a depooling of the network and, subsequently, in delays that are significantly higher than when a social planner coordinates diversion. The social optimum is itself difficult to characterize analytically and has limited practical appeal because it depends on problem parameters such as arrival rates and length of stay. Instead, we identify an alternative solution that does not require the exact knowledge of the parameters and may be used by the EMS agencies to coordinate diversion decisions when defensive diversion is present. We show that this solution is approximately optimal for the social planner's problem. Moreover, it is Pareto improving over the defensive equilibrium whereas the social optimum, in general, might not be.</description><author>Deo, Sarang; Gurvich, Itai</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Acquisition Spoils Retention: Direct Selling vs. Delegation Under CRM</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dong, Yan; Yao, Yuliang; Cui, Tony Haitao
The widespread implementation of customer relationship management technologies in business has allowed companies to increasingly focus on both acquiring and retaining customers. The challenge of designing incentive mechanisms that simultaneously focus on customer acquisition and customer retention comes from the fact that customer acquisition and customer retention are usually separate but intertwined tasks that make providing proper incentives more difficult. The present study develops incentive mechanisms that simultaneously address acquisition and retention of customers with an emphasis on the interactions between them. The main focus of this study is to examine the impact of the negative effect of acquisition on retention, i.e., the spoiling effect, on firm performance under direct selling and delegation of customer acquisition. Our main finding is that the negative effect of acquisition on retention has a significant impact on acquisition and retention efforts and firm profit. In particular, when the customer acquisition and retention are independent, the firm's profit is higher under direct selling than under delegation; however, when acquisition spoils retention, interestingly, the firm's profit may be higher under delegation. Our analysis also finds that the spoiling effect not only reduces the optimal acquisition effort but may also reduce retention effort under both direct selling and delegation. Comparing the optimal efforts under direct selling and delegation, the acquisition effort is always lower under delegation regardless of the spoiling effect, but the retention effort may be higher under delegation with the spoiling effect. Furthermore, when the customer antagonism effect from price promotions is considered, our main results hold regarding the firm's preferences between direct selling and delegation, which demonstrates the robustness of our model.</description><author>Dong, Yan; Yao, Yuliang; Cui, Tony Haitao</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling the Loss Distribution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chava, Sudheer; Stefanescu, Catalina; Turnbull, Stuart
In this paper, we focus on modeling and predicting the loss distribution for credit risky assets such as bonds and loans. We model the probability of default and the recovery rate given default based on shared covariates. We develop a new class of default models that explicitly accounts for sector specific and regime dependent unobservable heterogeneity in firm characteristics. Based on the analysis of a large default and recovery data set over the horizon 1980-2008, we document that the specification of the default model has a major impact on the predicted loss distribution, whereas the specification of the recovery model is less important. In particular, we find evidence that industry factors and regime dynamics affect the performance of default models, implying that the appropriate choice of default models for loss prediction will depend on the credit cycle and on portfolio characteristics. Finally, we show that default probabilities and recovery rates predicted out of sample are negatively correlated and that the magnitude of the correlation varies with seniority class, industry, and credit cycle.</description><author>Chava, Sudheer; Stefanescu, Catalina; Turnbull, Stuart</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exclusive Territories and Manufacturers' Collusion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Piccolo, Salvatore; Reisinger, Markus
This paper highlights the rationale for exclusive territories in a model of repeated interaction between competing supply chains. We show that with observable contracts exclusive territories have two countervailing effects on manufacturers' incentives to sustain tacit collusion. First, granting local monopolies to retailers softens competition in a one-shot game. Hence, punishment profits are larger, thereby rendering deviation more profitable. Second, exclusive territories stifle deviation profits because retailers of competing brands adjust their prices to the wholesale contract offered by a deviant manufacturer, whereas intrabrand competition prevents such "instantaneous reaction." We show that the latter effect tends to dominate, thereby making exclusive territories a more suitable organizational mode to cooperate. These insights are robust to endogenous communication between manufacturers. We also consider retailers' service investments. Here, a novel effect emerges that softens the procollusive value of exclusive territories: Retailers of a deviant manufacturer increase investments, which renders deviation more profitable.</description><author>Piccolo, Salvatore; Reisinger, Markus</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mixed Source</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Casadesus-Masanell, Ramon; Llanes, Gaston
W e study competitive interaction between a profit-maximizing firm that sells software and complementary services, and a free open-source competitor. We examine the firm's choice of business model between the proprietary model (where all software modules are proprietary), the open-source model (where all-modules are open source), and the mixed-source model (where some-but not all-modules are open). When a module is opened, users can access and improve the code, which increases quality and value creation. Opened modules, however, are available for others to use free of charge. We derive the set of possibly optimal business models when the modules of the firm and the open-source competitor are compatible (and thus can be combined) and incompatible, and show that (i) when the firm's modules are of high (low) quality, the firm is more open under incompatibility (compatibility) than under compatibility (incompatibility); (ii) firms are more likely to open substitute, rather than complementary, modules to existing open-source projects; and (iii) there may be no trade-off between value creation and value capture when comparing business models with different degrees of openness.</description><author>Casadesus-Masanell, Ramon; Llanes, Gaston</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuing the Treasury's Capital Assistance Program</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glasserman, Paul; Wang, Zhenyu
T he Capital Assistance Program (CAP) was created by the U. S. government in February 2009 to provide backup capital to large financial institutions unable to raise sufficient capital from private investors. Under the terms of the CAP, a participating bank receives contingent capital by issuing preferred shares to the Treasury combined with embedded options for both parties: The bank gets the option to redeem the shares or convert them to common equity, with conversion mandatory after seven years; the Treasury earns dividends on the preferred shares and gets warrants on the bank's common equity. We develop a contingent claims framework in which to estimate market values of these CAP securities. The interaction between the competing options held by the buyer and issuer of these securities creates a game between the two parties, and our approach captures this strategic element of the joint valuation problem and clarifies the incentives it creates. We apply our method to the 18 publicly held bank holding companies that participated in the Supervisory Capital Assessment Program (the stress test) launched together with the CAP. On average, we estimate that compared to a market transaction, the CAP securities carry a net value of approximately 30% of the capital invested for a bank participating to the maximum extent allowed under the terms of the program. We also find that the net value varies widely across banks. We compare our estimates with abnormal stock price returns for the stress test banks at the time the terms of the CAP were announced; we find correlations between 0.78 and 0.85, depending on the precise choice of period and set of banks included. These results suggest that our valuation aligns with shareholder perception of the value of the program, prompting questions about industry reactions and the overall impact of the program.</description><author>Glasserman, Paul; Wang, Zhenyu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Editorial Statement: Behavioral Economics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gneezy, Uri; Ho, Teck-Hua; List, John
nan</description><author>Gneezy, Uri; Ho, Teck-Hua; List, John</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Timing with Option-Implied Distributions: A Forward-Looking Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kostakis, Alexandros; Panigirtzoglou, Nikolaos; Skiadopoulos, George
We address the empirical implementation of the static asset allocation problem by developing a forward-looking approach that uses information from market option prices. To this end, we extract constant maturity S&amp;P 500 implied distributions and transform them to the corresponding risk-adjusted ones. Then we form optimal portfolios consisting of a risky and a risk-free asset and evaluate their out-of-sample performance. We find that the use of risk-adjusted implied distributions times the market and makes the investor better off than if she uses historical returns' distributions to calculate her optimal strategy. The results hold under a number of evaluation metrics and utility functions and carry through even when transaction costs are taken into account. Not surprisingly, the reported market timing ability deteriorated during the recent subprime crisis. An extension of the approach to a dynamic asset allocation setting is also presented.</description><author>Kostakis, Alexandros; Panigirtzoglou, Nikolaos; Skiadopoulos, George</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Losing Lead to Winning?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Jonah; Pope, Devin
Individuals, groups, and teams who are behind their opponents in competition tend to be more likely to lose. In contrast, we show that through increasing motivation, being slightly behind can actually increase success. Analysis of more than 18,000 professional basketball games illustrates that being slightly behind at halftime leads to a discontinuous increase in winning percentage. Teams behind by a point at halftime, for example, actually win more often than teams ahead by one, or approximately six percentage points more often than expected. This psychological effect is roughly half the size of the proverbial home-team advantage. Analysis of more than 45,000 collegiate basketball games finds consistent, though smaller, results. Experiments corroborate the field data and generalize their findings, providing direct causal evidence that being slightly behind increases effort and casting doubt on alternative explanations for the results. Taken together, these findings illustrate that losing can sometimes lead to winning.</description><author>Berger, Jonah; Pope, Devin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overconfidence by Bayesian-Rational Agents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Van den Steen, Eric
This paper derives two mechanisms through which Bayesian-rational individuals with differing priors will tend to be relatively overconfident about their estimates and predictions, in the sense of overestimating the precision of these estimates. The intuition behind one mechanism is slightly ironic: In trying to update optimally, Bayesian agents overweight information of which they overestimate the precision and underweight in the opposite case. This causes overall an overestimation of the precision of the final estimate, which tends to increase as agents get more data.</description><author>Van den Steen, Eric</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentives and Problem Uncertainty in Innovation Contests: An Empirical Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boudreau, Kevin J.; Lacetera, Nicola; Lakhani, Karim R.
Contests are a historically important and increasingly popular mechanism for encouraging innovation. A central concern in designing innovation contests is how many competitors to admit. Using a unique data set of 9,661 software contests, we provide evidence of two coexisting and opposing forces that operate when the number of competitors increases. Greater rivalry reduces the incentives of all competitors in a contest to exert effort and make investments. At the same time, adding competitors increases the likelihood that at least one competitor will find an extreme-value solution. We show that the effort-reducing effect of greater rivalry dominates for less uncertain problems, whereas the effect on the extreme value prevails for more uncertain problems. Adding competitors thus systematically increases overall contest performance for high-uncertainty problems. We also find that higher uncertainty reduces the negative effect of added competitors on incentives. Thus, uncertainty and the nature of the problem should be explicitly considered in the design of innovation tournaments. We explore the implications of our findings for the theory and practice of innovation contests.</description><author>Boudreau, Kevin J.; Lacetera, Nicola; Lakhani, Karim R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Going, Going, Gone? The Apparent Demise of the Accruals Anomaly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, Jeremiah; Hand, John R. M.; Soliman, Mark T.
Consistent with public statements made by sophisticated practitioners, we document that the hedge returns to Sloan's (Sloan, R. G. 1996. Do stock prices fully reflect information in accruals and cash flows about future earnings? Accounting Rev. 71(3) 289-315) accruals anomaly appear to have decayed in U. S. stock markets to the point that they are, on average, no longer reliably positive. We explore some potential reasons why this has happened. Our empirical analyses suggest that the anomaly's demise stems in part from an increase in the amount of capital invested by hedge funds into exploiting it, as measured by hedge fund assets under management and trading volume in extreme accrual firms. A decline in the size of the accrual mispricing signal, as measured by the magnitude of extreme decile accruals and the relative persistence of cash flows and accruals, may also play a (weaker) role.</description><author>Green, Jeremiah; Hand, John R. M.; Soliman, Mark T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comarketing Alliances: Should You Contract on Actions or Outcomes?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chennamaneni, Pavan Rao; Desiraju, Ramarao
Comarketing alliances often involve multiple partners, and a given partner's marketing efforts on behalf of the alliance can indirectly affect the demand of the other partners. Individual partners, however, can ignore the effects of such an externality and invest suboptimally to the detriment of the alliance. This paper examines the relative effectiveness of outcome-and action-based contracts in providing the alliance partners with the incentives to invest appropriately. We develop a mathematical model in which a focal firm (e. g., Sony) contracts with two partners (e. g., McDonald's and Old Navy) when each of these partners is privately informed about the impact of the alliance on its demand. Our analysis evaluates the strengths and weaknesses of outcome- (or output-) and action-based (or input-based) contracts in settings with varying levels of the demand externality. We find that when there is either no externality or a relatively weak positive externality, there is a strict preference for output-based contracts; that preference, however, is reversed with a sufficiently strong positive externality. This paper explains the underlying rationale for these findings.</description><author>Chennamaneni, Pavan Rao; Desiraju, Ramarao</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Benefits of Competitive Upward Channel Decentralization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Yunchuan; Tyagi, Rajeev K.
Upward channel decentralization occurs when firms choose to not manufacture products by themselves and procure products from upstream suppliers. Current voices from marketing scholars and practitioners have predominantly focused on the cost benefits when production is outsourced to lower-cost upstream suppliers. In this paper, we study the effects of upward channel decentralization where competing firms can outsource their production to upstream suppliers who do not have any advantages on production costs. We show how downstream firms can still benefit from upward channel decentralization provided their product positioning is endogenous. Thus, we provide a new theory on the strategic benefits of upward channel decentralization. We also use this framework to show a new benefit to manufacturers selling through downstream retailers rather than directly. We examine the implications of our theory for consumer and social welfare, and also draw managerial implications.</description><author>Liu, Yunchuan; Tyagi, Rajeev K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Does a Retailer's Service Plan Affect a Manufacturer's Warranty?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Bo; Zhang, Xubing
A service plan is a type of optional warranty beyond manufacturers' base warranties that retailers offer to consumers. In this paper, we examine how a service plan affects the role played by a manufacturer's base warranty. Analysis shows that when consumers can assess product quality (i.e., the probability of product failure), the manufacturer's warranty is negatively affected by the presence of a service plan. In the presence of such a plan, a base warranty is offered only when the manufacturer is very cost-efficient in providing a warranty relative to the retailer. In this case, although the double-marginalization problem is aggravated, offering a (limited) base warranty reduces the total warranty cost in the channel and provokes the retailer into enlarging the service plan coverage. When consumers cannot assess product quality, a high-quality manufacturer is motivated to offer a base warranty to signal its quality. In the presence of a service plan, however, a very cost-efficient manufacturer is discouraged from doing so.</description><author>Jiang, Bo; Zhang, Xubing</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Generating Ambiguity in the Laboratory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stecher, Jack; Shields, Timothy; Dickhaut, John
This article develops a method for drawing samples from a distribution with no finite quantiles or moments. The method provides researchers with a way to give subjects the experience of ambiguity. In any experiment, learning the distribution from experience is impossible for the subjects, essentially because it is impossible for the experimenter. We characterize our method, illustrate it in simulations, and then test it in a laboratory experiment. Our method does not withhold sampling information, does not assume that the subject is incapable of making statistical inferences, is replicable across experiments, and requires no special apparatus. We compare our method to the techniques used in related experiments that attempt to produce an ambiguous experience for the subjects.</description><author>Stecher, Jack; Shields, Timothy; Dickhaut, John</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Experimental Study of Information Revelation Policies in Sequential Auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cason, Timothy N.; Kannan, Karthik N.; Siebert, Ralph
Theoretical models of information asymmetry have identified a trade-off between the desire to learn and the desire to prevent an opponent from learning private information. This paper reports a laboratory experiment that investigates if actual bidders account for this trade-off, using a sequential procurement auction with private cost information and varying information revelation policies. Specifically, the Complete Information Revelation Policy, where all submitted bids are revealed between auctions, is compared to the Incomplete Information Revelation Policy, where only the winning bid is revealed. The experimental results are largely consistent with the theoretical predictions. For example, bidders pool with other types to prevent an opponent from learning significantly more often under a Complete Information Revelation Policy. Also as predicted, the procurer pays less when employing an Incomplete Information Revelation Policy only when the market is highly competitive. Bids are usually more aggressive than the risk-neutral quantitative prediction, which is broadly consistent with risk aversion.</description><author>Cason, Timothy N.; Kannan, Karthik N.; Siebert, Ralph</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Integrated Sequencing and Scheduling in Coil Coating</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoehn, Wiebke; Koenig, Felix G.; Moehring, Rolf H.; Luebbecke, Marco E.
We consider a complex planning problem in integrated steel production. A sequence of coils of sheet metal needs to be color coated in consecutive stages. Different coil geometries and changes of colors necessitate time-consuming setup work. In most coating stages one can choose between two parallel color tanks. This can either reduce the number of setups needed or enable setups concurrent with production. A production plan comprises the sequencing of coils and the scheduling of color tanks and setup work. The aim is to minimize the makespan for a given set of coils. We present an optimization model for this integrated sequencing and scheduling problem. A core component is a graph theoretical model for concurrent setup scheduling. It is instrumental for building a fast heuristic that is embedded into a genetic algorithm to solve the sequencing problem. The quality of our solutions is evaluated via an integer program based on a combinatorial relaxation, showing that our solutions are within 10% of the optimum. Our algorithm is implemented at Salzgitter Flachstahl GmbH, a major German steel producer. This has led to an average reduction in makespan by over 13% and has greatly exceeded expectations.</description><author>Hoehn, Wiebke; Koenig, Felix G.; Moehring, Rolf H.; Luebbecke, Marco E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fund Flows, Performance, Managerial Career Concerns, and Risk Taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Ping; Kale, Jayant R.; Pagani, Marco; Subramanian, Ajay
We develop a unified model of the interactions among investors, fund companies, and fund managers. We show that the interplay between a manager's incentives from her compensation structure and career concerns leads to a nonmonotonic (approximately U-shaped) relation between her risk choices and prior performance relative to her peers. Significantly outperforming (underperforming) managers are less (more) likely to be fired in the future and are also more likely to increase relative risk. Ceteris paribus, relative risk declines with the level of employment risk faced by a manager. Using a large sample of mutual fund managers, we find strong support for the hypothesized U-shaped relation between relative risk and prior performance. Our findings also highlight the importance of employment risk as the underlying driver of risk shifting by fund managers. Our theoretical model also generates additional hypotheses that link determinants of the fund flow-performance relation and managers' employment risk to their risk-taking behavior. In support, our empirical analysis shows that funds with higher expense ratios have less convex fund flow-performance relations and less convex U-shaped relations between relative risk and prior performance; funds with younger managers, who face greater employment risk, have more convex U-shaped relative risk-prior performance relations; and managers in larger fund families have lower incentives to engage in risk shifting, thereby leading to a less convex U-shaped relation.</description><author>Hu, Ping; Kale, Jayant R.; Pagani, Marco; Subramanian, Ajay</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Price Competition with Fixed Capacities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martinez-de-Albeniz, Victor; Talluri, Kalyan
In this paper, we study price competition for an oligopoly in a dynamic setting, where each of the sellers has a fixed number of units available for sale over a fixed number of periods. Demand is stochastic, and depending on how it evolves, sellers may change their prices at any time. This reflects the fact that firms constantly, and almost costlessly, change their prices, reacting to updates in their estimates of market demand, competitor prices, or inventory levels. In a setting with demand uncertainty, we show that there is a unique subgame-perfect equilibrium for a duopoly, in which all states sellers engage in Bertrand competition and the seller with the lower equilibrium reservation value sells a unit at a price equal to the competitor's equilibrium reservation value. This structure therefore extends the marginal-value concept of bid-price control, used in many revenue management implementations, to a competitive model. We give a closed-form solution to the equilibrium price paths for a duopoly and extend all the results to an n-firm oligopoly. We then study extensions to multiple customer types, uncertain valuations, and differentiated products.</description><author>Martinez-de-Albeniz, Victor; Talluri, Kalyan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anticipatory Sorting and Gender Segregation in Temporary Employment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernandez-Mateo, Isabel; King, Zella
We examine the roots of gender segregation in the screening process by using a longitudinal data set of candidates considered for temporary projects at a staffing firm and following their progress through the hiring pipeline. Theories invoked to explain gender segregation across jobs traditionally rely on firm-specific human capital and expectations of future commitment to explain this phenomenon. These do not apply in this setting. Yet we find that the staffing firm is more likely to shortlist women for low-paid projects and less likely to do so for high-paid ones. These effects are due to women being considered for different projects than men, and associated at least partially to the level of competition within vacancies. Although client companies also exhibit some gender-sorting behavior in the later steps of the hiring process, they are more likely to prefer women and less likely to sort them into lower-paid projects. Our findings are consistent with "anticipatory gender-sorting" mechanisms, by which first screeners generate segregation when narrowing down the pool of candidates for later decision makers. We discuss the implications of this case for theories of gender stratification and workplace inequality, especially in mediated labor markets.</description><author>Fernandez-Mateo, Isabel; King, Zella</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Preferences at Different Time Periods: An Experimental Investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abdellaoui, Mohammed; Diecidue, Enrico; Oencueler, Ayse
Intertemporal decision making under risk involves two dimensions: time preferences and risk preferences. This paper focuses on the impact of time on risk preferences, independent of the intertemporal trade-off of outcomes, i.e., time preferences. It reports the results of an experimental study that examines how delayed resolution and payment of risky options influence individual choice. We used a simple experimental design based on the comparison of two-outcome monetary lotteries with the same delay. Raw data clearly reveal that subjects become more risk tolerant for delayed lotteries. Assuming a prospect theory-like model under risk, we analyze the impact of time on utility and decision weights, independent of time preferences. We show that the subjective treatment of outcomes (i.e., utility) is not significantly affected by time. In fact, the impact of time is completely absorbed by the probability weighting function. The effect of time on risk preferences was found to generate probabilistic optimism resulting in a higher risk tolerance for delayed lotteries.</description><author>Abdellaoui, Mohammed; Diecidue, Enrico; Oencueler, Ayse</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monte Carlo Bounds for Game Options Including Convertible Bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beveridge, Christopher; Joshi, Mark
We introduce two new methods to calculate bounds for zero-sum game options using Monte Carlo simulation. These extend and generalize upper-bound duality results to the case where both parties of a contract have Bermudan optionality. It is shown that the primal-dual simulation method can still be used as a generic way to obtain bounds in the extended framework, and we apply the new results to the pricing of convertible bonds by simulation.</description><author>Beveridge, Christopher; Joshi, Mark</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Should Be Responsible for Software Security? A Comparative Analysis of Liability Policies in Network Environments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>August, Terrence; Tunca, Tunay I.
In recent years, vendor liability for software security vulnerabilities has been the center of an important debate in the software community and a topic gaining government attention in legislative committees and hearings. The importance of this question surrounding vendor security liability is amplified when one considers the increasing emergence of zero-day attacks where hackers take advantage of vulnerabilities before the software vendor has a chance to release protective patches. In this paper, we compare the effectiveness of three software liability policies: vendor liability for damages, vendor liability for patching costs, and government imposed security standards. We find that vendor liability for losses is not effective in improving social welfare in the short run, while liability for patching costs can be effective if either patching costs are large and the likelihood of a zero-day attack is low, or patching costs are small and zero-day likelihood is high. In the long run, when the vendor can invest in reducing the likelihood of security vulnerabilities, loss liability is still ineffective when the zero-day attack probability is high but can increase both vendor investment in security and social welfare when zero-day attack likelihood is sufficiently low. When the zero-day attack probability is high, patch liability is ineffective if user patching costs are large, but partial patch liability can boost vendor investment and improve welfare when patching costs are small. In contrast, in an environment with low zero-day attack probability, full vendor patch liability can be optimal. Finally, comparing the effectiveness of the three liability policies under study, we find that government imposed standards on software security investment can be preferable to both patching and loss liability on the vendor, if zero-day attack likelihood is sufficiently low. However, if zero-day attacks are a common occurrence and patching costs are not too high, partial patch liability is the most effective policy.</description><author>August, Terrence; Tunca, Tunay I.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entry and Patenting in the Software Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cockburn, Iain M.; MacGarvie, Megan J.
To what extent are firms kept out of a market by patents covering related technologies? Do patents held by potential entrants make it easier to enter markets? We estimate the empirical relationship between market entry and patents for 27 narrowly defined categories of software products during the period 1990-2004. Controlling for demand, market structure, average patent quality, and other factors, we find that a 10% increase in the number of patents relevant to market reduces the rate of entry by 3%-8%, and this relationship intensified following expansions in the patentability of software in the mid-1990s. However, potential entrants with patent applications relevant to a market are more likely to enter it. Finally, patents appear to substitute for complementary assets in the entry process, because patents have both greater entry-deterring and entry-promoting effects for firms without prior experience in other markets.</description><author>Cockburn, Iain M.; MacGarvie, Megan J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>