<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>MS0</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Job Mission as a Substitute for Monetary Incentives: Benefits and Limits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cassar, Lea
Many jobs are connected to a prosocial mission-namely, to a social purpose beyond profit maximization. I use three laboratory experiments to investigate if employers can use the mission to economize on monetary incentives. In my first experiment, I exogenously vary whether the agents' effort generates a donation to a charity of their choice (matched mission), generates a donation to a charity chosen by another subject (random mission), or generates no donation (no mission). I find that the mission, whether matched or random, increases effort compared to the no-mission condition. Consistent with the theory, nonmotivated principals exploit the agents' motivation by offering lower piece rates, whereas very motivated principals pay higher piece rates to boost the donation. I find no difference in the effort and piece rate between the matched- and random-mission conditions. In my second experiment, I use a selected pool of motivated subjects but still observe no difference between these two treatments. In my third experiment, I explore whether the effect of mission-matching may arise through gift exchange: principals decide between choosing the mission or delegating the choice to the agent. I do not find evidence that agents who are delegated the mission choice reciprocate with higher effort. These findings suggest that while a prosocial mission allows for economizing on monetary incentives, there are no further gains from increasing the quality of the mission-matching.</description><author>Cassar, Lea</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Complementarity of Signals in Early-Stage Equity Investment Decisions: Evidence from a Randomized Field Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bapna, Sofia
This study employs a randomized field experiment to causally identify what type of signal is likely to complement another signal in the context of financing technology ventures. The study examines the effect of product certification by expert intermediaries, prominent customers, and social proof (that is, others' interest in investing in a venture) on interest in investing. These three signals are primarily signals of a venture's product, market, and investment characteristics, respectively. The study finds that signals of product certification and prominent customers, and product certification and social proof are complements. In particular, investors who were able to view the combined product certification and prominent customer signals have a 72% higher likelihood of indicating an interest in making an equity investment than those who did not receive any of the three signals. Similarly, investors who were able to view the combined product certification and social proof signals have a 65% higher likelihood of indicating an interest in investing. These results suggest that in the context of technology ventures, a signal about product characteristics is the key to unlocking the value of signals of market or investment characteristics.</description><author>Bapna, Sofia</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Philanthropic Campaigns and Customer Behavior: Field Experiments on an Online Taxi Booking Platform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Singh, Jasjit; Teng, Nina; Netessine, Serguei
Firms commonly undertake philanthropic campaigns as a means of attracting and retaining customers. Such campaigns often take the form of charity-linked promotions, whereby a firm donates a specific amount to a charitable cause when a customer takes up the promotion through a related purchase. We carried out three field experiments to study such promotions in the context of an online taxi-booking platform. Customers were randomly assigned to different treatment groups, which received either a charity linked or a discount-based promotion from a range of monetary amounts. Take-up rates for charity-linked promotions were not only much smaller than for discount-based promotions but also less sensitive to the exact amount involved, consistent with a view that the decision to take up a charity-linked promotion was driven in part by a "warm glow" from mere association with giving. We also find a selection effect in promotion take-up: charity-linked promotions were disproportionately taken up by people who had already been more active customers. Although a promotion take-up does seem to represent new demand rather than mere substitution of a booking that would have occurred anyway, longitudinal data analysis reveals little evidence of a lasting treatment effect on long-term demand beyond the promotion period for either kind of promotion. Given the high cost relative to benefit for the promotional bookings themselves, this finding raises concerns regarding the prevalent practice of firms devoting significant funds for short-term promotions without rigorously examining their exact impact.</description><author>Singh, Jasjit; Teng, Nina; Netessine, Serguei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Alliance Formation and Firm Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cabral, Luis; Pacheco-de-Almeida, Goncalo
We consider the formation of alliances that potentially create complementarities, that is, when the value function is supermodular in firm resources. We show that, in a frictionless world where information is perfect and managers optimize, firm alliances disproportionately increase the value of high-resource-level firms, resulting in higher variance and higher skewness of the distribution of firm value; moreover, higher-value alliances are subject to regression to the mean at a faster rate. These effects are magnified if the degree of complementarities is endogenously determined by each firm's investment. We also consider alliances where matching and/or information about firm resources are imperfect, and show that complementarities are a necessary but not sufficient condition for alliances to cause an increase in firm value; and that complementarities are neither a necessary nor a sufficient condition for alliances to be correlated with higher firm value.</description><author>Cabral, Luis; Pacheco-de-Almeida, Goncalo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Bridge Too Far: Divestiture as a Strategic Reaction to Status Inconsistency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Pengfei; Jensen, Michael
This study focuses on the market identities of firms and suggests that identity ambiguity is caused not only by bridging horizontal product categories but also by status inconsistency stemming from bridging vertical status categories. Focusing specifically on how firms reduce status inconsistency by restructuring their business portfolios, we argue that status inconsistency motivates firms to divest business units to present a more coherent vertical market identity. Emphasizing the interplay between horizontal and vertical identity ambiguity, we argue furthermore that status-inconsistent units that are related to the core business units within a firm are more likely to be divested. Using a comprehensive sample of publicly traded U.S. firms from 1998 to 2014, we report that status inconsistency increases the likelihood of divestiture that decreases status inconsistency, particularly for high-status firms. Moreover, although status-inconsistent units are generally more likely to be divested, this effect is stronger for core business units.</description><author>Wang, Pengfei; Jensen, Michael</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From the Editor</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Simchi-Levi, David
nan</description><author>Simchi-Levi, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do General Managerial Skills Spur Innovation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Custodio, Claudia; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro
We show that firms with chief executive officers (CEOs) who gain general managerial skills over their lifetime of work experience produce more patents. We address the potential endogenous CEO-firm matching bias using firm-CEO fixed effects and variation in the enforceability of noncompete agreements across states and over time during the CEO's career. Our findings suggest that generalist CEOs spur innovation because they acquire knowledge beyond the firm's current technological domain, and they have skills that can be applied elsewhere should innovation projects fail. We conclude that an efficient labor market for executives can promote innovation by providing a mechanism of tolerance for failure.</description><author>Custodio, Claudia; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Peer-to-Peer Product Sharing: Implications for Ownership, Usage, and Social Welfare in the Sharing Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benjaafar, Saif; Kong, Guangwen; Li, Xiang; Courcoubetis, Costas
We describe an equilibrium model of peer-to-peer product sharing, or collaborative consumption, where individuals with varying usage levels make decisions about whether or not to own a homogeneous product. Owners are able to generate income from renting their products to nonowners while nonowners are able to access these products through renting on an as-needed basis. We characterize equilibrium outcomes, including ownership and usage levels, consumer surplus, and social welfare. We compare each outcome in systems with and without collaborative consumption and examine the impact of various problem parameters. Our findings indicate that collaborative consumption can result in either lower or higher ownership and usage levels, with higher ownership and usage levels more likely when the cost of ownership is high. Our findings also indicate that consumers always benefit from collaborative consumption, with individuals who, in the absence of collaborative consumption, are indifferent between owning and not owning benefitting the most. We study both profit-maximizing and social-welfare- maximizing platforms and compare equilibrium outcomes under both in terms of ownership, usage, and social welfare. We find that the difference in social welfare between the profit-maximizing and social-welfare-maximizing platforms is relatively modest.</description><author>Benjaafar, Saif; Kong, Guangwen; Li, Xiang; Courcoubetis, Costas</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>First-Place Loving and Last-Place Loathing: How Rank in the Distribution of Performance Affects Effort Provision</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gill, David; Kissova, Zdenka; Lee, Jaesun; Prowse, Victoria
Rank-order relative-performance evaluation, in which pay, promotion, symbolic awards, and educational achievement depend on the rank of individuals in the distribution of performance, is ubiquitous. Whenever organizations use rank-order relative-performance evaluation, people receive feedback about their rank. Using a real-effort experiment, we aim to discover whether people respond to the specific rank that they achieve. In particular, we leverage random variation in the allocation of rank among subjects who exerted the same effort to obtain a causal estimate of the rank response function that describes how effort provision responds to the content of rank-order feedback. We find that the rank response function is U-shaped. Subjects exhibit "first-place loving" and "last-place loathing": that is, subjects work hardest after being ranked first or last. We discuss implications of our findings for the optimal design of performance feedback policies, workplace organizational structures, and incentives schemes.</description><author>Gill, David; Kissova, Zdenka; Lee, Jaesun; Prowse, Victoria</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond Return Predictability: Economic Value and Links to the Macroeconomy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gargano, Antonio; Pettenuzzo, Davide; Timmermann, Allan
Studies of bond return predictability find a puzzling disparity between strong statistical evidence of return predictability and the failure to convert return forecasts into economic gains. We show that resolving this puzzle requires accounting for important features of bond return models such as volatility dynamics and unspanned macro factors. A three-factor model comprising a forward spread, a weighted combination of forward rates, and a macro factor generates notable gains in out-of-sample forecast accuracy compared with a model based on the expectations hypothesis. Such gains in predictive accuracy translate into higher risk-adjusted portfolio returns after accounting for estimation error and model uncertainty. Consistent with models featuring unspanned macro factors, our forecasts of future bond excess returns are strongly negatively correlated with survey forecasts of short rates.</description><author>Gargano, Antonio; Pettenuzzo, Davide; Timmermann, Allan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Get with the Program: Software-Driven Innovation in Traditional Manufacturing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Branstetter, Lee G.; Drev, Matej; Kwon, Namho
This paper documents the increasing importance of software for successful innovation in manufacturing sectors well beyond the traditional definition of electronics and information technology. Using panel data for 229 publicly listed firms from 18 countries across four manufacturing industries over the period 1981-2005, we find significant variation across firms in the software intensity of their innovative activity. Firms that exhibit a higher level of software intensity generate more patents per R&amp;D dollar, and their investment in R&amp;D is more highly valued by equity markets.</description><author>Branstetter, Lee G.; Drev, Matej; Kwon, Namho</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sourcing Innovation: On Feedback in Contests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mihm, Jurgen; Schlapp, Jochen
It is notoriously difficult to provide outside parties with adequate incentives for innovation. Contests-in which solvers compete for a prize offered by the contest holder-have been shown to be an effective incentive mechanism. Despite considerable interest in this concept, we lack a thorough understanding of important aspects of contests; in particular, feedback from the contest holder to the solvers has received only limited attention. This paper discusses how contest holders can improve contest outcomes by devising an optimal information structure for their feedback policies. We first identify when, and when not, to give feedback as well as which type of feedback to give: public (which all solvers can observe) or private (which only the focal solver can observe). We uncover a nontrivial relationship between contest characteristics and optimal feedback choices. Second, we examine whether the contest holder should mandate interim feedback or instead allow solvers to seek feedback at their own discretion. Third, we discuss how changing the granularity of feedback information affects its value to solvers.</description><author>Mihm, Jurgen; Schlapp, Jochen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Controlling vs. Enabling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hagiu, Andrei; Wright, Julian
How does a firm decide whether to employ professionals and control how they deliver services to clients, or to operate as a platform enabling independent professionals to provide services directly to clients? Similarly, how does a manufacturer decide whether to allow sales agents to choose certain costly actions (e.g., kickbacks to clients) or to take control of these actions itself? We answer this question using a principal-agent framework in which both the principal and the agent must be incentivized to carry out investments (or effort) that increase the revenue they jointly create. Our theory explains when the principal should take control over a particular decision ("control") or should instead allow the agent to make the decision ("enable"). It does so both for the case when there are multiple such transferable decisions for a single agent, and for the case when there are many agents and one transferable decision for each. We also consider the possibility of cost asymmetries between the principal and the agent, spillovers across agents, and the misclassification of the principal as an employer even though agents are allocated the relevant control rights. Finally, we explain how the "control versus enable" choice and its associated trade-offs differ from the classic "make versus buy" choice.</description><author>Hagiu, Andrei; Wright, Julian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Quality and Entering Through Tying: Experimental Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Hyunjin; Luca, Michael
Dominant platform businesses often develop products in adjacent markets to complement their core business. One common approach used to gain traction in these adjacent markets has been to pursue a tying strategy. For example, Microsoft preinstalled Internet Explorer into Windows, and Apple set Apple Maps as the iOS default. Policy-makers have raised concerns that dominant platforms may be leveraging their market power to gain traction for lower quality products when they use a tying strategy. In this paper, we empirically explore this question by examining Google's decision to tie its new reviews product to its search engine. We experimentally vary the reviews displayed above Google's organic search results to show either exclusively Google reviews (Google's current tying strategy) or reviews from multiple platforms determined to be the best-performing by Google's own organic search algorithm. We find that users prefer the version that does not exclude competitor reviews. Furthermore, looking at observational data on user traffic to Yelp from search engines, we find that Google's exclusion of downstream competitors may have been effective. The share of Yelp's traffic coming from Google has declined over this period, relative to traffic from Bing and Yahoo (which do not exclude other companies' reviews), and Google reviews has grown more quickly than Yelp and TripAdvisor during the period in which they excluded these (and other) reviews providers. Overall, these results suggest that tying has the potential to facilitate entry in complementary markets even when the tied product is of worse quality than competitors.</description><author>Kim, Hyunjin; Luca, Michael</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Adaptive Distributionally Robust Optimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertsimas, Dimitris; Sim, Melvyn; Zhang, Meilin
We develop a modular and tractable framework for solving an adaptive distributionally robust linear optimization problem, where we minimize the worst-case expected cost over an ambiguity set of probability distributions. The adaptive distributionally robust optimization framework caters for dynamic decision making, where decisions adapt to the uncertain outcomes as they unfold in stages. For tractability considerations, we focus on a class of second-order conic (SOC) representable ambiguity set, though our results can easily be extended to more general conic representations. We show that the adaptive distributionally robust linear optimization problem can be formulated as a classical robust optimization problem. To obtain a tractable formulation, we approximate the adaptive distributionally robust optimization problem using linear decision rule (LDR) techniques. More interestingly, by incorporating the primary and auxiliary random variables of the lifted ambiguity set in the LDR approximation, we can significantly improve the solutions, and for a class of adaptive distributionally robust optimization problems, exact solutions can also be obtained. Using the new LDR approximation, we can transform the distributionally adaptive robust optimization problem to a classical robust optimization problem with an SOC representable uncertainty set. Finally, to demonstrate the potential for solving management decision problems, we develop an algebraic modeling package and illustrate how it can be used to facilitate modeling and obtain high-quality solutions for medical appointment scheduling and inventory management problems.</description><author>Bertsimas, Dimitris; Sim, Melvyn; Zhang, Meilin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the Sources of Risk Underlying the Cross Section of Commodity Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, Gurdip; Gao, Xiaohui; Rossi, Alberto G.
We show that a model featuring an average commodity factor, a carry factor, and a momentum factor is capable of describing the cross-sectional variation of commodity returns. More parsimonious one- and two-factor models that feature only the average and/or carry factors are rejected. To provide an economic interpretation, we show that innovations in global equity volatility can price portfolios formed on carry, while innovations in a commodity-based measure of speculative activity can price portfolios formed on momentum. Finally, we characterize the relation between the factors and the investment opportunity set.</description><author>Bakshi, Gurdip; Gao, Xiaohui; Rossi, Alberto G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing Channel Profits When Retailers Have Profitable Outside Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Inderst, Roman; Shaffer, Greg
The channel-coordination literature typically focuses on how a supplier can overcome channel inefficiencies stemming from misaligned pricing incentives. In contrast, we show that when an incumbent supplier faces competition from other suppliers to supply the downstream firms, it may want to create inefficiencies. Our analysis offers useful prescriptions for how incumbent suppliers should react to competitive threats by smaller competitors, how manufacturers should react to powerful retailers who can produce their own private-label brands, and how upstream firms should optimally treat downstream firms who may have different marginal costs of distribution. Our analysis also explains why wholesale prices and thus final-goods prices would be expected to decrease when there is an increase in upstream or downstream competition.</description><author>Inderst, Roman; Shaffer, Greg</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Environmental Benefits of Internet-Enabled C2C Closed-Loop Supply Chains: A Quasi-Experimental Study of Craigslist</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dhanorkar, Suvrat
Recently, online matching platforms (e.g., Craigslist, FreeCycle, Gumtree) have enabled consumers to directly connect with each other to buy/sell used consumer goods (electronics, furniture, packaging, etc.) that would have otherwise ended up in the waste stream. Such matching platforms can facilitate the creation of consumer-to-consumer (C2C) closed-loop supply chains (CLSCs) for used goods, which can enhance product reuse and limit reliance on recycling and disposal alternatives. Yet, the true environmental benefits of these internet-enabled C2C CLSCs remain to be ascertained. In this study, I use a quasi-experimental setup to examine how Craigslist's entry into various U.S. geographic markets impacts a key environmental outcome: municipal solid waste (MSW). I assemble a data set from various disparate sources to test my hypothesis. I find that, on average, Craigslist's entry into a geographic market results in a 2%-6% annual reduction in MSW per capita generated. I conduct a variety of robustness checks, falsification tests, and validation checks to provide support to my findings. Overall, this study provides deeper insights into the potential of online reuse platforms for the creation and coordination of C2C CLSCs. To my knowledge, this is the first study of closed-loop supply chains in a C2C context.</description><author>Dhanorkar, Suvrat</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer Subsidies with a Strategic Supplier: Commitment vs. Flexibiliy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemama, Jonathan; Cohen, Maxime C.; Lobel, Ruben; Perakis, Georgia
Governments use consumer incentives to promote green technologies (e.g., solar panels and electric vehicles). Our goal in this paper is to study how policy adjustments over time will interact with production decisions from the industry. We model the interaction between a government and an industry player in a two-period game setting under uncertain demand. We show how the timing of decisions affects the risk sharing between the government and the supplier, ultimately affecting the cost of the subsidy program. In particular, we show that when the government commits to a fixed policy, it encourages the supplier to produce more at the beginning of the horizon. Consequently, a flexible subsidy policy is on average more expensive, unless there is a significant negative demand correlation across time periods. However, we show that the variance of the total sales is lower in the flexible setting, implying that the government's additional spending reduces the adoption level uncertainty. In addition, we show that for flexible policies, the supplier is better off in terms of expected profits, whereas the consumers can either benefit or not depending on the price elasticity of demand. Finally, we test our insights with a numerical example calibrated on data from a solar subsidy program.</description><author>Chemama, Jonathan; Cohen, Maxime C.; Lobel, Ruben; Perakis, Georgia</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Commitment to a Production Schedule with Uncertain Supply and Demand: Renewable Energy in Day-Ahead Electricity Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sunar, Nur; Birge, John R.
We consider a day-ahead electricity market that consists of multiple competing renewable firms (e.g., wind generators) and conventional firms (e.g., coal-fired power plants) in a discrete-time setting. The market is run in every period, and all firms submit their price-contingent production schedules in every day-ahead market. Following the clearance of a day-ahead market, in the next period, each (renewable) firm chooses its production quantity (after observing its available supply). If a firm produces less than its cleared day-ahead commitment, the firm pays an undersupply penalty in proportion to its underproduction. We explicitly characterize firms' equilibrium strategies by introducing and analyzing a supply function competition model. The purpose of an undersupply penalty is to improve reliability by motivating each firm to commit to quantities it can produce in the following day. We prove that in equilibrium, imposing or increasing a market-based undersupply penalty rate in a period can result in a strictly larger renewable energy commitment at all prices in the associated day-ahead market, and can lead to lower equilibrium reliability in all periods with probability 1. We also show in an extension that firms with diversified technologies result in lower equilibrium reliability than single-technology firms in all periods with probability 1.</description><author>Sunar, Nur; Birge, John R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Open Routing in Service Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arlotto, Alessandro; Frazelle, Andrew E.; Wei, Yehua
We study the behavior of strategic customers in an open-routing service network with multiple stations. When a customer enters the network, she is free to choose the sequence of stations that she visits, with the objective of minimizing her expected total system time. We propose a two-station game with all customers present at the start of service and deterministic service times, and we find that strategic customers "herd," that is, in equilibrium all customers choose the same route. For unobservable systems, we prove that the game is supermodular, and we then identify a broad class of learning rules-which includes both fictitious play and Cournot best response-that converges to herding in finite time. By combining different theoretical and numerical analyses, we find that the herding behavior is prevalent in many other congested open-routing service networks, including those with arrivals over time, those with stochastic service times, and those with more than two stations. We also find that the system under herding performs very close to the first-best outcome in terms of cumulative system time.</description><author>Arlotto, Alessandro; Frazelle, Andrew E.; Wei, Yehua</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing the Impact of Service Level When Customer Needs Are Uncertain: An Empirical Investigation of Hospital Step-Down Units</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Carri W.; Green, Linda; Lekwijit, Suparerk; Lu, Lijian; Escobar, Gabriel
Many service systems have servers with different capabilities and customers with varying needs. One common way this occurs is when servers are hierarchical in their skills or in the level of service they can provide. Much of the literature studying such systems relies on an understanding of the relative costs and benefits associated with serving different customer types by the different levels of service. In this work, we focus on estimating these costs and benefits in a complex healthcare setting where the major differentiation among server types is the intensity of service provided. Step-down units (SDUs) were initially introduced in hospitals to provide an intermediate level of care for semicritically ill patients who are not sick enough to require intensive care but not stable enough to be treated in the general medical/surgical ward. One complicating factor is that the needs of customers is sometimes uncertain-specifically, it is difficult to know a priori which level of care a particular patient needs. Using data from 10 hospitals from a single hospital network, we take a data-driven approach to classify patients based on severity and empirically estimate the clinical and operational outcomes associated with routing these patients to the SDU. Our findings suggest that an SDU may be a cost-effective way to treat patients when used for patients who are post-ICU (intensive care unit). However, the impact of SDU care is more nuanced for patients admitted from the emergency department and may result in increased mortality risk and hospital length of stay for patients who should be treated in the ICU. Our results imply that more study is needed when using SDU care this way.</description><author>Chan, Carri W.; Green, Linda; Lekwijit, Suparerk; Lu, Lijian; Escobar, Gabriel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Scheduling with Testing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levi, Retsef; Magnanti, Thomas; Shaposhnik, Yaron
We study a new class of scheduling problems that capture common settings in service environments, in which one has to serve a collection of jobs that have a priori uncertain attributes (e.g., processing times and priorities) and the service provider has to decide how to dynamically allocate resources (e.g., people, equipment, and time) between testing (diagnosing) jobs to learn more about their respective uncertain attributes and processing jobs. The former could inform future decisions, but could delay the service time for other jobs, while the latter directly advances the processing of the jobs but requires making decisions under uncertainty. Through novel analysis we obtain surprising structural results of optimal policies that provide operational managerial insights, efficient optimal and near-optimal algorithms, and quantification of the value of testing. We believe that our approach will lead to further research to explore this important practical trade-off.</description><author>Levi, Retsef; Magnanti, Thomas; Shaposhnik, Yaron</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multiperiod Stock Allocation via Robust Optimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jackson, Peter L.; Muckstadt, John A.; Li, Yuexing
We consider a one-warehouse, N-retailer, multiperiod, stock allocation problem in which holding costs are identical at each location and no stock is received from outside suppliers for the duration of the planning horizon. No shipments are allowed between retailers. The only motive for holding inventory at the central warehouse for allocation in future periods is the so-called risk pooling motive. We apply robust optimization to this problem extending the inventory policy to allow for an adaptive, nonanticipatory shipment policy. We consider two alternatives for the uncertainty set, one in which risk pooling is implicit and another for which risk pooling is explicit. The explicit risk pooling uncertainty set grows by no more than the square of the number of retailers. The general problem can be solved using Benders' decomposition. A special case gives rise to closed-form solutions for both uncertainty set alternatives. The explicit risk pooling uncertainty set leads to a square root law in which the optimal stock to reserve at the central warehouse grows with the square root of the number of retailers. The experimental results confirm the value of the robust optimization approach and provide managerial insights into the operation of such systems.</description><author>Jackson, Peter L.; Muckstadt, John A.; Li, Yuexing</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Sales Schemes for Network Goods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parakhonyak, Alexei; Vikander, Nick
This paper considers a monopolist's product-launch strategy in the presence of network effects, focusing on how to exploit these effects to the maximum possible extent. In our formal framework, the firm sets a price for its product and chooses a sales scheme, which effectively determines how consumers can learn from each other about the product's popularity. Our results on the profitability of different schemes provide insights on a variety of managerial issues that are of practical relevance for product launch. Specifically, to best exploit network effects, our results suggest releasing preorder and sales information to consumers. They also suggest taking a sequential approach to multimarket product launch, launching first in smaller markets before larger ones. Moreover, they identify possible benefits of promoting prerelease consumer communication, and they support the idea of targeting independent-minded consumers, so they can serve as opinion leaders for those who follow.</description><author>Parakhonyak, Alexei; Vikander, Nick</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contracting with Opportunistic Partners: Theory and Application to Technology Development and Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Casas-Arce, Pablo; Kittsteiner, Thomas; Asis Martinez-Jerez, F.
After a contract is signed, contracting partners may engage in opportunistic behavior aimed at circumventing the original intention of the agreement governing their business relationship, complying with the letter but not the spirit of the contract. We use an incomplete contracts approach to show that the anticipation and observability of such behavior are typically not enough to prevent it when parties can renegotiate contractual outcomes. This is because contractually specified incentives inevitably have conflicting effects: they simultaneously increase the likelihood of welfare-improving investments and welfare-reducing opportunistic behavior. The possibility of such opportunism thus limits the effectiveness of contractual incentives. We also discuss how our results relate to contracting practices observed in industries characterized by rapid innovation, such as information technology.</description><author>Casas-Arce, Pablo; Kittsteiner, Thomas; Asis Martinez-Jerez, F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Local Access to Finance Matter? Evidence from US Oil and Natural Gas Shale Booms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilje, Erik P.
I exploit exogenous changes in local credit supply from shale discoveries to identify where and when local access to finance is economically important for firms. I find that the real effects of a credit supply shock are linked to local lending market characteristics. Changes in local credit supply have significant real effects in lending markets dominated by small banks, while there is no effect in other markets. These results suggest that small banks, which do not benefit from deep internal capital markets, face economically meaningful frictions in accessing external interbank markets to fund loans. The effect in other markets, which have large multimarket banks, indicates that these markets are not as dependent on local funding sources for lending. These findings illustrate the important role that the internal capital markets of banks have on real outcomes.</description><author>Gilje, Erik P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting the Trade-off Between Risk and Incentives: The Shocking Effect of Random Shocks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corgnet, Brice; Hernan-Gonzalez, Roberto
Despite its central role in the theory of incentives, empirical evidence of a trade-off between risk and incentives remains scarce. We reexamine this trade-off in a workplace lab environment and find that, in line with theory, principals increase fixed pay while lowering performance pay when the relationship between effort and output is noisier. Unexpectedly, agents produce substantially more in the noisy environment than in the baseline despite weaker incentives. In addition, principals' earnings are significantly higher in the noisy environment. We show that these findings can be accounted for when agents maximize a non-CARA utility function or when they exhibit loss aversion.</description><author>Corgnet, Brice; Hernan-Gonzalez, Roberto</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inverse Optimization: Closed-Form Solutions, Geometry, and Goodness of Fit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Timothy C. Y.; Lee, Taewoo; Terekhov, Daria
In classical inverse linear optimization, one assumes that a given solution is a candidate to be optimal. Real data are imperfect and noisy, so there is no guarantee that this assumption is satisfied. Inspired by regression, this paper presents a unified framework for cost function estimation in linear optimization comprising a general inverse optimization model and a corresponding goodness-of-fit metric. Although our inverse optimization model is nonconvex, we derive a closed-formsolution and present the geometric intuition. Our goodness-of-fit metric, rho, the coefficient of complementarity, has similar properties to R-2 from regression and is quasi-convex in the input data, leading to an intuitive geometric interpretation. While rho is computable in polynomial time, we derive a lower bound that possesses the same properties, is tight for several important model variations, and is even easier to compute. We demonstrate the application of our framework for model estimation and evaluation in production planning and cancer therapy.</description><author>Chan, Timothy C. Y.; Lee, Taewoo; Terekhov, Daria</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contracting in Medical Equipment Maintenance Services: An Empirical Investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Tian Heong; de Vericourt, Francis; Besbes, Omar
Maintenance service plans (MSPs) are contracts for the provision of maintenance by a service provider to an equipment operator. These plans can have different payment structures and risk allocations, which induce various types of incentives for agents in the service chain. How do such structures affect service performance and service chain value? We provide an empirical answer to this question by using unique panel data covering the sales and service records of more than 700 diagnostic body scanners. We exploit the presence of a standard warranty period and employ a matching approach to isolate the incentive effects of MSPs from the confounding effects of endogenous contract selection. We find that moving the equipment operator from a basic, pay-per-service plan to a fixed-fee, full-protection plan not only reduces reliability but also increases equipment service costs. Furthermore, that increase is driven by both the operator and the service provider. Our results indicate that incentive effects arising from MSPs leads to losses in service chain value, and we provide the first evidence that a basic pay-per-service plan-under which risk of equipment failure is borne by the operator-can improve performance and reduce costs.</description><author>Chan, Tian Heong; de Vericourt, Francis; Besbes, Omar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Service System with Dependent Service and Patience Times</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Chenguang; Bassamboo, Achal; Perry, Ohad
Motivated by recent empirical evidence, we consider a large service system in which the patience time of each customer depends on his service requirement. Our goal is to study the impact of such dependence on key performance measures, such as expected waiting times and average queue length, as well as on optimal capacity decisions. Since the dependence structure renders exact analysis intractable, we employ a stationary fluid approximation that is based on the entire joint distribution of the service and patience times. Our results show that even moderate dependence has significant impacts on system performance, so considering the patience and service times to be independent when they are in fact dependent is futile. We further demonstrate that Pearson's correlation coefficient, which is commonly used to measure and rank dependence, is an insufficient statistic, and that the entire joint distribution is required for comparative statics. Thus, we propose a novel framework, incorporating the fluid model with bivariate dependence orders and copulas, to study the impacts of the aforementioned dependence. We then demonstrate how that framework can be applied to facilitate revenue optimization when staffing and abandonment costs are incurred. Finally, the effectiveness of the fluid-based approximations and optimal-staffing prescriptions is demonstrated via simulations.</description><author>Wu, Chenguang; Bassamboo, Achal; Perry, Ohad</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Online Piracy and the "Longer Arm" of Enforcement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dey, Debabrata; Kim, Antino; Lahiri, Atanu
Controlling digital piracy has remained a top priority for manufacturers of information goods, as well as for many governments around the world. Among the many forms taken by digital piracy, we focus on an increasingly common one-namely, online piracy-that is facilitated by torrent sites and cyberlockers who bring together consumers of pirated content and its suppliers. Motivated by recent empirical literature that makes a clear distinction between antipiracy efforts that restrict supply of pirated goods (supply-side enforcement) and ones that penalize illegal consumption (demand-side enforcement), we develop a simple economic model and discover some fundamental differences between these two types in terms of their impacts on innovation and welfare. All in all, supply-side enforcement turns out to be the "longer arm"-it has a more desirable economic impact in the long run. Our results have clear implications for manufacturers, consumers, and policy makers.</description><author>Dey, Debabrata; Kim, Antino; Lahiri, Atanu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Open Source Software and Firm Productivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nagle, Frank
As open source software (OSS) is increasingly used as a key input by firms, understanding its impact on productivity becomes critical. This study measures the firm-level productivity impact of nonpecuniary (free) OSS and finds a positive and significant value-added return for firms that have an ecosystem of complementary capabilities. There is no such impact for firms without this ecosystem of complements. Dynamic panel analysis, instrumental variables, and a variety of robustness checks are used to address measurement error concerns and to add support for a more causal interpretation of the results. For firms with an ecosystem of complements, a 1% increase in the use of nonpecuniary OSS leads to an increase in value- added productivity of between 0.002% and 0.008%. This effect is smaller for larger firms, and the results indicate that prior research underestimates the amount of IT firms use.</description><author>Nagle, Frank</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning from Inventory Availability Information: Evidence from Field Experiments on Amazon</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cui, Ruomeng; Zhang, Dennis J.; Bassamboo, Achal
Many online retailers provide real-time inventory availability information. Customers can learn from the inventory level and update their beliefs about the product. Thus, consumer purchasing behavior may be impacted by the availability information. Based on a unique setting from Amazon lightning deals, which displays the percentage of inventory consumed in real time, we explore whether and how consumers learn from inventory availability information. Identifying the effect of learning on consumer decisions has been a notoriously difficult empirical question because of endogeneity concerns. We address this issue by running two randomized field experiments on Amazon in which we create exogenous shocks on the inventory availability information for a random subset of Amazon lightning deals. In addition, we track the dynamic purchasing behavior and inventory information for 23,665 lightning deals offered by Amazon and use their panel structure to further explore the relative effect of learning. We find evidence of consumers learning from inventory information: a decrease in product availability causally attracts more sales in the future; in particular, a 10% increase in past claims leads to a 2.08% increase in cart add-ins in the next hour. Moreover, we show that buyers use observable product characteristics to moderate their inferences when learning from others; a deep discount weakens the learning momentum, whereas a good product rating amplifies the learning momentum.</description><author>Cui, Ruomeng; Zhang, Dennis J.; Bassamboo, Achal</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning and Hierarchies in Service Systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bimpikis, Kostas; Markakis, Mihalis G.
Motivated by diverse application areas such as healthcare, call centers, and crowdsourcing, we consider the design and operation of service systems that process tasks with types that are ex ante unknown, and employ servers with different skill sets. Our benchmark model involves two types of tasks, Easy and Hard, and servers that are either Junior or Senior in their abilities. The service provider determines a resource allocation policy, i.e., how to assign tasks to servers over time, with the goal of maximizing the system's long-term throughput. Information about a task's type can only be obtained while serving it. In particular, the more time a Junior server spends on a task without service completion, the higher her belief that the task is Hard and thus needs to be rerouted to a Senior server. This interplay between service time and task-type uncertainty implies that the system's resource allocation policy and staffing levels implicitly determine how the provider prioritizes between learning and actually serving. We show that the performance loss due to the uncertainty in task types can be significant and, interestingly, that the system's stability region is largely dependent on the rate at which information about tasks' types is generated. Furthermore, we consider endogenizing the servers' capabilities: assuming that training is costly, we explore the problem of jointly optimizing over the training levels of the system's server pools, the staffing levels, and the resource allocation policy. We find that among optimal designs there always exists one with a "hierarchical" structure, where all tasks are initially routed to the least skilled servers and then progressively move to more skilled ones, if necessary. Comparative statics indicate that uncertainty in task types leads to significantly higher staffing cost and less specialized server pools.</description><author>Bimpikis, Kostas; Markakis, Mihalis G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multidimensional Bargaining and Inventory Risk in Supply Chains: An Experimental Study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davis, Andrew M.; Hyndman, Kyle
We study the impact of multidimensional bargaining and the location of inventory risk on the performance of a two-stage supply chain. We conduct a controlled human subjects experiment where a retailer and supplier either interact through ultimatum offers or dynamically bargain over contract terms, including a wholesale price and, potentially, an order quantity. We also manipulate whether the risk associated with unsold inventory lies with the retailer or the supplier or is endogenously determined in the bargaining process. One key insight is that supply chain efficiency is significantly higher when the order quantity is included in the negotiation and that, contrary to the normative theory, this leads to a Pareto improvement whereby both the supplier and retailer earn higher profits. A second important result, also counter to the normative theory, is that the party incurring the cost of unsold inventory always earns a lower profit than its counterpart, regardless of the bargaining environment or inventory risk location. To explain these data, we posit that retailers and suppliers are affected by an anchoring bias and demonstrate that it can explain many of our results.</description><author>Davis, Andrew M.; Hyndman, Kyle</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Relational Contracts for Quality Enforcement in Supply Chains</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bondareva, Mariya; Pinker, Edieal
We model the interaction of a single buyer with a single supplier within a market in a developing country with homogeneous local suppliers and homogeneous buyers from developed nations. The buyer sources a product from a supplier and then inspects and sells it on the market, subject to quality standards such as regulations about chemical content. Suppliers decide howmuch effort to exert to ensure compliance with quality standards. Buyers are assumed to comply with contracts because they are based in countries with strong legal systems. We assume that legal enforcement of the supplier's contractual obligations is not possible. We model the interaction between buyer and supplier as a repeated game in which the partnership can be terminated by the buyer if the supplier refuses to pay penalties for quality violations. After termination, the buyer and supplier each search for a new business partner. We model the interaction between buyer and supplier using relational contacts in which penalties for quality failures are set so that the supplier voluntarily pays them. We show that optimal relational contracts have dynamic form in this setting because the value of the outside option available to the parties, if the relationship is terminated, is determined by the contract terms. We characterize the properties of the optimal dynamic equilibria and analyze the use of third-party quality certifications within this framework.</description><author>Bondareva, Mariya; Pinker, Edieal</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contracts for Healthcare Referral Services: Coordination via Outcome-Based Penalty Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adida, Elodie; Bravo, Fernanda
This work focuses on the business-to-business interaction between a service requester and a service provider in a healthcare environment. The requester is the primary caregiver responsible for managing the health of a population of patients. When a patient requires advanced care outside of the requester's expertise, the requester refers the patient to a provider and pays for the referral services. Treatment may succeed or fail, and in the case of failure, the requester incurs further follow-up costs. The requester may exert preventive effort to reduce the volume of referrals. The provider may exert nonreimbursable effort to reduce the chance of treatment failure. We analyze payment contracts between the two firms. We find that fee-for-service (FFS) induces neither system nor social optimum effort outcomes. However, a penalty contract can generally coordinate the effort decisions with either the system optimum or the social optimum. Furthermore, we find that patients may benefit from having a coordinating contract replace FFS. However, the types of procedures that make a coordinating contract most advantageous for the requester and provider are not necessarily the same as those that make the patients better off than under FFS. Yet, in most cases, the coordinating contract improves social welfare, as compared to FFS, and brings it close to the social optimum. Hence, the requester-provider coordinating contract can be considered as an improvement over FFS for the entire system.</description><author>Adida, Elodie; Bravo, Fernanda</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of Personal Information in Online Markets with Endogenous Privacy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Montes, Rodrigo; Sand-Zantman, Wilfried; Valletti, Tommaso
We investigate the effects of price discrimination on prices, profits, and consumer surplus when (a) at least one competing firm can use consumers' private information to price discriminate yet (b) consumers can prevent such use by paying a "privacy cost." Unlike a monopolist, competing duopolists do not always benefit from a higher privacy cost because each firm's profit decreases-and consumer surplus increases-with that cost. Under such competition, the optimal strategy for an owner of consumer data that sells information in a single block is selling to only one firm, thereby maximizing the stakes for rival buyers. The resulting inefficiencies imply that policy makers should devote more attention to discouraging exclusivity deals and less to ensuring that consumers can easily protect their privacy.</description><author>Montes, Rodrigo; Sand-Zantman, Wilfried; Valletti, Tommaso</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling Consumer Footprints on Search Engines: An Interplay with Social Media</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghose, Anindya; Ipeirotis, Panagiotis G.; Li, Beibei
It is now well understood that social media plays an increasingly important role in consumers' decision making. However, an overload of social media content in product search engines can hinder consumers from efficiently seeking information. We propose a structural econometric model to understand consumers' preferences and costs on search engines to improve user experience under unstructured social media. Our model combines an optimal stopping framework with an individual-level random utility choice model and analyzes click behavior in conjunction with purchase choices. Our model accounts for three major constraints in a consumer's decision-making process: (1) interdependency in decision making for different alternatives, (2) sequential arrival of information revealed by click-throughs, and (3) nonnegligible search cost. Our approach allows us to jointly estimate consumers' heterogeneous preferences and search costs under the interplay of social media and search engines, and to predict search and purchase behavior for each consumer. We validate the model using an individual session-level data set of approximately seven million observations resulting in room bookings in 2,117 U.S. hotels. Interestingly, our analysis allows us to quantify the trade-off between consumers' benefits and cognitive costs from using large-scale unstructured social media information during decision making. Our policy experiments show that providing a carefully curated digest of social media content during the earlier stages of consumer search (i.e., on the search results summary page) can lead to a 12.01% increase in the overall search engine revenue.</description><author>Ghose, Anindya; Ipeirotis, Panagiotis G.; Li, Beibei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Aversion and Precautionary Savings in Dynamic Settings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bommier, Antoine; Le Grand, Francois
We study the saving behavior of infinitely long-lived agents who face income uncertainty and deterministic interest rates. Using monotone recursive preferences, we prove that risk aversion unambiguously increases savings. The result accounts for possibly binding borrowing constraints and holds for very general specification of income uncertainty, which can follow any kind of stochastically monotone process.</description><author>Bommier, Antoine; Le Grand, Francois</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Charity in the Laboratory: Matching, Competition, and Group Identity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Charness, Gary; Holder, Patrick
We conduct a laboratory experiment in which participants can make donations to real charities. We vary whether the experimenter provides matching funds for any such donations, and whether there is individual or team competition for these matching funds. Our results indicate that providing matching funds for all donations does increase donations from 23% to 33% of the endowment. While individual competition for matching funds had nearly the same effectiveness as matching all donations, by far the most effective approach was to form (anonymous) teams that competed for matching funds; this led to donations of 47% of the endowment. We appeal to the notion of group identity to explain our results-participants seemed to be reluctant to "let down their team" in a competition. Our results can be seen as providing support for the notion that combining group identity and competition creates a motivation that can potentially be harnessed effectively for prosocial purposes.</description><author>Charness, Gary; Holder, Patrick</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Encouraging Help Across Projects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crama, Pascale; Sting, Fabian J.; Wu, Yaozhong
Companies struggle with timely project execution despite employing sophisticated management methods. Although help across projects is critical for time performance, it has not been explicitly incorporated into project management ( PM) systems. We model a PM system, based on an innovative real-life practice, that both incorporates and shapes project managers' helping behavior. A help process is at the core of this system, in which project managers may ask for and provide help while top management facilitates such exchanges. We find that companies should take a nuanced approach when designing help exchange and time-based incentives in tandem. A company that faces high project rewards after delays and highly effective help can benefit from inducing help because doing so enables the pursuit of projects it might abandon if delayed or even at the outset. The formal help process delivers value by creating and exploiting interdependencies between projects. These interdependencies allow project prioritization by inducing different effort levels in otherwise identical projects. A help process also allows the company to "tune" the timing of efforts by front-loading or back-loading project work. The benefits of a help system accrue through cost efficiencies, increased probability of success under help, and intertemporal incentive effects that encourage early efforts. However, because the help process creates the opportunity for free riding, a help system is not always recommended and a no-help system may perform better, especially when there are low project rewards after delay and low opportunity costs for project work.</description><author>Crama, Pascale; Sting, Fabian J.; Wu, Yaozhong</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Adjusting to the Information Environment: News Tangibility and Mutual Fund Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chuprinin, Oleg; Gaspar, Sergio; Massa, Massimo
We study the relation between mutual funds' performance and shocks to the public information environment of their investments. For each stock, we distinguish between quantitative, or tangible, news (expressed with numeric characters) and qualitative news (expressed as verbal content). We find that funds that trade more actively in response to changes in the stocks' information tangibility earn higher risk-adjusted returns. Funds that are particularly sensitive to such fluctuations have smaller managerial teams and employ managers who are more focused. Overall, our evidence suggests that signals associated with changes in the type of public information constitute a channel of value creation in asset management.</description><author>Chuprinin, Oleg; Gaspar, Sergio; Massa, Massimo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Day Returns of Stock Distributions: An Anchoring Explanation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Eric C.; Lin, Tse-Chun; Luo, Yan; Ren, Jinjuan
We offer a new anchoring explanation for the ex-day abnormal returns of stock distributions, including stock dividend distributions, splits, and reverse splits. We propose that investors tend to anchor on cum-day prices in valuating ex-distribution stocks, resulting in a positive association between ex-day returns and adjustment factors. We find that this positive return-factor relation exists for all three types of stock distributions and in both the pre- and post-decimalization periods. Furthermore, we find that this positive return-factor relation is more pronounced among events that are more subject to investors' anchoring propensity, featured by less investor attention, greater arbitrage difficulty, greater valuation uncertainty, less investor sophistication, and higher market sentiment. Last, using brokerage account data, we show that stocks that are traded by investors with more investment experience demonstrate a weaker return-factor relation.</description><author>Chang, Eric C.; Lin, Tse-Chun; Luo, Yan; Ren, Jinjuan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Coverage, Coarseness, and Classification: Determinants of Social Efficiency in Priority Queues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gurvich, Itai; Lariviere, Martin A.; Ozkan, Can
Customers often resent priority queues even though priorities are often necessary to maximize either social welfare or revenue. Consequently, it is useful to consider the level of social inefficiency introduced when the design of a priority scheme is turned over to a revenue-maximizing firm. In this paper we study how the priority scheme chosen by a revenue-maximizing firm differs from the one a social planner would use. We study a single-server queue with customers who draw their valuations from a continuous distribution and have a per-period waiting cost that is proportional to their realized valuations. The decision maker must post a menu offering a finite number of waiting time-price pairs. There are then three dimensions on which a revenue maximizer and social planner can differ: coverage (i.e., how many customers in total to serve), coarseness (i.e., how many classes of service to offer), and classification (i.e., how to map customers to priority levels). We show that differences between the decision-makers' priority policies are all about classification. Both are content to offer very coarse schemes with just two priority levels, and they will have negligible differences in coverage. However, differences in classification are persistent. Further, a revenue maximizer may-relative to the social planner-have too few or too many high-priority customers. Whether the revenue maximizer overstuffs or understuffs the high-priority class depends on a measure of consumer surplus that is captured by the mean residual life function of the valuation distribution.</description><author>Gurvich, Itai; Lariviere, Martin A.; Ozkan, Can</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evidence of Upcoding in Pay-for-Performance Programs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bastani, Hamsa; Goh, Joel; Bayati, Mohsen
Recent Medicare legislation seeks to improve patient care quality by financially penalizing providers for hospital-acquired infections (HAIs). However, Medicare cannot directly monitor HAI rates and instead relies on providers accurately self-reporting HAIs in claims to correctly assess penalties. Consequently, the incentives for providers to improve service quality may disappear if providers upcode, i.e., misreport HAIs (possibly unintentionally) in a manner that increases reimbursement or avoids financial penalties. Identifying upcoding in claims data is challenging because of unobservable confounders (e.g., patient risk). We leverage state-level variations in adverse event reporting regulations and instrumental variables to discover contradictions in HAI and present-on-admission (POA) infection reporting rates that are strongly suggestive of upcoding. We conservatively estimate that 10,000 out of 60,000 annual reimbursed claims for POA infections (18.5%) were upcoded HAIs, costing Medicare $200 million. Our findings suggest that self-reported quality metrics are unreliable and, thus, that recent legislation may result in unintended consequences.</description><author>Bastani, Hamsa; Goh, Joel; Bayati, Mohsen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity Risk and Mutual Fund Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dong, Xi; Feng, Shu; Sadka, Ronnie
This paper demonstrates that the ability of fund managers to create value depends on market liquidity conditions, which in turn introduces a liquidity risk exposure (beta) for skilled managers. We document an annual liquidity beta performance spread of 4% in the cross section of mutual funds over the period 1983-2014. Liquidity risk premia explain an insubstantial fraction of this spread; instead, the spread can be attributed to the differential ability of high liquidity beta funds to outperform across high and low market liquidity states, due to a differential rate of either mispricing correction or intensity of informed trading. Tests based on mispricing, proxied by a comprehensive set of 68 anomalies, and tick-by-tick trades, from a large proprietary institutional trading data set, corroborate the contribution of these channels. The results highlight the interaction between informed investors, mispricing, and liquidity beta.</description><author>Dong, Xi; Feng, Shu; Sadka, Ronnie</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Service Systems with Heterogeneous Customers: Investigating the Effect of Telemedicine on Chronic Care</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rajan, Balaraman; Tezcan, Tolga; Seidmann, Abraham
Medical specialists treating chronic conditions typically face a heterogeneous set of patients. Such heterogeneity arises because of differences in medical conditions as well as the travel burden each patient faces to visit the clinic periodically. Given this heterogeneity, we compare the strategic behavior of revenue-maximizing and welfare-maximizing specialists and prove that the former will serve a smaller patient population, spend more time with the patients, and have shorter waiting times. We also analyze the impact of telemedicine technology on patient utility and the specialists' operating decisions. We consider both the case when specialists can freely set their own fee for service and the case when fees are set exogenously by a third-party payer. We prove that with the introduction of telemedicine, the specialists become more productive and the overall social welfare increases, although some patients, unexpectedly, will be worse off. Our analytical results lead to some important policy implications for facilitating the further deployment of telemedicine in the care of chronically ill patients.</description><author>Rajan, Balaraman; Tezcan, Tolga; Seidmann, Abraham</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Integration and Liquidity Crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Castiglionesi, Fabio; Feriozzi, Fabio; Lorenzoni, Guido
This paper analyzes the effects of financial integration on the stability of the banking system. Financial integration allows banks in different regions to smooth local liquidity shocks by borrowing and lending on a world interbank market. We show under which conditions financial integration induces banks to reduce their liquidity holdings and to shift their portfolios toward more profitable but less liquid investments. Integration helps reallocate liquidity when different banks are hit by uncorrelated shocks. However, when a correlated (systemic) shock hits, the total liquid resources in the banking system are lower than in autarky. Therefore, financial integration leads to more stable interbank interest rates in normal times but to larger interest rate spikes in crises. These results hold in a setup in which financial integration is welfare improving from an ex ante point of view. We also look at the model's implications for financial regulation and show that, in a second-best world, financial integration can increase the welfare benefits of liquidity requirements.</description><author>Castiglionesi, Fabio; Feriozzi, Fabio; Lorenzoni, Guido</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the External Validity of Social Preference Games: A Systematic Lab-Field Study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Galizzi, Matteo M.; Navarro-Martinez, Daniel
We present a lab-field experiment designed to systematically assess the external validity of social preferences elicited in a variety of experimental games. We do this by comparing behavior in the different games with several behaviors elicited in the field and with self-reported behaviors exhibited in the past, using the same sample of participants. Our results show that the experimental social preference games do a poor job explaining both social behaviors in the field and social behaviors from the past. We also include a systematic review and meta-analysis of previous literature on the external validity of social preference games.</description><author>Galizzi, Matteo M.; Navarro-Martinez, Daniel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When to Use Provider Triage in Emergency Departments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kamali, Michael F.; Tezcan, Tolga; Yildiz, Ozlem
We study triage decisions in emergency departments (EDs) and provide a general procedure for determining when to apply provider triage (PT) based on operational and financial considerations using a steady-state, many-server fluid approximation. We then apply the proposed method in the setting of a teaching hospital's ED and obtain closed-form expressions for the range of arrival rates for which PT outperforms the traditional nurse triage economically. We show that the proposed solution methodology based on this approximation procedure is asymptotically optimal under a many-server asymptotic regime. We also demonstrate via simulation experiments that the proposed policy performs within 0.82% of the best solution obtained via a computationally intensive total enumeration method.</description><author>Kamali, Michael F.; Tezcan, Tolga; Yildiz, Ozlem</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of E-book Distribution on Print Sales: Analysis of a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hailiang; Hu, Yu Jeffrey; Smith, Michael D.
Digital distribution introduces many new strategic questions for the creative industries-notably, how the use of new digital channels will impact sales in established channels. We analyze this question in the context of e-book and hardcover sales by exploiting a natural experiment that exogenously delayed the release of a publisher's new Kindle e-books in April and May 2010. Using new books released simultaneously in e-book and print formats in March and June 2010 as the control group, we find that delaying e-book availability results in a 43.8% decrease in e-book sales but no increase in print book sales on Amazon.com or among other online or offline retailers. We also find that the decrease in e-book sales is greater for books with less prerelease buzz. Together, we find no evidence of strong cannibalization between print books and e-books in the short term and no support for the sequential distribution of books in print versions followed by e-book versions.</description><author>Chen, Hailiang; Hu, Yu Jeffrey; Smith, Michael D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Analysis of Price vs. Revenue Protection: Government Subsidies in the Agriculture Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alizamir, Saed; Iravani, Foad; Mamani, Flamed
The agriculture industry plays a critical role in the U.S. economy, and various industry sectors depend on the output of farms. To protect and raise farmers' income, the U.S. government offers two subsidy programs to farmers: the Price Loss Coverage (PLC) program, which pays farmers a subsidy when the market price falls below a reference price, and the Agriculture Risk Coverage (ARC) program, which is triggered when farmers' revenue is below a threshold. Given the unique features of PLC and ARC, we develop models to analyze their impacts on consumers, farmers, and the government. Our analysis generates several insights. First, while PLC always motivates farmers to plant more acres compared to the no-subsidy case, farmers may plant fewer acres under ARC, leading to a lower crop supply. Second, despite the prevailing intuition that ARC generally dominates PLC, we show that both farmers and consumers may be better off under PLC for a large range of parameter values, even when the reference price represents the historical average market price. Third, the subsidy that increases consumer surplus results in higher government expenditure. Finally, we calibrate our model with U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) data and provide insights about the effects of crop and market characteristics on the relative performance of PLC and ARC. We provide guidelines to farmers for enrolling crops in the subsidy programs, and show that our guidelines are supported by farmers' enrollment statistics. We also show that if the economic and political frictions caused by running the subsidy programs is significant, the subsidy that benefits both consumers and farmers may actually result in lower social welfare.</description><author>Alizamir, Saed; Iravani, Foad; Mamani, Flamed</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Scheduling Promotion Vehicles to Boost Profits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baardman, Lennart; Cohen, Maxime C.; Panchamgam, Kiran; Perakis, Georgia; Segev, Danny
In addition to setting price discounts, retailers need to decide how to schedule promotion vehicles, such as flyers and TV commercials. Unlike the promotion pricing problem that received great attention from both academics and practitioners, the promotion vehicle scheduling problem was largely overlooked, and our goal is to study this problem both theoretically and in practice. We model the problem of scheduling promotion vehicles to maximize profits as a nonlinear bipartite matching-type problem, where promotion vehicles should be assigned to time periods, subject to capacity constraints. Our modeling approach is motivated and calibrated using actual data in collaboration with Oracle Retail, leading us to introduce and study a class of models for which the boost effects of promotion vehicles on demand are multiplicative. From a technical perspective, we prove that the general setting considered is computationally intractable. Nevertheless, we develop approximation algorithms and propose a compact integer programming formulation. In particular, we show how to obtain a (1 - epsilon)-approximation using an integer program of polynomial size, and investigate the performance of a greedy procedure, both analytically and computationally. We also discuss an extension that includes cross-term effects to capture the cannibalization aspect of using several vehicles simultaneously. From a practical perspective, we test our methods on actual data through a case study, and quantify the impact of our models. Under our model assumptions and for a particular item considered in our case study, we show that a rigorous optimization approach to the promotion vehicle scheduling problem allows the retailer to increase its profit by 2% to 9%.</description><author>Baardman, Lennart; Cohen, Maxime C.; Panchamgam, Kiran; Perakis, Georgia; Segev, Danny</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Split-Award Auctions: Insights from Theory and Experiments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaturvedi, Aadhaar; Katok, Elena; Beil, Damian R.
We investigate procurement in a setting in which the buyer is bound by sourcing rules. Sourcing rules may limit the minimum and maximum amounts of business that can be awarded to a single supplier or dictate the minimum number of suppliers who are awarded business, thus necessitating split awards. The buyer announces the splits before the auction, and suppliers bid accordingly. We consider two auction formats: the sealed-bid first-price auction, and a version of the open-bid descending-price auction. We characterize the suppliers' symmetric equilibrium bidding strategy for both formats and find that the two formats yield the same expected buyer's cost. We characterize the cost of multisourcing, showing among other things that it is always costly for the buyer to split its award among more suppliers if the suppliers' costs are regularly distributed, but that doing so can actually reduce the buyer's expected auction payment if the suppliers' costs are not regularly distributed. The results from controlled laboratory experiments, involving human subjects, indicate that expected cost equivalence fails when costs are regularly distributed because suppliers bid more aggressively in the sealed-bid auction. However, for split-award auctions with nonregularly distributed costs, the sealed-bid prices are actually higher than predicted by theory. We explain these mismatches between observations and theory through a behavioral model based on bidders' aversion to anticipated regret. The experimental results indicate that the theory does a good job of predicting the relationship between the buyer's average cost and the award splits, as well as the cost of multisourcing. Importantly, the experiments confirm that when suppliers' costs come from a nonregular distribution, it may be to the buyer's advantage to diversify the supply base more than is strictly necessitated by sourcing rules.</description><author>Chaturvedi, Aadhaar; Katok, Elena; Beil, Damian R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing Uncertainty from Point Forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gaba, Anil; Popescu, Dana G.; Chen, Zhi
The paper develops a model for combining point forecasts into a predictive distribution for a variable of interest. Our approach allows for point forecasts to be correlated and admits uncertainty on the distribution parameters given the forecasts. Further, it provides an easy way to compute an augmentation factor needed to equate the dispersion of the point forecasts to that of the predictive distribution, which depends on the correlation between the point forecasts and on the number of forecasts. We show that ignoring dependence or parameter uncertainty can lead to assuming an unrealistically narrow predictive distribution. We further illustrate the implications in a newsvendor context, where our model leads to an order quantity that has higher variance but is biased in the less costly direction, and generates an increase in expected profit relative to other methods.</description><author>Gaba, Anil; Popescu, Dana G.; Chen, Zhi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Analysis for Large Pools of Loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sirignano, Justin; Giesecke, Kay
Financial institutions, government-sponsored enterprises, and asset-backed security investors are often exposed to delinquency and prepayment risk from large numbers of loans. Examples include mortgages, credit cards, and auto, student, and business loans. Because of the size of the pools, the measurement of these exposures is computationally expensive. This paper develops and tests efficient numerical methods for the analysis of large pools of loans as well as asset-backed securities backed by such pools. For a broad class of statistical and machine learning models of loan-level risk in discrete time, we prove a law of large numbers and a central limit theorem for the pool-level risk. The asymptotics are then used to construct computationally efficient approximations for a large pool. The approximations aggregate the full loan-level dynamics, making it possible to take advantage of the detailed loan-level data often available in practice. We furthermore prove a convergence rate for the approximation and a uniform integrability result. The latter allows the approximation to be applied to a wide class of pool-level risk statistics. To demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach, we implement it on a data set of over 25 million mortgages. The results show the accuracy and speed of the approximation in comparison to brute-force simulation of a pool, for a variety of pools with different risk profiles.</description><author>Sirignano, Justin; Giesecke, Kay</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Closing a Supplier's Energy Efficiency Gap Through Assessment Assistance and Procurement Commitment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nguyen, Jason; Donohue, Karen; Mehrotra, Mili
This paper analyzes the energy efficiency (EE) investment decisions of a capital-constrained manufacturer that competes with an alternative supplier for the business of a large industrial buyer. Through a series of game-theoretic models, we characterize when it is beneficial for the buyer to offer EE instruments, including assessment assistance and procurement commitment, and how these instruments interact with third-party assessment assistance to affect the supplier's EE investment level. We find that assessment assistance helps reduce the EE gap but procurement commitment is required to eliminate it. We also find that the availability of third-party assessment assistance reduces the buyer's incentive to offer both of its instruments, a scenario that potentially lowers the supplier's EE investment level. Our findings provide insights for buyers and policy makers interested in improving supply-chain EE.</description><author>Nguyen, Jason; Donohue, Karen; Mehrotra, Mili</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Welfare Analysis of Dynamic Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Ningyuan; Gallego, Guillermo
Dynamic pricing is designed to increase the revenues or profits of firms by adjusting prices in response to changes in the marginal value of capacity. We examine the impact of dynamic pricing on social welfare and consumers' surplus. We present a dynamic pricing formulation designed to maximize welfare and show that the welfare-maximizing dynamic pricing policy has the same structural properties as the revenue-maximizing policy. For systems with scarce capacity, we show that the revenue-maximizing dynamic pricing policy and the market-clearing price are both asymptotically optimal for welfare. We also find in most cases that revenue-maximizing dynamic pricing improves consumers' surplus compared to the revenue-maximizing static price. Our findings can potentially transform the public image of dynamic pricing and provide new managerial insights as well as policy implications: (1) in large-scale systems with scarce capacity, a central planner would essentially implement the same pricing policy as a firm with monopoly power; (2) the revenue-maximizing dynamic pricing policy can benefit customers when the demand elasticity is in a small bounded interval as is the case for several important demand functions.</description><author>Chen, Ningyuan; Gallego, Guillermo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust Multiclass Queuing Theory for Wait Time Estimation in Resource Allocation Systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bandi, Chaithanya; Trichakis, Nikolaos; Vayanos, Phebe
In this paper, we study systems that allocate different types of scarce resources to heterogeneous allocatees based on predetermined priority rules-the U.S. deceased-donor kidney allocation system or the public housing program. We tackle the problem of estimating the wait time of an allocatee who possesses incomplete system information with regard, for example, to his relative priority, other allocatees' preferences, and resource availability. We model such systems as multiclass, multiserver queuing systems that are potentially unstable or in transient regime. We propose a novel robust optimization solution methodology that builds on the assignment problem. For first-come, first-served systems, our approach yields a mixed-integer programming formulation. For the important case where there is a hierarchy in the resource types, we strengthen our formulation through a drastic variable reduction and also propose a highly scalable heuristic, involving only the solution of a convex optimization problem (usually a second-order cone problem). We back the heuristic with an approximation guarantee that becomes tighter for larger problem sizes. We illustrate the generalizability of our approach by studying systems that operate under different priority rules, such as class priority. Numerical studies demonstrate that our approach outperforms simulation. We showcase how our methodology can be applied to assist patients in the U.S. deceased-donor kidney waitlist. We calibrate our model using historical data to estimate patients' wait times based on their kidney quality preferences, blood type, location, and rank in the waitlist.</description><author>Bandi, Chaithanya; Trichakis, Nikolaos; Vayanos, Phebe</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Faithful Strategies: How Religion Shapes Nonprofit Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Filistrucchi, Lapo; Prufer, Jens
This paper studies the strategies employed by Catholic and Protestant nonprofit hospitals in Germany and traces them back to the theological foundations of those religions. Using a unique data set, we find that Catholic nonprofit hospitals follow a strategy of horizontal diversification and maximization of the number of patients treated. By contrast, Protestant hospitals pursue a strategy of horizontal specialization and focus on vertical differentiation, putting in more sophisticated inputs and producing more complex services. These effects increase if the environment of a hospital gets more competitive. We present a model that rationalizes the strategic differences as a result of the difference between Catholic and Protestant values identified in the literature. We then test alternative explanations to the observed empirical differences and show that none of them is supported by the data.</description><author>Filistrucchi, Lapo; Prufer, Jens</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Temporary Contract Adjustment to a Retailer with a Private Demand Forecast</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nasser, Sherif; Turcic, Danko
This paper analyzes a setting in which a manufacturer (he) and a retailer (she) face uncertain demand, but the retailer has an information advantage in the form of a private demand forecast. Such information asymmetry causes the manufacturer to incur a hidden information cost. The results show that a manufacturer can leverage his timing advantage to strategically implement a temporary contract adjustment (TCA) mechanism, which allows him to counter his informational disadvantage and either eliminate or reduce the hidden information cost. The manufacturer implements the TCA mechanism by designing the supply contract with two sets of terms: presignal and postsignal. Presignal terms engage the retailer before observing the forecast signal and induce her to decide under high uncertainty. As a result, she overinvests when the forecast signal is low. Postsignal terms engage her after the signal, allowing her to make use of the information and purchase additional stock efficiently based on the forecast signal. This ability to utilize the forecast information allows the manufacturer to set more efficient contract terms. By applying the TCA mechanism to a simple wholesale price contract, the manufacturer can achieve the effect of free, partial information revelation as if he observes a coarse version of the retailer's private forecast. By applying the TCA mechanism to a (stronger) quantity-transfer menu, the manufacturer can achieve the effect of free, full information revelation (i.e., full information profits) as if he fully observes the same version of the forecast, without the retailer directly sharing her private information.</description><author>Nasser, Sherif; Turcic, Danko</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The (Neural) Dynamics of Stochastic Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Webb, Ryan
The standard framework for modeling stochastic choice, the random utility model, is agnostic about the temporal dynamics of the decision process. In contrast, a general class of bounded accumulation models from psychology and neuroscience explicitly relate decision times to stochastic choice behavior. This article demonstrates that a random utility model can be derived from the general class of bounded accumulation models, and characterizes how the resulting distribution of random utility depends on response time. This relationship can bias the estimation of structural preference parameters. The bias can be alleviated via the inclusion of standard observables directly in the econometric specification, or through incorporating novel observables such as response time or neurobiological data. Examples of estimating risk and brand preferences are pursued.</description><author>Webb, Ryan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Random Projection Estimation of Discrete-Choice Models with Large Choice Sets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiong, Khai Xiang; Shum, Matthew
We introduce random projection, an important dimension-reduction tool from machine learning, for the estimation of aggregate discrete-choice models with high-dimensional choice sets. Initially, high-dimensional data are projected into a lower-dimensional Euclidean space using random projections. Subsequently, estimation proceeds using cyclical monotonicity moment inequalities implied by the multinomial choice model; the estimation procedure is semiparametric and does not require explicit distributional assumptions to be made regarding the random utility errors. Our procedure is justified via the Johnson-Lindenstrauss lemma-the pairwise distances between data points are preserved through random projections. The estimator works well in simulations and in an application to a supermarket scanner data set.</description><author>Chiong, Khai Xiang; Shum, Matthew</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quality and Pricing Decisions in a Market with Consumer Information Sharing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Baojun; Yang, Bicheng
We provide a dynamic, game-theoretic model to examine a firm's quality and pricing decisions for its new experience goods. Early consumers do not observe product quality prior to purchase but can learn it after purchase and share that product-quality information with later consumers-for example, through online reviews. Both the firm's quality decision and its cost efficiency are the firm's private information and not directly observed by the consumer. The early consumers can make a rational inference from the firm's price about its cost and quality taking into account the firm's profit incentive from the later informed consumers. We find that in equilibrium a more cost-efficient firm chooses higher quality than does an inefficient firm. One might intuit that a firm will offer higher quality if its high efficiency is known to consumers than if its efficiency is not known, because it will no longer need to convince consumers that it is not the inefficient firm. Our analysis shows that, surprisingly, the opposite may be true-when a firm's high efficiency is publicly known, the firm may reduce its product quality rather than increase it. Furthermore, consumers' knowledge about the firm's cost efficiency can reduce the consumer surplus. We also show that an improvement in the average cost efficiency in the market can lower the consumer surplus.</description><author>Jiang, Baojun; Yang, Bicheng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Coupons Expand or Cannibalize Revenue? Evidence from an e-Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reimers, Mike; Xie, Claire
Coupons have been a mainstay of marketing for decades all over the world, but their short- and long-run effects on sales are still not understood fully. We develop a model of consumer demand to empirically study whether firms can indeed use coupons as a means to price discriminate by attracting new consumers without losing (cannibalizing) revenue from existing ones, and whether these new consumers return to the firm after the price promotion. In addition, we ask what types of businesses are most likely to benefit from such promotions. Following alcohol revenue for restaurants using e-coupons, we find that offering a coupon increases demand during the promotion, and to a lesser degree after the promotion, suggesting that coupons can be used to price discriminate, while an advertising effect is less obvious. While coupons increase profits on average, the effect on each firm's profits depends on the firm's characteristics.</description><author>Reimers, Mike; Xie, Claire</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private Ownership and the Cost of Public Debt: Evidence from the Bond Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Badertscher, Brad A.; Givoly, Dan; Katz, Sharon P.; Lee, Hanna
A number of studies have examined the effect of public and private ownership on the cost of debt and concluded that the cost of debt of privately owned firms is higher, driven mainly by the poorer information environment in which these firms operate. We extend this strand of research in two ways. First, we identify and empirically establish the mechanisms that bring about a higher cost of debt to privately owned firms-namely, the limited access that these firms have to the equity capital market, their high rate of management and private-equity ownership, and their less conservative reporting. Second, we improve the reliability of the estimates of the effect of ownership type on the cost of debt by controlling for the different information environments in which privately and publicly owned firms operate. This is accomplished through the use of a sample consisting of publicly owned and privately owned firms that have public debt and are therefore subject to identical reporting and disclosure requirements. Certain data and design features allow us to better control for other factors that might lead to the observed difference in the cost of debt between the two groups of firms. The results contribute to our understanding of the role of ownership type on the cost of capital.</description><author>Badertscher, Brad A.; Givoly, Dan; Katz, Sharon P.; Lee, Hanna</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Motivating User-Generated Content with Performance Feedback: Evidence from Randomized Field Experiments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Ni; Burtch, Gordon; Gu, Bin; Hong, Yili; Liang, Chen; Wang, Kanliang; Fu, Dongpu; Yang, Bo
We design a series of online performance feedback interventions that aim to motivate the production of user-generated content (UGC). Drawing on social value orientation (SVO) theory, we develop a novel set of alternative feedback message framings, aligned with cooperation (e.g., your content benefited others), individualism (e.g., your content was of high quality), and competition (e.g., your content was better than others). We hypothesize how gender (a proxy for SVO) moderates response to each framing, and we report on two randomized experiments, one in partnership with a mobile-app-based recipe crowdsourcing platform, and a follow-up experiment on Amazon Mechanical Turk involving an ideation task. We find evidence that cooperatively framed feedback is most effective for motivating female subjects, whereas competitively framed feedback is most effective at motivating male subjects. Our work contributes to the literatures on performance feedback and UGC production by introducing cooperative performance feedback as a theoretically motivated, novel intervention that speaks directly to user's altruistic intent in a variety of task settings. Our work also contributes to the message-framing literature in considering competition as a novel addition to the altruism-egoism dichotomy oft explored in public good settings.</description><author>Huang, Ni; Burtch, Gordon; Gu, Bin; Hong, Yili; Liang, Chen; Wang, Kanliang; Fu, Dongpu; Yang, Bo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The ABCs of Financial Education: Experimental Evidence on Attitudes, Behavior, and Cognitive Biases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carpena, Fenella; Cole, Shawn; Shapiro, Jeremy; Zia, Bilal
This paper uses a large-scale field experiment in India to study attitudinal, behavioral, and cognitive constraints that can stymie the link between financial education and financial outcomes. The study complements financial education with (i) financial incentives on a financial literacy test to affect participant motivation, (ii) financial goal setting to provide a psychological nudge, and (iii) personalized financial counseling to enhance the intensity of treatment. The analysis finds no impact of financial incentives on learning but significant effects of both goal setting and counseling on real financial outcomes. These results identify important complements to financial education that can bridge the gap between financial knowledge and behavior change.</description><author>Carpena, Fenella; Cole, Shawn; Shapiro, Jeremy; Zia, Bilal</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical Investigation of an Equity Pairs Trading Strategy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Huafeng; Chen, Shaojun; Chen, Zhuo; Li, Feng
We show that an equity pairs trading strategy generates large and significant abnormal returns. We find that two components of the trading signal (i.e., short-term reversal and pairs momentum) have different dynamic and cross-sectional properties. The pairs momentum is largely explained by the one-month version of the industry momentum. Therefore, the pairs trading profits are largely explained by the short-term reversal and a version of the industry momentum.</description><author>Chen, Huafeng; Chen, Shaojun; Chen, Zhuo; Li, Feng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Final Demand for Structured Finance Securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Merrill, Craig B.; Nadauld, Taylor D.; Strahan, Philip E.
Structured finance boomed during the run-up to the 2008 financial crisis. Highly rated, structured securities offered higher yield than other similarly rated bonds because of their concentration of systematic risk, but regulatory capital requirements did not account for this risk. As a result, regulated entities facing capital constraints had an incentive to invest in them. We show that life insurance companies exposed to unrealized losses from low interest rates in the early 2000s increased their holdings of highly rated securitized assets, consistent with regulatory arbitrage distorting the demand to hold these assets.</description><author>Merrill, Craig B.; Nadauld, Taylor D.; Strahan, Philip E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wage Elasticities in Working and Volunteering: The Role of Reference Points in a Laboratory Study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Exley, Christine L.; Terry, Stephen J.
We experimentally test how effort responds to wages-randomly assigned to accrue to individuals or to a charity-in the presence of expectations-based reference points or targets. When individuals earn money for themselves, higher wages lead to higher effort with relatively muted targeting behavior. When individuals earn money for a charity, higher wages instead lead to lower effort with substantial targeting behavior. A reference-dependent theoretical framework suggests an explanation for this differential impact: when individuals place less value on earnings, such as when accruing earnings for a charity instead of themselves, more targeting behavior and a more sluggish response to incentives should result. Results from an additional experiment add support to this explanation. When individuals select into earning money for a charity and thus likely place a higher value on those earnings, targeting behavior is muted and no longer generates a negative effort response to higher wages.</description><author>Exley, Christine L.; Terry, Stephen J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Truth Telling Under Oath</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacguemet, Nicolas; Luchini, Stephane; Rosaz, Julie; Shogren, Jason F.
Oath taking for senior executives has been promoted as a means to enhance honesty within and toward organizations. Herein we explore whether people who voluntarily sign a solemn truth-telling oath are more committed to sincere behavior when offered the chance to lie. We design an experiment to test how the oath affects truth telling in two contexts: a neutral context replicating the typical experiment in the literature, and a "loaded" context in which we remind subjects that "a lie is a lie." We consider four payoff configurations, with differential monetary incentives to lie, implemented as within-subjects treatment variables. The results are reinforced by robustness investigations in which each subject made only one lying decision. Our results show that the oath reduces lying, especially in the loaded environment-falsehoods are reduced by 50%. The oath, however, has a weaker effect on lying in the neutral environment. The oath did affect decision times in all instances: the average person takes significantly more time deciding whether to lie under oath.</description><author>Jacguemet, Nicolas; Luchini, Stephane; Rosaz, Julie; Shogren, Jason F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Connections Within Executive Teams and Management Forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ke, Ruihao; Li, Meng; Ling, Zhejia; Zhang, Yuan
We examine the role of teamwork within the top executive teams in generating management forecasts. Using social connections within the executive team to capture the team's interaction, cooperation, and teamwork, we find that social connections among team members are associated with higher management forecast accuracy, consistent with economic theories that information is dispersed within a firm and with sociology insights that social connections facilitate information sharing. Further analyses show that the association between social connections and forecast accuracy is stronger when the teams are just beginning to work together, when their firms face more uncertainty or adversity, and when the CEOs are less powerful. Our results hold for a subsample of executive teams that experience pseudo exogenous shocks to their social connectedness. Taken together, our results underscore the importance of teamwork among executives in the forecast generation process.</description><author>Ke, Ruihao; Li, Meng; Ling, Zhejia; Zhang, Yuan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option Prices in a Model with Stochastic Disaster Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Seo, Sang Byung; Wachter, Jessica A.
Contrary to well-known asset pricing models, volatilities implied by equity index options exceed realized stock market volatility and exhibit a pattern known as the volatility skew. We explain both facts using a model that can also account for the mean and volatility of equity returns. Our model assumes a small risk of economic disaster that is calibrated based on international data on large consumption declines. We allow the disaster probability to be stochastic, which turns out to be crucial to the model's ability both to match equity volatility and to reconcile option prices with macroeconomic data on disasters.</description><author>Seo, Sang Byung; Wachter, Jessica A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Private Information Settles the Bill: Money and Privacy in Google's Market for Smartphone Applications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kummer, Michael; Schulte, Patrick
We shed light on a money-for-privacy trade-off in the market for smartphone applications ("apps"). Developers offer their apps at lower prices in return for greater access to personal information, and consumers choose between low prices and more privacy. We provide evidence for this pattern using data from 300,000 apps obtained from the Google Play Store (formerly Android Market) in 2012 and 2014. Our findings show that the market's supply and demand sides both consider an app's ability to collect private information, measured by the apps's use of privacy-sensitive permissions: (1) cheaper apps use more privacy-sensitive permissions; (2) given price and functionality, demand is lower for apps with sensitive permissions; and (3) the strength of this relationship depends on contextual factors, such as the targeted user group, the app's previous success, and its category. Our results are robust and consistent across several robustness checks, including the use of panel data, a difference-in-differences analysis, "twin" pairs of apps, and various measures of privacy-sensitivity and app demand.</description><author>Kummer, Michael; Schulte, Patrick</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When You Work with a Superman, Will You Also Fly? An Empirical Study of the Impact of Coworkers on Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tan, Tom Fangyun; Netessine, Serguei
We examine a large operational data set in a casual restaurant setting to study how coworkers' sales ability level affects other workers' sales performance. We find that waiters react nonlinearly to their coworkers' ability. In particular, when coworkers' overall sales ability is low, increasing this ability may prompt waiters to redouble both upselling and cross-selling efforts. When overall coworkers' ability is high, however, further increasing their ability may trigger waiters to reduce sales efforts. Our empirical findings imply that, to maximize sales, managers should mix waiters with heterogeneous ability levels during the same shift. Through a counterfactual analysis, we find that considering the inverted U-shaped peer effects when optimizing current waiters' schedules without changing their utilization may increase total sales by approximately 2.48% at no extra cost.</description><author>Tan, Tom Fangyun; Netessine, Serguei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Buyer Uncertainty About Seller Capacity: Causes, Consequences, and a Partial Solution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Horton, John J.
Employers in an online labor market often pursue workers with little capacity to take on more work. The pursuit of low-capacity workers is consequential, as these workers are more likely to reject employer inquires, causing a reduction in the probability that a job opening is ultimately filled. In an attempt to shift more employer attention to workers with greater capacity, the market-designing platform examined in this paper introduced a new signaling feature into the market. It was effective, in that when a worker signaled having high capacity, he or she received more invitations from employers, rejected a smaller fraction of those invitations, quoted lower prices to do the work, and was more likely to be hired. A back-of-the-envelope calculation suggests the signaling feature alone could increase market surplus by as much as 6%, both by increasing the number of matches formed and by helping to allocate projects to workers with lower costs.</description><author>Horton, John J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Term Structures of Coentropy in International Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chabi-Yo, Fousseni; Colacito, Riccardo
We propose a new entropy-based correlation measure (coentropy) to evaluate the performance of international asset pricing models. Coentropy captures the codependence of two random variables beyond normality. We document that the coentropy of international stochastic discount factors (SDFs) can be decomposed into a series of entropy-based correlations of permanent and transitory components of the SDFs. We employ the cross section of G-10 countries to obtain model-free estimates of all the components of coentropy at various horizons and we show that the generalization of the long-run risk model featuring two predictable components of consumption growth rates, global disasters, and recursive preferences can account for the composition of codependence at all horizons.</description><author>Chabi-Yo, Fousseni; Colacito, Riccardo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Group Affiliation and Default Prediction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beaver, William H.; Cascino, Stefano; Correia, Maria; McNichols, Maureen F.
Using a large sample of business groups from more than 100 countries around the world, we show that group information matters for parent and subsidiary default prediction. Group firms may support each other when in financial distress. Potential group support represents an off-balance sheet asset for the receiving firm and an off-balance sheet liability for the firm offering support. We find that subsidiary information improves parent default prediction over and above group-level consolidated information possibly because intragroup exposures are netted out upon consolidation. Moreover, we document that improvements in parent default prediction decrease in the extent of parent-country financial reporting transparency, a finding that suggests that within-group information matters most when consolidated financial statements are expected to be of lower quality. We also show that parent and other group-firms' default risk exhibits predictive power for subsidiary default. Lastly, we find that within-group information explains cross-sectional variation in CDS spreads. Taken together, our findings contribute to the prior literature on default prediction and have direct relevance to investors, credit-rating agencies, and accounting regulators.</description><author>Beaver, William H.; Cascino, Stefano; Correia, Maria; McNichols, Maureen F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic Risks and Asset Pricing: Evidence from a Dynamic Stochastic General Equilibrium Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Erica X. N.; Li, Haitao; Wang, Shujing; Yu, Cindy
We study the relation between macroeconomic fundamentals and asset pricing through the lens of a dynamic stochastic general equilibrium (DSGE) model. We provide full-information Bayesian estimation of the DSGE model using macroeconomic variables and extract the time series of four latent fundamental shocks of the model: neutral technology shock, investment-specific technological shock, monetary policy shock, and risk shock. Asset pricing tests show that our model-implied four-factor model can explain a number of prominent cross-sectional return spreads: size, book-to-market, investment, earnings, and long-term reversal. The investment-specific technological shock and risk shock play the most important role in explaining those return spreads.</description><author>Li, Erica X. N.; Li, Haitao; Wang, Shujing; Yu, Cindy</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Search Among Queues Under Quality Differentiation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Luyi; Debo, Laurens G.; Gupta, Varun
Customers looking for service providers often face search frictions and have to trade off quality and availability. To understand customers' search behavior when they are confronted with a large collection of vertically differentiated, congested service providers, we build a model in which arriving customers conduct a costly sequential search to resolve uncertainty about service providers' quality and queue length and select one to join by optimal stopping rules. Customers search, in part, because of variations in waiting time across service providers, which, in turn, is determined by the search behavior of customers. Thus, an equilibrium emerges. We characterize customers' equilibrium search/join behavior in a mean field model as the number of service providers grows large. We find that reducing either the search cost or customer arrival rate may increase the average waiting time in the system as customers substitute toward high-quality service providers. Moreover, with lower search costs, the improved quality obtained by customers may not make up for the prolonged wait, therefore degrading the average search reward and, more importantly, decreasing customer welfare; when customers search, their welfare can even be lower than if they are not allowed to search at all.</description><author>Yang, Luyi; Debo, Laurens G.; Gupta, Varun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Sharing and Spillovers: Evidence from Financial Analysts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hwang, Byoung-Hyoun; Liberti, Jose Maria; Sturgess, Jason
We study how information sharing within an organization affects individual performance. We look at situations in which the same analyst, while working at the same broker, covers multiple mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;As), in particular the acquirer prior to the M&amp;A and the merged firm thereafter. We find that earnings forecasts for the merged firm are significantly more accurate when the analyst has a colleague (working at the same broker) covering the target prior to the M&amp;A. This holds particularly true if acquirer analysts and target analysts reside in the same locale, if they are part of a smaller team, and if the target analyst is of higher quality. Our findings highlight the importance of information spillovers on individual performance in knowledge-based industries.</description><author>Hwang, Byoung-Hyoun; Liberti, Jose Maria; Sturgess, Jason</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Financial Covenants in Private Loan Contracts on Classification Shifting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fan, Yun; Thomas, Wayne B.; Yu, Xiaoou
This study examines whether firms with private loan contracts that contain debt covenants based on earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation, and amortization (EBITDA) are more likely to misclassify core expenses as special items (i.e., classification shift). Misclassifying core expenses as income-decreasing special items allows the firm to increase EBITDA and thereby potentially avoid debt covenant violations. Consistent with our expectation, firms misclassify core expenses as special items when at least one EBITDA-related financial covenant is close to being violated. In addition, classification shifting is more prominent when financially distressed firms are close to violating at least one EBITDA-related covenant. Whereas prior research on classification shifting focuses primarily on equity market incentives (e.g., meeting analysts' earnings forecasts), our study extends this research to private loan contracts to highlight that creditors also affect classification shifting. Classification shifting appears to be an additional earnings management technique used by managers to avoid debt covenant violations.</description><author>Fan, Yun; Thomas, Wayne B.; Yu, Xiaoou</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Socially Beneficial Rationality: The Value of Strategic Farmers, Social Entrepreneurs, anti For-Profit Firms in Crop Planting Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Ming; Liu, Yan; Wang, Wenbin
The price fluctuation in agricultural markets is an obstacle to poverty reduction for small-scale farmers in developing countries. We build a microfoundation to study how farmers with heterogeneous production costs, under price fluctuations, make crop-planting decisions over time to maximize their individual welfare. We consider both strategic farmers, who rationally anticipate the near-future price as a basis for making planting decisions, and naive farmers, who shortsightedly react to the most recent crop price. The latter behavior may cause recurring overproduction or underproduction, which leads to price fluctuations. We find it important to cultivate a sufficient number of strategic farmers because their self-interested behavior alone, made possible by sufficient market information, can reduce price volatility and improve total social welfare. In the absence of strategic farmers, a well-designed preseason buyout contract, offered by a social entrepreneur or a for-profit firm to a fraction of contract farmers, brings benefit to farmers as well as to the firm itself. More strikingly, the contract not only equalizes the individual welfare in the long run among farmers of the same production cost, but it also reduces individual welfare disparity over time among farmers with heterogeneous costs regardless of whether they are contract farmers or not. On the other hand, a nonsocially optimal buyout contract may reflect a social entrepreneur's over-subsidy tendency or a for-profit firm's speculative incentive to mitigate but not eliminate the market price fluctuation, both preventing farmers from achieving the most welfare.</description><author>Hu, Ming; Liu, Yan; Wang, Wenbin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interbank Networks and Backdoor Bailouts: Benefiting from Other Banks' Government Guarantees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eisert, Tim; Eufinger, Christian
This paper explains why banks derive a benefit from being highly interconnected. We show that when banks are protected by government guarantees, they can significantly increase their expected returns by channeling funds through the interbank market before these funds are invested in real assets. If banks that are protected by implicit or explicit government guarantees act as intermediaries between other banks and real investments, there is the possibility that these intermediary banks will be rescued by their governments if the real assets fail. This additional hedge increases the likelihood that banks and their creditors are repaid relative to a direct investment in those same real assets. We show that this incentive to exploit the government guarantees of other banks leads to long intermediation chains and a degree of interconnectedness that is above the welfare-optimal level, which justifies regulatory intervention.</description><author>Eisert, Tim; Eufinger, Christian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling Municipal Yields With (and Without) Bond Insurance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chun, Albert Lee; Namvar, Ethan; Ye, Xiaoxia; Yu, Fan
We develop an intensity-based model of municipal yields, making simultaneous use of the credit default swap premiums of the insurers and both insured and uninsured municipal bond transactions. We estimate the model individually for 61 municipal issuers by exploiting the dramatic decline in credit quality of the bond insurers from July 2007 to June 2008, and decompose the municipal yield spread based on the estimated parameters. The decomposition reveals a dominant role of the liquidity component as well as interactions between liquidity and default similar to those modeled by Chen et al. [Chen H, Cui R, He Z, Milbradt K (2018) Quantifying liquidity and default risks of corporate bonds over the business cycle. Rev. Financial Stud. 31(3):852-897.] for corporate bonds. Toward the end of the sample period, our model also reproduces the "yield inversion" phenomenon documented in the literature.</description><author>Chun, Albert Lee; Namvar, Ethan; Ye, Xiaoxia; Yu, Fan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What You Don't Know...Can't Hurt You? A Natural Field Experiment on Relative Performance Feedback in Higher Education</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Azmat, Ghazala; Bagues, Manuel; Cabrales, Antonio; Iriberri, Nagore
This paper studies the effect of providing feedback to college students on their position in the grade distribution by using a natural field experiment. This information was updated every six months during a three-year period. We find that greater grades transparency decreases educational performance, as measured by the number of examinations passed and grade point average (GPA). However, self-reported satisfaction, as measured by surveys conducted after feedback is provided but before students take their examinations, increases. We provide a theoretical framework to understand these results, focusing on the role of prior beliefs and using out-of-trial surveys to test the model. In the absence of treatment, a majority of students underestimate their position in the grade distribution, suggesting that the updated information is "good news" for many students. Moreover, the negative effect on performance is driven by those students who underestimate their position in the absence of feedback. Students who overestimate initially their position, if anything, respond positively. The performance effects are short lived-by the time students graduate, they have similar accumulated GPA and graduation rates.</description><author>Azmat, Ghazala; Bagues, Manuel; Cabrales, Antonio; Iriberri, Nagore</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When and How to Diversify-A Multicategory Utility Model for Personalized Content Recommendation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Song, Yicheng; Sahoo, Nachiketa; Ofek, Elie
Sometimes we desire change, a break from the same, or an opportunity to fulfill different aspects of our needs. Noting that consumers seek variety, several approaches have been developed to diversify items recommended by personalized recommender systems. However, current diversification strategies operate under a one-shot paradigm without considering the evolution of preferences resulting from recent consumption. Therefore, such methods often sacrifice accuracy. In the context of online media, we show that by recognizing that consumption in a session is the result of a sequence of utility-maximizing selections from various categories, one can increase recommendation accuracy by dynamically tailoring the diversity of suggested items to the diversity sought by the consumer. Our approach is based on a multicategory utility model that captures a consumer's preference for different categories of content, how quickly the consumer satiates with one category and wishes to substitute it with another, and how the consumer trades off costly search efforts with selecting from a recommended list to discover new content. Taken together, these three elements allow us to characterize how an individual selects a diverse set of items to consume over the course of a session and how likely the individual is to click on recommended content. We estimate the model using a clickstream data set from a large media outlet and apply it to determine the most relevant content to recommend at different stages of an online session. We find that our approach generates recommendations that are on average about 10% more accurate than optimized alternatives and about 25% more accurate than those diversified using existing diversification strategies. Moreover, the proposed method recommends content with diversity that more closely matches the diversity sought by readers, exhibiting lower concentration-diversification bias than other personalized recommender systems. Using a policy simulation, we estimate that recommending content using the proposed approach would result in visitors reading 23% additional articles at the studied website and deriving 35% higher utility. This could lead to immediate gains in revenue for the publisher and longer-term improvements in customer satisfaction and retention at the site.</description><author>Song, Yicheng; Sahoo, Nachiketa; Ofek, Elie</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Benefits When Prescription Drug Manufacturers Offer Copay Coupons?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>King, Gregory J.; Chao, Xiuli; Duenyas, Izak
The rising cost of prescription drugs is a concern in the United States. To manage drug costs, insurance companies induce patients to choose less-expensive medications by making them pay higher copayments for more-expensive drugs, especially when multiple drug options are available to treat a condition. However, drug manufacturers have responded by offering copay coupons-coupons intended to be used by those already with prescription drug coverage. Recent empirical work has shown that such coupons significantly increase insurer costs without much benefit to patients, who incur lower out-of-pocket expenses with coupons but may eventually see higher costs passed to them. As a result, there is pressure from the insurance industry and consumer advocacy groups to ban copay coupons. In this paper we analyze how copay coupons affect patients, insurance companies, and drug manufacturers, while addressing the question of whether insurance companies would in fact always benefit from a copay coupon ban. We find that copay coupons tend to benefit drug manufacturers with large profit margins relative to other manufacturers, while generally, but not always, benefiting patients; insurer costs tend to increase with coupons from high-price drug manufacturers and decrease with coupons from low-price manufacturers. Although often helping drug manufacturers and increasing insurer costs, we also identify situations in which copay coupons benefit both patients and insurers. Thus, a blanket ban on copay coupons would not necessarily benefit insurance companies. In addition to the policy implications of our work, we make concrete managerial recommendations to insurers. We discuss how they should set formulary selection policies taking into account the fact that drug manufacturers may offer coupons; and we suggest how they can benefit from subsidizing coupons from drug manufacturers with low-price drugs, or from having drug manufacturers compete on price, to receive a favorable formulary position (i.e., copay).</description><author>King, Gregory J.; Chao, Xiuli; Duenyas, Izak</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Product Preannouncement: Phantom Products and the Osborne Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rao, Ram; Turut, Ozge
The mere preannouncement of a new product can affect consumer choice, thus complicating preannouncement strategy. This is because a preannounced product that is unavailable immediately can still be one of the alternatives in a consumer's mind at the time of choice. Such unavailable products, also known as phantom products, influence the reference point that consumers compare alternatives to when making a choice, as has been widely demonstrated in experimental studies. Thus, in addition to encouraging consumers to postpone purchase in favor of a future product, preannouncement also changes their preference for the currently available products when consumers do not prefer to postpone. In this paper we explore preannouncement strategy by analyzing a model that incorporates the effect of new product preannouncement (NPP) on consumer preferences and compare the results with a benchmark case in which consumer preferences across the existing products are not influenced by preannouncement. We find that when we take into account the effect of NPP on consumer preferences across the existing products, although postponement of purchase by some consumers remains beneficial, the preference for the current product offering with a lower quality can suffer so much that the significant lowering of current profits is not offset by future gains. Thus, preannouncement may no longer be the optimal strategy for the firm with a lower-quality product, which in turn explains the "Osborne effect." Our results also challenge the conventional wisdom in new product preannouncement literature.</description><author>Rao, Ram; Turut, Ozge</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting Risk Perception: New Insights from Data Science</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhatia, Sudeep
We outline computational techniques for predicting perceptions of risk. Our approach uses the structure of word distribution in natural language data to uncover rich representations for a very large set of naturalistic risk sources. With the application of standard machine learning techniques, we are able to accurately map these representations onto participant risk ratings. Unlike existing methods in risk perception research, our approach does not require any specialized participant data and is capable of generalizing its learned mappings to make quantitative predictions for novel (out-of-sample) risks. Our approach is also able to quantify the strength of association between risk sources and a very large set of words and concepts and, thus, can be used to identify the cognitive and affective factors with the strongest relationship with risk perception and behavior.</description><author>Bhatia, Sudeep</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Alternative Approaches to Comparative nth-Degree Risk Aversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Liqun; Neilson, William S.
This paper extends the three main approaches to comparative risk aversion-the risk premium approach and the probability premium approach of Pratt (1964) [Risk aversion in the small and in the large. Econometrica 32(1-2):122-136] and the comparative statics approach of Jindapon and Neilson (2007) [Higher-order generalizations of Arrow-Pratt and Ross risk aversion: A comparative statics approach. J. Econom. Theory 136(1):719-728]-to study comparative nth-degree risk aversion. These extensions can accommodate trading off an nth-degree risk increase and an nth-degree risk increase for any m, such that 1 &lt;= m &lt; n. It goes on to show that, in the expected utility framework, all of these general notions of comparative nth-degree risk aversion are equivalent and can be characterized by the concept of (n/m)th-degree Ross more risk aversion of Liu and Meyer (2013) [Substituting one risk increase for another: A method for measuring risk aversion.</description><author>Liu, Liqun; Neilson, William S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Price Dispersion Changes When Upgrades Are Introduced: Theory and Empirical Evidence from the Airline Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cui, Yao; Orhun, A. Yesim; Duenyas, Izak
This paper studies the effect of introducing a new vertical differentiation strategy, paying for an upgrade to a premium product after purchasing the base product, on the price dispersion of the base product arising from existing price discrimination strategies. In particular, we examine how a major U.S. airline's price dispersion in the coach cabin changes after introducing the option to upgrade to a new type of premium economy seating within the coach cabin. We first provide a theoretical analysis that highlights two competing pressures that the new premium economy seating upgrades created on coach class prices. On the one hand, the airline benefits from lowering its prices because by allowing more customers to purchase in the first place, it increases the probability of selling upgrades (admission effect). On the other hand, for some customers, the value of flying with the airline increases because of the upgrade availability, therefore the airline may find it optimal to increase its prices (valuation effect). In the second part of the paper, we conduct an empirical investigation of the impact of upgrade introduction on coach class prices, based on a proprietary transaction-level data set from a major U.S. airline company. The empirical analysis tests the main predictions of our theoretical model and examines further nuances. The results show that the introduction of the premium economy seating upgrades is associated with an increase in the price dispersion and revenues in the coach class, the admission effect is stronger than the valuation effect on the low end of the price distribution, and the opposite is true on the high end of the price distribution. Finally, we discuss implications of our results for firm revenues and consumer welfare.</description><author>Cui, Yao; Orhun, A. Yesim; Duenyas, Izak</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Decision Making in Sequential Business-to-Business Auctions: A Structural Econometric Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lu, Yixin; Gupta, Alok; Keller, Wolfgang; van Heck, Eric
We develop a dynamic structural model of competitive bidding in multiunit sequential business-to-business auctions. Our model accounts for two notable characteristics of these auctions: (i) bidders have multiple purchase opportunities for the same product, and (ii) winning bidders in each round can acquire multiple units of the same product. We apply the model to bidding data from the world's largest flower wholesale market at which trades are facilitated through fast-paced, sequential, Dutch auctions. Using a two-step estimation approach, we are able to recover the structural parameters effectively and efficiently. We then conduct policy counterfactuals to evaluate the performance of alternative design choices. The results suggest that the current auction practice still has ample room for improvement. In light of this, we propose an optimization framework that can facilitate auctioneers' decisions in making the trade-off between revenue maximization and operational efficiency.</description><author>Lu, Yixin; Gupta, Alok; Keller, Wolfgang; van Heck, Eric</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hidden Persuaders: Do Small Gifts Lubricate Business Negotiations?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marechal, Michel Andre; Thoeni, Christian
Gift-giving customs are ubiquitous in social, political, and business life. Legal regulation and industry guidelines for gifts are often based on the assumption that large gifts potentially influence behavior and create conflicts of interest, but small gifts do not. However, scientific evidence on the impact of small gifts on business relationships is scarce. We conducted a natural field experiment in collaboration with sales agents of a multinational consumer products company to study the influence of small gifts on the outcome of business negotiations. We find that small gifts matter. On average, sales representatives generate more than twice as much revenue when they distribute a small gift at the onset of their negotiations. However, we also find that small gifts tend to be counterproductive when purchasing and sales agents meet for the first time, suggesting that the nature of the business relationship crucially affects the profitability of gifts.</description><author>Marechal, Michel Andre; Thoeni, Christian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Moral Perceptions of Advised Actions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coffman, Lucas C.; Gotthard-Real, Alexander
Can an organization avoid blame for an unpopular action when an adviser advises it to do it? We present experimental evidence suggesting this is the case-advice to be selfish substantially decreases punishment of being selfish. Further, this result is true despite advisers' misaligned incentives, known to all: Through a relational contract incentive, advisers are motivated to tell the decision makers what they want to hear. Through incentivized elicitations, we find suggestive evidence that advice moves punishment by affecting beliefs of how necessary the selfish action was. In follow-up treatments, however, we show advice does not decrease punishment solely through a beliefs channel. Advice not only changes beliefs about what happened, but also the perceived morality of it. Finally, in treatments in which advisers are available, the data suggest selfish decision makers act more selfishly.</description><author>Coffman, Lucas C.; Gotthard-Real, Alexander</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash Hedging in a Supply Chain</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kouvelis, Panos; Wu, Xiaole; Xiao, Yixuan
We study hedging cash-flow risks in a supply chain where firms invest internal funds to improve production efficiencies. We offer a decomposition framework to capture the cost-reduction and flexibility effect of hedging. It allows us to understand how a firm's hedging choice depends on its supply chain partner's decision, and how such interaction is affected by supply chain characteristics such as market size, cash-flow volatility, and correlation. When firms' cash flows are independent of each other, they are more likely to hedge with a larger market size. When cash flows are correlated, the impact of market size and volatility on firms' hedging decisions presents multiple patterns, contingent on whether their risks amplify or offset each other.</description><author>Kouvelis, Panos; Wu, Xiaole; Xiao, Yixuan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of Commitments When Selling to Strategic Consumers: A Supply Chain Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kabul, Mustafa O.; Parlakturk, All K.
We consider a decentralized supply chain consisting of a retailer and a supplier that serves forward-looking consumers in two periods. In each period, the supplier and the retailer dynamically set the wholesale and retail price to maximize their own profits. The consumers are heterogeneous in their evaluations of the product and are strategic in deciding whether and when to buy the product, choosing the option that maximizes their utility, including waiting for a price markdown. We derive the equilibrium and study the value of price and quantity commitments from both the retailer's and the supplier's perspectives. We find that, although a centralized system always benefits from making price and quantity commitments, this is not true for a firm in a decentralized supply chain due to how the other firm responds to these commitments. We show that the retailer suffers from making a price or quantity commitment and that, similarly, the supplier does not benefit from making a price commitment. In these cases, commitments can harm not only the firm itself but also profitability of the other firm in the supply chain, thereby disadvantaging the entire supply chain. This happens because such commitments aggravate double-marginalization inefficiency in the supply chain. Furthermore, we show that eliminating this inefficiency through a coordinating contract (e.g., a two-part tariff or quantity discount) makes commitments beneficial.</description><author>Kabul, Mustafa O.; Parlakturk, All K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Malleable Lies: Communication and Cooperation in a High Stakes TV Game Show</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Turmunkh, Uyanga; van den Assem, Martijn J.; van Dolder, Dennie
We investigate the credibility of nonbinding preplay statements about cooperative behavior, using data from a high-stakes TV game show in which contestants play a variant on the classic Prisoner's Dilemma. We depart from the conventional binary approach of classifying statements as promises or not, and propose a more fine-grained two-by-two typology inspired by the idea that lying aversion leads defectors to prefer statements that are malleable to ex-post interpretation as truths. Our empirical analysis shows that statements that carry an element of conditionality or implicitness are associated with a lower likelihood of cooperation, and confirms that malleability is a good criterion for judging the credibility of cheap talk.</description><author>Turmunkh, Uyanga; van den Assem, Martijn J.; van Dolder, Dennie</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Price Fixing Benefit Corporate Managers?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gonzalez, Tanja Artiga; Schmid, Markus; Yermack, David
We study the effects of cartel participation on top corporate managers. Although a strong public interest exists in regulating price fixing, we find little evidence that either corporate governance or the legal system holds managers of cartel firms accountable. Instead, managers of cartel firms enjoy greater job security, receive higher cash bonuses, and more aggressively take profits from appreciated stock option awards. Legal sanctions against individual managers are infrequent, with enforcement actions focused on corporations rather than their officers. Managers seem to use concealment strategies actively to limit detection of cartel membership by their boards and auditors.</description><author>Gonzalez, Tanja Artiga; Schmid, Markus; Yermack, David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reexamining How Utility and Weighting Functions Get Their Shapes: A Quasi-Adversarial Collaboration Providing a New Interpretation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alempaki, Despoina; Canic, Emina; Mullett, Timothy L.; Skylark, William J.; Starmer, Chris; Stewart, Neil; Tufano, Fabio
In a paper published in Management Science in 2015, Stewart, Reimers, and Harris (SRH) demonstrated that shapes of utility and probability weighting functions could be manipulated by adjusting the distributions of outcomes and probabilities on offer as predicted by the theory of decision by sampling. So marked were these effects that, at face value, they profoundly challenge standard interpretations of preference theoretic models in which such functions are supposed to reflect stable properties of individual risk preferences. Motivated by this challenge, we report an extensive replication exercise based on a series of experiments conducted as a quasi-adversarial collaboration across different labs and involving researchers from both economics and psychology. We replicate the SRH effect across multiple experiments involving changes in many design features; importantly, however, we find that the effect is also present in designs modified so that decision by sampling predicts no effect. Although those results depend on model-based inferences, an alternative analysis using a model-free comparison approach finds no evidence of patterns akin to the SRH effect. On the basis of simulation exercises, we demonstrate that the SRH effect may be a consequence of misspecifkation biases arising in parameter recovery exercises that fit imperfectly specified choice models to experimental data. Overall, our analysis casts the SRH effect in an entirely new light.</description><author>Alempaki, Despoina; Canic, Emina; Mullett, Timothy L.; Skylark, William J.; Starmer, Chris; Stewart, Neil; Tufano, Fabio</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Data Analytics Supports Decentralized Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Lynn; Lou, Bowen; Hitt, Lorin
Data-analytics technology can accelerate the innovation process by enabling existing knowledge to be identified, accessed, combined, and deployed to address new problem domains. However, like prior advances in information technology, the ability of firms to exploit these opportunities depends on a variety of complementary human capital and organizational capabilities. We focus on whether analytics is more valuable in firms where innovation within a firm has decentralized groups of inventors or centralized ones. Our analysis draws on prior work measuring firm-analytics capability using detailed employee-level data and matches these data to metrics on intrafirm inventor networks that reveal whether a firm's innovation structure is centralized or decentralized. In a panel of 1,864 publicly traded firms from the years 1988-2013, we find that firms with a decentralized innovation structure have a greater demand for analytics skills and receive greater productivity benefits from their analytics capabilities, consistent with a complementarity between analytics and decentralized innovation. We also find that analytics helps decentralized structures to create new combinations and reuse of existing technologies, consistent with the ability of analytics to link knowledge across diverse domains and to integrate external knowledge into the firm. Furthermore, the effect primarily comes from the analytics capabilities of the noninventor employees as opposed to inventors themselves. These results show that the benefit of analytics on innovation depends on existing organizational structures. Similar to the IT-productivity paradox, these results can help explain a contemporary analytics-innovation paradox-the apparent slowdown in innovation despite the recent increase in analytics investments.</description><author>Wu, Lynn; Lou, Bowen; Hitt, Lorin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Penalties, Manipulation, and Investment Efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nan, Lin; Wen, Xiaoyan
In this study, we examine whether imposing a penalty based on an earlier positive signal and a bad realized outcome can be welfare-improving. We find that imposing a penalty helps to improve investment efficiency, but it also brings a deadweight cost of potential penalty for entrepreneurs with good projects. We show that when a good project has a much larger chance to achieve a good outcome than a bad project or when a large proportion of the penalty can be reimbursed to the investor, it is optimal to impose a penalty to deter entrepreneurs with bad projects from reporting positive signals to the greatest degree, as the benefit from reducing the investment inefficiency outweighs the expected deadweight cost. Otherwise, it is optimal not to impose any penalty. We also find that a larger penalty may induce more manipulation by a good entrepreneur. This is because, although a larger penalty directly discourages manipulation for both good and bad types by increasing the expected penalty cost, it also encourages upward manipulation by lowering the implicit financing cost upon a high signal. The encouraging effect is mostly pronounced for the good entrepreneur when the good entrepreneur has a much larger chance of success than the bad entrepreneur or when the reimbursement proportion is very high.</description><author>Nan, Lin; Wen, Xiaoyan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional Investors and Corporate Environmental, Social, and Governance Policies: Evidence from Toxics Release Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Incheol; Wan, Hong; Wang, Bin; Yang, Tina
This paper studies the role of institutional investors in influencing corporate environmental, social, and governance (ESG) policies by analyzing the relation between institutional ownership and toxic release from facilities to which institutions are geographically proximate. We develop a local preference hypothesis based on the delegated philanthropy and transaction-costs theories. Consistent with the hypothesis, local institutional ownership is negatively related to facility toxic release. The negative relation is stronger for local socially responsible investing (SRI) funds, local public pension funds, and local dedicated institutions. We also find that the relation is more negative in communities that prefer more stringent environmental policies and in communities of greater collective cohesiveness. Local institutional ownership, particularly local ownerships by SRI funds and public pension funds, is positively related to the probability that an ESG proposal is either introduced or withdrawn. The paper sheds light on the drivers behind institutions' ESG engagement and their effectiveness in influencing ESG.</description><author>Kim, Incheol; Wan, Hong; Wang, Bin; Yang, Tina</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A New Predictor of US Real Economic Activity: The S&amp;P 500 Option Implied Risk Aversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faccini, Renato; Konstantinidi, Eirini; Skiadopoulos, George; Sarantopoulou-Chiourea, Sylvia
We propose a new predictor of U.S. real economic activity (REA)-namely, the representative investor's implied relative risk aversion (IRRA) extracted from S&amp;P 500 option prices. IRRA is forward-looking and hence is expected to be related to future economic conditions. We document that U.S. IRRA predicts U.S. REA both in- and out-of-sample once we control for well-known REA predictors and take into account their persistence. An increase (decrease) in IRRA predicts a decrease (increase) in REA. We extend the empirical analysis by extracting IRRA from the South Korean, UK, Japanese, and German index option markets. We find that South Korea IRRA predicts the South Korea REA both in- and out-of-sample, as expected given the high liquidity of its index option market. We show that a parsimonious yet flexible production economy model calibrated to the U.S. economy can explain the documented negative relation between risk aversion and future economic growth.</description><author>Faccini, Renato; Konstantinidi, Eirini; Skiadopoulos, George; Sarantopoulou-Chiourea, Sylvia</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the Social Learning Effect in Contagious Switching Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Mandy Mantian; Yang, Sha; Xu, Daniel Yi
We study the contagious switching behavior related to a consumer's choice of wireless carriers, that is, that a consumer is more likely to switch wireless carriers if more of their contacts from the same carrier have switched. Contagious switching (or a positive network effect) can be driven by information-based social learning, as well as other mechanisms related to network size. Although previous marketing literature has documented the social-learning effect, most of the applications studied involve products in which consumers usually do not enjoy any direct benefits from a large network other than from information-based social learning. We explore the importance of the social-learning effect relative to other mechanisms that may also lead to the network effect. We propose a dynamic structural model with interpersonal interactions. To model the social-learning effect, a consumer uses feedback from his or her contacts who have switched from a focal carrier to update his or her quality expectations of alternative carriers. Our model further accounts for two unique aspects of consumer strategic learning: (i) the individual's perception on the signal of alternative carriers from contacts who switch is systematically different according to whether the signal comes from a loyal contact; and (ii) that the perceived noisiness of the signal on alternative carriers from a contact who has switched depends on the strength of the relationship between the individual and the contact. The remaining network effect not captured through social learning is modeled as a function of the size of the network. We solve the model with a two-step dynamic programming algorithm, with the assumption that a consumer is forward-looking and decides whether to stay with the same service carrier in each period by maximizing the total utility received from that day onward. We apply the proposed model to the data set of a mobile network operator in a European country. We find that churning/switching behavior is contagious in the network context and that one-third of general network effects can be attributed to social learning. We also detect strategic learning by consumers from their contacts in two ways: the experience signal on alternative carriers from a more loyal contact who has switched from the focal carrier is perceived to be more positive than that from a less loyal contact; and the social-learning effect is stronger from an individual's closest contacts. The simulation analysis demonstrates the value of our model in helping a company prioritize its customer relationship management effort.</description><author>Hu, Mandy Mantian; Yang, Sha; Xu, Daniel Yi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Manufacturers' Competition and Cooperation in Sustainability: Stable Recycling Alliances</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tian, Fang; Sosic, Greys; Debo, Laurens
Rather than organizing disposal of consumer-generated waste themselves, many states and countries have passed legislation that makes producers responsible for the proper disposal (i.e., recycling) of the products that they bring to the market. We study the stability of producers' strategies emerging under such legislation. In our paper, the producers compete with multiple differentiated products in consumer markets but may consider cooperating when recycling those products to benefit from economies of scale. Products made by different producers or sold in different markets might still be considered for joint recycling. Our main questions are when and whether firm-based recycling strategies (i.e., separately recycling products falling under same brand) or market-based recycling strategies (i.e., separately recycling products falling in the same product category) emerge as stable outcomes. To that end, we analyze a series of simple producer-market configurations. We first look at an asymmetric market model with two producers making three products in two markets, and then, we look at a symmetric market model with two producers competing with four products in two markets. Our results show that, with intense market competition and differentiated market sizes, producers may recycle their products on their own without cooperating with others. In some instances, they can add a product from their competitor to their recycling mix. Because these outcomes are never socially optimal, they may reduce social welfare and require government intervention. Otherwise, with less intense competition or more equitable market shares, all-inclusive (market-based) recycling is the most common stable outcome with high (low) scale economies, and the firms' independent choices might lead to social optima.</description><author>Tian, Fang; Sosic, Greys; Debo, Laurens</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Model of Customer Reward Programs with Finite Expiration Terms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Yacheng; Zhang, Dan
A little-understood phenomenon of customer reward programs is the prevalent use of finite reward expiration terms. We develop a theoretical framework to investigate the economic rationale behind this phenomenon and the trade-off between short and long expiration terms. In our model, a monopolistic firm sets the expiration term, along with the price and reward size, and interacts with consumers over an infinite horizon. Consumers are heterogeneous in shopping probabilities and product valuations and forward-looking in making purchase decisions. We find that a customer reward program with a finite expiration term can increase firm profits when (i) the valuation difference within the consumer population is intermediate and (ii) the shopping probabilities and valuations are negatively correlated among consumers. Several model extensions confirm the robustness of these results. Finally, we conduct an empirical investigation on the reward program practice of the top 100 U.S. retailers, which provides directional support for several key theoretical predictions.</description><author>Sun, Yacheng; Zhang, Dan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Social Responsibility and Firm Risk: Theory and Empirical Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albuquerque, Rui; Koskinen, Yrjo; Zhang, Chendi
This paper presents an industry equilibrium model where firms have a choice to engage in corporate social responsibility (CSR) activities. We model CSR as an investment to increase product differentiation that allows firms to benefit from higher profit margins. The model predicts that CSR decreases systematic risk and increases firm value and that these effects are stronger for firms with high product differentiation. We find supporting evidence for our predictions. We address a potential endogeneity problem by instrumenting CSR using data on the political affiliation of the firm's home state.</description><author>Albuquerque, Rui; Koskinen, Yrjo; Zhang, Chendi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Flash Crash: A Cautionary Tale About Highly Fragmented Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Menkveld, Albert J.; Yueshen, Bart Zhou
A breakdown of cross-market arbitrage activity could make markets more fragile and result in price crashes. We provide suggestive evidence for this novel channel based on a high-frequency analysis of the most salient crash in recent history: The Flash Crash. We further show that such an event can be extremely costly for a large seller trading in a particular venue as the seller effectively relies on local liquidity supply only. These findings highlight the vulnerability of today's highly fragmented markets.</description><author>Menkveld, Albert J.; Yueshen, Bart Zhou</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Provision of Public Goods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morgan, John; Tumlinson, Justin
Milton Friedman famously suggested that firms ought not divert profits toward public goods because shareholders can better make these contributions themselves. Despite this, activist shareholders are increasingly successful in persuading firms to be "socially responsible." We study firm behavior when shareholders care about public goods as well as profits and when managerial contracts reflect these concerns. Under these ideal conditions, managers redirect more profits toward public goods than shareholders would when acting separately-shareholders are poorer but happier. Further, so long as the public good is sufficiently desirable, the manager selects the socially optimal level of output, despite the mismatch between shareholder preferences and those of society at large.</description><author>Morgan, John; Tumlinson, Justin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of the Say-on-Pay Vote in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iliev, Peter; Vitanova, Svetla
The Dodd-Frank Act mandated advisory shareholder votes on executive compensation. To isolate the effect of holding a Say-on-Pay vote we use an exemption provided to a group of firms based on their public float. We find that the regulation increased the level of CEO pay and the fraction of performance-linked pay in the companies that had to comply with the new rule. This increase was larger for CEOs with higher ownership and longer tenure. Moreover, the market reacted negatively to the exemption from the Say-on-Pay rule suggesting general support for holding the Say-on-Pay votes. These effects are not present in placebo specifications in previous years or in different groups.</description><author>Iliev, Peter; Vitanova, Svetla</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Cost of Financing Education: Can Student Debt Hinder Entrepreneurship?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krishnan, Karthik; Wang, Pinshuo
We find that student debt is negatively related to the propensity to start a firm, particularly larger and more successful ventures. An exogenous change due to the Higher Education Amendments of 1998, which made student debt completely nondischargeable through personal bankruptcy, reduced the likelihood of entrepreneurship by student loan borrowers that were already in four-year college at the time of this regulation. Moreover, an exogenous shock to the level of student debt due to the Higher Education Amendments of 1992 negatively impacts entrepreneurship rates for students already in four-year college at the time of this regulation. Entrepreneurs with more student debt are more likely to fall behind on their student debt payments, and this relation is mitigated when their ventures are successful. Our evidence indicates that student debt inhibits entrepreneurship by exacerbating the effect of negative business outcomes on the individual.</description><author>Krishnan, Karthik; Wang, Pinshuo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Anomalies Are Publicized Broadly, Do Institutions Trade Accordingly?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Calluzzo, Paul; Moneta, Fabio; Topaloglu, Selim
This paper studies whether institutional investors trade on 14 well documented stock market anomalies. We show that there is an increase in anomaly-based trading when information about the anomalies is readily available through academic publications and the release of necessary accounting data. This finding is more pronounced among hedge funds and institutions with high turnover, that is, the subset of investors who likely have the abilities and incentives to act on the anomalies. We directly relate the increase in trading to the observed decay in post-publication anomaly returns. Our results support the role of institutional investors in the arbitrage process and in improving market efficiency.</description><author>Calluzzo, Paul; Moneta, Fabio; Topaloglu, Selim</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Segmentation and Software Security: Pricing Patching Rights</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>August, Terrence; Dao, Duy; Kim, Kihoon
The patching approach to security in the software industry has been less effective than desired. One critical issue with the status quo is that the endowment of "patching rights" (the ability for a user to choose whether security updates are applied) lacks the incentive structure to induce better security-related decisions. However, producers can differentiate their products based on the provision of patching rights. By characterizing the price for these rights, the optimal discount provided to those who relinquish rights and have their systems automatically updated in a timely manner, and the consumption and protection strategies taken by users in equilibrium as they strategically interact because of the security externality associated with product vulnerabilities, it is shown that the optimal pricing of these rights can segment the market in a manner that leads to both greater security and greater profitability. This policy greatly reduces unpatched populations and has a relative hike in profitability that is increasing in the extent to which patches are bundled together. Social welfare may decrease when automated patching costs are small because strategic pricing contracts usage in the market and also incentivizes loss-inefficient choices. However, welfare benefits when the policy either (1) greatly expands automatic updating in cases in which it is minimally observed or (2) significantly reduces the patching process burden of those who most value the software.</description><author>August, Terrence; Dao, Duy; Kim, Kihoon</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Markov Decision Processes with Exogenous Variables</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bray, Robert L.
I present two algorithms for solving dynamic programs with exogenous variables: endogenous value iteration and endogenous policy iteration. These algorithms are always at least as fast as relative value iteration and relative policy iteration, and they are faster when the endogenous variables converge to their stationary distributions sooner than the exogenous variables.</description><author>Bray, Robert L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Erlang-S: A Data-Based Model of Servers in Queueing Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Azriel, David; Feigin, Paul D.; Mandelbaum, Avishai
Classical queueing theory has typically focused on customers, and server availability has been taken for granted. However, data accessibility and the emergence of complex service systems, for example, call centers, revealed the need to stochastically model the complex behavior of servers. In this work, we propose a new model that accommodates such behavior; we call it Erlang-S, where "S" stands for servers. Our model assumes a pool of present servers, some of whom are available to serve customers from the queue while others are not, and the process of becoming available or unavailable is modeled explicitly. Our focus here is on applying the model to real systems, specifically call centers. Estimating the parameters of the new model from call-center data is challenging because reality is observed discretely in time as opposed to its continuous evolution. We therefore use an expectation-maximization algorithm that computes the expected number of relevant quantities given the discrete-time data. Erlang-S differs from the Erlang-A model, which has been commonly used for modeling call centers: the latter model assumes that all agents who are present are, in fact, available for service. When comparing predictions of the two models against call-center data, we find that Erlang-A generally overestimates queue length and consequently also the fraction of abandonment, and Erlang-S predicts reality more closely and usefully. Our conclusion is that it is important to model explicitly server dynamics to obtain accurate and valuable models of complex service systems.</description><author>Azriel, David; Feigin, Paul D.; Mandelbaum, Avishai</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sustainable Inventory with Robust Periodic-Affine Policies and Application to Medical Supply Chains</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bandi, Chaithanya; Han, Eojin; Nohadani, Omid
We introduce a new class of adaptive policies called periodic-affine policies, which allows a decision maker to optimally manage and control large-scale newsvendor networks in the presence of uncertain demand without distributional assumptions. These policies are data-driven and model many features of the demand such as correlation and remain robust to parameter misspecification. We present a model that can be generalized to multiproduct settings and extended to multiperiod problems. This is accomplished by modeling the uncertain demand via sets. In this way, it offers a natural framework to study competing policies such as base-stock, affine, and approximative approaches with respect to their profit, sensitivity to parameters and assumptions, and computational scalability. We show that the periodic-affine policies are sustainable-that is, time consistent-because they warrant optimality both within subperiods and over the entire planning horizon. This approach is tractable and free of distributional assumptions, and, hence, suited for real-world applications. We provide efficient algorithms to obtain the optimal periodic-affine policies and demonstrate their advantages on the sales data from one of India's largest pharmacy retailers.</description><author>Bandi, Chaithanya; Han, Eojin; Nohadani, Omid</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Submodular Risk Allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghamami, Samim; Glasserman, Paul
We analyze the optimal allocation of trades to portfolios when the cost associated with an allocation is proportional to each portfolio's risk. Our investigation is motivated by changes in the over-the-counter derivatives markets, under which some contracts may be traded bilaterally or through central counterparties, splitting a set of trades into two or more portfolios. A derivatives dealer faces risk-based collateral and capital costs for each portfolio, and it seeks to minimize total margin requirements through its allocation of trades to portfolios. When margin requirements are submodular, the problem becomes a submodular intersection problem. Its dual provides per-trade margin attributions, and assigning trades to portfolios based on the lowest attributed costs yields an optimal allocation. As part of this investigation, we derive conditions under which standard deviation and other risk measures are submodular functions of sets of trades. We compare systemwide optimality with individually optimal allocations in a market with multiple dealers.</description><author>Ghamami, Samim; Glasserman, Paul</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Partial Deregulation and Competition: Effects on Risky Mortgage Origination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Di Maggio, Marco; Kermani, Amir; Korgaonkar, Sanket
We exploit the preemption of national banks from state laws against predatory lending by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency (OCC) as a quasi-experiment to study the effect of deregulation and its interaction with competition on the supply of complex mortgages. Following the preemption ruling, national banks significantly increased their origination of loans with prepayment penalties relative to national banks in states without anti-predatory-lending laws. We highlight a competition channel: in counties where OCC-regulated lenders had larger market shares, non-OCC-regulated lenders responded by increasing their supply of contracts with riskier features, such as deferred amortization, which were not restricted by the state anti-predatory-lending law. Non-OCC lenders were able to lure borrowers into these higher-margin contracts by increasing their appeal with teaser rates.</description><author>Di Maggio, Marco; Kermani, Amir; Korgaonkar, Sanket</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing Ancillary Service Subscriptions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Ruxian; Dada, Maqbool; Sahin, Ozge
We investigate heterogeneous customer choice behavior in the presence of main products-ancillary services with options of pay-per-use and subscription-and outside option. The willingness to pay for a service subscription is derived as a dosed-form expression, which enables us to characterize the optimal pricing strategy and the impact of service subscriptions on customer surplus. Analytical results and numerical experiments show that offering service subscriptions may result in "win-win," "win-win-win," "win-win-lose," or "lose-lose-win" scenarios or in other situations for the firm, competitors, and customers in a variety of monopolistic and duopolistic scenarios. The advantages of service subscription still remain with heterogeneous customers differing on multiple dimensions including the nominal utility, uncertainty in the need of ancillary service, and purchase frequency. We find that if the product quality for both firms, measured by nominal utility, is not significantly different, more fierce price competition by offering a service subscription may result in a higher customer surplus, compared with that without a service subscription. Ancillary service subscription can help firms to better price-discriminate heterogeneous customers through different subscription decisions and subsequent purchase behavior.</description><author>Wang, Ruxian; Dada, Maqbool; Sahin, Ozge</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Near-Optimal Bayesian Ambiguity Sets for Distributionally Robust Optimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gupta, Vishal
We propose a Bayesian framework for assessing the relative strengths of data-driven ambiguity sets in distributionally robust optimization (DRO) when the underlying distribution is defined by a finite-dimensional parameter. The key idea is to measure the relative size between a candidate ambiguity set and a specific asymptotically optimal set. As the amount of data grows large, this asymptotically optimal set is the smallest convex ambiguity set that satisfies a novel Bayesian robustness guarantee that we introduce. This guarantee is defined with respect to a given class of constraints and is a Bayesian analog of more common frequentist feasibility guarantees from the DRO literature. Using this framework, we prove that many popular existing ambiguity sets are significantly larger than the asymptotically optimal set for constraints that are concave in the ambiguity. By contrast, we construct new ambiguity sets that are tractable, satisfy our Bayesian robustness guarantee, and are at most a small, constant factor larger than the asymptotically optimal set; we call these sets Bayesian near optimal. We further prove that asymptotically, solutions to DRO models with our Bayesian near-optimal sets enjoy strong frequentist robustness properties, despite their smaller size. Finally, our framework yields guidelines for practitioners selecting between competing ambiguity set proposals in DRO. Computational evidence in portfolio allocation using real and simulated data confirms that our framework, although motivated by asymptotic analysis in a Bayesian setting, provides practical insight into the performance of various DRO models with finite data under frequentist assumptions.</description><author>Gupta, Vishal</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Transparency in Business-to-Business Auction Markets: The Role of Winner Identity Disclosure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lu, Yixin; Gupta, Alok; Ketter, Wolfgang; van Heckd, Eric
One of the central issues in auction design is how much information should be disclosed to bidders. In this paper, we examine bidder's identity disclosure in sequential business-to-business (B2B) auctions. Specifically, we compare two information disclosure policies, one that publicly discloses winners' identities (the status quo) and an alternative policy that conceals winners' identities. Using a large-scale field experiment in the Dutch flower auction market, we find that concealing winners' identities can significantly increase the average winning price and thereby raise the seller's revenue. We further explore the underlying mechanism that drives the observed effect. The empirical analysis of bidding behavior in these auctions suggests that bidders tend to imitate some of their competitors who have won in previous rounds of auctions and shade their bids accordingly. Concealing winners' identities can disrupt such imitation heuristic, which in turn mitigates the price-declining trend in sequential rounds. Our findings have important implications for the design of information disclosure policies in B2B auction markets.</description><author>Lu, Yixin; Gupta, Alok; Ketter, Wolfgang; van Heckd, Eric</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing Appointment Booking Under Customer Choices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Nan; van de Ven, Peter M.; Zhang, Bo
Motivated by the increasing use of online appointment booking platforms, we study how to offer appointment slots to customers to maximize the total number of slots booked. We develop two models, nonsequential offering and sequential offering, to capture different types of interactions between customers and the scheduling system. In these two models, the scheduler offers either a single set of appointment slots for the arriving customer to choose from or multiple sets in sequence, respectively. For the nonsequential model, we identify a static randomized policy, which is asymptotically optimal when the system demand and capacity increase simultaneously, and we further show that offering all available slots at all times has a constant factor of two performance guarantee. For the sequential model, we derive a closed form optimal policy for a large class of instances and develop a simple, effective heuristic for those instances without an explicit optimal policy. By comparing these two models, our study generates useful operational insights for improving the current appointment booking processes. In particular, our analysis reveals an interesting equivalence between the sequential offering model and the nonsequential offering model with perfect customer preference information. This equivalence allows us to apply sequential offering in a wide range of interactive scheduling contexts. Our extensive numerical study shows that sequential offering can significantly improve the slot fill rate (6%-8% on average and up to 18% in our testing cases) compared with nonsequential offering. Given the recent and ongoing growth of online and mobile appointment booking platforms, our research findings can be particularly useful to inform user interface design of these booking platforms.</description><author>Liu, Nan; van de Ven, Peter M.; Zhang, Bo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Obscured Transparency? Compensation Benchmarking and the Biasing of Executive Pay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Vaan, Mathijs; Elbers, Benjamin; DiPrete, Thomas A.
The disclosure of compensation peer groups is argued to provide shareholders with valuable information that can be used to scrutinize chief executive officer (CEO) compensation. However, research suggests that there are substantial incentives for executives and directors to bias the compensation peer group upward such that the CEO can extract additional rent. We leverage the idea that reciprocated peer nominations are unlikely to be biased to construct counterfactual peer groups that allow us to measure the bias of disclosed peer groups. Analyses of 11 years of comprehensive data on compensation peer groups demonstrate that the average firm uses an upwardly biased peer group. The size of the bias increases when incentives and opportunities to do so are more pronounced. Specifically, results show that bias is larger when financial targets are not met and when exercising discretion in the selection of peer firms is justifiable. More importantly, upward bias in compensation peer groups is highly predictive of an increase in CEO compensation, suggesting that there is a strong incentive for CEOs to strategically select peers. Finally, although average peer group bias has gone down in recent years, the predictive effect of bias on pay has gone up. These findings call into question the practical impact of recent efforts to introduce greater transparency into the process for determining executive compensation.</description><author>de Vaan, Mathijs; Elbers, Benjamin; DiPrete, Thomas A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Minimal Frames and Transparent Frames for Risk, Time, and Uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leland, Jonathan W.; Schneider, Mark; Wilcox, Nathaniel T.
Behavior differs between transparent and nontransparent presentations of decisions, but "transparent presentation" has not been precisely defined. We formally define "transparent frames" for risk and time, establish their uniqueness, provide algorithms for constructing them, and compare them with "standard" presentation formats. A logic emerges for predicting systematic shifts in choice under risk and over time, and how violations of rational choice theory will depend on frames. An experiment verifies most of those predictions in choice under risk. We extend results to choice under uncertainty and also predict frame dependence of ambiguity aversion, a result supported by recent experimental evidence.</description><author>Leland, Jonathan W.; Schneider, Mark; Wilcox, Nathaniel T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ride Your Luck! A Field Experiment on Lottery-Based Incentives for Compliance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fabbri, Marco; Barbieri, Paolo Nicola; Bigoni, Maria
In a field experiment, we studied the performance of an incentive scheme that combines a lottery-based reward for compliance with probabilistic sanctions for noncompliance. For one month, bus passengers who purchased a ticket on board a subset of buses operating in a medium-sized Italian city participated in a lottery awarding a (sic)500 prize. The remaining buses-otherwise identical-were used as controls. We observed the amount of tickets sold on treated and control buses over three months, before, during, and after the introduction of the lottery. Results show that treated buses sold significantly more on-board tickets than control buses during the lottery period. In our setup, the estimated extra revenues from the ticket sales caused by the introduction of the lottery fell short of the amount of the total prizes raffled off. However, the incentive scheme proved cost-effective because not all the lottery prizes were claimed by winners.</description><author>Fabbri, Marco; Barbieri, Paolo Nicola; Bigoni, Maria</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Voting Rules in Sequential Search by Committees: Theory and Experiments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mak, Vincent; Seale, Darryl A.; Rapoport, Amnon; Gisches, Eyran J.
We propose a committee extension of the individual sequential search model called the "secretary problem," where collective decisions on when to stop the search are reached via a prespecified voting rule. We offer a game-theoretic analysis of our model and then report two experiments on three-person committees with either uncorrelated or perfectly correlated preferences under three different voting rules followed by a third experiment on single decision makers. Relative to equilibrium predictions, committees with uncorrelated preferences oversearched under minority and majority voting rules but, otherwise, undersearched or approximated equilibrium play. Individually, committee members were often less strategic when their preferences were uncorrelated than when they were perfectly correlated. Collectively, committees' decisions were more strategic than single decision makers' only under the unanimity rule, although still not significantly better in terms of the decision makers' welfare. Finally, across our experiments that involved committee search, the unanimity rule always optimized committee welfare.</description><author>Mak, Vincent; Seale, Darryl A.; Rapoport, Amnon; Gisches, Eyran J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Risk-Based Group Testing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aprahamian, Hrayer; Bish, Douglas R.; Bish, Ebru K.
Group testing (i.e., testing multiple subjects simultaneously with a single test) is essential for classifying a large population of subjects as positive or negative for a binary characteristic (e.g., presence of a disease). We study optimal group testing designs under subject-specific risk characteristics and imperfect tests, considering classification accuracy-, efficiency- and equity-based objectives, and characterize important structural properties of optimal testing designs. These properties allow us to model the testing design problems as partitioning problems, develop efficient algorithms, and derive insights on equity versus accuracy trade-off. One of our models reduces to a constrained shortest path problem, for a special case of which we develop a polynomial-time algorithm. We also show that determining an optimal risk-based Dorfman testing scheme that minimizes the expected number of tests is tractable, resolving an open conjecture. We demonstrate the value of optimal risk-based testing schemes with a case study of public health screening.</description><author>Aprahamian, Hrayer; Bish, Douglas R.; Bish, Ebru K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evidence for the Feedback Role of Performance Measurement Systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Shannon W.; Kimball, Amanda
Performance measurement systems (PMSs) are used to diagnose and remediate problems, termed the "decision-facilitating" or feedback role of management control. We examine whether use of PMSs by individual decision makers is associated with better performance. Experimental studies have isolated individual-level effects of feedback on decision quality; however, it is difficult to extend these findings to natural settings. Archival and survey studies offer evidence on the association between the presence of PMSs and performance but have had limited success in measuring decision makers' actual use of PMSs and addressing endogeneity of the decision to use PMSs. We use unobtrusively collected data on actual PMS use in 30 K-12 charter schools over three years to test whether teachers who make greater use of two PMSs are associated with greater growth in student learning. We find that teachers' use of PMSs is associated with increased student learning, consistent with the premise that PMSs facilitate teacher interventions and improve student outcomes. The results are both statistically and materially significant, and they are better explained by PMS use than by selection effects of better teachers using PMSs. Consistent with the organization's focus on "at-risk" students, the strongest effects of teachers' use of one PMS are concentrated among the lowest-performing students. In sum, we find broad support for the thesis that the feedback role of PMSs is associated with meaningful performance improvement.</description><author>Anderson, Shannon W.; Kimball, Amanda</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic Factors in Oil Futures Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heath, Davidson
This paper documents new evidence against perfect risk spanning in crude oil futures, and develops an affine futures pricing model that allows for unspanned macroeconomic factors. Compared to previous estimates, the oil spot premium is more volatile and strongly procyclical, which suggests that previous models miss the majority of variation in oil risk premiums. The estimates reveal a dynamic two-way relationship between oil futures and economic activity: productivity shocks are associated with higher oil prices, while oil price shocks affect economic activity by lowering future consumption spending. Unspanned macro factors also affect the valuation of real options.</description><author>Heath, Davidson</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Pricing Implications of Short-Sale Constraints in Imperfectly Competitive Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Hong; Wang, Yajun
We study the impact of short-sale constraints on market prices and liquidity in imperfectly competitive markets in which market makers have market power. In contrast to the existing literature, we show that because competition is imperfect, short-sale constraints decrease bid prices, increase ask prices, and drive up bid-ask spread volatility, with or without information asymmetry. If market makers are risk neutral, then short-sale constraints do not affect ask prices or ask depths. In addition, the impact of short-sale constraints can increase with market transparency. Our main results are unaffected by endogenous information acquisition or reduced information revelation because of short-sale constraints.</description><author>Liu, Hong; Wang, Yajun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Alpha: A Spectral Decomposition of Investment Performance Across Time Horizons</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaudhuri, Shomesh E.; Lo, Andrew W.
The value added by an active investor is traditionally measured using alpha, tracking error, and the information ratio. However, these measures do not characterize the dynamic component of investor activity, nor do they consider the time horizons over which weights are changed. In this paper, we propose a technique to measure the value of active investment that captures both the static and dynamic contributions of an investment process. This dynamic alpha is based on the decomposition of a portfolio's expected return into its frequency components using spectral analysis. The result is a static component that measures the portion of a portfolio's expected return resulting from passive investments and security selection and a dynamic component that captures the manager's timing ability across a range of time horizons. Our framework can be universally applied to any portfolio and is a useful method for comparing the forecast power of different investment processes. Several analytical and empirical examples are provided to illustrate the practical relevance of this decomposition.</description><author>Chaudhuri, Shomesh E.; Lo, Andrew W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Alpha: A Spectral Decomposition of Investment Performance Across Time Horizons (vol 65, pg 3949, 2018)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaudhuri, Shomesh E.; Lo, Andrew W.
nan</description><author>Chaudhuri, Shomesh E.; Lo, Andrew W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Design and Dynamic Pricing of Vertically Differentiated Inventories</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stamatopoulos, Ioannis; Tzamos, Christos
We study a model in which a monopoly firm designs the quality profile of its inventory and then dynamically updates its pricing menu for a finite selling horizon to maximize revenue. In a counterfactual scenario, a social planner goes through the same process to maximize total welfare. We show that in both scenarios the problem of dynamically pricing heterogeneous-quality (vertically differentiated) inventories is equivalent to that of dynamically pricing homogeneous-quality inventories, in the sense that a solution to one implies a solution to the other. Moreover, we prove a strong scarcity result, which suggests that the sale of a product drives up the prices on all remaining products, whether of higher or lower quality. We then consider product line design under a production technology that utilizes costly and potentially limited resources. We show that with unlimited (but costly) resources, the revenue maximizer undersupplies quality to all products compared with the social planner. With limited resources, we show that the revenue maximizer exhibits elitism: he overallocates (underallocates) resources on the production of high-quality (low-quality) products. However, as the volume of expected consumer arrivals increases to infinity, both the revenue maximizer and the welfare maximizer allocate resources equally across products.</description><author>Stamatopoulos, Ioannis; Tzamos, Christos</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Soft Floors in Auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zeithammer, Robert
Several of the auction-driven exchanges that facilitate programmatic buying of internet display advertising have recently introduced "soft floors" in addition to standard reserve prices (called "hard floors" in the industry). A soft floor is a bid level below which a winning bidder pays his own bid instead of paying the second-highest bid as in a second-price auction most ad exchanges use by default. This paper characterizes soft floors' revenue-generating potential as a function of the distribution of bidder independent private values. When bidders are symmetric (identically distributed), soft floors have no effect on revenue, because a symmetric equilibrium always exists in strictly monotonic bidding strategies, and standard revenue-equivalence arguments thus apply. The industry often motivates soft floors as tools for extracting additional expected revenue from an occasional high bidder, for example a bidder retargeting the consumer making the impression. Such asymmetries in the distribution of bidder preferences do not automatically make soft floors profitable. This paper presents two examples of tractable modeling assumptions about such occasional high bidders, with one example implying low soft floors always hurt revenues because of strategic bid-shading by the regular bidders, and the other example implying high soft floors can increase revenues by making the regular bidders bid more aggressively.</description><author>Zeithammer, Robert</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Speculation and the Bond Market: An Empirical No-Arbitrage Framework</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barillas, Francisco; Nimark, Kristoffer
An affine no-arbitrage asset pricing framework is developed that allows for agents to have rational but heterogeneous expectations. The framework can match both bond yields and the observed dispersion of yield expectations in survey data. Heterogeneous information introduces a speculative component in bond prices that is (i) statistically distinct from classical components such as risk premia and expectations about future short rates and (ii) quantitatively important, at times accounting for up to 125 basis points of U.S. yields. Allowing for heterogeneous expectations also changes the estimated relative importance of risk premia and expectations about future short rates in historical bond yields compared to a standard affine model. The framework imposes weaker restrictions than existing heterogeneous information asset pricing models and is thus well suited to empirically quantify the importance of relaxing the common information assumption.</description><author>Barillas, Francisco; Nimark, Kristoffer</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Index Membership and Small Firm Financing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Charles; Gustafson, Matthew; Velthuis, Raisa
This paper investigates the extent to which index membership affects small firm financing. Using a regression discontinuity specification around the lower cutoff of the Russell 2000 small-cap index, we find that index membership causes small firms to transition away from bank financing in favor of seasoned equity offerings. These effects are concentrated in the year following Russell 2000 additions and do not reverse immediately upon deletions. Liquidity, the elasticity of demand for equity, and analyst coverage also significantly increase following Russell 2000 additions but do not significantly decrease following deletions. Finally, firms added to the Russell 2000 obtain lower spreads and have fewer covenants on the bank loans that they do initiate. Our findings are consistent with index membership mitigating the financing frictions of small firms by improving their information environment through increased investor awareness.</description><author>Cao, Charles; Gustafson, Matthew; Velthuis, Raisa</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning in Repeated Auctions with Budgets: Regret Minimization and Equilibrium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balseiro, Santiago R.; Gur, Yonatan
In online advertising markets, advertisers often purchase ad placements through bidding in repeated auctions based on realized viewer information. We study how budget-constrained advertisers may compete in such sequential auctions in the presence of uncertainty about future bidding opportunities and competition. We formulate this problem as a sequential game of incomplete information, in which bidders know neither their own valuation distribution nor the budgets and valuation distributions of their competitors. We introduce a family of practical bidding strategies we refer to as adaptive pacing strategies, in which advertisers adjust their bids according to the sample path of expenditures they exhibit, and analyze the performance of these strategies in different competitive settings. We establish the asymptotic optimality of these strategies when competitors' bids are independent and identically distributed over auctions, but also when competing bids are arbitrary. When all the bidders adopt these strategies, we establish the convergence of the induced dynamics and characterize a regime (well motivated in the context of online advertising markets) under which these strategies constitute an approximate Nash equilibrium in dynamic strategies: the benefit from unilaterally deviating to other strategies, including ones with access to complete information, becomes negligible as the number of auctions and competitors grows large. This establishes a connection between regret minimization and market stability, by which advertisers can essentially follow approximate equilibrium bidding strategies that also ensure the best performance that can be guaranteed off equilibrium.</description><author>Balseiro, Santiago R.; Gur, Yonatan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Consumers, Revenue Management, and the Design of Loyalty Programs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chun, So Yeon; Ovchinnikov, Anton
We study the interaction between the design of a premium-status loyalty program, revenue management, and strategic consumer behavior. Specifically, we consider a contemporaneous change where firms across several industries switch their loyalty programs from quantity-based toward spending-based designs. This change has been met with fierce opposition from the media and consumers. Building on the microfoundations of strategic, forward-looking, and status-seeking consumer behavior, we endogenize strategic consumer response to firms' pricing and loyalty program design decisions, and we characterize conditions under which, by coordinating these decisions, firms can benefit from strategic consumer behavior. We further show that by switching to a spending-based design, firms can benefit from strategic behavior even more, under broader conditions, and in a Pareto-improving way. Finally, we also analyze combined designs, which utilize a combination of quantity and/or spending requirements, and show how they can be used to better manage the transition toward spending-based designs, possibly minimizing negative consumer reactions.</description><author>Chun, So Yeon; Ovchinnikov, Anton</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Growth, Profitability, and Investment Opportunities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, Ilan; Maio, Paulo
We show that recent prominent equity factor models are to a large degree compatible with the Intertemporal CAPM (ICAPM) framework. Factors associated with alternative profitability measures forecast the equity premium in a way that is consistent with the ICAPM. Several factors based on firms' asset growth predict a significant decline in stock market volatility, thus being consistent with their positive prices of risk. The investment-based factors are also strong predictors of an improvement in future economic activity. The time-series predictive ability of most equity state variables is not subsumed by traditional ICAPM state variables. Importantly, factors that earn larger risk prices tend to be associated with state variables that are more correlated with future investment opportunities or economic activity. Moreover, these risk price estimates can be reconciled with plausible risk-aversion parameter estimates. Overall, the ICAPM can be used as a common theoretical background for recent multifactor models.</description><author>Cooper, Ilan; Maio, Paulo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Market Threats and Stock Crash Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Si; Zhan, Xintong
This paper examines the effect of product market threats on firms' stock crash risk. Competitive pressure from the product market aggravates managers' incentive to withhold negative information. When negative information is accumulated to a tipping point, the accumulated information comes out all at once and leads to an abrupt and large decline in stock price. Using a measure of product market threats, our regressions find that firms facing more threats are more prone to stock crashes. This result is confirmed by an instrumental variable analysis and a difference-in-difference analysis with an exogenous shock to market competition.</description><author>Li, Si; Zhan, Xintong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Agency and Endogenous Risk-Taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wong, Tak-Yuen
I study a continuous-time principal-agent model in which a multitasking agent engages in unobserved risk-taking. Risk-taking creates short-term profits but also increases the chance of large losses. The optimal contract incentivizes excessive risk-taking when the agent has insufficient skin in the game. Moreover, if the low effort is not too value-destroying and the private benefit of shirking is low enough, the principal can eliminate risk-taking by implementing the low effort. However, with variable project scale, addressing the risk-taking incentives by downsizing projects is not optimal. The implementation of the optimal contract shows that risk management should take agency problems into account. Complete hedging against downside risks provides incentives for the agent to gamble.</description><author>Wong, Tak-Yuen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Getting the Rich and Powerful to Give</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kessler, Judd B.; Milkman, Katherine L.; Zhang, C. Yiwei
What motivates the rich and powerful to exhibit generosity? We explore this important question in a large field experiment. We solicit donations from 32,174 alumni of an Ivy League university, including thousands of rich and powerful alumni. Consistent with past psychology research, we find that the rich and powerful respond dramatically, and differently than others, to being given a sense of agency over the use of donated funds. Gifts from rich and powerful alumni increase by 100%-350% when they are given a sense of agency. This response arises primarily on the intensive margin with no effect on the likelihood of donating. Results suggest that motivating the rich and powerful to act may require tailored interventions.</description><author>Kessler, Judd B.; Milkman, Katherine L.; Zhang, C. Yiwei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effectiveness of Incentive Schemes in the Presence of Implicit Effort Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goerg, Sebastian J.; Kube, Sebastian; Radbruch, Jonas
Agents' decisions to exert effort depend on the incentives and the potential costs involved. So far, most of the attention has been on the incentive side. However, our laboratory experiments underline that both the incentive and the cost side can be used separately to shape work performance. In our experiment, subjects work on a real-effort slider task. Between treatments, we vary the incentive scheme used for compensating workers. Additionally, by varying the available outside options, we explore the role of implicit costs of effort in determining workers' performance. We observe that incentive contracts and implicit costs interact in a nontrivial manner. In general, performance decreases as implicit costs increase. Yet the magnitude of the reaction differs across incentive schemes and across the offered outside options, which, in turn, alters estimated output elasticities. In addition, comparisons between incentive schemes crucially depend on the implicit costs.</description><author>Goerg, Sebastian J.; Kube, Sebastian; Radbruch, Jonas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Supply Chain Proximity and Product Quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bray, Robert L.; Serpa, Juan Camilo; Colak, Ahmet
We estimate the effect of supply chain proximity on product quality. Merging four automotive data sets, we create a supply chain sample that reports the failure rate of 27,807 auto components, the location of 529 upstream component factories, and the location of 275 downstream assembly plants. We find that defect rates are higher when upstream and downstream factories are farther apart. Specifically, we estimate that increasing the distance between an upstream component factory and a downstream assembly plant by an order of magnitude increases the component's expected defect rate by 3.9%. We find that quality improves more slowly across geographically dispersed supply chains. We also find that supply chain distance is more detrimental to quality when automakers produce early-generation models or high-end products, when they buy components with more complex configurations, or when they source from suppliers who invest relatively little in research and development.</description><author>Bray, Robert L.; Serpa, Juan Camilo; Colak, Ahmet</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dealer Liquidity Provision and the Breakdown of the Law of One Price: Evidence from the CDS-Bond Basis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Jaewon; Shachar, Or; Shin, Sean Seunghun
We examine dealers' liquidity provision against mispricing in the corporate bond market from 2005 to 2009. Dealers on average serve as stabilizing liquidity providers by trading against widening price gaps between corporate bonds and credit default swaps (the CDS-bond basis). However, dealers cut back on liquidity provision as they suffer losses, mispricing becomes wider, or the funding situation worsens, consistent with the limited capital capacity of financial intermediaries. We also show that the unwinding of basis arbitrage trading can amplify mispricing by documenting that bond returns following the Lehman collapse were very low for bonds with strong preexisting basis arbitrage activity and for bonds underwritten by Lehman Brothers. Liquidity demand due to the exit of arbitrageurs can be a major driver of disruption in credit markets.</description><author>Choi, Jaewon; Shachar, Or; Shin, Sean Seunghun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Data-Driven Patient Scheduling in Emergency Departments: A Hybrid Robust-Stochastic Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Shuangchi; Sim, Melvyn; Zhang, Meilin
Emergency care necessitates adequate and timely treatment, which has unfortunately been compromised by crowding in many emergency departments (EDs). To address this issue, we study patient scheduling in EDs so that mandatory targets imposed on each patient's door-to-provider time and length of stay can be collectively met with the largest probability. Exploiting patient flow data from the ED, we propose a hybrid robustst-ochastic approach to formulating the patient scheduling problem, which allows for practical features, such as a time-varying patient arrival process, general consultation time distributions, and multiple heterogeneous physicians. In contrast to the conventional formulation of maximizing the joint probability of target attainment, which is computationally excruciating, the hybrid approach provides a computationally amiable formulation that yields satisfactory solutions to the patient scheduling problem. This formulation enables us to develop a dynamic scheduling algorithm for making recommendations about the next patient to be seen by each available physician. In numerical experiments, the proposed hybrid approach outperforms both the sample average approximation method and an asymptotically optimal scheduling policy.</description><author>He, Shuangchi; Sim, Melvyn; Zhang, Meilin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commodity Price Forecasts, Futures Prices, and Pricing Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cortazar, Gonzalo; Millard, Cristobal; Ortega, Hector; Schwartz, Eduardo S.
Even though commodity-pricing models have been successful in fitting the term structure of futures prices and its dynamics, they do not generate accurate true distributions of spot prices. This paper develops a new approach to calibrate these models using not only observations of oil futures prices, but also analysts' forecasts of oil spot prices. We conclude that to obtain reasonable expected spot curves, analysts' forecasts should be used, either alone or jointly with futures data. The use of both futures and forecasts, instead of using only forecasts, generates expected spot curves that do not differ considerably in the short/medium term, but long term estimations are significantly different. The inclusion of analysts' forecasts in addition to futures, instead of only futures prices, does not alter significantly the short/medium part of the futures curve but does have a significant effect on long-term futures estimations.</description><author>Cortazar, Gonzalo; Millard, Cristobal; Ortega, Hector; Schwartz, Eduardo S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Innovation Along the Supply Chain</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chu, Yongqiang; Tian, Xuan; Wang, Wenyu
In this paper, we document a positive effect of supplier-customer geographic proximity on supplier innovation. To establish causality, we explore plausibly exogenous variation in proximity caused by customer relocations. The positive effect of supplier-customer proximity on supplier innovation is stronger when customers are more innovative themselves, when suppliers and customers are closer in technological space, and when customers' demand accounts for a larger fraction of suppliers' total sales. These findings suggest that the feedback channel and the demand channel are likely underlying mechanisms through which supplier-customer proximity affects supplier innovation. Overall, our paper sheds new light on the real effect of supplier-customer relationship on corporate innovation.</description><author>Chu, Yongqiang; Tian, Xuan; Wang, Wenyu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cournot Competition in Networked Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bimpikis, Kostas; Ehsani, Shayan; Ilkilic, Rahmi
The paper considers a model of competition among firms that produce a homogeneous good in a networked environment. A bipartite graph determines which subset of markets a firm can supply to. Firms compete A la Cournot and decide how to allocate their production output to the markets they are directly connected to. We provide a characterization of the production quantities at the unique equilibrium of the resulting game for any given network. Our results identify a novel connection between the equilibrium outcome and supply paths in the underlying network structure. We then proceed to study the impact of changes in the competition structure, for example, due to a firm expanding into a new market or two firms merging, on firms' profits and consumer surplus. The modeling framework we propose can be used in assessing whether expanding in a new market is profitable for a firm, identifying opportunities for collaboration, for example, a joint venture between competing firms, and guiding regulatory action in the context of market design and antitrust analysis.</description><author>Bimpikis, Kostas; Ehsani, Shayan; Ilkilic, Rahmi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Multisourcing with Dependent Supplies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feng, Qi; Jia, Justin; Shanthikumar, J. George
As multisourcing becomes a widely adopted strategy in dynamic procurement planning, firms inevitably source from suppliers with dependent material flows, and such supply dependence, created by common second-tier suppliers or a common economic environment, is often positive. We show that firms can experience significant profit loss when implementing a policy computed based on a model that ignores the dependence among suppliers' stochastic material flows. The profit loss is particularly significant when a firm earns a low margin or faces an unreliable and fragmented supplier base. Analysis of the firm's dynamic multisourcing strategy under dependent supply uncertainties, however, is challenging. By expanding the space of ordering decision to a class of contingency policies, we identify conditions under which the dynamic planning model has a concave transformation. This approach allows us to characterize the optimal procurement policy. Moreover, our analysis suggests that the firm may order more from a less reliable supplier than from a more reliable one who charges the same procurement cost. The order allocation to the less reliable supplier can be even larger when the capacities are more dependent. Though the analysis of our base model is conducted for dependent supply capacities that are independent across periods, we show that the results can be generalized to Markov-modulated supplies or general supply functions that are stochastically linear in midpoint.</description><author>Feng, Qi; Jia, Justin; Shanthikumar, J. George</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Budgeting, Psychological Contracts, and Budgetary Misreporting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gallani, Susanna; Krishnan, Ranjani; Marinich, Eric J.; Shields, Michael D.
This study examines the effect of psychological contract breach on budgetary misreporting. Psychological contracts are mental models or schemas that govern how employees understand their exchange relationships with their employers. Psychological contract breach leads to feelings of violation and can occur even when employees' economic contracts are fulfilled. We study the effects of psychological contract breach on three common types of employee participation in budgeting that differ in the degree of employees' influence over their approved budgets. These include affirmative budgeting (full influence), consultative budgeting (moderate influence), and authoritative budgeting (low influence). When organizations communicate that employees will be involved in budgeting, employees develop psychological contracts of affirmative budgeting. If employees subsequently experience authoritative or consultative budgeting, their psychological contracts are breached. Employees who experience psychological contract breach seek redress through budgetary misreporting. Experimental results indicate that psychological contract breach partially mediates the relation between budgeting type and budgetary misreporting. Results also indicate asymmetry in the effects of psychological contract breach versus repair. Effects of breach on budgetary misreporting persist even after the breach no longer occurs.</description><author>Gallani, Susanna; Krishnan, Ranjani; Marinich, Eric J.; Shields, Michael D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Pricing with Disagreement and Uncertainty About the Length or Business Cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrei, Daniel; Carlin, Bruce; Hasler, Michael
We study an economy with incomplete information in which two agents are uncertain and disagree about the length of business cycles. That is, the agents do not question whether the economy is growing or not, but instead continuously estimate how long economic cycles will last-i.e., they learn about the persistence of fundamentals. Learning about persistence generates high and persistent stock return volatility mostly during recessions, but also (to a smaller extent) during economic booms. Disagreement among agents fluctuates and earns a risk premium. A clear risk-return trade-off appears only when conditioning on the sign and magnitude of disagreement. We confirm these predictions empirically.</description><author>Andrei, Daniel; Carlin, Bruce; Hasler, Michael</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Arbitrage Involvement and Security Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hwang, Byoung-Hyoun; Liu, Baixiao; Xu, Wei
We propose that hedge funds more aggressively buy underpriced stocks when they are allowed to short. To test our proposition, we utilize the institutional feature in Hong Kong in virtue of which only stocks added to a special list can be shorted. Our first-stage analysis uses hedge fund holdings data and provides evidence that the emergency of shortable securities, indeed, causes hedge funds to more aggressively buy seemingly underpriced stocks. Our second-stage analysis presents evidence that hedge funds' increased involvement in these stocks helps correct underpricing and moves prices in the direction of fundamentals.</description><author>Hwang, Byoung-Hyoun; Liu, Baixiao; Xu, Wei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inferring Commitment from Rates of Organizational Transition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jago, Arthur S.; Laurin, Kristin
Organizations often implement changes that can signal their values. However, the most objectively efficient changes do not necessarily serve as the best signals. Across seven experiments, we investigate how different rates of transition influence people's perceptions of how committed organizations are to the values underlying changes or improvements. We find that slower, less efficient transitions signal greater commitment compared with faster, more efficient transitions that reach otherwise identical endpoints (Experiment 1). Using mediation and moderation strategies, we demonstrate that this discontinuity occurs because people assume slower transitions require relatively more effort to enact (Experiments 2 and 3). Moreover, these commitment inferences persist beyond the point at which changes end (Experiment 4), when further improvement along the same dimension is no longer possible (Experiment 5), and regardless of whether the organization decided to transition either quickly or slowly (Experiment 6). This effect reverses, however, when people can directly compare slower and faster transitions that ultimately reach identical endpoints (Experiment 7). Taken together, these findings suggest that people often infer greater commitment from slower transitions that unfold over time, even when those transitions are objectively inferior to faster alternatives.</description><author>Jago, Arthur S.; Laurin, Kristin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fairness in Bankruptcies: An Experimental Study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cappelen, Alexander W.; Luttens, Roland Iwan; Sorensen, Erik O.; Tungodden, Bertil
The pari passu principle of awarding claimants proportionally to their pre-insolvency claims is the most prominent principle in the law of insolvency. We report from a lab experiment designed to study whether people find this principle a fair solution to the bankruptcy problem. The experimental design generates situations where participants work and accumulate claims in firms, some of which subsequently go bankrupt. Third-party arbitrators are randomly assigned to determine how the liquidation value of the bankrupt firms should be distributed between claimants. Our main finding is that there is a striking support for the pari passu principle. We estimate a random utility model that allows for the arbitrators to differ in what they consider a fair solution to the bankruptcy problem and find that about 85% of the participants endorse the proportional rule. We also find that a nonnegligible fraction of the arbitrators follow the constrained equal losses rule, while there is almost no support in our experiment for the constrained equal awards rule or other fairness rules suggested in the normative literature.</description><author>Cappelen, Alexander W.; Luttens, Roland Iwan; Sorensen, Erik O.; Tungodden, Bertil</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Sharp Test of the Portability of Expertise</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, Etan A.; Rao, Justin M.; Rothschild, David
To what extent does expertise depend on context? We observe professionals perform a task that is logically isomorphic to-but contextually distinct from-a familiar task in which they are skilled. We find that performance plummets when contextual cues disappear, suggesting that the expertise we observe on the familiar task is more heuristic than conceptual and does not travel far.</description><author>Green, Etan A.; Rao, Justin M.; Rothschild, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Coordinating with a "Problem Solver"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Glazer, Jacob; Rubinstein, Ariel
A "problem solver" (PS) is an agent who when interacting with other agents does not "put himself in their shoes" but rather chooses a best response to a uniform distribution over all possible configurations consistent with the information he receives about the other agents' moves. We demonstrate the special features of a PS by analyzing a modified coordination game. In the first stage, each of the other participants-who are treated as conventional players-chooses a location. The PS then receives some partial information about their moves and chooses his location. The PS wishes to coordinate with any one of the conventional players and they wish to coordinate with him but not with each other. Equilibria are characterized and shown to have different properties than those of Nash equilibria when the PS is treated as a conventional player.</description><author>Glazer, Jacob; Rubinstein, Ariel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mix Stickiness Under Asymmetric Cost Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Antle, Rick; Bogetoft, Peter
In most organizations, the agent has superior information about the relative costs of different products or activities. This handicaps the principal when the principal seeks to adjust the product mix. Our main conceptual finding is that there is "mix stickiness." The agent's superior information about the relative costs of different products or activities leads to an advantage for the status quo; that is, there is inertia (or stickiness) in the mix of products or activities pursued. The historical mix has an advantage because the asymmetric information about relative costs has less of an impact when the mix does not change. If the mix changes, the producer can extract information rents by claiming high costs on the least reduced or most expanded products. Only in the case of larger shifts in the environment will the mix change. Changing the mix comes with the advantage of making rationing cheaper. Our analysis gives new insight into several business practices. It suggests, for example, that for moderate downsizing, a reinforcement approach of proportionally cutting all activities (lawn mowing) is optimal. When more dramatic downsizing is called for, a reorientation approach of eliminating certain activities (divesting) is optimal. It also suggests that outsourcing may come at the cost of reduced adaptability, and it may help explain why most, if not all, healthcare systems struggle to control cost.</description><author>Antle, Rick; Bogetoft, Peter</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Credit-Collections Optimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chehrazi, Naveed; Glynn, Peter W.; Weber, Thomas A.
Based on a dynamic model of the stochastic repayment behavior exhibited by delinquent credit-card accounts in the form of a self-exciting point process, a bank can control the arrival intensity of repayments using costly account-treatment actions. A semi-analytic solution to the corresponding stochastic optimal control problem is obtained using a recursive approach. For a linear cost of treatment effort, the optimal policy in the two-dimensional (intensity, balance) space is described by the frontier of a convex action region. The unique optimal policy significantly reduces a bank's loss given default and concentrates the collection effort onto the best possible actions at the best possible times so as to minimize the sum of the expected discounted outstanding balance and the discounted cost of the collection effort, thus maximizing the net value of any given delinquent credit-card account.</description><author>Chehrazi, Naveed; Glynn, Peter W.; Weber, Thomas A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Separate and Concentrate: Accounting for Patient Complexity in General Hospitals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuntz, Ludwig; Scholtes, Stefan; Sulz, Sandra
Scholars have recently suggested the reorganization of general hospitals into organizationally separate divisions for routine and non-routine services to overcome operational misalignments between the two types of services. We provide empirical evidence for this proposal from a quality perspective, using over 250,000 patient discharge records from 60 German hospitals across 39 high-mortality disease segments, and focusing on in-hospital mortality as outcome. Disentangling the effects of high, absolute, and relative hospital volumes in a disease group, our analysis suggests that routine and complex patients would benefit from a hospital organization with a multi-specialty hub for emergency and non-routine elective services at its core, complemented by organizationally separate disease-focused hospitals-within-hospitals for routine services. We also provide evidence that the hub hospital can further improve service quality for complex patients by adopting a disease-based rather than medical specialty-based departmental routing strategy for newly arriving patients. A counterfactual analysis, based on a simultaneous equations probit model that simultaneously controls for endogeneity of volume, focus, and routing strategy, suggests that the proposed reorganization could have reduced mortality in the sample by 13.43% (95% CI [6.87%; 18.95%]) for routine patients and by 11.67% (95% CI [6.13%; 16.86%]) for the most complex patients.</description><author>Kuntz, Ludwig; Scholtes, Stefan; Sulz, Sandra</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mobile Messaging for Offline Group Formation in Prosocial Activities: A Large Field Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Tianshu; Gao, Guodong; Jin, Ginger Zhe
In this paper, we use mobile messaging to leverage recipients' social ties and encourage offline prosocial activities in groups. In particular, we conduct a randomized field experiment with 80,000 blood donors and study how behavioral interventions and economic rewards motivate offline group formation. We find that two commonly used interventions-reminder messages and individual reward-are ineffective in motivating group formation because they do not compensate donors for the cost of bringing friends. In contrast, we find that group reward-a new reward that is contingent on a donor bringing a friend-is effective in motivating group formation. Furthermore, group reward tends to attract different types of donors, especially those who are traditionally less active in online social settings but have more local social ties. Structural estimation further reveals the underlying mechanisms, suggesting that group reward is four times more cost-effective than individual reward in driving total donation. Our study suggests that motivating offline group formation is a promising approach to boost prosocial activities.</description><author>Sun, Tianshu; Gao, Guodong; Jin, Ginger Zhe</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Third-Party Reviews and Quality Provision</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Keehyung; Chung, Kevin; Lim, Noah
This paper seeks to understand the relational factors that may affect the decisions of both third-party raters and service providers in a setting where service providers compete with one another. We employ laboratory economics experiments to examine how removing anonymity and allowing for repeated interactions between the rater and the service provider impact both the ratings assigned by the rater and the quality levels expended by the service provider. Our methodology enables us to observe the true quality level chosen by a service provider, which allows us to accurately detect any bias in the assessment of the third-party rater. The experimental results show that the decisions of both the rater and the service provider are very sensitive to the relational factors that govern their interaction. When the rater and the service provider know each other's identities, we observe a high proportion of overrating even though raters earn less monetary rewards for doing so, and the propensity to overrate is even stronger with repeated interactions. Furthermore, the service provider chooses low quality levels. We develop and estimate a model that captures the rater's psychological trade-off between remaining objective and helping the service provider compete in the marketplace, and the evolution of the service provider's beliefs about the rater's preferences.</description><author>Kim, Keehyung; Chung, Kevin; Lim, Noah</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intertemporal Price Discrimination with Complementary Products: E-Books and E-Readers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Hui
This paper studies intertemporal price discrimination (IPD) with complementary products in the context of e-readers and e-books. Using individual-level data (2008-2012), I estimate a dynamic demand model for e-reader adoption and subsequent book quantity, reading format, and retailer choices in several book genres. I use the estimates to simulate a monopolist's optimal dynamic pricing strategies when facing forward-looking consumers. The results illustrate how skimming/penetration pricing incentives for e-readers and harvesting/investing incentives for e-books interact in this novel setting. The optimal joint IPD strategy is skimming for e-readers and investing for e-books. Counterfactual results suggest that combining IPD with complementary product pricing improves firm profitability because it attenuates the limitations of each pricing approach. In a single-product IPD setting, firms' pricing power is limited when consumers anticipate future price changes and delay purchases. Adding complementary products offers firms two pricing instruments; opposite price trajectories provide conflicting incentives for consumers, limiting intertemporal arbitrage. In a static complementary product setting, firms' pricing power is limited when the relative elasticity between the two products is heterogeneous and conflicting among consumers. Adding IPD sorts heterogeneous consumers into different periods and reduces the need to balance across consumer types.</description><author>Li, Hui</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Sale and Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bimpikis, Kostas; Crapis, Davide; Tahbaz-Salehi, Alireza
This paper studies the strategic interaction between a monopolistic seller of an information product and a set of potential buyers that compete in a downstream market. The setting is motivated by information markets in which (i) sellers have the ability to offer information products of different qualities and (ii) the information product provides potential buyers not only with more precise information about the fundamentals, but also with a coordination device that can be used in their strategic interactions with their competitors. Our results illustrate that the nature and intensity of competition among the information provider's customers play first-order roles in determining the information provider's optimal strategy. We show that when the customers view their actions as strategic complements, the provider finds it optimal to offer the most accurate information at the provider's disposal to all potential customers. In contrast, when buyers view their actions as strategic substitutes, the provider maximizes the provider's profits by either (i) restricting the overall supply of the information product or (ii) distorting its content by offering a product of inferior quality. We also establish that the provider's incentive to restrict the supply or quality of information provided to the downstream market intensifies in the presence of information leakage.</description><author>Bimpikis, Kostas; Crapis, Davide; Tahbaz-Salehi, Alireza</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finding a Needle in a Haystack: The Effects of Searching and Learning on Pick-Worker Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Batt, Robert J.; Gallino, Santiago
The rise in online and multichannel retailing has pushed retailers to give increased attention to their order-fulfillment operations. We study "chaotic storage" fulfillment systems in which dissimilar items are stored together in a single location. This necessitates a searching task as part of the picking process, which has not been previously studied. We show that pick times increase by as much as 16% as the searching task becomes more difficult. However, the deleterious effect of searching decreases with pick-worker experience. Using simulation, we show that pick times can be improved by incorporating distance, bin density, and picker experience into pick assignments and pick routing. Through properly combining the details of the task and the workers, order-fulfillment productivity can be increased by approximately 5%.</description><author>Batt, Robert J.; Gallino, Santiago</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer Search and Retail Market Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rhodes, Andrew; Zhou, Jidong
A puzzling feature of many retail markets is the coexistence of large multiproduct firms and smaller firms with narrow product ranges. This paper provides a possible explanation for this puzzle, by studying how consumer search frictions influence the structure of retail markets. In our model, single-product firms that supply different products can merge to form a multiproduct firm. Consumers wish to buy multiple products and, due to search frictions, value the one-stop shopping convenience associated with a multiproduct firm. We find that, when search frictions are relatively large, all firms are multiproduct in equilibrium. However, when search frictions are smaller, the equilibrium market structure is asymmetric, with different retail formats coexisting. This allows firms to better segment the market and, as such, typically leads to the weakest price competition. When search frictions are low, this asymmetric market structure is also the worst for consumers. Moreover, due to the endogeneity of market structure, a reduction in the search friction can increase market prices and harm consumers.</description><author>Rhodes, Andrew; Zhou, Jidong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Selection of Risk Models and Bank Capital Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colliard, Jean-Edouard
The regulatory use of banks' internal models makes capital requirements more risk sensitive but invites regulatory arbitrage. I develop a framework to study bank regulation with strategic selection of risk models. A bank supervisor can discourage arbitrage by auditing risk models and implements capital ratios less risk sensitive than in the first-best to reduce auditing costs. The optimal capital ratios of a national supervisor can be different from those set by supranational authorities, in which case the supervisor optimally tolerates biased models. I discuss the empirical implications of this "hidden model" problem, and policy answers such as leverage ratios and more reliance on backtesting mechanisms.</description><author>Colliard, Jean-Edouard</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Design Implications of Extended Producer Responsibility for Durable Products</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Ximin; Atasu, Atalay; Toktay, L. Beril
We analyze product design implications of extended producer responsibility (EPR)-based take-back legislation on durable goods. In particular, we observe that durable product design incentives under EPR may involve an inherent trade-off that has not been explored to date: Durable goods producers can respond to EPR by making their products more recyclable or more durable, where the former decreases the unit recycling cost and the latter reduces the volume the producer has to recycle. When these two design attributes do not go hand in hand, as is the case for many product categories, product design implications of EPR can be counterintuitive. We find that more stringent collection targets (defined as the portion of total product volume to be collected) or recycling targets (defined as the portion of each collected product unit to be recycled) may imply reduced recyclability or durability. Moreover, although collection and recycling targets appear to be similar EPR implementation levers for increasing the total amount of materials recycled, they, in fact, have opposing effects in driving producers' design choices. As a result, EPR may have unintended consequences for the environment. A calibrated numerical study on the photovoltaic panel (PVP) industry allows us to show that more stringent EPR requirements (such as those proposed by the recent recast of the WEEE directive) can lead to a PVP technology choice with lower recyclability and higher durability and, consequently, result in higher greenhouse gas emissions. These results call for a careful analysis of the benefits of EPR legislation in the context of durable goods.</description><author>Huang, Ximin; Atasu, Atalay; Toktay, L. Beril</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lobbying on Regulator" Enforcement Actions: Evidence from US Commercial and Savings Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lambert, Thomas
This paper analyzes the relationship between bank lobbying and supervisory decisions of regulators and documents its moral hazard implications. Exploiting bank-level information on the universe of commercial and savings banks in the United States, I find that regulators are 44.7% less likely to initiate enforcement actions against lobbying banks. This result is robust across measures of lobbying and accounts for endogeneity concerns by employing instrumental variables strategies. In addition, I show that lobbying banks are riskier and reliably underperform their nonlobbying peers. Overall, these results appear rather inconsistent with an information-based explanation of bank lobbying, but consistent with the theory of regulatory capture.</description><author>Lambert, Thomas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Good and Bad Variance Premia and Expected Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kilic, Mete; Shaliastovich, Ivan
We measure "good" and "bad" variance premia that capture risk compensations for the realized variation in positive and negative market returns, respectively. The two variance premium components jointly predict excess returns over the next one and two years with statistically significant positive (negative) coefficients on the good (bad) component. The R(2)s reach about 10% for aggregate equity and portfolio returns and 20% for corporate bond returns. To explain the new empirical evidence, we develop a model that highlights the differential impact of upside and downside risk on equity and variance risk premia.</description><author>Kilic, Mete; Shaliastovich, Ivan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fostering Entrepreneurship: Promoting Founding or Funding?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hellmann, Thomas; Thiele, Veikko
Governments across the globe are eager to foster entrepreneurial ecosystems, yet there is no consensus on what policies to use. We develop a theory about the equilibrium consequences of two canonical types of entrepreneurship policies: policies that encourage entrepreneurs to found new ventures and policies that encourage investors to fund new ventures. We distinguish between a short-term impact on current market activity versus a long-term impact on future activity. Investing in entrepreneurial ventures requires tacit knowledge that is mainly acquired through prior entrepreneurial experience, implying that the supply of capital depends on successful entrepreneurs from prior generations. Recognizing this intergenerational linkage has a profound impact on the market equilibrium and the effect of entrepreneurship policies. Our analysis identifies a rationale for using funding polices.</description><author>Hellmann, Thomas; Thiele, Veikko</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Offshoring Return Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoberg, Gerard; Moon, S. Katie
We use 10-K filings to construct novel text-based measures of the extent to which U.S. firms are exposed to three offshore activities: the sale of output, purchase of input, and ownership of producing assets. Our main result is that selling output abroad is associated with higher stock returns, especially when output is sold to more central nations in the real trade network. In contrast, offshore input serves as a hedge. Our findings are consistent with the conclusion that aggregate quantity shocks are the primary source of the return premium we document in the global trade network.</description><author>Hoberg, Gerard; Moon, S. Katie</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Asymmetric Social Ties, Structural Embeddedness, and Tie Strength on Online Content Contribution Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rishika, Rishika; Ramaprasad, Jui
For a social media community to thrive and grow, it is critical that users of the site interact with each other and contribute content to the site. We study the role of social ties in motivating user preference expression, a form of user content contribution, in an online social media community. We examine the role of three types of ties, reciprocated, follower, and followee ties, and assess whether the structural and relational properties of a user's social network moderate the social influence effect in user contribution. A unique disaggregate level panel data set of users' contributions and social tie formation activities from an online music platform is employed to study the impact of social ties. To address identification issues, we adopt a quasi-experimental approach based on dynamic propensity score matching. The results provide strong evidence of the influence of online network ties in online contribution behavior. We find that the influence of reciprocated ties is the greatest, followed by influence from followee ties and then follower ties. Additional analysis reveals that reciprocated and followee ties have even greater influence when they contribute new information for a focal user. Structural embeddedness and tie strength among network ties are found to amplify the effect of social contagion in online contribution. We conduct several sensitivity and robustness checks that lend credible support to our findings. The results add to the greater understanding of social influence in online contribution and provide valuable managerial insights into designs of online communities to enable greater user participation.</description><author>Rishika, Rishika; Ramaprasad, Jui</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Has Section 404 of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act Discouraged Corporate Investment? New Evidence from a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albuquerque, Ana; Zhu, Julie Lei
Prior studies conclude that an unintended consequence of firms complying with the Sarbanes-Oxley Act is lower levels of risk-taking activities, including investment. We first show that prior studies cannot isolate the effects of SOX from other contemporaneous events. We then use the implementation requirements of SOX404 to construct a natural experiment that isolates the effects of SOX404 for a sample of small firms. We do not find a reduction in investment and other risk-taking activities for firms that had to comply with SOX404, relative to other firms. Because small firms are expected to be the most adversely affected by the regulation, our results cast doubt on the notion that SOX404 had a negative impact on larger firms.</description><author>Albuquerque, Ana; Zhu, Julie Lei</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Only When Others Are Watching: The Contingent Efforts of High Status Group Members</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lount, Robert B.; Doyle, Sarah P.; Brion, Sebastien; Pettit, Nathan C.
This research examines how an individual's place in the status hierarchy affects their willingness to expend effort on group tasks, why this occurs, and a contingency governing this relationship. Among firefighter teams (Study 1), MBA student workgroups (Study 2), and undergraduates in the laboratory (Study 3), we find that the relationship between status and effort, through performance expectations, is contingent on the perceived visibility of one's efforts (i.e., task visibility). When task visibility is high, greater status leads to higher performance expectations. When task visibility is low or absent, this relationship was not present. Overall, our findings help paint a more complete picture of the relationship between status, performance expectations, and effort in workgroups while also furthering our understanding of the psychological experience of status.</description><author>Lount, Robert B.; Doyle, Sarah P.; Brion, Sebastien; Pettit, Nathan C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Primacy of "What" over "How Much": How Type and Quantity Shape Healthiness Perceptions of Food Portions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Peggy J.; Haws, Kelly L.; Scherr, Karen; Redden, Joseph P.; Bettman, James R.; Fitzsimons, Gavan J.
Healthy eating goals influence many consumer choices, such that evaluating the healthiness of food portions is important. Given that both the type and quantity of food jointly contribute to weight and overall health, evaluations of a food portion's healthiness ought to consider both type and quantity. However, existing literature tends to examine food type and food quantity separately. Across seven studies, we show that consumers treat type as a primary dimension and quantity as a secondary dimension, such that a change in type (versus quantity) has a greater impact on perceived healthiness or health goal impact, even when holding objective impact constant in terms of calories. We also examine whether one reason this effect occurs is because most consumers consider type (a categorical attribute) before quantity (a continuous attribute). We conclude by discussing extensions of these ideas to other perceptual assessments involving both type and quantity (e.g., price perceptions).</description><author>Liu, Peggy J.; Haws, Kelly L.; Scherr, Karen; Redden, Joseph P.; Bettman, James R.; Fitzsimons, Gavan J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multiple Goals as Reference Points: One Failure Makes Everything Else Feel Worse</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weingarten, Evan; Bhatia, Sudeep; Mellers, Barbara
It is well known that goals serve as reference points, and their influence on pleasure can be understood with prospect theory's value function. We examine how people feel about their progress on two goals (i.e., academics and fitness). What happens when they achieve one goal but fail to reach another? In four studies, we test the assumptions needed to explain hedonic reactions to progress along two goals. Loss aversion and diminishing sensitivity hold on each variable separately. However, we find violations of additivity in the integration of the emotions about outcomes. A success in one goal and a failure in another feel worse than the sum of the pleasure and pain associated with the gain and loss, respectively.</description><author>Weingarten, Evan; Bhatia, Sudeep; Mellers, Barbara</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing Through Asset Sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex; Mann, William
Most research on firm financing studies debt versus equity issuance. We model an alternative source, non-core asset sales, and identify three new factors that contrast it with equity. First, unlike asset purchasers, equity investors own a claim to the firm's balance sheet (the "balance sheet effect"). This includes the cash raised, mitigating information asymmetry. Contrary to the intuition of Myers and Majluf [Myers SC, Majluf NS (1984) Corporate financing and investment decisions when firms have information that investors do not have. J. Financial Econom. 13(2):187-2211, even if non-core assets exhibit less information asymmetry, the firm issues equity if the financing need is high. Second, firms can disguise the sale of low-quality assets-but not equity-as motivated by dissynergies (the "camouflage effect"). Third, selling equity implies a "lemons" discount for not only the equity issued but also the rest of the firm, since both are perfectly correlated (the "correlation effect"). A discount on assets need not reduce the stock price, since non-core assets are not a carbon copy of the firm.</description><author>Edmans, Alex; Mann, William</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political Promotion, CEO Incentives, and the Relationship Between Pay and Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Xiaping; Lemmon, Michael; Pan, Xiaofei; Qian, Meijun; Tian, Gary
Both theory and empirical evidence suggest that managers' career concerns can serve as an important source of implicit economic incentives. We examine how incentives for political promotion are related to compensation policy and firm performance in Chinese state-owned enterprises. We find that the likelihood that the CEO receives a political promotion is positively related to firm performance. We also find that CEOs with a higher likelihood of political promotion have lower pay levels and lower pay-performance sensitivity. Overall, the evidence suggests that competition in the political job market helps mitigate weak monetary incentives for CEOs in China.</description><author>Cao, Xiaping; Lemmon, Michael; Pan, Xiaofei; Qian, Meijun; Tian, Gary</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Algorithmic Bias? An Empirical Study of Apparent Gender-Based Discrimination in the Display of STEM Career Ads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lambrecht, Anja; Tucker, Catherine
We explore data from a field test of how an algorithm delivered ads promoting job opportunities in the science, technology, engineering and math fields. This ad was explicitly intended to be gender neutral in its delivery. Empirically, however, fewer women saw the ad than men. This happened because younger women are a prized demographic and are more expensive to show ads to. An algorithm that simply optimizes cost-effectiveness in ad delivery will deliver ads that were intended to be gender neutral in an apparently discriminatory way, because of crowding out. We show that this empirical regularity extends to other major digital platforms.</description><author>Lambrecht, Anja; Tucker, Catherine</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Responsive Pricing of Fashion Products: The Effects of Demand Learning and Strategic Consumer Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aviv, Yossi; Wei, Mike Mingcheng; Zhang, Fuqiang
This paper studies the potential benefits of responsive pricing and demand learning to sellers of seasonal fashion goods. As typical in such markets, demand uncertainty is high at the beginning of a season, but there is a potential opportunity to learn about demand via early sales observations. Additionally, although the consumers have general preference for purchasing a fashion product earlier rather than later in the season, they may exhibit strategic behavior-contemplating the benefits of postponing their purchase in anticipation of end-of-season discounts. Our results demonstrate that the benefits of responsive pricing, in comparison with a benchmark case of a fixed-price policy, depend sharply on the nature of the consumers' behavior. Interestingly, in stark contrast to markets of myopic consumers, when the consumers are all strategic, the benefits of responsive pricing tend to worsen when there is a higher potential for learning. We explain this counterintuitive outcome by pointing to two phenomena: the spread effect and information shaping. For example, sellers of fashion products that consider upgrading their pricing systems to incorporate "accurate response" strategies (i.e., integrating learning and responsive pricing) should be aware of the possibility that such action might lead them to a new and potentially worse equilibrium, particularly when there is a higher opportunity to learn. Despite the fact that price commitment completely eliminates the seller's ability to learn, it appears to increasingly dominate responsive pricing as the portion of strategic consumers in the market increases. But, although performing better than responsive pricing, a price-commitment policy is typically limited in performing effective discrimination. Finally, we studied the potential benefits of quick response strategies-ones that embed both dynamic pricing and quick inventory replenishment during the sales season-and found that they are particularly significant under strategic consumer behavior. We explain this result by arguing that quick response provides the seller with a real option that serves as an effective implicit threat to the consumers: encouraging them to buy earlier at premium prices rather than wait for discounts at the end of the season.</description><author>Aviv, Yossi; Wei, Mike Mingcheng; Zhang, Fuqiang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sex Matters: Gender Bias in the Mutual Fund Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Niessen-Ruenzi, Alexandra; Ruenzi, Stefan
We document significantly lower inflows in female-managed funds than in male-managed funds. This result is obtained with field data and with data from a laboratory experiment. We find no gender differences in performance. Thus, rational statistical discrimination is unlikely to explain the fund flow effect. We conduct an implicit association test and find that subjects with stronger gender bias according to this test invest significantly less in female-managed funds. Our results suggest that gender bias affects investment decisions and thus offer a new potential explanation for the low fraction of women in the mutual fund industry.</description><author>Niessen-Ruenzi, Alexandra; Ruenzi, Stefan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Market Predictability and Industrial Metal Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobsen, Ben; Marshall, Ben R.; Visaltanachoti, Nuttawat
Price movements in industrial metals such as copper and aluminum predict stock returns. Increasing industrial metal prices are good news for equity markets in recessions and bad news in expansions. A one-standard-deviation increase in industrial metal returns predicts a price drop of one and a half percent in monthly stock market returns in expansions and an increase of around a half percent during recessions. The predictability is distinct to and compares favorably with that from more established predictors.</description><author>Jacobsen, Ben; Marshall, Ben R.; Visaltanachoti, Nuttawat</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Reaction to Mandatory Nonfinancial Disclosure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grewal, Jody; Riedl, Edward J.; Serafeim, George
We examine the equity market reaction to events associated with the passage of a directive in the European Union (EU) mandating increased nonfinancial disclosure. These disclosures relate to firms' environmental, social, and governance (ESG) performance, and would be applicable to firms listed on EU exchanges or with significant operations in the EU. We predict and find (i) an average negative market reaction of -0.79% across all firms, (ii) a less negative market reaction for firms having higher predirective nonfinancial performance, and (iii) a less negative reaction for firms having higher predirective nonfinancial disclosure levels. In addition, results are accentuated for firms having the most material ESG issues, as well as investors anticipating proprietary and political costs as a result of the mandated disclosures. Finally, we find that the negative market reaction is concentrated in firms with weak preregulation ESG performance and disclosure, which exhibit an average return of -1.54%; in contrast, firms with strong preregulation disclosure and performance exhibit an average positive return of 0.52%. Overall, the results are consistent with the equity market perceiving net costs (benefits) for firms with weak (strong) nonfinancial performance and disclosure around key events surrounding the mandatory disclosure regulation of nonfinancial information.</description><author>Grewal, Jody; Riedl, Edward J.; Serafeim, George</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Vulnerability Analysis of the Financial Network</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khabazian, Aein; Peng, Jiming
Since the financial crisis in 2007-2008, the vulnerability of a financial system has become a major concern in financial engineering. In this paper, we analyze the vulnerability of a financial network based on the linear optimization model introduced by Eisenberg and Noe [Eisenberg L, Noe TH (2001) Systemic risk in financial systems. Management Sci. 47(2):236-249.], in which the right-hand side of the constraints is subject to market shock and only limited information regarding the liability matrix is exposed. We develop a new extended sensitivity analysis to characterize the conditions under which a bank is solvent, in default, or bankrupted and estimate the probability of insolvency and the probability of bankruptcy under mild conditions on the market shock and the network structure. Particularly, we show that although an increment in the total asset may not be able to improve the stability of the financial system, a larger asset inequality in the system will reduce its stability. Moreover, under a certain assumption on the market shock and the network structure, we show that the least stable network can be attained at some network with a monopoly node, which also has the highest probability of insolvency. The probability of bankruptcy in the network when all the nodes receive shocks is estimated. We also estimate the impact of bankruptcy of the monopoly node in a well-balanced network and explore the domino effect of bankruptcy when the network has a tridiagonal structure. Numerical experiments are presented to verify the theoretical conclusions.</description><author>Khabazian, Aein; Peng, Jiming</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade Relationships, Indirect Economic Links, and Mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harford, Jarrad; Schonlau, Robert; Stanfield, Jared
The economic links between firms created by customer and supplier relationships are critical determinants of those firms' values and actions. We demonstrate that significant trade relationships and indirect economic links incrementally explain which firms are more likely to be involved in acquisitions, which pairs of firms are more likely to merge, and which mergers will have the greatest impact, both on value and in motivating follow-on mergers by rivals. Firms with major trade relationships are significantly less likely to acquire, or be acquired by, firms that do not share in those relationships.</description><author>Harford, Jarrad; Schonlau, Robert; Stanfield, Jared</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tail Risk Concerns Everywhere</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, George P.; Lu, Xiaomeng; Song, Zhaogang
We show that the beta with respect to an index of global ex ante tail risk concerns (GRIX), which we construct using out-of-the-money options on multiple global assets, negatively drives cross-sectional return variations across asset classes, including international equity indices, foreign currencies, and government bond futures. The pricing power of GRIX becomes stronger when more asset-class-level tail risk concerns are incorporated in the index construction. GRIX also dominates asset-class-level tail risk concerns in pricing assets within each asset class. These evidences imply that the pricing effect of tail risk concerns works predominantly as a global channel. The GRIX pricing effect is distinct from that of tail risk factors based on historical realizations, consistent with the interpretation that tail risk concerns likely reflect investors' ex ante subjective belief about tail risk.</description><author>Gao, George P.; Lu, Xiaomeng; Song, Zhaogang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning Preferences with Side Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Farias, Vivek F.; Li, Andrew A.
Product and content personalization is now ubiquitous in e-commerce. There are typically not enough available transactional data for this task. As such, companies today seek to use a variety of information on the interactions between a product and a customer to drive personalization decisions. We formalize this problem as one of recovering a large-scale matrix with side information in the form of additional matrices of conforming dimension. Viewing the matrix we seek to recover and the side information we have as slices of a tensor, we consider the problem of slice recovery, which is to recover specific slices of "simple" tensors from noisy observations of the entire tensor. We propose a definition of simplicity that on the one hand elegantly generalizes a standard generative model for our motivating problem and on the other hand subsumes low-rank tensors for a variety of existing definitions of tensor rank. We provide an efficient algorithm for slice recovery that is practical for massive data sets and provides a significant performance improvement over state-of-the-art incumbent approaches to tensor recovery. Furthermore, we establish near-optimal recovery guarantees that, in an important regime, represent an order improvement over the best available results for this problem. Experiments on data from a music streaming service demonstrate the performance and scalability of our algorithm.</description><author>Farias, Vivek F.; Li, Andrew A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Supplier Diversification Under Buyer Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chod, Jiri; Trichakis, Nikolaos; Tsoukalas, Gerry
When should a firm diversify its supply base? Most extant theories attribute supplier diversification to supplier risk. Herein, we develop a new theory that attributes supplier diversification to buyer risk. When suppliers are subject to the risk of buyer default, buyers may take costly action to signal creditworthiness so as to obtain more favorable terms. But once signaling costs are sunk, buyers sourcing from a single supplier become vulnerable to future holdup. Although ex ante supply base diversification can be effective at alleviating the holdup problem, we show that it comes at the expense of higher up-front signaling costs. We resolve the ensuing trade-off and show that diversification emerges as the preferred strategy in equilibrium. Our theory can help explain sourcing strategies when risk in a trade relationship originates from the sourcing firm, for example, a small-to-medium enterprise or a start-up; a setting that has eluded existing theories so far.</description><author>Chod, Jiri; Trichakis, Nikolaos; Tsoukalas, Gerry</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Impact of Managerial Commitment on Risk Taking with Dynamic Fund Flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaniel, Ron; Tompaidis, Stathis; Zhou, Ti
We present a model with dynamic investment flows, where fund managers have the ability to generate excess returns, and study how forcing them to commit part or all of their personal wealth to the fund they manage affects fund risk taking. We contrast the behavior of a manager who may invest her personal wealth in a private account to a manager who is either forced to commit her wealth to the fund she manages or not allowed to hold risky assets held by the fund privately. We show that a fund managed by a manager with higher ability does not necessarily achieve higher expected returns but achieves lower idiosyncratic volatility. For a manager with constant ability, restrictions placed on her personal account do not influence her choices in the fund, while for a manager whose ability varies stochastically, they result in higher expected returns and idiosyncratic volatilities. Fund strategies can be nonmonotone both in the manager's commitment level and the ratio of manager to investor wealth. Our results are robust to incomplete information and to competing managers with correlated ability.</description><author>Kaniel, Ron; Tompaidis, Stathis; Zhou, Ti</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Yardstick Competition Reduce Waiting Times?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Savva, Nicos; Tezcan, Tolga; Yildiz, Ozlem
Yardstick competition is a regulatory scheme for local monopolists (e.g., hospitals), where the monopolist's reimbursement is linked to performance relative to other equivalent monopolists. This regulatory scheme is known to provide cost-reduction incentives and serves as the theoretical underpinning behind the hospital prospective reimbursement system used throughout the developed world. This paper uses a game-theoretic queueing model to investigate how yardstick competition performs in service systems (e.g., hospital emergency departments), where in addition to incentivizing cost reduction the regulator wants to incentivize waiting time reduction. We first show that the form of cost-based yardstick competition used in practice results in inefficiently long waiting times. We then demonstrate how yardstick competition can be appropriately modified to achieve the dual goal of cost and waiting-time reduction. In particular, we show that full efficiency (first-best) can be restored if the regulator makes the providers' reimbursement contingent on their service rates and is also able to charge a provider-specific "toll" to consumers. More important, if such a toll is not feasible, as may be the case in healthcare, we show that there exists an alternative and particularly simple yardstick-competition scheme, which depends on the average waiting time only, that can significantly improve system efficiency (second-best). This scheme is easier to implement because it does not require the regulator to have detailed knowledge of the queueing discipline. We conclude with a numerical investigation that provides insights on the practical implementation of yardstick competition for hospital emergency departments, and we also present a series of modelling extensions.</description><author>Savva, Nicos; Tezcan, Tolga; Yildiz, Ozlem</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Time Shifting on TV Consumption and Ad Viewership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Belo, Rodrigo; Ferreira, Pedro; de Matos, Miguel Godinho; Reis, Filipa
In this paper we study the impact of time shifting on TV consumption and ad viewership. We analyze the results of a field experiment in which a random sample of "triple-play" households were given a set of premium TV channels broadcasting popular movies and TV shows without commercial breaks. A random subset of these households were given access to these channels with time shifting (automated cloud recording for later viewing or rewinding of broadcasted programs), while the remainder were not. This design allowed us to identify the effects of time shifting on TV consumption. On average, we found that receiving access to the channels with time shifting increased total TV consumption because it increased time-shifted viewership while leaving live viewership unchanged. The increase in the live viewership of these channels was similar to the reduction in the live viewership of the originally available channels, resulting in a net zero effect on live viewership. It appears that time shifting does not change the concentration of live viewership, but it does increase the concentration of total TV viewership, because it is used disproportionately to watch the most popular programs. Finally, we found that time shifting does not change the likelihood of skipping ads during live viewership, suggesting that households do not use time shifting to strategically avoid ads.</description><author>Belo, Rodrigo; Ferreira, Pedro; de Matos, Miguel Godinho; Reis, Filipa</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Product Design by Sequential Experiments in High Dimensions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Joo, Mingyu; Thompson, Michael L.; Allenby, Greg M.
The identification of optimal product and package designs is challenged when attributes and their levels interact. Firms recognize this by testing trial products and designs prior to launch, during which the effects of interactions are revealed. A difficulty in conducting analysis for product design is dealing with the high dimensionality of the design space and the selection of promising product configurations for testing. We propose an experimental criterion for efficiently testing product profiles with high demand potential in sequential experiments. The criterion is based on the expected improvement in market share of a design beyond the current best alternative. We also incorporate a stochastic search variable selection method to selectively estimate relevant interactions among the attributes. A validation experiment confirms that our proposed method leads to improved design concepts in a high-dimensional space compared with alternative methods.</description><author>Joo, Mingyu; Thompson, Michael L.; Allenby, Greg M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overcommitment in Cloud Services: Bin Packing with Chance Constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Maxime C.; Keller, Philipp W.; Mirrokni, Vahab; Zadimoghaddam, Morteza
This paper considers a traditional problem of resource allocation: scheduling jobs on machines. One such recent application is cloud computing; jobs arrive in an online fashion with capacity requirements and need to be immediately scheduled on physical machines in data centers. It is often observed that the requested capacities are not fully utilized, hence offering an opportunity to employ an overcommitment policy, that is, selling resources beyond capacity. Setting the right overcommitment level can yield a significant cost reduction for the cloud provider while only inducing a very low risk of violating capacity constraints. We introduce and study a model that quantifies the value of overcommitment by modeling the problem as bin packing with chance constraints. We then propose an alternative formulation that transforms each chance constraint to a submodular function. We show that our model captures the risk pooling effect and can guide scheduling and overcommitment decisions. We also develop a family of online algorithms that are intuitive, easy to implement, and provide a constant factor guarantee from optimal. Finally, we calibrate our model using realistic workload data and test our approach in a practical setting. Our analysis and experiments illustrate the benefit of overcommitment in cloud services and suggest a cost reduction of 1.5% to 17%, depending on the provider's risk tolerance.</description><author>Cohen, Maxime C.; Keller, Philipp W.; Mirrokni, Vahab; Zadimoghaddam, Morteza</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gender Differences in Job Entry Decisions: A University-Wide Field Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Samek, Anya
The gender difference in competitiveness has been cited as an important factor driving the gender gap in labor market outcomes. Using a field experiment with more than 35,000 university students, I explore the impact of compensation scheme on willingness to apply for a job. I find that competitive compensation schemes that depend on relative performance disproportionately deter women from applying. I do not find the same deterrence effect under a compensation scheme in which students face uncertain payoffs independent of performance. I also test the impact of describing the job as helping a charity, and this increases the willingness to apply but does not affect the gender gap. My findings are important for managers, who need to understand the impact of different compensation schemes on the share of women recruited for a job posting.</description><author>Samek, Anya</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"Dice"-sion-Making Under Uncertainty: When Can a Random Decision Reduce Risk?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delage, Erick; Kuhn, Daniel; Wiesemann, Wolfram
Stochastic programming and distributionally robust optimization seek deterministic decisions that optimize a risk measure, possibly in view of the most adverse distribution in an ambiguity set. We investigate under which circumstances such deterministic decisions are strictly outperformed by random decisions, which depend on a randomization device producing uniformly distributed samples that are independent of all uncertain factors affecting the decision problem. We find that, in the absence of distributional ambiguity, deterministic decisions are optimal if both the risk measure and the feasible region are convex or alternatively, if the risk measure is mixture quasiconcave. We show that some risk measures, such as mean (semi-)deviation and mean (semi-)moment measures, fail to be mixture quasiconcave and can, therefore, give rise to problems in which the decision maker benefits from randomization. Under distributional ambiguity, however, we show that, for any ambiguity-averse risk measure satisfying a mild continuity property, we can construct a decision problem in which a randomized decision strictly outperforms all deterministic decisions.</description><author>Delage, Erick; Kuhn, Daniel; Wiesemann, Wolfram</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>