<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>MS6</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Estimating Demand for Mobile Applications in the New Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghose, Anindya; Han, Sang Pil
In 2013, the global mobile app market was estimated at over US$50 billion and is expected to grow to $150 billion in the next two years. In this paper, we build a structural econometric model to quantify the vibrant platform competition between mobile (smartphone and tablet) apps on the Apple iOS and Google Android platforms and estimate consumer preferences toward different mobile app characteristics. We find that app demand increases with the in-app purchase option wherein a user can complete transactions within the app. On the contrary, app demand decreases with the in-app advertisement option where consumers are shown ads while they are engaging with the app. The direct effects on app revenue from the inclusion of an in-app purchase option and an in-app advertisement option are equivalent to offering a 28% price discount and increasing the price by 8%, respectively. We also find that a price discount strategy results in a greater increase of app demand in Google Play compared with Apple App Store, and app developers can maximize their revenue by providing a 50% discount on their paid apps. Using the estimated demand function, we find that mobile apps have enhanced consumer surplus by approximately $33.6 billion annually in the United States, and we discuss various implications for mobile marketing analytics, app pricing, and app design strategies.</description><author>Ghose, Anindya; Han, Sang Pil</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gender Interactions Within the Family Firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amore, Mario Daniele; Garofalo, Orsola; Minichilli, Alessandro
We analyze whether gender interactions at the top of the corporate hierarchy affect corporate performance. Using a comprehensive data set of family-controlled firms in Italy, we find that female directors significantly improve the operating profitability of female-led companies. To mitigate endogeneity concerns, we assess executive transitions using a triple-difference approach complemented by propensity score matching and instrumental variables. Finally, we show that the positive effect of female interactions on profitability is reduced when the firm is located in geographic areas characterized by gender prejudices and when the firm is large.</description><author>Amore, Mario Daniele; Garofalo, Orsola; Minichilli, Alessandro</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Does the Devil Make Work? An Empirical Study of the Impact of Workload on Worker Productivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tan, Tom Fangyun; Netessine, Serguei
we analyze a large, detailed operational data set from a restaurant chain to shed new light on how workload (defined as the number of tables or diners that a server simultaneously handles) affects servers' performance (measured as sales and meal duration). We use an exogenous shock-the implementation of labor scheduling software-and time-lagged instrumental variables to disentangle the endogeneity between demand and supply in this setting. We show that servers strive to maximize sales and speed efforts simultaneously, depending on the relative values of sales and speed. As a result, we find that, when the overall workload is small, servers expend more and more sales efforts with the increase in workload at a cost of slower service speed. However, above a certain workload threshold, servers start to reduce their sales efforts and work more promptly with the further rise in workload. In the focal restaurant chain, we find that this saturation point is currently not reached and, counterintuitively, the chain can reduce the staffing level and achieve both significantly higher sales (an estimated 3% increase) and lower labor costs (an estimated 17% decrease).</description><author>Tan, Tom Fangyun; Netessine, Serguei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Partnership Formation: The Role of Social Status</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, Haimanti; Dugar, Subhasish
We experimentally test for the effect of social status on the likelihood of partnership formation. We consider a two-player game where the opportunity to perform a hidden action by one player may render partnership formation difficult. In this context, we study how the assignment of partners' status to the top, middle, or bottom position of a preexisting status hierarchy affects collaboration. We find that partnership formation is remarkably sensitive to the partners' status affiliations. Collaboration is easiest when both partners share the same social status, and the probability of partnership formation decreases significantly as the status gap between the partners increases, entailing massive inefficiency.</description><author>Bhattacharya, Haimanti; Dugar, Subhasish</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring the Performance of Large-Scale Combinatorial Auctions: A Structural Estimation Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Sang Won; Olivares, Marcelo; Weintraub, Gabriel Y.
The main advantage of a procurement combinatorial auction (CA) is that it allows suppliers to express cost synergies through package bids. However, bidders can also strategically take advantage of this flexibility, by discounting package bids and "inflating" bid prices for single items, even in the absence of cost synergies; the latter behavior can hurt the performance of the auction. It is an empirical question whether allowing package bids and running a CA improves performance in a given setting. In this paper, we develop a structural estimation approach that estimates the firms' cost structure using bidding data and use these estimates to evaluate the performance of the auction. To overcome the computational difficulties arising from the large number of bids observed in large-scale CAs, we propose a novel simplified model of bidders' behavior based on pricing package characteristics. We apply our method to the Chilean school meals auction, in which the government procures half a billion dollars' worth of meal services every year and bidders submit thousands of package bids. Our estimates suggest that bidders' cost synergies are economically significant in this application (similar to 5%), and the current CA mechanism achieves high allocative efficiency (similar to 98%) and reasonable margins for the bidders (similar to 5%). Overall, this work develops the first practical tool to evaluate the performance of large-scale first-price CAs commonly used in procurement settings.</description><author>Kim, Sang Won; Olivares, Marcelo; Weintraub, Gabriel Y.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comment on "A Model of Probabilistic Choice Satisfying First-Order Stochastic Dominance" by Pavlo Blavatskyy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loomes, Graham; Rodriguez-Puerta, Inmaculada; Pinto-Prades, Jose-Luis
We present examples of existing evidence that lead us to be cautious about claims made in the original paper [Blavatskyy PR (2011) A model of probabilistic choice satisfying first-order stochastic dominance. Management Sci. 57(3):542-548] that the proposed model provides a better fit to experimental data than do existing models. We raise concerns about the accuracy of this and other assertions and about the adequacy of the comparisons made with alternative models in the existing literature.</description><author>Loomes, Graham; Rodriguez-Puerta, Inmaculada; Pinto-Prades, Jose-Luis</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Will the Global Village Fracture Into Tribes? Recommender Systems and Their Effects on Consumer Fragmentation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hosanagar, Kartik; Fleder, Daniel; Lee, Dokyun; Buja, Andreas
Personalization is becoming ubiquitous on the World Wide Web. Such systems use statistical techniques to infer a customer's preferences and recommend content best suited to him (e.g., "Customers who liked this also liked ..."). A debate has emerged as to whether personalization has drawbacks. By making the Web hyperspecific to our interests, does it fragment Internet users, reducing shared experiences and narrowing media consumption? We study whether personalization is in fact fragmenting the online population. Surprisingly, it does not appear to do so in our study. Personalization appears to be a tool that helps users widen their interests, which in turn creates commonality with others. This increase in commonality occurs for two reasons, which we term volume and product-mix effects. The volume effect is that consumers simply consume more after personalized recommendations, increasing the chance of having more items in common. The product-mix effect is that, conditional on volume, consumers buy a more similar mix of products after recommendations.</description><author>Hosanagar, Kartik; Fleder, Daniel; Lee, Dokyun; Buja, Andreas</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Lives in the C-Suite? Organizational Structure and the Division of Labor in Top Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guadalupe, Maria; Li, Hongyi; Wulf, Julie
Top management structures in large U.S. firms have changed significantly since the mid-1980s. The size of the executive team-the group of managers reporting directly to the CEO-doubled during this period. This growth was driven primarily by an increase in functional managers rather than general managers, a phenomenon we term "functional centralization." Using panel data on senior management positions, we show that changes in the structure of the executive team are tightly linked to changes in firm diversification and information technology investments. These relationships depend crucially on the function involved; those closer to the product ("product" functions, e.g., marketing and R&amp;D) behave differently from functions further from the product ("administrative" functions, e.g., finance, law, and human resources). We argue that this distinction is driven by differences in the information-processing activities associated with each function and apply this insight to refine and extend existing theories of centralization. We also discuss the implications of our results for organizational forms beyond the executive team.</description><author>Guadalupe, Maria; Li, Hongyi; Wulf, Julie</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Working Harder or Hardly Working? Posting Performance Eliminates Social Loafing and Promotes Social Laboring in Workgroups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lount, Robert B.; Wilk, Steffanie L.
The current paper examines how posting performance-an act that triggers increased social comparisons between workers-influences employees' motivation when working in groups. In the study, posting employee performance moderated the relationship between groupwork and employee motivation. When individual performance was publicly posted in the workplace, employees working in a group performed better than when working alone (i.e., social laboring); however, when individual performance was not posted, employees working in a group performed worse than when working alone (i.e., social loafing). The findings shed light on how social comparisons can have positive implications for employee performance in groups.</description><author>Lount, Robert B.; Wilk, Steffanie L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rewarding Volunteers: A Field Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lacetera, Nicola; Macis, Mario; Slonim, Robert
We conducted a field experiment with the American Red Cross (ARC) to study the effects of economic incentives on volunteer activities. The experiment was designed to assess local and short-term effects as well as spatial and temporal substitution, heterogeneity, and spillovers. Subjects offered $5, $10, and $15 gift cards to give blood were more likely to donate and more so for the higher reward values. The incentives also led to spatial displacement and a short-term shift in the timing of donation activity, but they had no long-term effects. Many of the effects were also heterogeneous in the population. We also detected a spillover effect whereby informing some individuals of rewards through official ARC channels led others who were not officially informed to be more likely to donate. Thus, the effect of incentives on prosocial behavior includes not only the immediate local effects but also spatial displacement, social spillovers, and dramatic heterogeneity. We discuss the implications of these findings for organizations with activities that rely on volunteers for the supply of key inputs or products as well as for government agencies and public policy.</description><author>Lacetera, Nicola; Macis, Mario; Slonim, Robert</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crowding Out in the Labor Market: A Prosocial Setting Is Necessary</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hossain, Tanjim; Li, King King
Recent studies, mostly from prosocial settings, suggest that monetary rewards may crowd out effort exertion by economic agents. We design a field experiment with data entry workers to investigate the extent of such crowding-out effects in a labor market. Using simple variations in the job description of a task, we induce a natural work setting under the work frame and emphasize social preference under the social frame. We find that crowding out of labor participation critically depends on framing-whereas small monetary rewards reduce the participation rate under the social frame, the participation rate is nondecreasing in the wage rate under the work frame. Moreover, among the workers who participate in the task, those who receive a positive wage perform a considerably higher amount of work than those who are paid zero wage under either frame. Thus, there is weak evidence of crowding out only when the task is explicitly given a prosocial flavor and not under a regular work setting. Furthermore, emphasizing social preference in the labor market in such a way reduces the overall labor supply and seems to have an adverse effect on the quality of work.</description><author>Hossain, Tanjim; Li, King King</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Bayesian Semiparametric Approach for Endogeneity and Heterogeneity in Choice Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Yang; Ansari, Asim
Marketing variables that are included in consumer discrete choice models are often endogenous. Extant treatments using likelihood-based estimators impose parametric distributional assumptions, such as normality, on the source of endogeneity. These assumptions are restrictive because misspecified distributions have an impact on parameter estimates and associated elasticities. The normality assumption for endogeneity can be inconsistent with some marginal cost specifications given a price-setting process, although they are consistent with other specifications. In this paper, we propose a heterogeneous Bayesian semiparametric approach for modeling choice endogeneity that offers a flexible and robust alternative to parametric methods. Specifically, we construct centered Dirichlet process mixtures (CDPM) to allow uncertainty over the distribution of endogeneity errors. In a similar vein, we also model consumer preference heterogeneity nonparametrically via a CDPM. Results on simulated data show that incorrect distributional assumptions can lead to poor recovery of model parameters and price elasticities, whereas the proposed semiparametric model is able to robustly recover the true parameters in an efficient fashion. In addition, the CDPM offers the benefits of automatically inferring the number of mixture components that are appropriate for a given data set and is able to reconstruct the shape of the underlying distributions for endogeneity and heterogeneity errors. We apply our approach to two scanner panel data sets. Model comparison statistics indicate the superiority of the semiparametric specification and the results show that parameter and elasticity estimates are sensitive to the choice of distributional forms. Moreover, the CDPM specification yields evidence of multimodality, skewness, and outlying observations in these real data sets.</description><author>Li, Yang; Ansari, Asim</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing Global Sourcing: Inventory Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jain, Nitish; Girotra, Karan; Netessine, Serguei
The use of global suppliers has increased considerably over the last three decades. Operations management theory establishes that global sourcing requires more units of inventory, but since these units are often procured at a lower cost from global suppliers the capital invested in inventory and the consequent financial burden may increase or decrease with global sourcing. This study provides rigorous firm-level empirical evidence that links the global sourcing practices of public U. S. firms and their inventory investments. We process bill of lading manifests (customs forms) to extract information on over half a million sea shipments from global suppliers to U. S. public firms and link this information with quarterly financial data from the Compustat database. We provide stylized facts on the participation of different firms and sectors in global trade. Using a simultaneous equation model, we find that an increase in global sourcing results in an increase in inventory investment. A 10% shift in sourcing from domestic to global suppliers increases the inventory investment by 8.8% for an average firm in our sample. We also find that increasing the number of suppliers can mitigate this increase in inventory investment: for example, going from single to dual sourcing reduces inventory investment by about 11%. We illustrate the use of our estimates to identify the impact of changing global sourcing strategy on inventory investment and operational performance metrics.</description><author>Jain, Nitish; Girotra, Karan; Netessine, Serguei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Home or Overseas? An Analysis of Sourcing Strategies Under Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Xiaole; Zhang, Fuqiang
Motivated by the recent backshoring trend, this paper studies a sourcing game where competing firms may choose between efficient sourcing (e. g., sourcing from overseas) and responsive sourcing (e. g., sourcing from a home country). Efficient sourcing usually provides a cost advantage, whereas responsive sourcing allows a firm to obtain more accurate demand information when making procurement decisions. By characterizing the equilibrium outcome, we find some interesting results driven by the strategic interaction between the firms. First, a firm may still use efficient sourcing in equilibrium even when the cost advantage associated with efficient sourcing does not exist. This is because the firm can dampen competition by reducing the correlation between its own demand information and the competitor's. Second, a cost hike in efficient sourcing (e. g., the rising labor cost in Asia) may benefit all the firms in the industry. The reason is that the cost hike may alleviate competition by inducing a new equilibrium sourcing structure. This paper also sheds some light on the recent backshoring trend. First, our analysis indicates that more firms will shift from efficient sourcing to responsive sourcing in equilibrium (i.e., backshore) if the market size shrinks, the demand becomes more volatile, or the sourcing costs rise simultaneously. Second, a firm's backshoring behavior reduces the competition on the cost dimension, but it also has an ambiguous informational impact on the other firms in the market. In particular, some firms may benefit from increased correlation of their demand information under Cournot competition with substitutable products. Overall, the backshoring behavior can be beneficial to all the firms sticking to their original sourcing strategies under certain conditions.</description><author>Wu, Xiaole; Zhang, Fuqiang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Pricing of Perishable Assets Under Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gallego, Guillermo; Hu, Ming
We study dynamic price competition in an oligopolistic market with a mix of substitutable and complementary perishable assets. Each firm has a fixed initial stock of items and competes in setting prices to sell them over a finite sales horizon. Customers sequentially arrive at the market, make a purchase choice, and then leave immediately with some likelihood of no purchase. The purchase likelihood depends on the time of purchase, product attributes, and current prices. The demand structure includes time-variant linear and multinomial logit demand models as special cases. Assuming deterministic customer arrival rates, we show that any equilibrium strategy has a simple structure, involving a finite set of shadow prices measuring capacity externalities that firms exert on each other: equilibrium prices can be solved from a one-shot price competition game under the current-time demand structure, taking into account capacity externalities through the time-invariant shadow prices. The former reflects the transient demand side at every moment, and the latter captures the aggregate supply constraints over the sales horizon. This simple structure sheds light on dynamic revenue management problems under competition, which helps capture the essence of the problems under demand uncertainty. We show that the equilibrium solutions from the deterministic game provide precommitted and contingent heuristic policies that are asymptotic equilibria for its stochastic counterpart, when demand and supply are sufficiently large.</description><author>Gallego, Guillermo; Hu, Ming</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inside Debt and the Design of Corporate Debt Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anantharaman, Divya; Fang, Vivian W.; Gong, Guojin
Theory posits that managerial holdings of debt ("inside debt") align managers' incentives with those of outside debtholders. Executive pensions, consisting of rank-and-file (RAF) plans and supplemental executive retirement plans (SERPs), and other deferred compensation (ODC) have debt-like payoffs, and could therefore function as inside debt. However, whereas SERPs are often unfunded and unsecured, RAF plans are funded and secured to some extent, and ODC may be invested in equity and withdrawn flexibly before retirement. Special arrangements in executive debt-like compensation could hence weaken or even nullify any incentive-alignment effect. We find that higher CEO debt-like compensation leads to lower promised yield and fewer covenants in a sample of loans originated in 2006-2008. This effect is driven entirely by benefits accrued under SERPs, consistent with SERPs more closely resembling risky corporate debt; balances accrued under RAF and ODC plans do not provide similar effects. Furthermore, promised yields are lower when debt-like compensation claims can be withdrawn only after outside debt claims are expected to settle. Our findings persist after accounting for endogeneity using state personal income tax rates as an instrument for CEOs' willingness to defer compensation. Overall, the evidence suggests that executive debt-like compensation is only effective at resolving stockholder-debtholder conflicts when its payoffs are truly debt-like and that lenders' perceptions are affected not only by the magnitude of debt-like compensation but also by its seniority.</description><author>Anantharaman, Divya; Fang, Vivian W.; Gong, Guojin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Uncertainty, Disagreement, and Credit Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buraschi, Andrea; Trojani, Fabio; Vedolin, Andrea
We study how the equilibrium risk sharing of agents with heterogeneous perceptions of aggregate consumption growth affects bond and stock returns. Although credit spreads and their volatilities increase with the degree of heterogeneity, the decreasing risk premium on moderately levered equity can produce a violation of basic capital structure no-arbitrage relations. Using bottom-up proxies of aggregate belief dispersion, we give empirical support to the model predictions and show that risk premia on corporate bond and stock returns are systematically explained by their exposures to aggregate disagreement shocks.</description><author>Buraschi, Andrea; Trojani, Fabio; Vedolin, Andrea</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment Banks' Entry into New IPO Markets and IPO Underpricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fung, Simon Yu Kit; Gul, Ferdinand A.; Radhakrishnan, Suresh
We examine the relationship between investment banks' initial public offering (IPO) market shares and their prior IPO underpricing in the new IPO market for China-based companies on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. To gain expertise in Chinese business practices, investment banks have the incentive to obtain business in this new IPO market by providing high offer prices to the issuer, leading to less underpricing and less money on the table. We hypothesize and find that the less an investment bank underprices China-based company IPOs, the greater its subsequent market share of China-based company IPOs in the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. Furthermore, this relationship is driven by a bank's initial China-based company IPO deals. These results suggest that in new IPO markets, investment banks' initial market shares, obtained through lower underpricing, help them grow their market shares in later periods, possibly through the expertise gained in the initial business.</description><author>Fung, Simon Yu Kit; Gul, Ferdinand A.; Radhakrishnan, Suresh</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Branch-and-Cut Method for Dynamic Decision Making Under Joint Chance Constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Minjiao; Kucukyavuz, Simge; Goel, Saumya
In this paper, we consider a finite-horizon stochastic mixed-integer program involving dynamic decisions under a constraint on the overall performance or reliability of the system. We formulate this problem as a multistage (dynamic) chance-constrained program, whose deterministic equivalent is a large-scale mixed-integer program. We study the structure of the formulation and develop a branch-and-cut method for its solution. We illustrate the efficacy of the proposed model and method on a dynamic inventory control problem with stochastic demand in which a specific service level must be met over the entire planning horizon. We compare our dynamic model with a static chance-constrained model, a dynamic risk-averse optimization model, a robust optimization model, and a pseudo-dynamic approach and show that significant cost savings can be achieved at high service levels using our model.</description><author>Zhang, Minjiao; Kucukyavuz, Simge; Goel, Saumya</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Observation Bias: The Impact of Demand Censoring on Newsvendor Level and Adjustment Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rudi, Nils; Drake, David
In an experimental newsvendor setting, we investigate three phenomena: level behavior-the decision maker's average ordering tendency; adjustment behavior-the tendency to adjust period-to-period order quantities; and observation bias-the tendency to let the degree of demand feedback influence order quantities. We find that, in three of four conditions, the portion of mismatch cost that results from adjustment behavior exceeds the portion of mismatch cost caused by level behavior. Observation bias is studied through censored demand feedback, a situation that arguably represents most newsvendor settings. When demands are uncensored, subjects tend to order below the normative quantity when they face high margin and above the normative quantity when they face low margin, but in neither case do they order beyond mean demand (the pull-to-center effect). Censoring in general leads to lower quantities, magnifying the below-normative-level behavior when they face high margin but partially counterbalancing the above-normative-level behavior when they face low margin, violating the pull-to-center effect in both cases.</description><author>Rudi, Nils; Drake, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Literacy, Financial Education, and Downstream Financial Behaviors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernandes, Daniel; Lynch, John G.; Netemeyer, Richard G.
Policy makers have embraced financial education as a necessary antidote to the increasing complexity of consumers' financial decisions over the last generation. We conduct a meta-analysis of the relationship of financial literacy and of financial education to financial behaviors in 168 papers covering 201 prior studies. We find that interventions to improve financial literacy explain only 0.1% of the variance in financial behaviors studied, with weaker effects in low-income samples. Like other education, financial education decays over time; even large interventions with many hours of instruction have negligible effects on behavior 20 months or more from the time of intervention. Correlational studies that measure financial literacy find stronger associations with financial behaviors. We conduct three empirical studies, and we find that the partial effects of financial literacy diminish dramatically when one controls for psychological traits that have been omitted in prior research or when one uses an instrument for financial literacy to control for omitted variables. Financial education as studied to date has serious limitations that have been masked by the apparently larger effects in correlational studies. We envisage a reduced role for financial education that is not elaborated or acted upon soon afterward. We suggest a real but narrower role for "just-in-time" financial education tied to specific behaviors it intends to help. We conclude with a discussion of the characteristics of behaviors that might affect the policy maker's mix of financial education, choice architecture, and regulation as tools to help consumer financial behavior.</description><author>Fernandes, Daniel; Lynch, John G.; Netemeyer, Richard G.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volume Flexibility in Services: The Costs and Benefits of Flexible Labor Resources</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kesavan, Saravanan; Staats, Bradley R.; Gilland, Wendell
Organizations can create volume flexibility-the ability to increase capacity up or down to meet demand for a single service-through the use of flexible labor resources (e.g., part-time and temporary workers, as compared to full-time workers). Although organizations are increasingly using these resources, the relationship between flexible labor resources and financial performance has not been examined empirically in the service setting. We use two years of archival data from 445 stores of a large retailer to study this relationship. We hypothesize and find that increasing the labor mix of temporary or part-time workers shows an inverted U-shaped relationship with sales and profit while temporary labor mix has a U-shaped relationship with expenses. Thus, although flexible labor resources can create volume flexibility for a firm along multiple dimensions, it is possible to have too much of a good thing.</description><author>Kesavan, Saravanan; Staats, Bradley R.; Gilland, Wendell</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retail Store Density and the Cost of Greenhouse Gas Emissions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cachon, Gerard P.
The density, size, and location of stores in a retailer's network influences both the retailer's and the consumers' costs. With stores few and far between, consumers must travel a long distance to shop, whereas shopping trips are shorter with a dense network of stores. The layout of the retail supply chain is of interest to retailers who have emission reduction targets and urban planners concerned with sprawl. Are small local shops preferred over large, "big-box" retailers? A model of the retail supply chain is presented that includes operating costs (such as fuel and rent for floor space) as well as a cost for environmental externalities associated with carbon emissions. A focus on exclusively minimizing operating costs may substantially increase emissions (by 67% in one scenario) relative to the minimum level of emissions. A price on carbon is an ineffective mechanism for reducing emissions. The most attractive option is to improve consumer fuel efficiency-doubling the fuel efficiency of cars reduces long-run emissions by about one-third, whereas an improvement in truck fuel efficiency has a marginal impact on total emissions.</description><author>Cachon, Gerard P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Long-Run Role of the Media: Evidence from Initial Public Offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Laura Xiaolei; Sherman, Ann E.; Zhang, Yong
The unique characteristics of the U.S. initial public offering (IPO) process, particularly the strict quiet period regulations, allow us to explore the effects of media coverage when the coverage does not contain genuine news (i.e., hard information that was previously unknown). We show that a simple, objective measure of pre-IPO media coverage is positively related to the stock's long-term value, liquidity, analyst coverage, and institutional investor ownership. Our results are robust to additional controls for size, to using abnormal or excess media, and to an instrumental variable approach. We also find that pre-IPO media coverage is negatively related to future expected returns, measured by the implied cost of capital. In all, we find a long-term role for media coverage, consistent with Merton's attention or investor recognition hypothesis.</description><author>Liu, Laura Xiaolei; Sherman, Ann E.; Zhang, Yong</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Compensation and Peer Effects in Competing Sales Teams</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Tat Y.; Li, Jia; Pierce, Lamar
This paper examines how compensation systems impact peer effects and competition in collocated sales teams. We use department store sales data to show that compensation systems influence worker incentives to help and compete with peers within the same firm, which in turn changes the capability of the firm to compete with rivals. Compensation also affects how salespeople impact peers at collocated competing firms, thereby impacting market competition. Moreover, compensation influences how salespeople strategically discount prices in response to peers. Our results suggest that heterogeneity in worker ability enhances firm performance under team-based compensation while hurting individual-based firms and that peer interactions are critical considerations in designing sales force incentive plans and broader firm strategy.</description><author>Chan, Tat Y.; Li, Jia; Pierce, Lamar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Balancing Acquisition and Retention Spending for Firms with Limited Capacity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ovchinnikov, Anton; Boulu-Reshef, Beatrice; Pfeifer, Phillip E.
This paper discusses the interaction between revenue management and customer relationship management for a firm that operates in a customer retention situation but faces limited capacity. We present a dynamic programming model for how the firm balances investments in customer acquisition and retention, as well as retention across multiple customer types. We characterize the optimal policy and discuss how the policy changes depending on capacity limitations. We then contrast the modeling results with those of a behavioral experiment in which subjects acted as managers making acquisition and retention decisions. In the modeling part of the paper, we introduce a concept of the value of an incremental customer (VIC), and show that when capacity is unlimited, VIC equals customer lifetime value (CLV), but when capacity is limited, VIC is much smaller and changes dynamically depending on the number of customers and their mix. As a result, the optimal spending is constant and depends on CLV for the firms with unlimited capacity, but changes dynamically and is generally unrelated to CLV when capacity is limited. In the experimental part, we introduce a concept of conditional optimality for the analysis of state-dependent decisions. Applying this concept to our data, we document a number of decision biases, specifically the subjects' tendency to overspend on retaining high-value customers and underspend on lower-value customers retention and acquisition. We show that providing CLV information exacerbates these biases and leads to a loss of net revenue when capacity is limited, but providing information about the marginal costs of acquisition and retention eliminated these biases and increases net revenue.</description><author>Ovchinnikov, Anton; Boulu-Reshef, Beatrice; Pfeifer, Phillip E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm-Level Productivity, Risk, and Return</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Imrohoroglu, Ayse; Tuezel, Selale
This paper provides new evidence about the link between firm-level total factor productivity (TFP) and stock returns. We estimate firm-level TFP and show that it is strongly related to several firm characteristics such as size, the book-to-market ratio, investment, and hiring rate. Low productivity firms earn a significant premium over high productivity firms in the following year, and this premium is countercyclical. We show that a production-based asset pricing model calibrated to match the cross section of measured firm-level TFPs can replicate the empirical relationship between TFP, many firm characteristics, and stock returns. Our results offer an explanation as to how these firm characteristics rationally predict returns.</description><author>Imrohoroglu, Ayse; Tuezel, Selale</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Giving Feedback to Clients</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ho, Teck-Hua; Yeung, Catherine
We examine a prevalent form of client-agent interaction through a feedback-giving game. In this game, a client undertakes a nontrivial task and is compensated based on her task performance, which is only made known to her when the client-agent interaction ends. Meanwhile, her performance is disclosed to an agent, who must then give the client feedback on her performance. Upon receiving the feedback, the client reports her happiness level, which in turn determines the agent's payoff. In eight studies involving 928 subjects, we vary the way the agent's cash earnings depend on the client's reported happiness. When we make the agent's earnings proportional to the client's reported happiness, the agent inflates his feedback, and the client reports a higher level of happiness (than that reported in a control condition where the agent always provides honest feedback). We show that neither the agent nor the client behaves altruistically in their reporting. The client reports being happier because she overestimates her performance and mistakenly believes that the agent's feedback is genuine. The agent stops inflating his feedback when doing so no longer benefits him. Finally, our main findings are shown to be robust with respect to several factors, including making the agent's feedback consequential in affecting the client's payoff. In summary, we show that the agent behaves opportunistically, and the client's overconfidence of her own performance is what makes this strategy successful.</description><author>Ho, Teck-Hua; Yeung, Catherine</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Differences in Trading and Pricing Between Stock and Index Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lemmon, Michael; Ni, Sophie Xiaoyan
We find that the demand for stock options that increases exposure to the underlying is positively related to the individual investor sentiments and past market returns, whereas the demand for index options is invariant to these factors. These differences in trading patterns are also reflected in the differences in the composition of traders with different types of options-options on stocks are actively traded by individual investors, whereas trades in index options are more often motivated by the hedging demand of sophisticated investors. Consistent with a demand-based view of option pricing, the individual investor sentiments and past market returns are related to time-series variations in the slope of the implied volatility smile of stock options, but they have little impact on the prices of index options. The pricing impact is more pronounced in options with a higher concentration of unsophisticated investors and those with higher delta hedging costs. Our results provide evidence that factors not related to fundamentals also impact security prices.</description><author>Lemmon, Michael; Ni, Sophie Xiaoyan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crowdsourcing with All-Pay Auctions: A Field Experiment on Taskcn</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Tracy Xiao; Yang, Jiang; Adamic, Lada A.; Chen, Yan
To explore the effects of different incentives on crowdsourcing participation and submission quality, we conduct a randomized field experiment on Taskcn, a large Chinese crowdsourcing site using mechanisms with features of an all-pay auction. In our study, we systematically vary the size of the reward as well as the presence of a soft reserve, or early high-quality submission. We find that a higher reward induces significantly more submissions and submissions of higher quality. In comparison, we find that high-quality users are significantly less likely to enter tasks where a high-quality solution has already been submitted, resulting in lower overall quality in subsequent submissions in such soft reserve treatments.</description><author>Liu, Tracy Xiao; Yang, Jiang; Adamic, Lada A.; Chen, Yan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Content When Mutual Funds Deviate from Benchmarks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Hao; Verbeek, Marno; Wang, Yu
The consensus wisdom of active mutual fund managers, as reflected in their average over- and underweighting decisions, contains valuable information about future stock returns. Analyzing a comprehensive sample of active U.S. equity funds from 1984 to 2008, we find that stocks heavily overweighted by active funds out-perform their underweighted counterparts by more than 7% per year, after adjustments for their loadings on the market, size, value, and momentum factors. This large premium dissipates quickly as the consensus view becomes publicly available. These results are consistent with the notion that informed investing by active mutual funds enhances the informativeness of stock prices. In addition, active mutual funds invest only a small portion of fund assets in high alpha stocks, in accordance with the consensus view that active mutual funds on average fail to outperform passive benchmarks.</description><author>Jiang, Hao; Verbeek, Marno; Wang, Yu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Money Talks: Rebate Mechanisms in Reputation System Design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Lingfang; Xiao, Erte
Reputation systems that rely on voluntary feedback from traders are important in creating and sustaining trust in markets. Feedback nevertheless is a public good, and providing it is often costly. We combine theory with a laboratory experiment to study the effect of a seller precommitment mechanism: Sellers have an option to commit by providing a rebate to reduce the buyer's feedback reporting cost before making purchasing decisions. Our theory predicts that this mechanism induces noncooperative sellers to cooperate in the listed-price market. Using a buyer-seller trust game with a unilateral feedback scheme, we find that the seller's rebate decision has a significant impact on the buyer's purchasing decision via signaling the seller's cooperative type. More importantly, market efficiency under the precommitment mechanism increases with the probability that sellers will provide a rebate. Compared with the no rebate mechanism market, more efficient trades can be achieved when the sellers offer a rebate to the buyers in the market with the rebate mechanism, even when the rebate does not cover the full cost of feedback reporting.</description><author>Li, Lingfang; Xiao, Erte</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Timing Ability of Government Bond Fund Managers: Evidence from Portfolio Holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Jing-Zhi; Wang, Ying
This study examines the ability of government bond fund managers to time the bond market, based on their monthly or quarterly holdings of Treasury securities during the 1997-2006 period. We find that, on average, government bond funds exhibit significantly positive timing ability at the one-month horizon under an unconditional holdings-based timing measure. However, our results indicate that managers' actions based on public information can explain the documented positive timing ability-namely, the average government bond fund has neutral or even slightly negative conditional market timing ability once public information is controlled for. Nonetheless, we find evidence that fund managers specializing in Treasury securities can better interpret public information than general government bond fund managers do.</description><author>Huang, Jing-Zhi; Wang, Ying</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diasporas and Outsourcing: Evidence from oDesk and India</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghani, Ejaz; Kerr, William R.; Stanton, Christopher
We examine the role of the Indian diaspora in the outsourcing of work to India. Our data are taken from oDesk, the world's largest online platform for outsourced contracts. Despite oDesk minimizing many of the frictions that diaspora connections have traditionally overcome, diaspora connections still matter on oDesk, with ethnic Indians substantially more likely to choose a worker in India. This higher placement is the result of a greater likelihood of choosing India for the initial contract and substantial path dependence in location choices. We further examine wage and performance outcomes of outsourcing as a function of ethnic connections. Our examination of potential rationales for the greater ethnic-based placement of contracts assesses taste-based preferences and information differences.</description><author>Ghani, Ejaz; Kerr, William R.; Stanton, Christopher</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mobile Targeting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Luo, Xueming; Andrews, Michelle; Fang, Zheng; Phang, Chee Wei
Mobile technologies enable marketers to target consumers by time and location. This study builds on a large-scale randomized experiment of short message service (SMS) texts sent to 12,265 mobile users. We draw on contextual marketing theory to hypothesize how different combinations of mobile targeting determine consumer responses to mobile promotions. We identify that temporal targeting and geographical targeting individually increase sales purchases. Surprisingly, the sales effects of employing these two strategies simultaneously are not straightforward. When targeting proximal mobile users, our findings reveal a negative sales-lead time relationship; sending same-day mobile promotions yields an increase in the odds of consumer purchases compared with sending them two days prior to the promoted event. However, when targeting nonproximal mobile users, there is an inverted-U, curvilinear relationship. Sending one-day prior SMSs yields an increase in the odds of consumer purchases by 9.5 times compared with same-day SMSs and an increase in the odds of consumer purchases by 71% compared with two-day prior SMSs. These results are robust to unobserved heterogeneity, alternative estimation models, bootstrapped resamples, randomization checks, consumer mobile usage behavior, and segmentation of consumer scenarios. In addition, we conducted follow-up surveys to delve into the psychological mechanisms explaining the findings in our field experiment. In line with consumer construal arguments, consumers who received SMSs close (far) in time and location formed a more (less) concrete mental construal, which in turn, increased their involvement and purchase intent. These findings suggest that understanding the when, where, and how of mobile targeting strategies is crucial. Marketers can save money by carefully designing their mobile targeting campaigns.</description><author>Luo, Xueming; Andrews, Michelle; Fang, Zheng; Phang, Chee Wei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting the Equity Risk Premium: The Role of Technical Indicators</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neely, Christopher J.; Rapach, David E.; Tu, Jun; Zhou, Guofu
Academic research relies extensively on macroeconomic variables to forecast the U.S. equity risk premium, with relatively little attention paid to the technical indicators widely employed by practitioners. Our paper fills this gap by comparing the predictive ability of technical indicators with that of macroeconomic variables. Technical indicators display statistically and economically significant in-sample and out-of-sample predictive power, matching or exceeding that of macroeconomic variables. Furthermore, technical indicators and macroeconomic variables provide complementary information over the business cycle: technical indicators better detect the typical decline in the equity risk premium near business-cycle peaks, whereas macroeconomic variables more readily pick up the typical rise in the equity risk premium near cyclical troughs. Consistent with this behavior, we show that combining information from both technical indicators and macroeconomic variables significantly improves equity risk premium forecasts versus using either type of information alone. Overall, the substantial countercyclical fluctuations in the equity risk premium appear well captured by the combined information in technical indicators and macroeconomic variables.</description><author>Neely, Christopher J.; Rapach, David E.; Tu, Jun; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Kerry Met Sally: Politics and Perceptions in the Demand for Movies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roos, Jason M. T.; Shachar, Ron
Movie producers and exhibitors make various decisions requiring an understanding of moviegoer's preferences at the local level. Two examples of such decisions are exhibitors' allocation of screens to movies and producers' allocation of advertising across different regions of the country. This study presents a predictive model of local demand for movies with two unique features. First, arguing that consumers' political tendencies have an unutilized predictive power for marketing models, we allow consumers' heterogeneity to depend on their voting tendencies. Second, instead of relying on the commonly used genre classifications to characterize movies, we estimate latent movie attributes. These attributes are not determined a priori by industry professionals but rather reflect consumers' perceptions, as revealed by their moviegoing behavior. Box-office data over five years from 25 counties in the U.S. Midwest provide support for this model. First, consumers' preferences are related to their political tendencies. For example, we find that counties that voted for congressional Republicans prefer movies starring young, Caucasian, female actors over those starring African American, male actors. Second, perceived attributes provide new insights into consumers' preferences. For example, one of these attributes is the movie's degree of seriousness. Finally, and most importantly, the two improvements proposed here have a meaningful impact on forecasting error, decreasing it by 12.6%.</description><author>Roos, Jason M. T.; Shachar, Ron</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Examining the Impact of Ranking on Consumer Behavior and Search Engine Revenue</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghose, Anindya; Ipeirotis, Panagiotis G.; Li, Beibei
In this paper, we study the effects of three different kinds of search engine rankings on consumer behavior and search engine revenues: direct ranking effect, interaction effect between ranking and product ratings, and personalized ranking effect. We combine a hierarchical Bayesian model estimated on approximately one million online sessions from Travelocity, together with randomized experiments using a real-world hotel search engine application. Our archival data analysis and randomized experiments are consistent in demonstrating the following: (1) A consumer-utility-based ranking mechanism can lead to a significant increase in overall search engine revenue. (2) Significant interplay occurs between search engine ranking and product ratings. An inferior position on the search engine affects "higher-class" hotels more adversely. On the other hand, hotels with a lower customer rating are more likely to benefit from being placed on the top of the screen. These findings illustrate that product search engines could benefit from directly incorporating signals from social media into their ranking algorithms. (3) Our randomized experiments also reveal that an "active" personalized ranking system (wherein users can interact with and customize the ranking algorithm) leads to higher clicks but lower purchase propensities and lower search engine revenue compared with a "passive" personalized ranking system (wherein users cannot interact with the ranking algorithm). This result suggests that providing more information during the decision-making process may lead to fewer consumer purchases because of information overload. Therefore, product search engines should not adopt personalized ranking systems by default. Overall, our study unravels the economic impact of ranking and its interaction with social media on product search engines.</description><author>Ghose, Anindya; Ipeirotis, Panagiotis G.; Li, Beibei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Ability of Global Stock Exchange Mechanisms to Mitigate Home Bias: Evidence from Euronext</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pownall, Grace; Vulcheva, Maria; Wang, Xue
This paper examines the effects on equity home bias of two mechanisms adopted by Euronext when it was formed by the merger of four European countries' stock exchanges in 2002. The two structural mechanisms are the integration of trading platforms across the four predecessor exchanges and the creation of named segments of the integrated exchange on which firms could voluntarily list by precommitting to enhanced disclosure and transparency. Employing a difference-in-differences research design using other European Union companies as a control group, we document that the integration of the Euronext market was associated with a reduction in home bias for firms listed on the named segments of the Euronext exchange, but not for the nonsegment Euronext firms. Our results suggest that the reduction in transaction costs from the integration of the trading platforms did not make the nonsegment Euronext firms more attractive to the specific investors for whom the transaction costs were reduced. On the other hand, the decrease in information costs due to the precommitments to enhanced transparency made the segment firms more attractive to all categories of foreign investors, consistent with the information costs hypothesis.</description><author>Pownall, Grace; Vulcheva, Maria; Wang, Xue</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Integration and Productivity: Satellite-Tracked Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Natividad, Gabriel
This paper introduces satellite-tracked real-time data from a large fishing firm managing its vertically, horizontally, and geographically linked ships to study the causal impact of integration on total factor productivity (TFP) after the firm acquired its vertically unintegrated contractual fish suppliers. TFP increased 16% among newly integrated ships, whereas it did not vary for already owned ships. Some classic mechanisms such as increased effort due to monitoring do not systematically explain TFP gains under integration, whereas evidence on hold-up threat alleviation is mixed. Importantly, enhanced knowledge transfer and hierarchical authority enacting productivity-improving operational practices among newly integrated ships are more likely explanations of the results.</description><author>Natividad, Gabriel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Split-Award Auctions for Supplier Retention</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaturvedi, Aadhaar; Beil, Damian R.; Martinez-de-Albeniz, Victor
To stay abreast of current supply-market pricing, it is common for procurement managers to frequently organize auctions among a pool of qualified suppliers (the supply base). Sole awards can alienate losing suppliers and cause them to defect from the supply base. To maintain the supply base and thereby control the high costs of finding and qualifying new suppliers, buyers often employ split awards, which in turn inflate purchase costs. This results in a trade-off that we investigate in an infinite-horizon stationary setting in which the relative cost position of each supplier is randomly drawn in every period. We characterize the optimal split award that minimizes long-run costs (purchasing and qualification) and show that maintaining a constant supply-base size-using a "qualify-up-to" policy-is optimal for the buyer. We find that neither the extent of multisourcing nor the buyer's value of split awards compared with winner-take-all auctions are monotonic in the qualification cost and that split-award auctions can increase ex ante system, buyer, and supplier benefits simultaneously. To our knowledge, this is the first paper studying split-award auctions for supply-base maintenance, and it will hopefully galvanize further research on this important topic.</description><author>Chaturvedi, Aadhaar; Beil, Damian R.; Martinez-de-Albeniz, Victor</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wallflowers: Experimental Evidence of an Aversion to Standing Out</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, Daniel; Linardi, Sera
An extensive literature on reputation signaling in prosocial settings has focused on an intrinsic desire for positive reputation. In this paper, we provide experimental evidence that some individuals are averse to both positive and negative reputation and will therefore respond to visibility by signaling that they are an '' average altruism type '' relative to their audience. We formalize our hypotheses about '' wallflower '' behavior in a theoretical model. Our experimental results show that instead of uniformly increasing contributions, visibility draws contributions toward the middle of others' contributions. As a result, visibility is associated with higher levels of giving only in scenarios where others are giving a large amount. We also observe heterogeneity in reputation concerns: wallflower behavior is particularly strong for women and can be observed in several different settings.</description><author>Jones, Daniel; Linardi, Sera</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Multiperiod Pricing with Service Guarantees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borgs, Christian; Candogan, Ozan; Chayes, Jennifer; Lobel, Ilan; Nazerzadeh, Hamid
We study the multiperiod pricing problem of a service firm with capacity levels that vary over time. Customers are heterogeneous in their arrival and departure periods as well as valuations, and are fully strategic with respect to their purchasing decisions. The firm's problem is to set a sequence of prices that maximizes its revenue while guaranteeing service to all paying customers. We provide a dynamic programming based algorithm that computes the optimal sequence of prices for this problem in polynomial time. We show that due to the presence of strategic customers, available service capacity at a time period may bind the price offered at another time period. This phenomenon leads the firm to utilize the same price in multiple periods, in effect limiting the number of different prices that the service firm utilizes in optimal price policies. Also, when customers become more strategic ( patient for service), the firm offers higher prices. This may lead to the underutilization of capacity, lower revenues, and reduced customer welfare. We observe that the firm can combat this problem if it has an ability, beyond posted prices, to direct customers to different service periods.</description><author>Borgs, Christian; Candogan, Ozan; Chayes, Jennifer; Lobel, Ilan; Nazerzadeh, Hamid</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Judgment of Garbage: End-of-Pipe Treatment and Waste Reduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dutt, Nilanjana; King, Andrew A.
M any scholars have argued that systems for treating waste impede organizations from preventing waste in the first place. They theorize that end-of-pipe (EOP) treatment diminishes the incentive to avoid creating waste in the production process and obscures the information necessary to devise prevention techniques. This prediction has been widely accepted, influencing both policy and practice, despite both a lack of supporting empirical evidence and the existence of a counterprediction. In this paper, we use data describing U.S. manufacturing establishments from 1991 to 2005 to test the connection between EOP treatment and waste reduction. Our findings show that EOP treatment is associated with an initial jump in reported waste, followed by ongoing reduction. We analyze these results by exploring mechanisms that may drive this relationship. For practitioners, our paper provides critical guidance about strategies for reducing waste. For scholars of environmental management, our paper provides new insight on when facilities accomplish "source reduction" of process waste. For broader management theories of operations and organizational design, our analysis provides new insight on boundary conditions for extrapolation from existing theories. Finally, our paper provides new guidance for the formulation of effective regulatory policy.</description><author>Dutt, Nilanjana; King, Andrew A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Targeted Advertising in Magazine Markets and the Advent of the Internet</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chandra, Ambarish; Kaiser, Ulrich
T his paper examines how the ability of traditional media firms to engage in targeted advertising has changed with the advent of the Internet. We find that the premium for reaching a homogeneous audience increases for magazines that have a companion website, as well as for those whose readers are more likely to be online. This indicates a complementarity between offline and online channels with respect to targeted advertising. We hypothesize that this result is driven by multihoming consumers who enhance the value of targeted advertising, in contrast to the usual assumption that multiple advertising messages are redundant.</description><author>Chandra, Ambarish; Kaiser, Ulrich</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Eliciting Prospect Theory When Consequences Are Measured in Time Units: "Time Is Not Money"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abdellaoui, Mohammed; Kemel, Emmanuel
We elicited the prospect theory components (utility, probability weighting, and loss aversion) when consequences are expressed as the time dedicated to a specific task or activity. A similar elicitation was performed for monetary consequences to allow an across-attribute (time/money) comparison of the elicited components (at the individual level). We obtained less concave utility and smaller loss aversion for time than for money. Moreover, while the probability weighting was predominantly inverse S-shaped for both attributes, it was less sensitive to probabilities and more elevated for time than for money. This finding implies more optimism for gains and more pessimism for losses.</description><author>Abdellaoui, Mohammed; Kemel, Emmanuel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>From the Horse's Mouth: Economic Conditions and Investor Expectations of Risk and Return</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amromin, Gene; Sharpe, Steven A.
Data obtained from monthly Gallup/UBS surveys from 1998 to 2007 and from a special supplement to the Michigan Surveys of Consumer Attitudes and Behavior, run in 22 monthly surveys between 2000 and 2005, are used to analyze stock market beliefs and portfolio choices of household investors. We show that the key variables found to be positive predictors of actual stock returns in the asset-pricing literature are also highly correlated with investor's subjective expected returns, but with the opposite sign. Moreover, our analysis of the microdata indicates that subjective expectations of both risk and returns on stocks are strongly influenced by perceptions of economic conditions. In particular, when investors believe macroeconomic conditions are more expansionary, they tend to expect both higher returns and lower volatility. This is difficult to reconcile with the canonical view that expected returns on stocks rise during recessions to compensate household investors for increased exposure or sensitivity to macroeconomic risks. Finally, the relevance of these investors' subjective expectations is supported by the finding of a significant link between their expectations and portfolio choices. In particular, we show that portfolio equity positions tend to be higher for those respondents that anticipate higher expected returns or lower uncertainty.</description><author>Amromin, Gene; Sharpe, Steven A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrepreneurial Exits and Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, Vikas A.; Hsu, David H.
We examine how initial public offerings (IPOs) and acquisitions affect entrepreneurial innovation as measured by patent counts and forward patent citations. We construct a firm-year panel data set of all venture capital-backed biotechnology firms founded between 1980 and 2000, tracked yearly through 2006. We address the possibility of unobserved self-selection into exit mode by using coarsened exact matching, and in two additional ways: (1) comparing firms that filed for an IPO (or announced a merger) with those not completing the transaction for reasons unrelated to innovation, and (2) using an instrumental variables approach. We find that innovation quality is highest under private ownership and lowest under public ownership, with acquisition intermediate between the two. Together with a set of within-exit mode analyses, these results are consistent with the proposition that information confidentiality mechanisms shape innovation outcomes. The results are not explained by inventor-level turnover following exit events or by firms' preexit window dressing behavior.</description><author>Aggarwal, Vikas A.; Hsu, David H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Private Equity Returns Result from Wealth Transfers and Short-Termism? Evidence from a Comprehensive Sample of Large Buyouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harford, Jarrad; Kolasinski, Adam
We test whether the well-documented high returns of private equity sponsors result from wealth transfers from other financial claimants and counterparties and from a focus on short-term profits at the expense of long-term value. Debt investors who finance buyouts, as well as buyers of private equity portfolio companies, represent the two potential sources of wealth transfers. However, we find that, on average, public companies benefit when they buy financial sponsors' portfolio companies, experiencing positive abnormal returns upon the announcement of the acquisition and long-run posttransaction abnormal returns indistinguishable from zero. We further find that large portfolio company payouts to private equity on average have no relation to future portfolio company distress, suggesting that debt investors are not suffering systematic wealth losses either. However, we find some evidence of wealth transfers from both strategic buyers and debt investors in some special situations. Finally, we find that portfolio companies invest no differently than a matched sample of public control firms, even when they are not profitable, an observation inconsistent with short-termism.</description><author>Harford, Jarrad; Kolasinski, Adam</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dark Side of Competition for Status</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Charness, Gary; Masclet, David; Villeval, Marie Claire
Unethical behavior within organizations is not rare. We investigate experimentally the role of status-seeking behavior in sabotage and cheating activities aiming at improving one's performance ranking in a flat-wage environment. We find that average effort is higher when individuals are informed about their relative performance. However, ranking feedback also favors disreputable behavior. Some individuals do not hesitate to incur a cost to improve their rank by sabotaging others' work or by increasing artificially their own performance. Introducing sabotage opportunities has a strong detrimental effect on performance. Therefore, ranking incentives should be used with care. Inducing group identity discourages sabotage among peers but increases in-group rivalry.</description><author>Charness, Gary; Masclet, David; Villeval, Marie Claire</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Risk Management: Integrating Liquidity, Hedging, and Operating Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gamba, Andrea; Triantis, Alexander J.
We analyze the value created by a dynamic integrated risk management strategy involving liquidity management, derivatives hedging, and operating flexibility, in the presence of several frictions. We show that liquidity serves a critical and distinct role in risk management, justifying high levels of cash. We find that the marginal value associated with derivatives hedging is likely to be low, though we explain why some empirical studies find a higher value. We explore the complex interactions between operating flexibility and financial risk management, finding that substitution effects are nonmonotonic and are affected by operating leverage, the nature of operating flexibility, and the effectiveness of the hedging instrument.</description><author>Gamba, Andrea; Triantis, Alexander J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Celebrity Endorsements, Firm Value, and Reputation Risk: Evidence from the Tiger Woods Scandal</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Knittel, Christopher R.; Stango, Victor
We estimate the stock market effects of the Tiger Woods scandal on his sponsors and sponsors' competitors. In the 10-15 trading days after the onset of the scandal, the full portfolio of sponsors lost more than 2% of market value, with losses concentrated among the core three sponsors: Electronic Arts, Nike, and PepsiCo (Gatorade). Sponsors' day-by-day losses correlate strongly with Google search intensity regarding the endorsement-related impact of the scandal, as well as with qualitative indicators of "endorsement-related news." At least some sponsors' losses were competitors' gains, suggesting that endorsement deals are partially a business-stealing strategy. However, competitors who were themselves celebrity endorsement intensive fared relatively worse than those who were not endorsement intensive, and that difference also correlates day by day with news/search intensity regarding the scandal. It appears that the scandal sent a negative marketwide signal about the reputation risk associated with celebrity endorsements.</description><author>Knittel, Christopher R.; Stango, Victor</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Governance Institutions and Adaptation Costs: Evidence from the Fall of the Berlin Wall</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frank, Douglas H.
This paper investigates how institutions governing the employment relationship influence firms' adaptation to environmental changes. After the Berlin Wall fell, migration from East Germany accounted for an abrupt increase in the supply of a key resource-labor-in the West. I study responses to this disruption among firms in the economically important machinery and equipment industry. I find that western firms adapted to migration by increasing employment unless they were affiliated with a works council, an institution that limits the firm's autonomy in managing its workforce. I also find evidence of institution-contingent responses to migration in two areas of firm strategy: vertical boundaries and the focus on exploration versus exploitation. The results suggest that "hybrid" (i.e., less hierarchical) governance institutions increase adaptation costs. The results also indicate that such adaptation costs have implications for multiple aspects of firm decision making that are nominally beyond the scope of those governance institutions.</description><author>Frank, Douglas H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fast or Rational? A Response-Times Study of Bayesian Updating</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Achtziger, Anja; Alos-Ferrer, Carlos
We present a simple model for decision making under uncertainty building on dual-process theories from psychology, and use it to illustrate a possible component of intuitive decision making of particular relevance for managerial settings. Decisions are the result of the interaction between two decision processes. The first one captures optimization based on Bayesian updating of beliefs. The second corresponds to a form of reinforcement learning capturing the tendency to rely on past performance. The model predicts that (i) in the case of conflict between the two processes, correct responses are associated with longer response times, but (ii) if both processes are aligned, errors are slower. Furthermore, (iii) response times in the case of conflict are longer than in the case of alignment. We confirm the predictions of the model in an experiment using a paradigm where an associative win-stay, lose-shift process conflicted with rational belief updating.</description><author>Achtziger, Anja; Alos-Ferrer, Carlos</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Broadband in School: Impact on Student Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Belo, Rodrigo; Ferreira, Pedro; Telang, Rahul
This paper examines the effects of providing broadband to schools on students' performance. We use a rich panel of data on broadband use and students' grades from all middle schools in Portugal. Employing a first-differences specification to control for school-specific unobserved effects and instrumenting the quality of broadband to account for unobserved time-varying effects, we show that high levels of broadband use in schools were detrimental for grades on the ninth-grade national exams in Portugal. For the average broadband use in schools, grades reduced 0.78 of a standard deviation from 2005 to 2009. We also show that broadband has a negative impact on exam scores regardless of gender, subject, or school quality and that the way schools allow students to use the Internet affects their performance. In particular, students in schools that block access to websites such as YouTube perform relatively better.</description><author>Belo, Rodrigo; Ferreira, Pedro; Telang, Rahul</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Holding the Hunger Games Hostage at the Gym: An Evaluation of Temptation Bundling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milkman, Katherine L.; Minson, Julia A.; Volpp, Kevin G. M.
We introduce and evaluate the effectiveness of temptation bundling-a method for simultaneously tackling two types of self-control problems by harnessing consumption complementarities. We describe a field experiment measuring the impact of bundling instantly gratifying but guilt-inducing "want" experiences (enjoying page-turner audiobooks) with valuable "should" behaviors providing delayed rewards (exercising). We explore whether such bundles increase should behaviors and whether people would pay to create these restrictive bundles. Participants were randomly assigned to a full treatment condition with gym-only access to tempting audio novels, an intermediate treatment involving encouragement to restrict audiobook enjoyment to the gym, or a control condition. Initially, full and intermediate treatment participants visited the gym 51% and 29% more frequently, respectively, than control participants, but treatment effects declined over time (particularly following Thanksgiving). After the study, 61% of participants opted to pay to have gym-only access to iPods containing tempting audiobooks, suggesting demand for this commitment device.</description><author>Milkman, Katherine L.; Minson, Julia A.; Volpp, Kevin G. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Horizontal Mergers in Multitier Decentralized Supply Chains</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cho, Soo-Haeng
The well-known economic theory predicts that consumer price will fall after a horizontal merger when the amount of marginal cost reduction from operating synergies exceeds the premerger markup of a merging firm. However, when a horizontal merger occurs in a multitier decentralized supply chain where a finite number of firms compete at each tier, we show that this result holds only when a merger occurs at the tier that acts as the leader in the supply chain. In this supply chain, a horizontal merger at any other tier will decrease consumer price when the cost reduction exceeds a certain threshold that is larger than the premerger markup. Moreover, this threshold is increasing as the supply chain gets longer and can be substantially larger than the premerger markup. When accounting for subsequent entry after a merger in long-run equilibrium, contrary to a common belief, a larger synergy from a merger does not necessarily benefit consumers more.</description><author>Cho, Soo-Haeng</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Turn-and-Earn Incentives with a Product Line</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen-Vernik, Dinah A.; Purohit, Devavrat
When manufacturers do not have sufficient capacity to meet demand and cannot increase prices, they have to determine other methods to allocate goods among retailers. A common allocation mechanism is based on a retailer's sales history: a retailer that has ordered larger quantities in the past should get a greater allocation than a retailer that has historically ordered smaller quantities. This mechanism, known as a turn-and-earn allocation rule, is commonly used in many industries such as automobiles, microprocessors, video game consoles, etc. The existing literature has considered the effect of turn-and-earn allocation rules when a manufacturer sells a single product. However, when we consider a product line, it is not clear whether the manufacturer is better off basing its allocation on the sales history of the entire product line or solely on the sales history of the product in short supply. In particular, a shortage of one product can lead retailers and consumers to move toward other products in the line. This, in turn, can have an effect on the manufacturer's optimal allocation mechanism. We examine this issue by developing a model of a supplier selling two substitutable goods through two retailers. Within this setup, we introduce a general turn-and-earn allocation rule that allows the entire sales history to influence allocation levels. Counter to previous work, we show that certain turn-and-earn rules not only help the manufacturer but can also help the retailer and increase total supply chain profits.</description><author>Cohen-Vernik, Dinah A.; Purohit, Devavrat</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing Retention in Service Relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aflaki, Sam; Popescu, Ioana
In a repeat business context, past experiences with a service provider affect customers' decisions to renew their contract. How should a strategic firm manage customized service over time to maximize the long-term value from each customer relationship? We propose a dynamic model that relies on behavioral theories and empirical evidence to capture the effect of past service experiences on service quality expectations, customer satisfaction, and retention. Although firms can benefit from managing service expectations at the beginning of a relationship, we find that varying service in the long run is not optimal. Behavioral regularities explain the structure of optimal service policies and limit the value of responsive service. Loss aversion expands the range of optimal constant policies; however, if satisfying experiences are more salient, then firms should constantly vary service levels. Loyal or high-margin customers need not warrant better service; those who anchor less on past service experiences do-provided that retention is improved by better past experiences. The effect of customer memory on service levels is determined by whether habituation or rather goodwill drives defection decisions.</description><author>Aflaki, Sam; Popescu, Ioana</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gender Differences in Willingness to Guess</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baldiga, Katherine
We present the results of an experiment that explores whether women are less willing than men to guess on multiple-choice tests. Our test consists of practice questions from SAT II history tests; we vary whether a penalty is imposed for a wrong answer and the salience of the evaluative nature of the task. We find that when no penalty is assessed for a wrong answer, all test takers answer every question. But, when there is a penalty for wrong answers, women answer significantly fewer questions than men. We see no differences in knowledge of the material or confidence in the test takers, and differences in risk preferences explain less than half of the observed gap. Making the evaluative aspect of the test more salient does not impact the gender gap. We show that, conditional on their knowledge of the material, test takers who skip questions do significantly worse on our test.</description><author>Baldiga, Katherine</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Supplier Encroachment Under Asymmetric Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Zhuoxin; Gilbert, Stephen M.; Lai, Guoming
Prior literature has shown that, for a symmetric information setting, supplier encroachment into a reseller's market can mitigate double marginalization and benefit both the supplier and the reseller. This paper extends the investigation of supplier encroachment to the environment where the reseller might be better informed than the supplier. We find that the launch of the supplier's direct channel can result in costly signaling behavior on the part of the reseller, in which he reduces his order quantity when the market size is small. Such a downward order distortion can amplify double marginalization. As a result, in addition to the "win-win" and "win-lose" outcomes for the supplier and the reseller, supplier encroachment can also lead to "lose-lose" and "lose-win" outcomes, particularly when the reseller has a significant efficiency advantage in the selling process and the prior probability of a large market is low. We further explore the implications of those findings for information management in supply chains. Complementing the conventional understanding, we show that with the ability to encroach, the supplier may prefer to sell to either a better informed or an uninformed reseller in different scenarios. On the other hand, as a result of a supplier developing encroachment capability, a reseller either may choose not to develop an advanced informational capability or may become more willing to find a means of credibly sharing his information.</description><author>Li, Zhuoxin; Gilbert, Stephen M.; Lai, Guoming</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trimmed Opinion Pools and the Crowd's Calibration Problem</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jose, Victor Richmond R.; Grushka-Cockayne, Yael; Lichtendahl, Kenneth C.
We introduce an alternative to the popular linear opinion pool for combining individual probability forecasts. One of the well-known problems with the linear opinion pool is that it can be poorly calibrated. It tends toward underconfidence as the crowd's diversity increases, i.e., as the variance in the individuals' means increases. To address this calibration problem, we propose the exterior-trimmed opinion pool. To form this pool, forecasts with low and high means, or cumulative distribution function (cdf) values, are trimmed away from a linear opinion pool. Exterior trimming decreases the pool's variance and improves its calibration. A linear opinion pool, however, will remain overconfident when individuals are overconfident and not very diverse. For these situations, we suggest trimming away forecasts with moderate means or cdf values. This interior trimming increases variance and reduces overconfidence. Using probability forecast data from U.S. and European Surveys of Professional Forecasters, we present empirical evidence that trimmed opinion pools can outperform the linear opinion pool.</description><author>Jose, Victor Richmond R.; Grushka-Cockayne, Yael; Lichtendahl, Kenneth C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Strategic Value of High-Cost Customers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Subramanian, Upender; Raju, Jagmohan S.; Zhang, Z. John
Many firms today manage their existing customers differentially based on profit potential, providing fewer incentives to less profitable customers and firing unprofitable customers. Although researchers and industry experts advocate this practice, results have been mixed. We examine this practice explicitly accounting for competition and find that some conventional prescriptions may not always hold. We analyze a setting where customers differ in their cost to serve. We find that when a firm can discriminate among its customers but the rival cannot, customer base composition influences the rival's poaching behavior. Consequently, even though a low-cost customer is more profitable when viewed in isolation, a high-cost customer may be strategically more valuable by discouraging poaching. Therefore, contrary to conventional advice, it can be profitable for a firm to retain unprofitable customers. Moreover, some customers may become more valuable to retain and receive better incentives when they are less profitable. We further show that, in competitive settings, traditional customer lifetime value metrics may lead to poor retention decisions because they do not account for the competitive externality that actions toward some customers impose on the cash flows from other customers. Our results suggest that firms may need to evolve from a segmentation mindset, which views each customer in isolation, to a customer portfolio mindset, which recognizes that the value of different customers is interlinked.</description><author>Subramanian, Upender; Raju, Jagmohan S.; Zhang, Z. John</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Product Differentiation over the State Space in the Mutual Fund Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Shujing; Qiu, Jiaping
By distancing themselves from others in risk factor loadings, mutual funds yield distinct returns and become better-performing funds in different market situations. This enables mutual funds to obtain stochastic market power and charge higher fees than they could otherwise. This strategy fundamentally differs from the conventional market segmentation strategy that targets investors with heterogeneous preferences. We present a model to study this novel form of financial product differentiation over the states of nature. Empirically, we find that the return attributable to risk factor loadings has a significant impact on a fund's market share. Fund fees are related to the positions of their factor loadings in the industry and funds with more extreme risk factor loadings charge higher fees.</description><author>Li, Shujing; Qiu, Jiaping</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the Effect of Advertising on Stock Returns and Firm Value: Theory and Evidence from a Structural Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vitorino, Maria Ana
This paper brings structural modeling to the literature on financial research in marketing. I propose a dynamic investment-based model to understand the impact of advertising expenditures on stock returns and firm value. In addition, by interpreting advertising expenditures as an investment in brand capital, the approach in this paper provides a novel way to measure brand equity grounded in economic theory. Using the Euler equations from the firm's maximization problem, I derive closed-form expressions for the firm's equilibrium stock returns and market value, which depend on observable firm characteristics. I test the model's predictions by the generalized method of moments and data from a large cross section of publicly traded firms. The model is able to match simultaneously the pattern of average stock returns and firm values of portfolios sorted on advertising expenditures that standard asset pricing models cannot. The estimation results also show that brand equity accounts for a substantial fraction of firm market value (about 23%), and that this value varies substantially across industries. Implications of the findings for research at the intersection of marketing and finance are discussed.</description><author>Vitorino, Maria Ana</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uncertainty, Risk, and Incentives: Theory and Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Zhiguo; Li, Si; Wei, Bin; Yu, Jianfeng
Uncertainty has qualitatively different implications than risk in studying executive incentives. We study the interplay between profitability uncertainty and moral hazard, where profitability is multiplicative with managerial effort. Investors who face greater uncertainty desire faster learning, and consequently offer higher managerial incentives to induce higher effort from the manager. In contrast to the standard negative risk-incentive trade-off, this "learning-by-doing" effect generates a positive relation between profitability uncertainty and incentives. We document empirical support for this prediction.</description><author>He, Zhiguo; Li, Si; Wei, Bin; Yu, Jianfeng</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer Favorites and the Design of News</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xiang, Yi; Soberman, David
The objective of this paper is to better understand the factors that competitive news providers consider to design or deliver news programmes. The focus is broadcast news where, in any programming time period, a viewer watches (or consumes) one programme. We assume that each viewer is interested in a limited set of topics and that her utility only comes from the "most interesting" news she observes. The key questions we address are as follows: (a) Should firms adopt designs that facilitate the delivery of more information in their news programmes? (b) Does the decision of firms to implement such strategies depend on the complexity of the news programme (i.e., the number of news stories covered in the news product)? (c) How do such strategies influence competition? We show that firms may or may not benefit by providing better-designed news. The incentive to do this is strongly affected by the complexity of the news product and the intensity of competition between news providers.</description><author>Xiang, Yi; Soberman, David</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Governance and CEO Turnover: Do Something or Do the Right Thing?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fisman, Raymond J.; Khurana, Rakesh; Rhodes-Kropf, Matthew; Yim, Soojin
We study how corporate governance affects firm value through the decision of whether to fire or retain the chief executive officer (CEO). We present a model in which weak governance-which prevents shareholders from controlling the board-protects inferior CEOs from dismissal, while at the same time insulates the board from pressures by biased or uninformed shareholders. Whether stronger governance improves retain/replace decisions depends on which of these effects dominates. We use our theoretical framework to assess the effect of governance on the quality of firing and hiring decisions using data on the CEO dismissals of large U.S. corporations during 1994-2007. Our findings are most consistent with a beneficent effect of weak governance on CEO dismissal decisions, suggesting that insulation from shareholder pressure may allow for better long-term decision making.</description><author>Fisman, Raymond J.; Khurana, Rakesh; Rhodes-Kropf, Matthew; Yim, Soojin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Flows and the 2008 Boom/Bust in Oil Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Singleton, Kenneth J.
This paper explores the impact of investor flows and financial market conditions on returns in crude oil futures markets. I argue that informational frictions and the associated speculative activity may induce prices to drift away from "fundamental" values, and may result in price booms and busts. Particular attention is given to the interplay between imperfect information about real economic activity, including supply, demand, and inventory accumulation, and speculative activity in oil markets. Furthermore, I present new evidence that there were economically and statistically significant effects of investor flows on futures prices, after controlling for returns in the United States and emerging-economy stock markets, a measure of the balance sheet flexibility of large financial institutions, open interest, the futures/spot basis, and lagged returns on oil futures. The largest impacts on futures prices were from intermediate-term growth rates of index positions and managed-money spread positions. Moreover, my findings suggest that these effects were through risk or informational channels distinct from changes in convenience yield. Finally, the evidence suggests that hedge fund trading in spread positions in futures impacted the shape of term structure of oil futures prices.</description><author>Singleton, Kenneth J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sale of Price Information by Exchanges: Does It Promote Price Discovery?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cespa, Giovanni; Foucault, Thierry
Exchanges sell both trading services and price information. We study how the joint pricing of these products affects price discovery and the distribution of gains from trade in an asset market. A wider dissemination of price information reduces pricing errors and the transfer from liquidity traders to speculators. This effect reduces the fee that speculators are willing to pay for trading. Therefore, to raise its revenue from trading, a for-profit exchange optimally charges a high fee for price information so that only a fraction of speculators buy this information. As a result, price discovery is not as efficient as it would be with free price information. This problem is less severe if the exchange must compensate liquidity traders for a fraction of their losses.</description><author>Cespa, Giovanni; Foucault, Thierry</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Job Hopping, Information Technology Spillovers, and Productivity Growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tambe, Prasanna; Hitt, Lorin M.
The movement of information technology (IT) workers among firms is believed to be an important mechanism by which IT-related innovations diffuse throughout the economy. We use a newly developed source of employee microdata-an online resume database-to model IT workers' mobility patterns. We find that firms derive significant productivity benefits from the IT investments of other firms from which they hire IT labor. Our estimates indicate that over the last two decades, productivity spillovers from the IT investments of other firms transmitted through this channel have contributed 20%-30% as much to productivity growth as firms' own IT investments. Moreover, we find that the productivity benefits of locating near other IT-intensive firms can primarily be explained by the mobility of technical workers within the region. Our results are unique to the flow of IT workers among firms, not other occupations, which rules out some alternative explanations related to the similarity of firms that participate in the same labor flow network.</description><author>Tambe, Prasanna; Hitt, Lorin M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Industry Peers Respond to Control Threats?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Servaes, Henri; Tamayo, Ane
This paper studies how industry peers respond when another firm in the industry is the subject of a hostile takeover attempt. The industry peers cut their capital spending, free cash flows, and cash holdings, and increase their leverage and payouts to shareholders. They also adopt more takeover defenses. The stock price reaction upon announcement of the takeover is positive and larger for peer firms with higher capital spending and higher free cash flows. Before the takeover attempt, the peer firms borrow less and invest more than predicted. Both stock returns and performance improve after the takeover attempt. These results are consistent with the argument that the control threat has important spillover effects for the other firms in the industry.</description><author>Servaes, Henri; Tamayo, Ane</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Responses to Entry in Multi-Sided Markets: The Impact of Craigslist on Local Newspapers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Seamans, Robert; Zhu, Feng
How do firms respond to entry in multi-sided markets? We address this question by studying the impact of Craigslist, a website providing classified-advertising services, on local U.S. newspapers. We exploit temporal and geographical variation in Craigslist's entry to show that newspapers with greater reliance on classified-ad revenue experience a larger drop in classified-ad rates after Craigslist's entry. The impact of Craigslist's entry on the classified-ad side appears to propagate to other sides of the newspapers' market. On the subscriber side, these newspapers experience an increase in subscription prices, a decrease in circulation, and an increase in differentiation from each other. On the display-ad side, affected newspapers experience a decrease in display-ad rates. We also find evidence that affected newspapers are less likely to make their content available online. Finally, we estimate that Craigslist's entry leads to $5.0 billion (year 2000 dollars) in savings to classified-ad buyers during 2000-2007.</description><author>Seamans, Robert; Zhu, Feng</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forward-Looking Market Risk Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duan, Jin-Chuan; Zhang, Weiqi
A method for computing forward-looking market risk premium is developed in this paper. We first derive a theoretical expression that links forward-looking risk premium to investors' risk aversion and forward-looking volatility, skewness, and kurtosis of cumulative return. In addition, investors' risk aversion is theoretically linked to volatility spread, defined as the gap between the risk- neutral volatility deduced from option data and the physical return volatility exhibited by return data. The volatility spread formula serves as the basis for using the generalized method of moments to estimate investors' risk aversion. We adopt the generalized autoregressive conditional heteroskedasticity model for the physical return process and estimate the model using the S&amp;P 500 daily index returns and then deduce the forward-looking variance, skewness, and kurtosis of the corresponding cumulative return. The forward-looking risk premiums are estimated monthly over the sample period of 2001-2010, and all are found to be positive. Furthermore, two asset pricing tests are conducted. First, change in forward-looking risk premiums is negatively related to the S&amp;P 500 holding period return, reflecting that an increase in discount rate reduces current stock prices. Second, market illiquidity positively affects forward-looking risk premium, indicating that forward-looking risk premium contains an illiquidity risk premium component.</description><author>Duan, Jin-Chuan; Zhang, Weiqi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pareto Efficiency in Robust Optimization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iancu, Dan A.; Trichakis, Nikolaos
This paper formalizes and adapts the well-known concept of Pareto efficiency in the context of the popular robust optimization (RO) methodology for linear optimization problems. We argue that the classical RO paradigm need not produce solutions that possess the associated property of Pareto optimality, and we illustrate via examples how this could lead to inefficiencies and suboptimal performance in practice. We provide a basic theoretical characterization of Pareto robustly optimal (PRO) solutions and extend the RO framework by proposing practical methods that verify Pareto optimality and generate solutions that are PRO. Critically important, our methodology involves solving optimization problems that are of the same complexity as the underlying robust problems; hence, the potential improvements from our framework come at essentially limited extra computational cost. We perform numerical experiments drawn from three different application areas (portfolio optimization, inventory management, and project management), which demonstrate that PRO solutions have a significant potential upside compared with solutions obtained using classical RO methods.</description><author>Iancu, Dan A.; Trichakis, Nikolaos</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Hiring and Retention Policies for Heterogeneous Workers Who Learn</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arlotto, Alessandro; Chick, Stephen E.; Gans, Noah
We study the hiring and retention of heterogeneous workers who learn over time. We show that the problem can be analyzed as an infinite-armed bandit with switching costs, and we apply results from Bergemann and Valimaki [Bergemann D, Valimaki J (2001) Stationary multi-choice bandit problems. J. Econom. Dynam. Control 25(10): 1585-1594] to characterize the optimal hiring and retention policy. For problems with Gaussian data, we develop approximations that allow the efficient implementation of the optimal policy and the evaluation of its performance. Our numerical examples demonstrate that the value of active monitoring and screening of employees can be substantial.</description><author>Arlotto, Alessandro; Chick, Stephen E.; Gans, Noah</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Matthew: Effect or Fable?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Azoulay, Pierre; Stuart, Toby; Wang, Yanbo
In a market context, a status effect occurs when actors are accorded differential recognition for their efforts depending on their location in a status ordering, holding constant the quality of these efforts. In practice, because it is very difficult to measure quality, this ceteris paribus proviso often precludes convincing empirical assessments of the magnitude of status effects. We address this problem by examining the impact of a major status-conferring prize that shifts actors' positions in a prestige ordering. Specifically, using a precisely constructed matched sample, we estimate the effect of a scientist becoming a Howard Hughes Medical Institute (HHMI) Investigator on citations to articles the scientist published before the prize was awarded. We do find evidence of a postappointment citation boost, but the effect is small and limited to a short window of time. Consistent with theories of status, however, the effect of the prize is significantly larger when there is uncertainty about article quality, and when prize winners are of (relatively) low status at the time of election to the HHMI Investigator Program.</description><author>Azoulay, Pierre; Stuart, Toby; Wang, Yanbo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Onshore and Offshore Hedge Funds: Are They Twins?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aragon, George; Liang, Bing; Park, Hyuna
Contrary to offshore hedge funds, U.S.-domiciled ("onshore") funds are subject to strict marketing prohibitions, accredited investor requirements, a limited number of investors, and taxable accounts. We exploit these differences to test predictions about organizational design, investment strategy, capital flows, and fund performance. We find that onshore funds are associated with greater share restrictions, more liquid assets, and a reduced sensitivity of capital flows to superior past performance. We also find some evidence that onshore funds outperform offshore funds, depending on the sample period. The results suggest that a fund's investment and financial policies reflect differences in investor clienteles and the regulatory environment.</description><author>Aragon, George; Liang, Bing; Park, Hyuna</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Television Advertising and Online Search</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Joo, Mingyu; Wilbur, Kenneth C.; Cowgill, Bo; Zhu, Yi
Despite a 20-year trend toward integrated marketing communications, advertisers seldom coordinate television and search advertising campaigns. We find that television advertising for financial services brands increases both the number of related Google searches and searchers' tendency to use branded keywords in place of generic keywords. The elasticity of a brand's total searches with respect to its TV advertising is 0.17, an effect that peaks in the morning. These results suggest that practitioners should account for cross-media effects when planning, executing, and evaluating both television and search advertising campaigns.</description><author>Joo, Mingyu; Wilbur, Kenneth C.; Cowgill, Bo; Zhu, Yi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyst Recommendations, Mutual Fund Herding, and Overreaction in Stock Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Nerissa C.; Wei, Kelsey D.; Wermers, Russ
This paper documents that mutual funds "herd" (trade together) into stocks with consensus sell-side analyst upgrades, and herd out of stocks with consensus downgrades. This influence of analyst recommendation changes on fund herding is stronger for downgrades, and among managers with greater career concerns. These findings indicate that career-concerned managers are incentivized to follow analyst information, and that managers have a greater tendency to herd on negative stock information, given the greater reputational and litigation risk of holding losing stocks. Furthermore, starting in the mid-1990s (when aggregate mutual fund equity ownership is significantly higher), stocks traded by career-concerned herds of fund managers in response to analyst recommendation changes experience a significant same-quarter price impact, followed by a sharp subsequent price reversal. Our evidence suggests that analyst recommendation revisions induce herding by career-concerned fund managers, and that this type of trading has become price destabilizing with the increasing level of mutual fund ownership of stocks.</description><author>Brown, Nerissa C.; Wei, Kelsey D.; Wermers, Russ</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamics of Consumer Adoption of Financial Innovation: The Case of ATM Cards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Botao; Ching, Andrew T.
We develop a structural consumer life-cycle model to investigate consumers' adoption and usage decisions of ATM cards. If consumers are forward-looking with a known discount factor, our framework can control for the heterogeneous life span faced by consumers of different ages, and hence measure adoption costs more accurately. Moreover, our framework can recover the monetary value of total adoption costs. To estimate our model, we use an Italian panel data set, which contains information on consumers' adoption decisions for ATM cards, and their cash withdrawal patterns before and after adoption. Our results suggest that one could significantly overestimate adoption costs for the elderly when ignoring their shorter life span. Our policy experiments show that a sign-up bonus targeted to the elderly could be much more effective if implemented as a limited-time offer rather than a permanent offer. Interestingly, if the sign-up bonus is permanent, younger consumers may strategically postpone adoption.</description><author>Yang, Botao; Ching, Andrew T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Branch and Bound Algorithm for a Class of Biobjective Mixed Integer Programs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stidsen, Thomas; Andersen, Kim Allan; Dammann, Bernd
Most real-world optimization problems are multiobjective by nature, involving noncomparable objectives. Many of these problems can be formulated in terms of a set of linear objective functions that should be simultaneously optimized over a class of linear constraints. Often there is the complicating factor that some of the variables are required to be integral. The resulting class of problems is named multiobjective mixed integer programming (MOMIP) problems. Solving these kinds of optimization problems exactly requires a method that can generate the whole set of nondominated points (the Pareto-optimal front). In this paper, we first give a survey of the newly developed branch and bound methods for solving MOMIP problems. After that, we propose a new branch and bound method for solving a subclass of MOMIP problems, where only two objectives are allowed, the integer variables are binary, and one of the two objectives has only integer variables. The proposed method is able to find the full set of nondominated points. It is tested on a large number of problem instances, from six different classes of MOMIP problems. The results reveal that the developed biobjective branch and bound method performs better on five of the six test problems, compared with a generic two-phase method. At this time, the two-phase method is the most preferred exact method for solving MOMIP problems with two criteria and binary variables.</description><author>Stidsen, Thomas; Andersen, Kim Allan; Dammann, Bernd</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analysis of Product Rollover Strategies in the Presence of Strategic Customers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liang, Chao; Cakanyildirim, Metin; Sethi, Suresh P.
Frequent product introductions emphasize the importance of product rollover strategies. With single rollover, when a new product is introduced, the old product is phased out from the market. With dual rollover, the old product remains in the market along with the new product. Anticipating the introduction of the new product and the potential markdown of the old product, strategic customers may delay their purchases. We study the interaction between product rollover strategies and strategic customer purchasing behavior and find that single rollover is more valuable when the new product's innovation is low and the number of strategic customers is high. Interestingly and counter to intuition, the firm may have to charge a lower price for the old product as well as receive a lower profit with a higher value disposal (outside) option for the old product under single rollover. Facing a market composed of both strategic and myopic customers, the firm does not necessarily reduce the stocking level as more myopic customers become strategic.</description><author>Liang, Chao; Cakanyildirim, Metin; Sethi, Suresh P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Integrating Problem Solvers from Analogous Markets in New Product Ideation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Franke, Nikolaus; Poetz, Marion K.; Schreier, Martin
Who provides better inputs to new product ideation tasks, problem solvers with expertise in the area for which new products are to be developed or problem solvers from "analogous" markets that are distant but share an analogous problem or need? Conventional wisdom appears to suggest that target market expertise is indispensable, which is why most managers searching for new ideas tend to stay within their own market context even when they do search outside their firms' boundaries. However, in a unique symmetric experiment that isolates the effect of market origin, we find evidence for the opposite: Although solutions provided by problem solvers from analogous markets show lower potential for immediate use, they demonstrate substantially higher levels of novelty. Also, compared to established novelty drivers, this effect appears highly relevant from a managerial perspective: we find that including problem solvers from analogous markets versus the target market accounts for almost two-thirds of the well-known effect of involving lead users instead of average problem solvers. This effect is further amplified when the analogous distance between the markets increases, i.e., when searching in far versus near analogous markets. Finally, results indicate that the analogous market effect is particularly strong in the upper tail of the novelty distribution, which again underscores the effect's practical importance. All of this suggests that it might pay to systematically search across firm-external sources of innovation that were formerly out of scope for most managers.</description><author>Franke, Nikolaus; Poetz, Marion K.; Schreier, Martin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Individuals Have Preferences Used in Macro-Finance Models? An Experimental Investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Alexander L.; Kim, Hwagyun
Recent financial studies often assume that agents have Epstein-Zin preferences-preferences that require agents to care about when uncertainty is resolved. Under this "recursive-preference" framework, the preference for uncertainty resolution is entirely determined by an agent's preferences for risk and intertemporal substitution. To test the implications of this model, this paper presents an experiment designed to elicit subject preferences on risk, time, intertemporal substitution, and uncertainty resolution. Results reveal that most subjects prefer early resolution of uncertainty and have relative risk aversion greater than the reciprocal of the elasticity of intertemporal substitution, consistent with the predictions by recursive preferences. Subjects are classified in a finite mixture model by their risk, time, and intertemporal-substitution parameters. Regression results show that types predicted by the Epstein-Zin model to prefer early resolution choose early resolution with 20%-50% higher probability.</description><author>Brown, Alexander L.; Kim, Hwagyun</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Analysts Analyze Mergers?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tehranian, Hassan; Zhao, Mengxing; Zhu, Julie L.
After the completion of a merger and acquisition (M&amp;A) transaction, the target firm is delisted, but some analysts who covered it retain coverage of the merged firm. We hypothesize that this decision is based on two factors: the analyst's ability to cover the merged firm and his or her assessment of the M&amp;A deal. Consistent with these hypotheses, we find that the remaining target analysts provide more accurate earnings forecasts and more optimistic stock recommendations and growth forecasts for the merged firms than do the remaining acquirer analysts. We also find that a higher percentage of target analysts choosing to cover the merged firm is associated with better operating and long-term stock performance of that firm, but we do not find this relation with acquirer analysts. Our results extend the literature by showing that target analysts' coverage decisions reveal valuable information about a merged firm's future performance.</description><author>Tehranian, Hassan; Zhao, Mengxing; Zhu, Julie L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Firms Become Different? A Dynamic Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Selove, Matthew
This paper presents a dynamic investment game in which firms that are initially identical develop assets that are specialized to different market segments. The model assumes that there are increasing returns to investment in a segment, for example, as a result of word-of-mouth or learning curve effects. I derive three key results: (1) Under certain conditions there is a unique equilibrium in which firms that are only slightly different focus all of their investment in different segments, causing small random differences to expand into large permanent differences. (2) If, on the other hand, sufficiently large random shocks are possible, firms over time repeatedly change their strategies, switching focus from one segment to another. (3) A firm might want to reduce its own assets in the smaller segment in order to entice its competitor to shift focus to this segment.</description><author>Selove, Matthew</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should Sellers Prefer Auctions? A Laboratory Comparison of Auctions and Sequential Mechanisms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davis, Andrew M.; Katok, Elena; Kwasnica, Anthony M.
When bidders incur a cost to learn their valuations, bidder entry can impact auction performance. Two common selling mechanisms in this environment are an English auction and a sequential bidding process. Theoretically, sellers should prefer the auction, because it generates higher expected revenues, whereas bidders should prefer the sequential mechanism, because it generates higher expected bidder profits. We compare the two mechanisms in a controlled laboratory environment, varying the entry cost, and find that, contrary to the theoretical predictions, average seller revenues tend to be higher under the sequential mechanism, whereas average bidder profits are approximately the same. We identify three systematic behavioral deviations from the theoretical model: (1) in the auction, bidders do not enter 100% of the time; (2) in the sequential mechanism, bidders do not set preemptive bids according to the predicted threshold strategy; and (3) subsequent bidders tend to overenter in response to preemptive bids by first bidders. We develop a model of noisy bidder-entry costs that is consistent with these behaviors, and we show that our model organizes the experimental data well.</description><author>Davis, Andrew M.; Katok, Elena; Kwasnica, Anthony M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prospect Theory and the Newsvendor Problem</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nagarajan, Mahesh; Shechter, Steven
The newsvendor problem is a fundamental decision problem in operations management. Various independent experimental studies in laboratory settings have shown similar deviations from the theoretical optimal order quantity. We clarify that Prospect Theory, a prevalent framework for decision making under uncertainty, cannot explain the consistent empirical findings.</description><author>Nagarajan, Mahesh; Shechter, Steven</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Simultaneously Learning and Optimizing Using Controlled Variance Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>den Boer, Arnoud V.; Zwart, Bert
Price experimentation is an important tool for firms to find the optimal selling price of their products. It should be conducted properly, since experimenting with selling prices can be costly. A firm, therefore, needs to find a pricing policy that optimally balances between learning the optimal price and gaining revenue. In this paper, we propose such a pricing policy, called controlled variance pricing (CVP). The key idea of the policy is to enhance the certainty equivalent pricing policy with a taboo interval around the average of previously chosen prices. The width of the taboo interval shrinks at an appropriate rate as the amount of data gathered gets large; this guarantees sufficient price dispersion. For a large class of demand models, we show that this procedure is strongly consistent, which means that eventually the value of the optimal price will be learned, and derive upper bounds on the regret, which is the expected amount of money lost due to not using the optimal price. Numerical tests indicate that CVP performs well on different demand models and time scales.</description><author>den Boer, Arnoud V.; Zwart, Bert</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Design of Social Comparison Effects: Setting Reference Groups and Reference Points</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roels, Guillaume; Su, Xuanming
In this paper, we study how social planners should exploit social comparisons to pursue their objectives. We consider two modes of social comparison, referred to as behind-averse and ahead-seeking behaviors, depending on whether individuals experience a utility loss from underperforming or a utility gain from overperforming relative to their peers. Modeling social comparison as a game between players, we find that ahead-seeking behavior leads to output polarization, whereas behind-averse behavior leads to output clustering. A social planner can mitigate these effects in two ways: (i) by providing the full reference distribution of outputs instead of an aggregate reference point based on the average output and (ii) by assigning players into uniform rather than diverse reference groups. Social planners may thus need to tailor the reference structure to the predominant mode of social comparison and their objective. A performance-focused social planner may set the reference structure so as to maximize the output of either the top or the bottom player depending on whether she puts greater marginal weight to larger or smaller outputs. When the social planner also cares about utility, she faces a dilemma because performance optimization may not be aligned with utility maximization. Inevitably, the social planner will have to confront equity issues because better performance may not reflect greater effort or greater ability.</description><author>Roels, Guillaume; Su, Xuanming</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing and Revenue Management: The Value of Coordination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kocabiyikoglu, Ayse; Popescu, Ioana; Stefanescu, Catalina
The integration of systems for pricing and revenue management must trade off potential revenue gains against significant practical and technical challenges. This dilemma motivates us to investigate the value of coordinating decisions on prices and capacity allocation in a stylized setting. We propose two pairs of sequential policies for making static decisions-on pricing and revenue management-that differ in their degree of integration (hierarchical versus coordinated) and their pricing inputs (deterministic versus stochastic). For a large class of stochastic, price-dependent demand models, we prove that these four heuristics admit tractable solutions satisfying intuitive sensitivity properties. We further evaluate numerically the performance of these policies relative to a fully coordinated model, which is generally intractable. We find it interesting that near-optimal performance is usually achieved by a simple hierarchical policy that sets prices first, based on a nonnested stochastic model, and then uses these prices to optimize nested capacity allocation. This tractable policy largely outperforms its counterpart based on a deterministic pricing model. Jointly optimizing price and allocation decisions for the high-end segment improves performance, but the largest revenue benefits stem from adjusting prices to account for demand risk.</description><author>Kocabiyikoglu, Ayse; Popescu, Ioana; Stefanescu, Catalina</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Software Reuse in Incremental Software Development: A Transfer Pricing Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ceran, Yasin; Dawande, Milind; Liu, Dengpan; Mookerjee, Vijay
This study develops optimal transfer pricing schemes that manage software reuse in incremental software development, namely, a development regime wherein users begin utilizing parts of the system that are released to them even before the system is entirely completed. In this setting, conflicts can arise between developers and users from divergent interests concerning the release of functionalities in the project. The release of functionalities is influenced by reuse, i.e., the effort spent by the development team to write code that can be reused within the same project or in future projects. For example, the development team may choose to spend extra effort to make certain portions of the system reusable because doing so could reduce the effort needed to develop the entire system. However, the additional effort spent on reuse could delay the release of certain critical functionality, making such a strategy suboptimal for the users. Thus, optimal reuse decisions for developers and users could be different. In addition, from the firm's perspective, reuse decisions must not only balance the objectives of developers and users for the current project, but reuse effort may be spent to benefit future projects. Our study also highlights the fact that reuse may not always be beneficial for the firm. To this end, we consider different instances of the user-developer conflict and provide transfer pricing schemes that operate under information asymmetry and achieve two key properties: firm-level optimality and truth revelation.</description><author>Ceran, Yasin; Dawande, Milind; Liu, Dengpan; Mookerjee, Vijay</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Don't Ask Me If You Will Not Listen: The Dilemma of Consultative Participation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corgnet, Brice; Hernan Gonzalez, Roberto
We study the effect of consultative participation in an experimental principal-agent game, where the principal can consult the agent's preferred option regarding the cost function of the transfer to be implemented in the final stage of the game. We show that consulting the agent was beneficial to principals as long as they followed the agent's choice. Ignoring the agent's choice was detrimental to the principal because it engendered negative emotions and low levels of transfers. Nevertheless, the majority of principals were reluctant to change their mind and adopt the agent's proposal. Our results suggest that the ability to change one's own mind is an important dimension of managerial success.</description><author>Corgnet, Brice; Hernan Gonzalez, Roberto</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relationship Organization and Price Delegation: An Experimental Study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lim, Noah; Ham, Sung H.
Price delegation to the salesforce is a practice widely adopted by firms. This paper examines the relationship between price delegation and managerial profits using a laboratory economics experiment. A novel feature of our experiment is that we study how varying the relationship organization of the sales manager and salesperson to allow for (1) requests by the salesperson for the manager to choose price delegation, and for (2) the manager to award a small bonus after observing the salesperson's decisions, can affect behavior. The results show that, contrary to the theoretical prediction, managers choose price delegation frequently and salespeople respond reciprocally, leading to higher manager profits under price delegation. Moreover, this behavior increases when requests and bonuses are allowed. We show that a behavioral economics model that incorporates positive reciprocity can explain these results well.</description><author>Lim, Noah; Ham, Sung H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Giving It All Up on Valuation: A New Look at the Endowment Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schurr, Amos; Ritov, Ilana
In three experiments we show that the endowment effect-the tendency to demand more money for relinquishing owned goods than one is willing to pay for the same goods-fails to emerge when sellers are not fully depleted of their endowment. This finding is incompatible with prospect theory's account of the effect as stemming primarily from aversion to loss relative to the individual's current state. We suggest a new account of the endowment effect as reflecting the human aversion to "giving it all up" rather than simply an aversion to incurring any loss relative to the status quo. Experiments 1 and 2 show the effect employing a pricing paradigm. Experiment 3 examines what constitutes "all" in the giving-it-all-up effect.</description><author>Schurr, Amos; Ritov, Ilana</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Closer Look at the Short-Term Return Reversal</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Da, Zhi; Liu, Qianqiu; Schaumburg, Ernst
Stock returns unexplained by "fundamentals," such as cash flow news, are more likely to reverse in the short run than those linked to fundamental news. Making novel use of analyst forecast revisions to measure cash flow news, a simple enhanced reversal strategy generates a risk-adjusted return four times the size of the standard reversal strategy. Importantly, isolating the component of past returns not driven by fundamentals provides a cleaner setting for testing existing theories of short-term reversals. Using this approach, we find that both liquidity shocks and investor sentiment contribute to the observed short-term reversal, but in different ways: Specifically, the reversal profit is attributable to liquidity shocks on the long side because fire sales more likely demand liquidity, and it is attributable to investor sentiment on the short side because short-sale constraints prevent the immediate elimination of overvaluation.</description><author>Da, Zhi; Liu, Qianqiu; Schaumburg, Ernst</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed Bond Trading, Corporate Yield Spreads, and Corporate Default Prediction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Song; Zhou, Xing
Taking advantage of recently augmented corporate bond transaction data, we examine the pricing implications of informed trading in corporate bonds and its ability to predict corporate defaults. We find that microstructure measures of information asymmetry seem to capture adverse selection in corporate bond trading reasonably well. We demonstrate that information asymmetry in bond trading has explanatory power for corporate bond yield spreads, and this result holds after controlling for the transaction costs of liquidity, credit risk, and other traditional bond pricing factors. Furthermore, information asymmetry can help forecast corporate defaults after conditioning on other default prediction variables. Such forecasting ability of informed bond trading is especially useful for private firms because the bond market constitutes the only venue for informed traders to exploit their information advantages.</description><author>Han, Song; Zhou, Xing</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entropy-Based Optimization of Nonlinear Separable Discrete Decision Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nakagawa, Yuji; James, Ross J. W.; Rego, Cesar; Edirisinghe, Chanaka
This paper develops a new way to help solve difficult linear and nonlinear discrete-optimization decision models more efficiently by introducing a problem-difficulty metric that uses the concept of entropy from information theory. Our entropy metric is employed to devise rules for problem partitioning within an implicit enumeration method, where branching is accomplished based on the subproblem complexity. The only requirement for applying our metric is the availability of (upper) bounds on branching subproblems, which are often computed within most implicit enumeration methods such as branch-and-bound (or cutting-plane-based) methods. Focusing on problems with a relatively small number of constraints, but with a large number of variables, we develop a hybrid partitioning and enumeration solution scheme by combining the entropic approach with the recently developed improved surrogate constraint (ISC) method to produce the new method we call ISCENT. Our computational results indicate that ISCENT can be an order of magnitude more efficient than commercial solvers, such as CPLEX, for convex instances with no more than eight constraints. Furthermore, for nonconvex instances, ISCENT is shown to be significantly more efficient than other standard global solvers.</description><author>Nakagawa, Yuji; James, Ross J. W.; Rego, Cesar; Edirisinghe, Chanaka</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Resource Flexibility and Capital Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chod, Jiri; Zhou, Jianer
This paper examines how the optimal investment in the capacity of flexible and nonflexible resources is affected by financial leverage and, conversely, how a firm's resource flexibility affects its optimal capital structure. We consider a two-product firm that invests in the optimal capacity of product-flexible and product-dedicated resources in the presence of demand uncertainty. Before investing in capacity, the firm issues the optimal amount of debt, trading off the tax benefit and lower transaction cost of debt financing against the cost of financial distress and the agency cost associated with leverage. We show that in the presence of debt, resource flexibility has benefits in addition to reducing the mismatch between supply and demand. Namely, resource flexibility mitigates the shareholder-debtholder agency conflict as well as the risk of costly default. Most interestingly, we show that resource flexibility mitigates the underinvestment problem because it reduces the probability that a firm will go bankrupt with some of its capacity being fully utilized. When lenders anticipate that a firm will choose a relatively flexible capacity mix, they should provide more favorable credit terms, to which the firm should respond by issuing more debt. The main empirical predictions are that resource flexibility is negatively related to the cost of borrowing and positively related to debt.</description><author>Chod, Jiri; Zhou, Jianer</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium Discovery and Preopening Mechanisms in an Experimental Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Biais, Bruno; Bisiere, Christophe; Pouget, Sebastien
We experimentally analyze how to design preopening mechanisms facilitating coordination on high equilibrium liquidity and gains from trade. We allow a call auction to be preceded by a preopening or not, preopening orders to be binding or not, and the opening time to be deterministic or random. When the preopening is nonbinding, traders place manipulative orders, reducing the credibility of preplay communication. Random market opening deters manipulation, but also hinders communication by making it costly. Gains from trade are maximized when preopening orders are binding. This enables some traders to place early limit orders, attracting further liquidity.</description><author>Biais, Bruno; Bisiere, Christophe; Pouget, Sebastien</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Line Design with Seller-Induced Learning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xiong, Hui; Chen, Ying-Ju
In practice, some well-established service providers (sellers) offer one-time experiences or product demonstrations for the services that have been introduced to the market for years. Such activities, labeled as seller-induced learning, not only help the consumers learn more about themselves but also exploit the consumers by elaborating on the consumer heterogeneity. When the seller-induced learning completely resolves the consumers' valuation uncertainty, it can facilitate a more sophisticated price discrimination scheme and may give rise to a relatively more efficient allocation. Nevertheless, if there is residual valuation uncertainty, the seller may abandon the seller-induced learning to avoid the exacerbated ex post cannibalization. We show that an exploding offer shall sometimes be offered in conjunction with the seller-induced learning to encourage immediate purchases when uncertainty arises in only some consumers. We identify regimes under which the seller-induced learning is charged at a strictly positive price. Under these regimes, the seller need not sacrifice the ex post efficiency upon inducing consumer learning. Therefore, our result indicates that the seller-induced learning may eliminate the conflict between rent extraction and efficiency initiatives. However, quality distortion prevails when the seller provides an identical menu for all the consumers or the free seller-induced learning.</description><author>Xiong, Hui; Chen, Ying-Ju</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Portfolio Choice with Savoring and Disappointment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jouini, Elyes; Karehnke, Paul; Napp, Clotilde
We revisit the model proposed by Gollier and Muermann [Gollier C, Muermann A (2010) Optimal choice and beliefs with ex ante savoring and ex post disappointment. Management Sci. 56(8): 1272-1284; hereafter, GM]. In the GM model, for a given lottery, agents form anticipated expected payoffs and the set of possible anticipations is assumed to be exogenously fixed. We propose sets of possible anticipations that are endogenously determined. This permits us to compare and evaluate in a consistent manner lotteries with different supports and to revisit the portfolio choice problem. We obtain new conclusions and interesting insights. Our extended model can rationalize a variety of empirically observed puzzles such as a positive demand for assets with negative expected returns, preference for skewed returns, and underdiversification of portfolios.</description><author>Jouini, Elyes; Karehnke, Paul; Napp, Clotilde</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Death Can Tell: Are Executives Paid for Their Contributions to Firm Value?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nguyen, Bang Dang; Nielsen, Kasper Meisner
Using stock price reactions to sudden deaths of top executives as a measure of expected contribution to shareholder value, we examine the relationship between executive pay and managerial contribution to shareholder value. We find, first, that the managerial labor market is characterized by positive sorting: managers with high perceived contributions to shareholder value obtain higher pay. The executive pay-contribution relationship is stronger for professional executives and for executives with high compensation. We estimate, second, that an average top executive (chief executive officer) appears to retain 71% (65%) of the marginal rent from the firm-manager relationship. We examine, third, how the executive pay-contribution relationship varies with individual, firm, and industry characteristics. Overall, our results are informative for the ongoing discussion about the level of executive compensation.</description><author>Nguyen, Bang Dang; Nielsen, Kasper Meisner</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of Operational Flexibility in the Presence of Input and Output Price Uncertainties with Oil Refining Applications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dong, Lingxiu; Kouvelis, Panos; Wu, Xiaole
Refining is indispensable to almost every natural-resource-based commodity industry. It involves a series of complex processes that transform inputs with a wide range of quality characteristics into refined finished products sold to end markets. In this paper, we take the perspective of a profit-maximizing refiner that considers upgrading its existing simple refinery to include intermediate-conversion flexibility, i.e., the capability of converting heavy intermediate components to light ones. We present a stylized two-stage stochastic programming model of a petroleum refinery to investigate the value drivers of conversion flexibility and the impact of input and output market conditions on its economic potential. Conversion flexibility adds value to refineries by either transforming a nonprofitable situation into a profitable one (referred to as purchase benefit) or improving profitability of an already profitable situation (referred to as unit revenue benefit). In a real-data-calibrated numerical study, we find the value of conversion flexibility (VoC) to be significant, accounting for 40% of the expected profit with conversion, and the purchase benefit and unit revenue benefit are equally important. Contrary to the intuition that, as a recourse action, conversion offers higher value for greater input price volatility, we find that VoC may decrease in input price volatility as a result of the differential impacts of increasing price volatility on the purchase benefit and the unit revenue benefit. Refineries also vary in their range flexibility, i.e., the ability to accommodate a narrow or wide range of inputs of different quality levels. Whether the range flexibility increases or decreases the value of conversion flexibility is affected by the direction in which the refinery expands its processing range and the heaviness of crude oils.</description><author>Dong, Lingxiu; Kouvelis, Panos; Wu, Xiaole</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Buy-It-Now or Take-a-Chance: Price Discrimination Through Randomized Auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Celis, L. Elisa; Lewis, Gregory; Mobius, Markus; Nazerzadeh, Hamid
Increasingly detailed consumer information makes sophisticated price discrimination possible. At fine levels of aggregation, demand may not obey standard regularity conditions. We propose a new randomized sales mechanism for such environments. Bidders can "buy-it-now" at a posted price, or "take-a-chance" in an auction where the top d &gt; 1 bidders are equally likely to win. The randomized allocation incentivizes high-valuation bidders to buy-it-now. We analyze equilibrium behavior and apply our analysis to advertiser bidding data from Microsoft Advertising Exchange. In counterfactual simulations, our mechanism increases revenue by 4.4% and consumer surplus by 14.5% compared to an optimal second-price auction.</description><author>Celis, L. Elisa; Lewis, Gregory; Mobius, Markus; Nazerzadeh, Hamid</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mean Field Equilibria of Dynamic Auctions with Learning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iyer, Krishnamurthy; Johari, Ramesh; Sundararajan, Mukund
We study learning in a dynamic setting where identical copies of a good are sold over time through a sequence of second-price auctions. Each agent in the market has an unknown independent private valuation that determines the distribution of the reward she obtains from the good; for example, in sponsored search settings, advertisers may initially be unsure of the value of a click. Though the induced dynamic game is complex, we simplify analysis of the market using an approximation methodology known as mean field equilibrium (MFE). The methodology assumes that agents optimize only with respect to long-run average estimates of the distribution of other players' bids. We show a remarkable fact: In a mean field equilibrium, the agent has an optimal strategy where she bids truthfully according to a conjoint valuation. The conjoint valuation is the sum of her current expected valuation, together with an overbid amount that is exactly the expected marginal benefit of one additional observation about her true private valuation. Under mild conditions on the model, we show that an MFE exists, and that it is a good approximation to a rational agent's behavior as the number of agents increases. Formally, if every agent except one follows the MFE strategy, then the remaining agent's loss on playing the MFE strategy converges to zero as the number of agents in the market increases. We conclude by discussing the implications of the auction format and design on the auctioneer's revenue. In particular, we establish the revenue equivalence of standard auctions in dynamic mean field settings, and discuss optimal selection of reserve prices in dynamic auctions.</description><author>Iyer, Krishnamurthy; Johari, Ramesh; Sundararajan, Mukund</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bargaining Ability and Competitive Advantage: Empirical Evidence from Medical Devices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grennan, Matthew
In markets where buyers and suppliers negotiate, supplier costs, buyer willingness to pay, and competition determine only a range of potential prices, leaving the final price dependent on other factors (e. g., negotiating skill), which I call bargaining ability. I use a model of buyer demand and buyer-supplier bargaining, combined with detailed data on prices and quantities at the buyer-supplier relationship level, to estimate firm-bargaining abilities in the context of the coronary stent industry where different hospitals (buyers) pay different prices for the exact same product from the same supplier. I estimate that (1) variation in bargaining abilities explains 79% of this price variation, (2) bargaining ability has a large firm-specific component, and (3) changes in the distribution of bargaining abilities over time suggest learning as an important channel influencing bargaining ability. Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2014.2006.</description><author>Grennan, Matthew</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Emergent Life Cycle: The Tension Between Knowledge Change and Knowledge Retention in Open Online Coproduction Communities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kane, Gerald C.; Johnson, Jeremiah; Majchrzak, Ann
Online coproduction communities often face a challenge of whether to change or retain the knowledge they have created. Disparate and often conflicting theoretical models have been used to explain how these communities respond to this tension. We conducted a case study of how one online coproduction community-the nine-year history of the Wikipedia article on autism-handles this tension. We find that the nature of the change-retain tension and the community's response to it fluctuates considerably over the life of the community. These changes bear striking similarities to processes associated with traditional software development life cycles, despite the absence of traditional control mechanisms. What initially appear to be conflicts in the extant literature actually describe different roles and production focus at the different stages of development. Disruptive events signal the need for the community to shift production focus, which often involves members joining and leaving the production process, rather than adopting new roles.</description><author>Kane, Gerald C.; Johnson, Jeremiah; Majchrzak, Ann</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Improving Penetration Forecasts Using Social Interactions Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Toubia, Olivier; Goldenberg, Jacob; Garcia, Rosanna
We propose an approach for using individual-level data on social interactions (e. g., number of recommendations received by consumers, number of recommendations given by adopters, number of social ties) to improve the aggregate penetration forecasts made by extant diffusion models. We capture social interactions through an individual-level hazard rate in such a way that the resulting aggregate penetration process is available in closed form and nests extant diffusion models. The parameters of the model may be estimated by combining early aggregate penetration data with social interactions data collected from a sample of consumers in as few as one time period. We illustrate our approach by applying it to the mixed influence model (Bass model) and the more recent asymmetric influence model. A field study conducted in collaboration with a consumer packaged goods company and a marketing research company confirms that incorporating social interactions data using the proposed approach has the potential to result in improved aggregate penetration forecasts in managerially relevant settings.</description><author>Toubia, Olivier; Goldenberg, Jacob; Garcia, Rosanna</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When to Sell Your Idea: Theory and Evidence from the Movie Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Luo, Hong
I study a model of investment and sale of ideas and test its empirical implications using a novel data set from the market for original movie ideas. Consistent with the theoretical results, I find that buyers are reluctant to meet unproven sellers for early-stage ideas, which restricts sellers to either developing the ideas fully (to sell them later) or abandoning them. In contrast, experienced sellers can attract buyers at any stage, and they sell worse ideas sooner and better ideas later. These results have important managerial implications for buyers and sellers and show that, in such contexts, policy interventions that discourage buyer participation-such as stronger intellectual property protection-may diminish the market for ideas and hurt inexperienced sellers.</description><author>Luo, Hong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Selecting the Best? Spillover and Shadows in Elimination Tournaments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Jennifer; Minor, Dylan B.
We consider how past, current, and future competition within an elimination tournament affect the probability that the stronger player wins. We present a two-stage model that yields the following main results: (1) a shadow effect wherein the stronger the expected future competitor, the lower the probability that the stronger player wins in the current stage; and (2) an effort spillover effect wherein previous effort reduces the probability that the stronger player wins in the current stage. We test our theory predictions using data from high-stakes tournaments. Empirical results suggest that shadow and spillover effects influence match outcomes and have already been priced into betting markets.</description><author>Brown, Jennifer; Minor, Dylan B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Commercialization Strategies for Disruptive Technologies: Evidence from the Speech Recognition Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marx, Matt; Gans, Joshua S.; Hsu, David H.
When start-up innovation involves a potentially disruptive technology-initially lagging in the predominant performance metric, but with a potentially favorable trajectory of improvement-incumbents may be wary of engaging in cooperative commercialization with the start-up. While the prevailing theory of disruptive innovation suggests that this will lead to (exclusively) competitive commercialization and the eventual replacement of incumbents, we consider a dynamic strategy involving product market entry before switching to a cooperative commercialization strategy. Empirical evidence from the automated speech recognition industry from 1952 to 2010 confirms our main hypothesis.</description><author>Marx, Matt; Gans, Joshua S.; Hsu, David H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Seeing Stars: Matthew Effects and Status Bias in Major League Baseball Umpiring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Jerry W.; King, Brayden G.
This paper tests the assumption that evaluators are biased to positively evaluate high-status individuals, irrespective of quality. Using unique data from Major League Baseball umpires' evaluation of pitch quality, which allow us to observe the difference in a pitch's objective quality and in its perceived quality as judged by the umpire, we show that umpires are more likely to overrecognize quality by expanding the strike zone, and less likely to underrecognize quality by missing pitches in the strike zone for high-status pitchers. Ambiguity and the pitcher's reputation as a "control pitcher" moderate the effect of status on umpire judgment. Furthermore, we show that umpire errors resulting from status bias lead to actual performance differences for the pitcher and team.</description><author>Kim, Jerry W.; King, Brayden G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Push, Pull, or Both? A Behavioral Study of How the Allocation of Inventory Risk Affects Channel Efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davis, Andrew M.; Katok, Elena; Santamaria, Natalia
In this paper we experimentally investigate how the allocation of inventory risk in a two-stage supply chain affects channel efficiency and profit distribution. We first evaluate two common wholesale price contracts that differ in which party incurs the risk associated with unsold inventory: a push contract in which the retailer incurs the risk and a pull contract in which the supplier incurs the risk. Our experimental results show that a pull contract achieves higher channel efficiency than that of a push contract, and that behavior systematically deviates from the standard theory in three ways: (1) stocking quantities are set too low, (2) wholesale prices are more favorable to the party stocking the inventory, and (3) some contracts are erroneously accepted or rejected. To account for these systematic regularities, we extend the existing theory and structurally estimate a number of behavioral models. The estimates suggest that a combination of loss aversion with errors organizes our data remarkably well. We apply our behavioral model to the advance purchase discount (APD) contract, which combines features of push and pull by allowing both parties to share the inventory risk, in a separate experiment as an out-of-sample test, and we find that it accurately predicts channel efficiency and qualitatively matches decisions. Two practical implications of our work are that (1) the push contract performs close to standard theoretical benchmarks, which implies that it is robust to behavioral biases, and (2) the APD contract weakly Pareto dominates the push contract; retailers are better off and suppliers are no worse off under the APD contract.</description><author>Davis, Andrew M.; Katok, Elena; Santamaria, Natalia</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Advertising by Manufacturers and Dealers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xu, Linli; Wilbur, Kenneth C.; Siddarth, S.; Silva-Risso, Jorge M.
The central prediction of the current paper is that manufacturer price advertising may be a less effective tool for influencing demand than retailer price advertising. We manipulate the source of a price advertisement in an experiment run on a sample of pickup truck owners. Manufacturer price advertising leads to lower indicators of potential demand than dealer price advertising, even among consumers who are experienced with the brand. An econometric analysis of pickup truck sales, price, and advertising data shows that this effect is large enough to detect in market data. Manufacturer and dealer price advertising both increase the demand intercept and the responsiveness of demand to price, but the effects of dealer price advertising are larger. Although dealer price advertising is more effective than manufacturer price advertising, manufacturer price advertising may still be useful to reduce channel conflict.</description><author>Xu, Linli; Wilbur, Kenneth C.; Siddarth, S.; Silva-Risso, Jorge M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Corporate Sustainability on Organizational Processes and Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eccles, Robert G.; Ioannou, Ioannis; Serafeim, George
We investigate the effect of corporate sustainability on organizational processes and performance. Using a matched sample of 180 U. S. companies, we find that corporations that voluntarily adopted sustainability policies by 1993-termed as high sustainability companies-exhibit by 2009 distinct organizational processes compared to a matched sample of companies that adopted almost none of these policies-termed as low sustainability companies. The boards of directors of high sustainability companies are more likely to be formally responsible for sustainability, and top executive compensation incentives are more likely to be a function of sustainability metrics. High sustainability companies are more likely to have established processes for stakeholder engagement, to be more long-term oriented, and to exhibit higher measurement and disclosure of nonfinancial information. Finally, high sustainability companies significantly outperform their counterparts over the long term, both in terms of stock market and accounting performance.</description><author>Eccles, Robert G.; Ioannou, Ioannis; Serafeim, George</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Yield Optimization of Display Advertising with Ad Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balseiro, Santiago R.; Feldman, Jon; Mirrokni, Vahab; Muthukrishnan, S.
It is clear from the growing role of ad exchanges in the real-time sale of advertising slots that Web publishers are considering a new alternative to their more traditional reservation-based ad contracts. To make this choice, the publisher must trade off, in real-time, the short-term revenue from ad exchange with the long-term benefits of delivering good spots to the reservation ads. In this paper we formalize this combined optimization problem as a multiobjective stochastic control problem and derive an efficient policy for online ad allocation in settings with general joint distribution over placement quality and exchange prices. We prove the asymptotic optimality of this policy in terms of any arbitrary trade-off between the quality of delivered reservation ads and revenue from the exchange, and we show that our policy approximates any Pareto-optimal point on the quality-versus-revenue curve. Experimental results on data derived from real publisher inventory confirm that there are significant benefits for publishers if they jointly optimize over both channels. Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2014.2017.</description><author>Balseiro, Santiago R.; Feldman, Jon; Mirrokni, Vahab; Muthukrishnan, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Structure, Product Market Dynamics, and the Boundaries of the Firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hackbarth, Dirk; Mathews, Richmond; Robinson, David
We model a new product market opportunity as an option and ask whether it is best exploited by a large incumbent firm (integration) or by a small separate firm (nonintegration). Starting from a standard framework, in which value-maximizing investment and financing decisions are jointly determined, we show that integration protects assets in place value, whereas nonintegration protects option value and maximizes financial flexibility. We show that increases in standard measures of cash flow risk predict exploitation of new opportunities by specialized firms, whereas increases in product market competition (e. g., the risk of competitive preemption) predict exploitation by incumbents. We also show that alliances organized as licensing agreements or revenue-sharing contracts sometimes better balance the sources of value and thus may dominate more traditional forms of organization. These organizational equilibria arise from the dynamic interaction of the new opportunity's option-like features with realistic competitive forces.</description><author>Hackbarth, Dirk; Mathews, Richmond; Robinson, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Distinct Effects of Information Technology and Communication Technology on Firm Organization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bloom, Nicholas; Garicano, Luis; Sadun, Raffaella; Van Reenen, John
Guided by theories of "management by exception," we study the impact of information and communication technology on worker and plant manager autonomy and span of control. The theory suggests that information technology is a decentralizing force, whereas communication technology is a centralizing force. Using a new data set of American and European manufacturing firms, we find indeed that better information technologies (enterprise resource planning (ERP) for plant managers and computer-assisted design/computer-assisted manufacturing for production workers) are associated with more autonomy and a wider span of control, whereas technologies that improve communication (like data intranets) decrease autonomy for workers and plant managers. Using instrumental variables (distance from ERP's place of origin and heterogeneous telecommunication costs arising from regulation) strengthens our results. Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2014.2013.</description><author>Bloom, Nicholas; Garicano, Luis; Sadun, Raffaella; Van Reenen, John</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Choice with Illiquid Assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Andrew; Papanikolaou, Dimitris; Westerfield, Mark M.
We present a model of optimal allocation to liquid and illiquid assets, where illiquidity risk results from the restriction that an asset cannot be traded for intervals of uncertain duration. Illiquidity risk leads to increased and state-dependent risk aversion and reduces the allocation to both liquid and illiquid risky assets. Uncertainty about the length of the illiquidity interval, as opposed to a deterministic nontrading interval, is a primary determinant of the cost of illiquidity. We allow market liquidity to vary from "normal" periods, when all assets are fully liquid, to "illiquidity crises," when some assets can only be traded infrequently. The possibility of a liquidity crisis leads to limited arbitrage in normal times. Investors are willing to forgo 2% of their wealth to hedge against illiquidity crises occurring once every 10 years.</description><author>Ang, Andrew; Papanikolaou, Dimitris; Westerfield, Mark M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conscience Accounting: Emotion Dynamics and Social Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gneezy, Uri; Imas, Alex; Madarasz, Kristof
This paper presents theory and experiments where people's prosocial attitudes fluctuate over time following the violation of an internalized norm. We report the results of two experiments in which people who first made an immoral choice were then more likely to donate to charity than those who did not. In addition, those who knew that a donation opportunity would follow the potentially immoral choice behaved more unethically than those who did not know. We interpret this increase in charitable behavior as being driven by a temporal increase in guilt induced by past immoral actions. We term such behavior conscience accounting and discuss its importance in charitable giving and in the identification of social norms in choice behavior through time inconsistency.</description><author>Gneezy, Uri; Imas, Alex; Madarasz, Kristof</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Ignorance and the Robustness of Social Preferences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grossman, Zachary
Participants in dictator games frequently avoid learning whether their choice to maximize their own earnings will help or hurt the recipient and then choose selfishly, exploiting the "moral wiggle room" provided by their ignorance. However, this is found in an environment in which the dictator must actively learn the true payoffs, so inaction means ignorance. Does this effect persist when one must actively choose either to be ignorant or to be informed or when one must actively choose to remain ignorant? In fact, whereas 45% of dictators remain ignorant when one must click to become informed, this drops to 25% when one must click in either case and to 3% when one must click to remain ignorant. Although the exploitation of moral wiggle room is not merely an artifact, it is, much like social behavior itself, subject to environmental and psychological factors that may reinforce or undermine its impact.</description><author>Grossman, Zachary</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficiency Analysis of Cournot Competition in Service Industries with Congestion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perakis, Georgia; Sun, Wei
We consider Cournot competition in the presence of congestion effects. Our model consists of several service providers with differentiated services, each competing for users who are sensitive to both price and congestion. We distinguish two types of congestion effects, depending on whether spillover costs exist, that is, where one service provider's congestion cost increases with the other providers' output level. We quantify the efficiency of an unregulated oligopoly with respect to the optimal social welfare with tight upper and lower bounds. We show that, when there is no spillover, the welfare loss in an unregulated oligopoly is limited to 25% of the social optimum, even in the presence of highly convex costs. On the other hand, when spillover cost is present, there does not exist a constant lower bound on the efficiency of an unregulated oligopoly, even with affine cost. We show that the efficiency depends on the relative magnitude between the marginal spillover cost and the marginal benefit to consumers.</description><author>Perakis, Georgia; Sun, Wei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Assortment Packing Problem: Multiperiod Assortment Planning for Short-Lived Products</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caro, Felipe; Martinez-de-Albeniz, Victor; Rusmevichientong, Paat
Motivated by retailers' frequent introduction of new items to refresh product lines and maintain their market shares, we present the assortment packing problem in which a firm must decide, in advance, the release date of each product in a given collection over a selling season. Our formulation models the trade-offs among profit margins, preference weights, and limited life cycles. A key aspect of the problem is that each product is short-lived in the sense that, once introduced, its attractiveness lasts only a few periods and vanishes over time. The objective is to determine when to introduce each product to maximize the total profit over the selling season. Even for two periods, the corresponding optimization problem is shown to be NP-complete. As a result, we study a continuous relaxation of the problem that approximates the problem well, when the number of products is large. When margins are identical and product preferences decay exponentially, its solution can be characterized: it is optimal to introduce products with slower decays earlier. The structural properties of the relaxation also help us to develop several heuristics, for which we establish performance guarantees. We test our heuristics with data on sales and release dates of women's handbags from an accessories retailer. The numerical experiments show that the heuristics perform very well and can yield significant improvements in profitability.</description><author>Caro, Felipe; Martinez-de-Albeniz, Victor; Rusmevichientong, Paat</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Relationships Matter? Evidence from Loan Officer Turnover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drexler, Alejandro; Schoar, Antoinette
We show that the cost of employee turnover in firms that rely on decentralized knowledge and personal relationships depends on the firms' planning horizons and the departing employees' incentives to transfer information. Using exogenous shocks to the relationship between borrowers and loan officers, we document that borrowers whose loan officers are on leave are less likely to receive new loans from the bank, are more likely to apply for credit from other banks, and are more likely to miss payments or go into default. These costs are smaller when turnover is expected, as in the case of maternity leave, or when loan officers have incentives to transfer information, as in the case of voluntary resignations.</description><author>Drexler, Alejandro; Schoar, Antoinette</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational Information Leakage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Indjejikian, Raffi; Lu, Hai; Yang, Liyan
Empirical evidence suggests that information leakage in capital markets is common. We present a trading model to study the incentives of an informed trader (e. g., a well-informed insider) to voluntarily leak information about an asset's value to one or more independent traders. Our model shows that, although leaking information dissipates the insider's information advantage about the asset's value, it enhances his information advantage about the asset's execution price relative to other informed traders. The profit impact of these two effects are countervailing. When there are a sufficient number of other informed traders, the profit impact from enhanced information dominates. Hence, the insider has incentives to leak some of his private information. We label this rational information leakage and discuss its implications for the regulation of insider trading.</description><author>Indjejikian, Raffi; Lu, Hai; Yang, Liyan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Parents Matter? Effects of Lender Affiliation Through the Mortgage Boom and Bust</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gartenberg, Claudine
It is widely acknowledged that the 2007 mortgage crisis was preceded by a broad deterioration in underwriting diligence. This paper shows that this deterioration varied by the industry affiliation of mortgage lenders. Loans issued by homebuilders and stand-alone lenders were significantly less likely to default than loans issued by depository banks and affiliates of major financial institutions. I argue that homebuilders and stand-alone lenders had the least financial capacity to hold mortgages, and their resulting need to sell loans quickly on the secondary market forced them to issue safer loans. Tests of other explanations, including differences in information and incentives to avoid foreclosure externalities, receive little support. This study highlights a novel means by which firm boundaries influence firm adaptation to changing market conditions by defining the boundaries of the internal capital markets and hence the relative constraints of constituent units.</description><author>Gartenberg, Claudine</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Positioning on a Multiattribute Landscape</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adner, Ron; Csaszar, Felipe A.; Zemsky, Peter B.
Competitive positioning is a central, yet understudied, topic in strategy. Understanding positioning requires understanding two distinct mappings: how underlying policies are transformed into positions, and how positions are transformed into market performance. A complete treatment of positioning requires incorporating organizational design in the presence of policy interdependence; consumer choice in the presence of trade-offs among multiple product attributes; and competitive interactions among firms. We develop a model that integrates these elements. We show that in a multiattribute setting, trade-offs have critical, nonmonotonic effects on a range of strategy questions including the relationship between positions that are operationally efficient and those that remain viable in the face of competition as well as the concentration of market share in the industry. Of particular interest are implications for firm heterogeneity. We show that increases in business policy interdependence can decrease positioning heterogeneity among firms in an industry, depending on the nature of trade-offs. We also show that the relationship between strategy heterogeneity and positioning heterogeneity is moderated by the extent of policy interdependence.</description><author>Adner, Ron; Csaszar, Felipe A.; Zemsky, Peter B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Environmental Externalities and Cost of Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chava, Sudheer
I analyze the impact of a firm's environmental profile on its cost of equity and debt capital. Using implied cost of capital derived from analysts' earnings estimates, I find that investors demand significantly higher expected returns on stocks excluded by environmental screens (such as hazardous chemical, substantial emissions, and climate change concerns) compared to firms without such environmental concerns. Lenders also charge a significantly higher interest rate on the bank loans issued to firms with these environmental concerns. I provide evidence that the environmental profile of a firm is not simply proxying for an omitted component of its default risk. Further, firms with these environmental concerns have lower institutional ownership and fewer banks participate in their loan syndicate than firms without such environmental concerns. These results suggest that exclusionary socially responsible investing and environmentally sensitive lending can have a material impact on the cost of equity and debt capital of affected firms.</description><author>Chava, Sudheer</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Do Credit Markets Tell Us About the Speed of Leverage Adjustment?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elkamhi, Redouane; Pungaliya, Raunaq S.; Vijh, Anand M.
This paper proposes a new methodology to infer investors' expectations about the speed of leverage adjustment implicit in the prices of credit instruments. On average, the credit markets imply a fairly rapid annual speed of adjustment of 26% toward a firm's predicted leverage. The speed varies considerably across partitions formed by the differential implications of the pecking order, market timing, and trade-off theories of capital structure. This finding suggests that investors' expectations are formed in accordance with all three theories. We also show that the addition of firm fixed effects in the predicted leverage model gives noisier estimates of investors' expectations of future leverage, and that a firm's initial leverage is a poor estimate of its future leverage.</description><author>Elkamhi, Redouane; Pungaliya, Raunaq S.; Vijh, Anand M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Short Selling Amplify Price Declines or Align Stocks with Their Fundamental Values?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Curtis, Asher; Fargher, Neil L.
Critics of short selling argue that short sellers amplify price declines by targeting firms with falling prices in an unwarranted manner. Contrary to this viewpoint, we find that increases in short interest for firms following a price decline are associated with measures of overpricing based on financial statement analysis. Our results extend to short-selling activity following marketwide declines. We also find evidence consistent with the profitability of short selling following price declines being driven by valuation-based positions. Overall, our findings suggest short sellers primarily undertake valuation-based strategies following price declines and have implications for regulators. Limiting short selling following price declines is likely to impede efficient price discovery.</description><author>Curtis, Asher; Fargher, Neil L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commissions and Sales Targets Under Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gallego, Guillermo; Talebian, Masoud
We consider a game between two capacity providers that compete for customers through a broker who earns commissions on sales and sells to both loyal and nonloyal customers. The providers compete by selecting commission margins and sales targets above which the margins on total sales increase. We study the contract form in equilibrium and the effect that sales targets have on the profit split between the providers and the broker. We show that in equilibrium, contracts require positive sales targets that can be best described as a mechanism for the larger provider to profit at the expense of the smaller provider. The effect of sales targets is different when commission margins are exogenous and the providers compete by setting targets. In this case, it is the low-margin provider who benefits from sales targets at the expense of the broker, who in this context resists the imposition of targets.</description><author>Gallego, Guillermo; Talebian, Masoud</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should Event Organizers Prevent Resale of Tickets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cui, Yao; Duenyas, Izak; Sahin, Oezge
We are interested in whether preventing resale of tickets benefits the capacity providers for sporting and entertainment events. Common wisdom suggests that ticket resale is harmful to event organizers' revenues, and event organizers have tried to prevent resale of tickets. For instance, Ticketmaster recently proposed paperless (nontransferrable) ticketing, which would severely limit the opportunity to resell tickets. We consider a model that allows resale from both consumers and speculators with different transaction costs for each party. Surprisingly, we find that this wisdom is incorrect when event organizers use fixed pricing policies; in fact, event organizers benefit from reductions in consumers' (and speculators') transaction costs of resale. Even when multiperiod pricing policies are used, we find that an event organizer may still benefit from ticket resale if his capacity is small. Although paperless ticketing is suggested as a way to reduce ticket resale and prevent speculators from buying tickets, our results suggest that it may reduce the capacity providers' revenues in many situations. Instead, we propose ticket options as a novel ticket pricing mechanism. We show that ticket options (where consumers would initially buy an option to buy a ticket and then exercise at a later date) naturally reduce ticket resale significantly and result in significant increases in event organizers' revenues. Furthermore, since a consumer only risks the option price (and not the whole ticket price) if she cannot attend the event, options may face less consumer resistance than paperless tickets.</description><author>Cui, Yao; Duenyas, Izak; Sahin, Oezge</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crowdsourcing New Product Ideas Under Consumer Learning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Yan; Singh, Param Vir; Srinivasan, Kannan
We propose a dynamic structural model that illuminates the economic mechanisms shaping individual behavior and outcomes on crowdsourced ideation platforms. We estimate the model using a rich data set obtained from IdeaStorm.com, a crowdsourced ideation initiative affiliated with Dell. We find that, on IdeaStorm.com, individuals tend to significantly underestimate the costs to the firm for implementing their ideas but overestimate the potential of their ideas in the initial stages of the crowdsourcing process. Therefore, the "idea market" is initially overcrowded with ideas that are less likely to be implemented. However, individuals learn about both their abilities to come up with high-potential ideas as well as the cost structure of the firm from peer voting on their ideas and the firm's response to contributed ideas. We find that individuals learn rather quickly about their abilities to come up with high-potential ideas, but the learning regarding the firm's cost structure is quite slow. Contributors of low-potential ideas eventually become inactive, whereas the high-potential idea contributors remain active. As a result, over time, the average potential of generated ideas increases while the number of ideas contributed decreases. Hence, the decrease in the number of ideas generated represents market efficiency through self-selection rather than its failure. Through counterfactuals, we show that providing more precise cost signals to individuals can accelerate the filtering process. Increasing the total number of ideas to respond to and improving the response speed will lead to more idea contributions. However, failure to distinguish between high-and low-potential ideas and between high-and low-ability idea generators leads to the overall potential of the ideas generated to drop significantly.</description><author>Huang, Yan; Singh, Param Vir; Srinivasan, Kannan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Inventory Productivity Predict Future Stock Returns? A Retailing Industry Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alan, Yasin; Gao, George P.; Gaur, Vishal
We find that inventory productivity strongly predicts future stock returns among a sample of publicly listed U. S. retailers during the period from 1985 to 2010. A zero-cost portfolio investment strategy, which consists of buying from the two highest and selling from the two lowest quintiles formed on inventory turnover, earns more than 1% average monthly abnormal return benchmarked to the Fama-French-Carhart four-factor model. Our results are robust to different measures of inventory productivity, distinct from the well-known firm characteristics known to generate abnormal returns, and not driven by a particular subsample period. A longitudinal analysis of portfolio returns over longer holding periods shows that although inventory productivity is predictive of stock returns, its information dissipates about one to two years after release.</description><author>Alan, Yasin; Gao, George P.; Gaur, Vishal</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Fresh Start Effect: Temporal Landmarks Motivate Aspirational Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dai, Hengchen; Milkman, Katherine L.; Riis, Jason
The popularity of New Year's resolutions suggests that people are more likely to tackle their goals immediately following salient temporal landmarks. If true, this little-researched phenomenon has the potential to help people overcome important willpower problems that often limit goal attainment. Across three archival field studies, we provide evidence of a "fresh start effect." We show that Google searches for the term "diet" (Study 1), gym visits (Study 2), and commitments to pursue goals (Study 3) all increase following temporal landmarks (e. g., the outset of a new week, month, year, or semester; a birthday; a holiday). We propose that these landmarks demarcate the passage of time, creating many new mental accounting periods each year, which relegate past imperfections to a previous period, induce people to take a big-picture view of their lives, and thus motivate aspirational behaviors. Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2014.1901.</description><author>Dai, Hengchen; Milkman, Katherine L.; Riis, Jason</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Consumers Strategic? Structural Estimation from the Air-Travel Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Jun; Granados, Nelson; Netessine, Serguei
Consumers often consider delaying a purchase strategically, anticipating that prices might decrease. Combining two unique data sources from the air-travel industry (posted fare data and booking data), we use a structural model to estimate the fraction of strategic consumers in the population, assuming different levels of sophistication in consumers' perception of future prices: perfect foresight and weak-and strong-form rational expectations. We find that 5.2% to 19.2% of the population is strategic across markets, measured by the first and third quartiles. Our intermarket analysis indicates that shorter trips with more attractive outside options are populated with more strategic consumers. Using a nonparametric approach, we further find that most strategic consumers arrive either at the beginning of the booking horizon or close to departure. Finally, our counterfactual analysis shows that, contrary to conventional wisdom, the presence of strategic consumers does not necessarily hurt revenues. Rather, the impact varies by market. Commitment to a nondecreasing pricing strategy is more likely to benefit business markets than leisure markets, or it could even hurt leisure markets. Intermarket analysis shows that city pairs with lower Internet penetration, higher average price, and shorter distances tend to benefit more from such commitment as well.</description><author>Li, Jun; Granados, Nelson; Netessine, Serguei</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing and Investment Efficiency, Information Quality, and Accounting Biases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nan, Lin; Wen, Xiaoyan
In this paper, we investigate the effect of accounting biases on firms' financing decisions and the role of accounting biases in endogenous information quality. We show that in industries with generally low-profit prospects, a downward-biased accounting system performs better than a neutral accounting system, and a more downward bias helps mitigate both investment and financing inefficiency; whereas for industries with generally high-profit prospects, an upward-biased accounting system is better than a neutral accounting system, and a more upward bias helps improve financing efficiency. In addition, we find that a more downward-biased accounting system motivates good firms to exert more effort to improve the information quality, which improves overall efficiency.</description><author>Nan, Lin; Wen, Xiaoyan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contracts, Biases, and Consumption of Access Services</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leider, Stephen; Sahin, Oezge
W e study theoretically and empirically the consumption of access services. We demonstrate that consumption is affected by contract structure (pay-per-use versus three-part tariffs) even if the optimal consumption plans are identical. We find that, although there is extensive individual heterogeneity, on average, consumers' choices follow a structure that is similar to a nearly optimal heuristic and correctly react to imbalances between the number of free calls and call opportunities remaining. However, consumers use the free units too quickly, leading to overconsumption and lost surplus. These errors are partially driven by mistaken beliefs about the value distribution. We also measure subjects' willingness to pay for a contract with free access units, and we find that nearly half of subjects are willing to pay at least the full per-unit price, with a substantial fraction willing to overpay. In response, the optimal firm strategy offers a three-part tariff at a very small discount, which increases revenue by 8%-14% compared to only offering a pay-per-use contract.</description><author>Leider, Stephen; Sahin, Oezge</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonlinear Kalman Filtering in Affine Term Structure Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Peter; Dorion, Christian; Jacobs, Kris; Karoui, Lotfi
The extended Kalman filter, which linearizes the relationship between security prices and state variables, is widely used in fixed-income applications. We investigate whether the unscented Kalman filter should be used to capture nonlinearities and compare the performance of the Kalman filter with that of the particle filter. We analyze the cross section of swap rates, which are mildly nonlinear in the states, and cap prices, which are highly nonlinear. When caps are used to filter the states, the unscented Kalman filter significantly outperforms its extended counterpart. The unscented Kalman filter also performs well when compared with the much more computationally intensive particle filter. These findings suggest that the unscented Kalman filter may be a good approach for a variety of problems in fixed-income pricing.</description><author>Christoffersen, Peter; Dorion, Christian; Jacobs, Kris; Karoui, Lotfi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Credit Swap Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giesecke, Kay; Kim, Baeho; Kim, Jack; Tsoukalas, Gerry
This paper formulates and solves the selection problem for a portfolio of credit swaps. The problem is cast as a goal program that entails a constrained optimization of preference-weighted moments of the portfolio value at the investment horizon. The portfolio value takes account of the exact timing of protection premium and default loss payments, as well as any mark-to-market profits and losses realized at the horizon. The constraints address collateral and solvency requirements, initial capital, position limits, and other trading constraints that credit swap investors often face in practice. The multimoment formulation accommodates the complex distribution of the portfolio value, which is a nested expectation under risk-neutral and actual probabilities. It also generates computational tractability. Numerical results illustrate the features of optimal portfolios. In particular, we find that credit swap investment constraints can have a significant impact on optimal portfolios, even for simple investment objectives. Our problem formulation and solution approach extend to corporate bond portfolios and mixed portfolios of corporate bonds and credit derivatives.</description><author>Giesecke, Kay; Kim, Baeho; Kim, Jack; Tsoukalas, Gerry</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Friendships and Search Behavior in Labor Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sterling, Adina D.
This paper examines how organizations use employee networks to contend with job seekers' search behavior. According to prior research, in markets where job seekers engage in nonsequential job search, organizations respond with tactics such as exploding offers and recruiting candidates earlier. In this paper, I posit that organizations have a social structural response. I argue that in an attempt to avoid problems related to candidates' job search, organizations are more likely to provide job offers to candidates with friends in the hiring organization than to those without friends. I test and find support for this hypothesis in a study of entry-level professionals in business and law. After a period of trial employment, candidates were more likely to receive job offers from organizations if they had a friend employed there than if they did not. The implications of this study for research on labor markets, networks, and inequality are discussed.</description><author>Sterling, Adina D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Social Proximity Enhance Business Partnerships? Theory and Evidence from Ethnicity's Role in US Venture Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hegde, Deepak; Tumlinson, Justin
W e develop a formal model to understand the selection and influence effects of social proximity (homophily) between business partners. Consistent with the model's predictions, we find that U.S. venture capitalists (VCs) are more likely to select start-ups with coethnic executives for investment, particularly when the probability of the start-up's success appears low. Ethnic proximity between VCs and the start-ups they invest in is positively related to performance, measured by the probability of the companies' successful exit through acquisitions and initial public offerings (IPOs) and net income after IPO. Two-stage regression estimates suggest that these positive performance outcomes are largely due to influence, that is, superior communication and coordination between coethnic VCs and start-up executives after the investment. To the extent that VCs expect to work better with coethnic start-ups, they invest in coethnic ventures that are of lower observable quality than noncoethnic ventures.</description><author>Hegde, Deepak; Tumlinson, Justin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Management Insights</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorman, Michael F.
nan</description><author>Gorman, Michael F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Counterfeiters: Foes or Friends? How Counterfeits Affect Sales by Product Quality Tier</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qian, Yi
A key concern about counterfeits and weak intellectual property protection is that they may hamper innovation by displacing legitimate sales. This paper combines a natural policy experiment with randomized lab experiments to estimate the heterogeneous impacts of counterfeiting on the sales and consumer purchase intent related to branded products of various quality levels. I collect new product-line-level panel data (1993-2004) on Chinese shoe companies. I identify heterogeneous effects of counterfeit entry on sales of authentic products of three quality tiers, finding that counterfeits have both advertising effects for a brand and substitution effects for authentic products, additionally the effects linger for some years. The advertising effect dominates the substitution effect for high-end authentic product sales, and the substitution effect outweighs the advertising effect for low-end product sales. The positive effect of counterfeits is most pronounced for high-fashion products (such as women's high-leg boots and dress shoes), shoes tailored to young customers, and high-end products of brands not yet well-known at the time of counterfeiter entry.</description><author>Qian, Yi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Demand Estimation Procedure for Retail Assortment Optimization with Results from Implementations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fisher, Marshall; Vaidyanathan, Ramnath
We consider the problem of choosing, from a set of N potential stock-keeping units (SKUs) in a retail category, K SKUs to be carried at each store to maximize revenue or profit. Assortments can vary by store, subject to a maximum number of different assortments. We view a SKU as a set of attribute levels and also model possible substitutions when a customer's first choice is not in the assortment. We apply maximum likelihood estimation to sales history of the SKUs currently carried by the retailer to estimate the demand for attribute levels and substitution probabilities, and from this, the demand for any potential SKU, including those not currently carried by the retailer. We specify several alternative heuristics for choosing SKUs to be carried in an assortment. We apply this approach to optimize assortments for three real examples: snack cakes, tires, and automotive appearance chemicals. A portion of our recommendations for tires and appearance chemicals were implemented and produced sales increases of 5.8% and 3.6%, respectively, which are significant improvements relative to typical retailer annual comparable store revenue increases. We also forecast sales shares of 1, 11, and 25 new SKUs for the snack cake, tire, and automotive appearance chemical applications, respectively, with mean absolute percentage errors (MAPEs) of 16.2%, 19.1%, and 28.7%, which compares favorably to the 30.7% MAPE for chain sales of two new SKUs reported by Fader and Hardie (1996).</description><author>Fisher, Marshall; Vaidyanathan, Ramnath</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trust, Trustworthiness, and Information Sharing in Supply Chains Bridging China and the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oezer, Oezalp; Zheng, Yanchong; Ren, Yufei
Whether and how trust and trustworthiness differ between a collectivist society, e. g., China, and an individualistic one, e. g., the United States, generates much ongoing scientific debate and bears significant practical values for managing cross-country transactions. We experimentally investigate how supply chain members' countries of origin-China versus the United States-affect trust, trustworthiness, and strategic information sharing behavior in a cross-country supply chain. We consider a two-tier supply chain in which the upstream supplier solicits demand forecast information from the retailer to plan production; but the retailer has an incentive to manipulate her forecast to ensure abundant supply. The levels of trust and trustworthiness in the supply chain and supplier's capability to determine the optimal production quantity affect the efficacy of forecast sharing and the resulting profits. We develop an experimental design to disentangle these three aspects and to allow for real-time interactions between geographically distant and culturally heterogeneous participants. We observe that, when there is no prospect for long-term interactions, our Chinese participants consistently exhibit lower spontaneous trust and trustworthiness than their U. S. counterparts do. We quantify the differences in trust and trustworthiness between the two countries, and the resulting impact on supply chain efficiency. We also show that Chinese individuals exhibit higher spontaneous trust toward U. S. partners than Chinese ones, primarily because they perceive that individuals from the United States are more trusting and trustworthy in general. This positive perception toward U. S. people is indeed consistent with the U. S. participants' behavior in forecast sharing. In addition, we quantify that a Chinese supply chain enjoys a larger efficiency gain from repeated interactions than a U. S. one does, as the prospect of building a long-term relationship successfully sustains trust and trustworthiness by Chinese partners. We advocate that companies can reinforce the positive perception of westerners held by the Chinese population and commit to long-term relationships to encourage trust by Chinese partners. Finally, we also observe that both populations exhibit similar pull-to-center bias when solving a decision problem under uncertainty (i.e., the newsvendor problem). Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2014.1905.</description><author>Oezer, Oezalp; Zheng, Yanchong; Ren, Yufei</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Subsidizing the Distribution Channel: Donor Funding to Improve the Availability of Malaria Drugs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, Terry A.; Xiao, Wenqiang
In countries that bear the heaviest burden of malaria, most patients seek medicine for the disease in the private sector. Because the availability and affordability of recommended malaria drugs provided by the private-sector distribution channel is poor, donors (e. g., the Global Fund) are devoting substantial resources to fund subsidies that encourage the channel to improve access to these drugs. A key question for a donor is whether it should subsidize the purchases and/or the sales of the private-sector distribution channel. We show that the donor should only subsidize purchases and should not subsidize sales. We characterize the robustness of this result to four key assumptions: the product's shelf life is long, the retailer has flexibility in setting the price, the retailer is the only level in the distribution channel, and retailers are homogeneous.</description><author>Taylor, Terry A.; Xiao, Wenqiang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Turnover: Liquidity or Uncertainty?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barinov, Alexander
I show that turnover is unrelated to several alternative measures of liquidity risk and in most cases negatively, not positively, related to liquidity. Consequently, neither liquidity nor liquidity risk explains why higher turnover predicts lower future returns. I find that the aggregate volatility risk factor explains why higher turnover predicts lower future returns. This paper shows that the negative relation between turnover and future returns is stronger for firms with option-like equity, and this regularity is also explained by the aggregate volatility risk factor.</description><author>Barinov, Alexander</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Marriage and Managers' Attitudes to Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roussanov, Nikolai; Savor, Pavel
Marital status can both reflect and affect individual preferences. We explore the impact of marriage on corporate chief executive officers (CEOs) and find that firms run by single CEOs exhibit higher stock return volatility, pursue more aggressive investment policies, and do not respond to changes in idiosyncratic risk. These effects are weaker for older CEOs. Our findings continue to hold when we use variation in divorce laws across states to instrument for CEO marital status, which supports the hypothesis that marriage itself drives choices rather than it just reflecting innate heterogeneity in preferences. We explore various potential explanations for why single CEOs may be less risk averse. Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2014.1926.</description><author>Roussanov, Nikolai; Savor, Pavel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Aggregation and Allocative Efficiency in Smooth Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iyer, Krishnamurthy; Johari, Ramesh; Moallemi, Ciamac C.
Recent years have seen extensive investigation of the information aggregation properties of markets. However, relatively little is known about conditions under which a market will aggregate the private information of rational risk-averse traders who optimize their portfolios over time; in particular, what features of a market encourage traders to ultimately reveal their private information through trades? We consider a market model involving finitely many informed risk-averse traders interacting with a market maker. Our main result identifies a basic asymptotic smoothness condition on prices in the market that ensures information is aggregated as long as portfolios converge; furthermore, under this assumption, the allocation achieved is ex post Pareto efficient. Asymptotic smoothness is fairly mild: it requires that, eventually, infinitesimal purchases or sales should see the same per-unit price. Notably, we demonstrate that, under some mild conditions, algorithmic markets based on cost functions (or, equivalently, markets based on market scoring rules) aggregate the information of traders.</description><author>Iyer, Krishnamurthy; Johari, Ramesh; Moallemi, Ciamac C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Electronic Medical Records and Physician Productivity: Evidence from Panel Data Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhargava, Hemant K.; Mishra, Abhay Nath
This paper studies the impact of an electronic medical record (EMR) system on the productivity of physicians. Physicians influence a vast majority of treatment decisions and are central to the care delivery process; thus, it is important to understand how EMRs may impact the nature of their work. Our research builds on prior literature on physician productivity, IT productivity, and task-technology fit theory. We use a unique panel data set comprising 87 physicians specializing in internal medicine, pediatrics, and family practice, located in 12 primary care clinics of an academic healthcare system in the western United States. We employ the Arellano-Bond system generalized method of moments estimation technique on our data set, which contains 3,186 physician-month productivity observations collected over 39 months. We find that productivity drops sharply immediately after technology implementation and recovers partly over the next few months. The ultimate, longer-term impact depends on physician specialty. The net impact of the EMR system is more benign on internal medicine physicians than on pediatricians and family practitioners. We postulate that the fit provided by an EMR system to the task requirements of physicians of various specialties may be key to disentangling the productivity dynamics. Our research finds that on one hand, present-day EMR systems do not produce the kind of productivity gain that could lead to substantial savings in healthcare; at the same time, EMRs do not cause a major productivity loss on a sustained basis, as many physicians fear.</description><author>Bhargava, Hemant K.; Mishra, Abhay Nath</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sequential Search and Learning from Rank Feedback: Theory and Experimental Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Palley, Asa B.; Kremer, Mirko
T his paper studies the effect of limited information in a sequential search setting where a single selection is to be made from a set of random potential options. We consider both a full-information problem, where the decision maker observes the exact value of each option as she searches, and a partial-information problem, in which the decision maker only learns the rank of the current option relative to the options that have already been observed. We develop a model that allows for a sharp contrast between search behavior in the two information settings, both theoretically and empirically. We present the results of an experiment that tests, and supports, the key prediction of our model analysis-limited information induces longer search. Our data further suggest systematic deviations from the theoretical benchmarks in both informational settings. Importantly, subjects in our partial-information conditions are prone to stop prematurely during early stages of the search process and to suboptimally continue the search during late stages. We propose a simple model that succinctly captures the interplay of two symmetric choice and judgment biases that have asymmetric (but opposing) effects on the length of search. Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2014.1902.</description><author>Palley, Asa B.; Kremer, Mirko</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Constrained Assortment Optimization for the Nested Logit Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gallego, Guillermo; Topaloglu, Huseyin
We study assortment optimization problems where customer choices are governed by the nested logit model and there are constraints on the set of products offered in each nest. Under the nested logit model, the products are organized in nests. Each product in each nest has a fixed revenue associated with it. The goal is to find a feasible set of products, i.e., a feasible assortment, to maximize the expected revenue per customer. We consider cardinality and space constraints on the offered assortment, which limit the number of products and the total space consumption of the products offered in each nest, respectively. We show that the optimal assortment under cardinality constraints can be obtained efficiently by solving a linear program. The assortment optimization problem under space constraints is NP-hard. We show how to obtain an assortment with a performance guarantee of 2 under space constraints. This assortment also provides a performance guarantee of 1/(1 - is an element of) when the space requirement of each product is at most a fraction. of the space availability in each nest. Building on our results for constrained assortment optimization, we show that we can efficiently solve joint assortment optimization and pricing problems under the nested logit model, where we choose the assortment of products to offer to customers, as well as the prices of the offered products. Data, as supplemental material, are available at http://dx.doi.org/10.1287/mnsc.2014.1931.</description><author>Gallego, Guillermo; Topaloglu, Huseyin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conflicting Social Codes and Organizations: Hygiene and Authenticity in Consumer Evaluations of Restaurants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lehman, David W.; Kovacs, Balazs; Carroll, Glenn R.
Organization theory highlights the spread of norms of rationality in contemporary life. Yet rationality does not always spread without friction; individuals often act based on other beliefs and norms. We explore this problem in the context of restaurants and diners. We argue that consumers potentially apply either of two social codes when forming value judgments about restaurants: (1) an apparently rational science-based code of hygiene involving compliance with local health regulations or (2) a context-activated code of authenticity involving conformity to cultural norms. We propose that violations of the hygiene code recede in importance when the authenticity code is activated. This claim is supported by empirical analyses of 442,086 online consumer reviews and 52,740 governmental health inspections conducted from 2004 to 2011.</description><author>Lehman, David W.; Kovacs, Balazs; Carroll, Glenn R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting Almost Second-Degree Stochastic Dominance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tzeng, Larry Y.; Huang, Rachel J.; Shih, Pai-Ta
Leshno and Levy [Leshno M, Levy H (2002) Preferred by "all" and preferred by "most" decision makers: Almost stochastic dominance. Management Sci. 48(8):1074-1085] established almost stochastic dominance to reveal preferences for most rather than all decision makers with an increasing and concave utility function. In this paper, we first provide a counterexample to the main theorem of Leshno and Levy related to almost second-degree stochastic dominance. We then redefine this dominance condition and show that the newly defined almost second-degree stochastic dominance is the necessary and sufficient condition to rank distributions for all decision makers excluding the pathological concave preferences. We further extend our results to almost higher-degree stochastic dominance.</description><author>Tzeng, Larry Y.; Huang, Rachel J.; Shih, Pai-Ta</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Newsvendor Demand Chasing Revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lau, Nelson; Bearden, J. Neil
Existing research. on newsvendor behavior asserts that individuals engage in demand chasing adjusting their order quantities towards prior demand. Several metrics have been used to identify this heuristic. By simulation, current metrics are shown to yield excessive false positives, indicating demand chasing when the true order generating process is independent of prior demand. A simple correlation measure does not suffer from this problem and is proposed here as an alternative to some of the more commonly used measures.</description><author>Lau, Nelson; Bearden, J. Neil</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamics of Contract Design with Screening</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cvitanic, Jaksa; Wan, Xuhu; Yang, Huali
We analyze a novel principal-agent problem of moral hazard and adverse selection in continuous time. The constant private shock revealed at time 0 when the agent selects the contract has a long-term impact on the optimal contract. The latter is based not only on the continuation value of the agent who truthfully reports but is also contingent upon the continuation value of the agent who misreports, called the temptation value. The good agent is retired when the temptation value of the bad agent becomes large, because then it is expensive to motivate the good agent. The bad agent is retired when the temptation value of the good agent becomes small, because then the future payment does not provide sufficient incentives. We also compare the efficiency of the shutdown contract and the screening contract and find that the screening contract can bring more profit to the principal only when the agent's reservation utility is sufficiently small.</description><author>Cvitanic, Jaksa; Wan, Xuhu; Yang, Huali</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multistage Capital Budgeting for Shared Investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, Nicole Bastian; Pfeiffer, Thomas; Schneider, Georg
This paper studies the performance of delegated decision-making schemes in a two-stage, multidivision capital budgeting problem for a shared investment with an inherent abandonment option. Applying both robust goal congruence and sequential adverse selection frameworks, we show that the optimal capital budgeting mechanism entails a capital charge rate above the firm's cost of capital in the first stage but below the cost of capital in the second stage. Further, the first-stage asset cost-sharing rule depends only on the relative divisional growth profiles, and equal cost sharing can be optimal even when the divisions receive significantly different benefits from the shared investment project. In the presence of an adverse selection problem, all agency costs are incorporated into the second-stage budgeting mechanism, leaving the first-stage capital charge rate and asset-sharing rule unaffected even though the agency problem induces capital rationing at both stages.</description><author>Johnson, Nicole Bastian; Pfeiffer, Thomas; Schneider, Georg</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Acquisition During Online Decision Making: A Model-Based Exploration Using Eye-Tracking Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shi, Savannah Wei; Wedel, Michel; Pieters, F. G. M.
We propose a model of eye-tracking data to understand information acquisition patterns on attribute-by-product matrices, which are common in online choice environments such as comparison websites. The objective is to investigate how consumers gather product and attribute information from moment to moment. We propose a hierarchical hidden Markov model that consists of three connected layers: a lower layer that describes the eye movements, a middle layer that identifies information acquisition processes, and an upper layer that captures strategy switching. The proposed model accounts for the data better than several alternative models. The results show that consumers switch frequently between acquisition strategies, and they obtain information on only two or three attributes or products in a particular acquisition strategy before switching. Horizontal and contiguous eye movements play an important role in information acquisition. Furthermore, our results shed new light on the phenomenon of gaze cascades during choice. We discuss the implications for Web design, online retailing, and new directions for research on online choice.</description><author>Shi, Savannah Wei; Wedel, Michel; Pieters, F. G. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Hospice Operations Under Medicare Reimbursement Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ata, Baris; Killaly, Bradley L.; Olsen, Tava Lennon; Parker, Rodney P.
This paper analyzes the United States Medicare hospice reimbursement policy. The existing policy consists of a daily payment for each patient under care with a global cap of revenues accrued during the Medicare year, which increases with each newly admitted patient. We investigate the hospice's expected profit and provide reasons for a spate of recent provider bankruptcies related to the reimbursement policy; recommendations to alleviate these problems are given. We also analyze a hospice's incentives for patient management, finding several unintended consequences of the Medicare reimbursement policy. Specifically, a hospice may seek short-lived patients (such as cancer patients) over patients with longer expected lengths of stay. The effort with which hospices seek out, or recruit, such patients will vary during the year. Furthermore, the effort they apply to actively discharge a patient whose condition has stabilized may also depend on the time of year. These phenomena are unintended and undesirable but are a direct consequence of the Medicare reimbursement policy. We propose an alternative reimbursement policy to ameliorate these shortcomings.</description><author>Ata, Baris; Killaly, Bradley L.; Olsen, Tava Lennon; Parker, Rodney P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Sentiment, Disagreement, and the Breadth-Return Relationship</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cen, Ling; Lu, Hai; Yang, Liyan
We study the cross-sectional breadth-return relation by assuming that investors subject to market sentiment hold a biased belief in the aggregate. With a dynamic multiasset model, we predict that the breadth-return relationship can be either positive or negative depending on the relative strength of two offsetting forces-disagreement and sentiment. We find evidence consistent with our predictions. The breadth-return relationship is positive when the sentiment effect is small. However, the relationship becomes negative when (i) the time-series variation of market-wide sentiment is high and (ii) the cross-sectional dispersion of firm-specific exposure to market-wide sentiment variation is large. Our unified framework reconciles a few seemingly inconsistent empirical studies in this literature and explains puzzling cross-sectional return patterns observed during the Internet bubble and the subprime crisis periods.</description><author>Cen, Ling; Lu, Hai; Yang, Liyan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing Licensing in a Market for Technology</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arora, Ashish; Fosfuri, Andrea; Ronde, Thomas
Technology licensing is an important means for companies to extract more value from their intellectual assets. We build a model that helps understand how licensing activity should be organized within large corporations. More specifically, we compare decentralization-where the business unit using the technology makes licensing decisions-to centralized licensing. The business unit has superior information about licensing opportunities but may not have the appropriate incentives because its rewards depend on product market performance. If licensing is decentralized, the business unit forgoes valuable licensing opportunities because the rewards for licensing are (optimally) weaker than those for product market profits. This distortion is stronger when production-based incentives, especially private benefits, of business unit managers are more powerful, making centralization more attractive. Surprisingly, we find that interdependency across business units may result in more, not less, decentralization. Furthermore, even though centralization results in less information, centralized licensing deals are larger. Our model conforms to the existing evidence that reports heterogeneity across firms in both licensing propensity and organization of licensing.</description><author>Arora, Ashish; Fosfuri, Andrea; Ronde, Thomas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Control of Dividends, Capital Subscriptions, and Physical Inventories</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Lode; Shubik, Martin; Sobel, Matthew J.
Manufacturers manage interrelated flows of material and cash. Material needs capital, and sales contribute cash. Therefore, it may be beneficial to coordinate operational and financial decisions. We study a dynamic model of coordination in an equity-financed firm in which inventory and financial decisions interact in the presence of demand uncertainty, financial constraints, and a risk of default. The criterion is to maximize the expected present value of dividends net of capital subscriptions. The optimal target inventory level and financial decision variables are nondecreasing functions of the levels of inventory and retained earnings. Some important attributes of an optimal policy remain the same regardless of whether default precipitates Chapter 7 or Chapter 11 bankruptcy. The optimal policy is myopic, and if pertinent cost functions are piecewise linear, it is characterized with simple formulas. We show that the methods of inventory theory are useful in analyzing models of operational and financial coordination.</description><author>Li, Lode; Shubik, Martin; Sobel, Matthew J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Workflow Decisions for Investigators in Systems with Interruptions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dobson, Gregory; Tezcan, Tolga; Tilson, Vera
We model a system that consists of a stream of customers processed through three steps by two resources. The first resource, an investigator, handles the first step, in which she collects information from the customer and decides what work will be done in the second step by the second resource, the back office. In the third step, the investigator returns to the customer armed with the additional information or analysis done by the back office and provides the customer with a conclusion, solution, or diagnosis. The investigator has to prioritize either seeing a new customer or completing the work with a customer already in the system. While serving one customer, the investigator may be interrupted by requests from the other customers in the system. Our main objective is to understand the impact of the investigator's choices on system throughput. In addition, we are interested in the occupancy of the system (and thus the flow time of customers). We create a stylized queueing model to examine the investigator's decisions and show that, when interruptions are not an issue, the investigator should prioritize new customers to maximize throughput, keeping the system as full as possible. If customers who have been in the system for a long time generate interruptions and thus additional work for the investigator, we show that it is asymptotically optimal for the investigator to keep the system occupancy low and prioritize discharging customers. Our conclusions are based on a model of a re-entrant queue with dedicated servers serving multiple stations, with two novel features: a buffer that is shared between stations, and jobs in the system generating additional work for the servers.</description><author>Dobson, Gregory; Tezcan, Tolga; Tilson, Vera</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Evolving Impact of Combinatorial Opportunities and Exhaustion on Innovation by Business Groups as Market Development Increases: The Case of Taiwan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mahmood, Ishtiaq; Chung, Chi-Nien; Mitchell, Will
Business groups are key sources of innovation in emerging market economies, but we understand little about why innovativeness differs across groups and over time. Variation in the density of intragroup buyer-supplier ties, which are common structural linkages among group affiliates, can help explain both cross-sectional and temporal heterogeneity of group innovativeness. We argue that greater buyer-supplier density within a group initially creates combinatorial opportunities that contribute to group innovativeness but ultimately generates combinatorial exhaustion that constrains innovation. Combinatorial exhaustion will set in at lower levels of density as the market environment becomes more developed because the opportunity costs of local search increase. The research introduces a dynamic argument to studies of business-group innovation.</description><author>Mahmood, Ishtiaq; Chung, Chi-Nien; Mitchell, Will</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer Heterogeneity, Product Quality, and Distribution Channels</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shi, Hongyan; Liu, Yunchuan; Petruzzi, Nicholas C.
This paper shows that the effect of different distribution channel structures on product quality depends on the type of consumer heterogeneity and its distribution in a market. When consumer heterogeneity is uniformly distributed either vertically on willingness to pay or horizontally on transaction costs, a manufacturer may provide the same or lower product quality in a decentralized channel than in a centralized channel. In contrast, when consumer heterogeneity follows a more general distribution on willingness to pay, under certain conditions, the manufacturer may provide higher product quality in a decentralized channel than in a centralized channel. Decentralization also may lead to a higher product quality if consumer heterogeneity is uniformly distributed both vertically and horizontally, but not if consumer heterogeneity is uniformly distributed vertically on each of two product-quality attributes. Additionally, competition at the retail level may amplify these findings.</description><author>Shi, Hongyan; Liu, Yunchuan; Petruzzi, Nicholas C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Facilitating Fit Revelation in the Competitive Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gu, Zheyin; Xie, Ying
This study examines firms' strategic decisions in the competitive market regarding whether to engage in marketing activities to assist consumers in finding the fit between their personal tastes and products' horizontal attributes. We find that competitive firms' strategies to facilitate fit revelation critically depend on the product qualities they offer. In particular, a firm offering a high-quality product is more likely to facilitate fit revelation in the competitive market than it would as a market monopolist, whereas a firm offering a low-quality product is less likely to do so. In addition, the firm offering the high-quality product implements fit-revealing activities in a greater intensity than its rival that offers the low-quality product, if the quality difference between the two products is small and both products' qualities are sufficiently high.</description><author>Gu, Zheyin; Xie, Ying</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effects of Piracy on Quality of Information Goods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lahiri, Atanu; Dey, Debabrata
It is commonly believed that piracy of information goods leads to lower profits, which translate to lower incentives to invest in innovation and eventually to lower-quality products. Manufacturers, policy makers, and researchers all claim that inadequate piracy enforcement efforts translate to lower investments in product development. However, we find many practical examples that contradict this claim. Therefore, to examine this claim more carefully, we develop a rigorous economic model of the manufacturer's quality decision problem in the presence of piracy. We consider a monopolist who does not have any marginal costs but has a product development cost quadratic in the quality level produced. The monopolist faces a consumer market heterogeneous in its preference for quality and offers a quality level that maximizes its profit. We also allow for the possibility that the manufacturer may use versioning to counter piracy. We unexpectedly find that in certain situations, lower piracy enforcement increases the monopolist's incentive to invest in quality. We explain the reasons and welfare implications of our findings.</description><author>Lahiri, Atanu; Dey, Debabrata</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Information Technology-Enabled Flexibility on Formation and Market Value of Alliances</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tafti, Ali; Mithas, Sunil; Krishnan, M. S.
This study investigates the effect of information technology (IT) architecture flexibility on strategic alliance formation and firm value. We first examine the effect of three dimensions of IT architecture flexibility (open communication standards, cross-functional transparency, and modularity) on formation of three types of alliances (arm's-length, collaborative, and joint-venture alliances, respectively). Then, we examine how capabilities in IT flexibility can enhance the value derived from alliances. Our sample includes data from 169 firms that are publicly listed in the United States and that span multiple industries. We find that adoption of open communication standards is associated with the formation of arm's-length alliances, and modularity of IT architecture is associated with the formation of joint ventures. We also find that IT architecture flexibility enhances the value of arm's-length, collaborative, and joint-venture alliances. The contribution of IT flexibility to value is greater in the case of collaborative alliances than in arm's-length alliances. Taken together, these findings suggest that appropriate investments in IT can help to facilitate reconfiguration of resources and modification of processes in collaboration-intensive alliances.</description><author>Tafti, Ali; Mithas, Sunil; Krishnan, M. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collaborative Cost Reduction and Component Procurement Under Information Asymmetry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Sang-Hyun; Netessine, Serguei
During development of an innovative product there is often considerable uncertainty about component production cost, and it is of interest for both the manufacturer and the supplier to engage in a collaborative effort to reduce this uncertainty and lower the expected cost. Despite the obvious benefits this brings, the supplier may be reluctant to collaborate as he fears revealing his proprietary cost information. We investigate how information asymmetry and procurement contracting strategies interact to influence the supply chain parties' incentives to collaborate. We consider a number of procurement contracting strategies, and identify a simple strategy, expected margin commitment (EMC), that effectively promotes collaboration. The manufacturer prefers EMC if collaboration leads to a large reduction in unit cost and/or demand variability is low. Otherwise, a screening contract based on price and quantity is preferred. We also find that, paradoxically, ex post efforts to enhance supply chain efficiency may hinder ex ante collaboration that precedes production.</description><author>Kim, Sang-Hyun; Netessine, Serguei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Worst-Case Value at Risk of Nonlinear Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zymler, Steve; Kuhn, Daniel; Rustem, Berc
Portfolio optimization problems involving value at risk (VaR) are often computationally intractable and require complete information about the return distribution of the portfolio constituents, which is rarely available in practice. These difficulties are compounded when the portfolio contains derivatives. We develop two tractable conservative approximations for the VaR of a derivative portfolio by evaluating the worst-case VaR over all return distributions of the derivative underliers with given first-and second-order moments. The derivative returns are modelled as convex piecewise linear or-by using a delta-gamma approximation-as (possibly nonconvex) quadratic functions of the returns of the derivative underliers. These models lead to new worst-case polyhedral VaR (WPVaR) and worst-case quadratic VaR (WQVaR) approximations, respectively. WPVaR serves as a VaR approximation for portfolios containing long positions in European options expiring at the end of the investment horizon, whereas WQVaR is suitable for portfolios containing long and/or short positions in European and/or exotic options expiring beyond the investment horizon. We prove that-unlike VaR that may discourage diversification-WPVaR and WQVaR are in fact coherent risk measures. We also reveal connections to robust portfolio optimization.</description><author>Zymler, Steve; Kuhn, Daniel; Rustem, Berc</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diagnostic Accuracy Under Congestion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alizamir, Saed; de Vericourt, Francis; Sun, Peng
In diagnostic services, agents typically need to weigh the benefit of running an additional test and improving the accuracy of diagnosis against the cost of delaying the provision of services to others. Our paper analyzes how to dynamically manage this accuracy/congestion trade-off. To that end, we study an elementary congested system facing an arriving stream of customers. The diagnostic process consists of a search problem in which the service provider conducts a sequence of imperfect tests to determine the customer's type. We find that the agent should continue to perform the diagnosis as long as her current belief that the customer is of a given type falls into an interval that depends on the congestion level as well as the number of performed tests thus far. This search interval should shrink as congestion intensifies and as the number of performed tests increases if additional conditions hold. Our study reveals that, contrary to diagnostic services without congestion, the base rate (i.e., the prior probability of the customer type) has an effect on the agent's search strategy. In particular, the optimal search interval shrinks when customer types are more ambiguous a priori, i.e., as the base rate approaches the value at which the agent is indifferent between types. Finally, because of congestion effects, the agent should sometimes diagnose the customer as being of a given type, even if test results indicate otherwise. All these insights disappear in the absence of congestion.</description><author>Alizamir, Saed; de Vericourt, Francis; Sun, Peng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>GUB Covers and Power-Indexed Formulations for Wireless Network Design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>D'Andreagiovanni, Fabio; Mannino, Carlo; Sassano, Antonio
W e propose a pure 0-1 formulation for the wireless network design problem, i.e., the problem of configuring a set of transmitters to provide service coverage to a set of receivers. In contrast with classical mixed-integer formulations, where power emissions are represented by continuous variables, we consider only a finite set of power values. This has two major advantages: it better fits the usual practice and eliminates the sources of numerical problems that heavily affect continuous models. A crucial ingredient of our approach is an effective basic formulation for the single knapsack problem representing the coverage condition of a receiver. This formulation is based on the generalized upper bound (GUB) cover inequalities introduced by Wolsey [Wolsey L (1990) Valid inequalities for 0-1 knapsacks and mips with generalised upper bound constraints. Discrete Appl. Math. 29(2-3):251-261]; and its core is an extension of the exact formulation of the GUB knapsack polytope with two GUB constraints. This special case corresponds to the very common practical situation where only one major interferer is present. We assess the effectiveness of our formulation by comprehensive computational results over realistic instances of two typical technologies, namely, WiMAX and DVB-T.</description><author>D'Andreagiovanni, Fabio; Mannino, Carlo; Sassano, Antonio</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intertemporal CAPM with Conditioning Variables</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maio, Paulo
This paper derives and tests an intertemporal capital asset pricing model (ICAPM) based on a conditional version of the Campbell-Vuolteenaho two-beta ICAPM (bad beta, good beta (BBGB)). The novel factor is a scaled cash-flow factor that results from the interaction between cash-flow news and a lagged state variable (market dividend yield or consumer price index inflation). The cross-sectional tests over 10 portfolios sorted on size, 10 portfolios sorted on book-to-market, and 10 portfolios sorted on momentum show that the scaled ICAPM explains relatively well the dispersion in excess returns on the 30 portfolios. The results for an alternative set of equity portfolios (25 portfolios sorted on size and momentum) show that the scaled ICAPM prices particularly well the momentum portfolios. Moreover, the scaled ICAPM compares favorably with alternative asset pricing models in pricing both sets of equity portfolios. The scaled factor is decisive to account for the dispersion in average excess returns between past winner and past loser stocks. More specifically, past winners are riskier than past losers in times of high price of risk. Therefore, a time-varying cash-flow beta/price of risk provides a rational explanation for momentum.</description><author>Maio, Paulo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Advertising Mix for a Search Good</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Simon P.; Renault, Regis
We extend the persuasion game to bring it squarely into the economics of advertising. We model advertising as exciting consumer interest into learning more about the product, and determine a firm's equilibrium choice of advertising content over quality information, price information, and horizontal match information. Equilibrium is unique whenever advertising is necessary. The outcome is a separating equilibrium with quality unravelling. Lower-quality firms need to provide more information. For a given quality level, as a function of consumer visit costs, first quality information is disclosed, then price information and then horizontal product information are added to the advertising mix. Some suggestive evidence is provided from airline ads in newspapers.</description><author>Anderson, Simon P.; Renault, Regis</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crowdsourcing New Product Ideas over Time: An Analysis of the Dell IdeaStorm Community</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bayus, Barry L.
Several organizations have developed ongoing crowdsourcing communities that repeatedly collect ideas for new products and services from a large, dispersed "crowd" of nonexperts (consumers) over time. Despite its promises, little is known about the nature of an individual's ideation efforts in such an online community. Studying Dell's IdeaStorm community, serial ideators are found to be more likely than consumers with only one idea to generate an idea the organization finds valuable enough to implement, but they are unlikely to repeat their early success once their ideas are implemented. As ideators with past success attempt to again come up with ideas that will excite the organization, they instead end up proposing ideas similar to their ideas that were already implemented (i.e., they generate less diverse ideas). The negative effects of past success are somewhat mitigated for ideators with diverse commenting activity on others' ideas. These findings highlight some of the challenges in maintaining an ongoing supply of quality ideas from the crowd over time.</description><author>Bayus, Barry L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Appropriability Mechanisms and the Platform Partnership Decision: Evidence from Enterprise Software</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Peng; Ceccagnoli, Marco; Forman, Chris; Wu, D. J.
We examine whether ownership of intellectual property rights (IPR) or downstream capabilities is effective in encouraging entry into markets complementary to a proprietary platform by preventing the platform owner from expropriating rents from start-ups. We study this question in the context of the software industry, an environment where evidence of the efficacy of IPR as a mechanism to appropriate the returns from innovation has been mixed. Entry, in our context, is measured by an independent software vendor's (ISV's) decision to become certified by a platform owner and produce applications compatible with the platform. We find that ISVs with a greater stock of formal IPR (such as patents and copyrights), and those with stronger downstream capabilities (as measured by trademarks and consulting services) are more likely to join the platform, suggesting that these mechanisms are effective in protecting ISVs from the threat of expropriation. We also find that the effects of IPR on the likelihood of partnership are greater when an ISV has weak downstream capabilities or when the threat of imitation is greater, such as when the markets served by the ISV are growing quickly.</description><author>Huang, Peng; Ceccagnoli, Marco; Forman, Chris; Wu, D. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Pricing Competition with Strategic Customers Under Vertical Product Differentiation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Qian; Zhang, Dan
We consider dynamic pricing competition between two firms offering vertically differentiated products to strategic customers who are intertemporal utility maximizers. We show that price skimming arises as the unique pure-strategy Markov perfect equilibrium in the game under a simple condition. Our results highlight the asymmetric effect of strategic customer behavior on quality-differentiated firms. Even though the profit of either firm decreases as customers become more strategic, the low-quality firm suffers substantially more than the high-quality firm. Furthermore, we show that unilateral commitment to static pricing by either firm generally improves profits of both firms. Interestingly, both firms enjoy higher profit lifts when the high-quality firm commits rather than when the low-quality firm commits.</description><author>Liu, Qian; Zhang, Dan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Judging Borrowers by the Company They Keep: Friendship Networks and Information Asymmetry in Online Peer-to-Peer Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Mingfeng; Prabhala, Nagpurnanand R.; Viswanathan, Siva
We study the online market for peer-to-peer (P2P) lending, in which individuals bid on unsecured microloans sought by other individual borrowers. Using a large sample of consummated and failed listings from the largest online P2P lending marketplace, Prosper.com, we find that the online friendships of borrowers act as signals of credit quality. Friendships increase the probability of successful funding, lower interest rates on funded loans, and are associated with lower ex post default rates. The economic effects of friendships show a striking gradation based on the roles and identities of the friends. We discuss the implications of our findings for the disintermediation of financial markets and the design of decentralized electronic markets.</description><author>Lin, Mingfeng; Prabhala, Nagpurnanand R.; Viswanathan, Siva</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Costly Is Diversity? Affirmative Action in Light of Gender Differences in Competitiveness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Niederle, Muriel; Segal, Carmit; Vesterlund, Lise
Affirmative action is often criticized for causing reverse discrimination and lowering the qualifications of those hired under the policy. However, the magnitude of such adverse effects depends on whether the best suited candidate is hired absent the policy. Indeed affirmative action may compensate for the distortion discrimination imposes on the selection of candidates. This paper asks whether affirmative action can have a similar corrective impact when qualified individuals fail to apply for a job. We evaluate the effect of introducing a gender quota in an environment where high-performing women fail to enter competitions they can win. We show that guaranteeing women equal representation among winners increases their entry. The response exceeds that predicted by the change in probability of winning and is in part driven by women being more willing to compete against other women. The consequences are substantial as the boost in supply essentially eliminates the anticipated costs of the policy.</description><author>Niederle, Muriel; Segal, Carmit; Vesterlund, Lise</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Pay for Performance Detrimental to Innovation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ederer, Florian; Manso, Gustavo
Previous research in economics shows that compensation based on the pay-for-performance principle is effective in inducing higher levels of effort and productivity. On the other hand, research in psychology argues that performance-based financial incentives inhibit creativity and innovation. How should managerial compensation be structured if the goal is to induce managers to pursue more innovative business strategies? In a controlled laboratory setting, we provide evidence that the combination of tolerance for early failure and reward for long-term success is effective in motivating innovation. Subjects under such an incentive scheme explore more and are more likely to discover a novel business strategy than subjects under fixed-wage and standard pay-for-performance incentive schemes. We also find evidence that the threat of termination can undermine incentives for innovation, whereas golden parachutes can alleviate these innovation-reducing effects.</description><author>Ederer, Florian; Manso, Gustavo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Gender Diversity on the Performance of Business Teams: Evidence from a Field Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoogendoorn, Sander; Oosterbeek, Hessel; van Praag, Mirjam
This paper reports on a field experiment conducted to estimate the impact of the share of women in business teams on their performance. Teams consisting of undergraduate students in business studies start up a venture as part of their curriculum. We manipulated the gender composition of teams and assigned students randomly to teams, conditional on their gender. We find that teams with an equal gender mix perform better than male-dominated teams in terms of sales and profits. We explore various mechanisms suggested in the literature to explain this positive effect of gender diversity on performance (including complementarities, learning, monitoring, and conflicts) but find no support for them.</description><author>Hoogendoorn, Sander; Oosterbeek, Hessel; van Praag, Mirjam</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Infrastructure Planning for Electric Vehicles with Battery Swapping</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mak, Ho-Yin; Rong, Ying; Shen, Zuo-Jun Max
Electric vehicles (EVs) have been proposed as a key technology to help cut down the massive greenhouse gas emissions from the transportation sector. Unfortunately, because of the limited capacity of batteries, typical EVs can only travel for about 100 miles on a single charge and require hours to be recharged. The industry has proposed a novel solution centered around the use of "swapping stations," at which depleted batteries can be exchanged for recharged ones in the middle of long trips. The possible success of this solution hinges on the ability of the charging service provider to deploy a cost-effective infrastructure network, given only limited information regarding adoption rates. We develop robust optimization models that aid the planning process for deploying battery-swapping infrastructure. Using these models, we study the potential impacts of battery standardization and technology advancements on the optimal infrastructure deployment strategy.</description><author>Mak, Ho-Yin; Rong, Ying; Shen, Zuo-Jun Max</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Analysts Sacrifice Forecast Accuracy for Informativeness?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Louis, Henock; Sun, Amy X.; Urcan, Oktay
Analysts deviate from management guidance to correct for perceived earnings management. Although the deviations reduce forecast accuracy, they improve forecast informativeness, bringing the forecasts closer to the unmanaged earnings and reducing accruals mispricing. An implicit assumption in the literature is that more accurate analyst forecasts (i.e., estimates that are closer to the reported earnings) are better for investors, and that analysts' objective is to forecast the reported (managed) earnings accurately. Our analysis suggests that this is not necessarily the case and that an inaccurate forecast can actually be more informative than an accurate one. Prior studies on analysts' deviations from management guidance focus on analysts' incentives to issue estimates that managers can beat. These studies implicitly assume that analysts side with, management against the interests of their clients. Our analysis indicates that analysts could also deviate from management guidance to provide useful valuation information to their clients.</description><author>Louis, Henock; Sun, Amy X.; Urcan, Oktay</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Teams Make You Smarter: How Exposure to Teams Improves Individual Decisions in Probability and Reasoning Tasks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maciejovsky, Boris; Sutter, Matthias; Budescu, David V.; Bernau, Patrick
Many important decisions are routinely made by transient and temporary teams, which perform their duty and disperse. Team members often continue making similar decisions as individuals. We study how the experience of team decision making affects subsequent individual decisions in two seminal probability and reasoning tasks, the Monty Hall problem and the Wason selection task. Both tasks are hard and involve a general rule, thus allowing for knowledge transfers, and can be embedded in the context of markets that offer identical incentives to teams and individuals. Our results show that teams, trade closer to the rational level, learn the solution faster, and achieve this with weaker, less specific performance feedback than individuals. Most importantly, we observe significant knowledge transfers from team, decision making to subsequent individual performances that take place up to five weeks later, indicating that exposure to team decision making has strong positive spillovers on the quality of individual decisions.</description><author>Maciejovsky, Boris; Sutter, Matthias; Budescu, David V.; Bernau, Patrick</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inferring Reporting-Related Biases in Hedge Fund Databases from Hedge Fund Equity Holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Vikas; Fos, Vyacheslav; Jiang, Wei
This paper formally analyzes the biases related to self-reporting in hedge fund databases by matching the quarterly equity holdings of a complete list of 13F-filing hedge fund companies to the union of five major commercial databases of self-reporting hedge funds between 1980 and 2008. We find that funds initiate self-reporting after positive abnormal returns that do not persist into the reporting period. Termination of self-reporting, is followed by both return deterioration and outflows from the funds. The propensity to self-report is consistent with the trade-offs between the benefits (e.g., access to prospective investois) and costs (e.g., partial loss of trading secrecy and flexibility in selective marketing). Finally, returns of self-reporting funds are higher than that of nonreporting funds using characteristic-based benchmarks. However, the difference is not significant using alternative choices of performance measures.</description><author>Agarwal, Vikas; Fos, Vyacheslav; Jiang, Wei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Dispersion and Loss-Leader Pricing: Evidence from the Online Book Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Xinxin; Gu, Bin; Liu, Hongju
In this paper, we develop a theoretical model to analyze the pricing strategies of competing retailers with asymmetric cross-selling capabilities when product demand changes. Our results suggest that retailers with better opportunities for cross-selling have higher incentives to adopt loss-leader pricing on high-demand products than retailers with low cross-selling capabilities. As a result, price dispersion of a product across retailers rises when its demand increases. The predictions of our model are consistent with the empirical evidence from the online book retailing industry. Using product breadth as a proxy for cross-selling capability, we find that retailers with high cross-selling capabilities reduce prices on best sellers more aggressively than retailers with low cross-selling capabilities. As a result, price dispersion increases when a book makes it to the best-seller list, and the increase is mainly driven by the difference in pricing behavior between retailers with different cross-selling capabilities. Our empirical results are robust against a number of alternative explanations.</description><author>Li, Xinxin; Gu, Bin; Liu, Hongju</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Treatment Effectiveness and Side Effects: A Model of Physician Learning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Tat; Narasimhan, Chakravarthi; Xie, Ying
In this paper we study how treatment effectiveness and side effects impact the prescription decision of a risk-averse physician, and how detailing and patient feedback help reduce the physician's uncertainty in these two attributes in the erectile dysfunction category. To separately identify the impacts of effectiveness and side effects, we augment the observed prescription choices with unique data on self-reported reasons for switching in our estimation. Results show that the two new drugs Levitra and Cialis have higher mean effectiveness than the existing drug Viagra, but physicians have large uncertainty regarding the effectiveness for Levitra and side effects for Cialis: Detailing is effective in reducing the uncertainty for effectiveness but much less so for side effects. Based on the results, we investigate the roles of effectiveness and side effects in physicians' prescription choices, and the importance of detailing for new entrants in competing with incumbent drugs.</description><author>Chan, Tat; Narasimhan, Chakravarthi; Xie, Ying</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Markets and Firm Organization: How Financial Development Shapes European Corporate Groups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Belenzon, Sharon; Berkovitz, Tomer; Rios, Luis A.
We investigate the effect of financial development on the formation of European corporate groups. Because cross-country regressions are hard to interpret in a causal sense, we exploit exogenous industry measures to investigate a specific channel through which financial development may affect group affiliation: internal capital markets. Using a comprehensive firm-level data set on European corporate groups in 15 countries, we find that countries with less developed financial markets have a higher percentage of group affiliates in more capital-intensive industries. This relationship is more pronounced for young and small firms and for affiliates Of large and diversified groups. Our findings are consistent with the view that internal capital markets may, under some conditions, be more efficient than prevailing external markets, and that this may drive group affiliation even in developed economies.</description><author>Belenzon, Sharon; Berkovitz, Tomer; Rios, Luis A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Fragility of Commitment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morgan, John; Vardy, Felix
We show that the value of commitment is fragile in many standard games. When the follower faces a small cost to observe the leader's action, equilibrium payoffs are identical to the case where the leader's actions are unobservable. Applications of our result include standard Stackelberg-Cournot and differentiated product Bertrand games, as well as forms of indirect commitment, highlighted in Bulow et al. [Bulow J, Geanakoplos J, Klemperer P (1985) Multimarket oligopoly: Strategic substitutes and strategic complements. J. Political Econom. 93:488-511]. Weakening full rationality in favor of boundedly rational solution concepts such as quantal-response equilibrium restores the value of commitment.</description><author>Morgan, John; Vardy, Felix</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Total Cost Control in Project Management via Satisficing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goh, Joel; Hall, Nicholas G.
We consider projects with uncertain activity times and the possibility of expediting, or crashing, them. Activity times come from a partially specified distribution within a family of distributions. This family is described by one or more of the following details about the uncertainties: support, mean, and covariance. We allow correlation between past and future activity time performance across activities. Our objective considers total completion time penalty plus crashing and overhead costs. We develop a robust optimization model that uses a conditional value-at-risk satisficing measure. We develop linear and piecewise-linear decision rules for activity start time and crashing decisions. These rules are designed to perform robustly against all possible scenarios of activity time uncertainty, when implemented in either static or rolling horizon mode. We compare our procedures against the previously available Program Evaluation and Review Technique and Monte Carlo simulation procedures. Our computational studies show that, relative to previous approaches, our crashing policies provide both a higher level of performance, i.e., higher success rates and lower budget overruns, and substantial robustness to activity time distributions. The relative advantages and information requirements of the static and rolling horizon implementations are discussed.</description><author>Goh, Joel; Hall, Nicholas G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Axiomatic Approach to Systemic Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Chen; Iyengar, Garud; Moallemi, Ciamac C.
Systemic risk refers to the risk of collapse of an entire complex system as a result of the actions taken by the individual component entities or agents that comprise the system. Systemic risk is an issue of great concern in modern financial markets as well as, more broadly, in the management of complex business and engineering systems. We propose an axiomatic framework for the measurement and management of systemic risk based on the simultaneous analysis of outcomes across agents in the system and over scenarios of nature. Our framework defines a broad class of systemic risk measures that accomodate a rich set of regulatory preferences. This general class of systemic risk measures captures many specific measures of systemic risk that have recently been proposed as special cases and highlights their implicit assumptions. Moreover, the systemic risk measures that satisfy our conditions yield decentralized decompositions; i.e., the systemic risk can be decomposed into risk due to individual agents. Furthermore, one can associate a shadow price for systemic risk to each agent that correctly accounts for the externalities of the agent's individual decision making on the entire system.</description><author>Chen, Chen; Iyengar, Garud; Moallemi, Ciamac C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sourcing for Supplier Effort and Competition: Design of the Supply Base and Pricing Mechanism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Cuihong
We study a buyer's sourcing strategy along two dimensions: the supply base design and the pricing mechanism, considering supplier competition and cost-reduction effort. The supply base design concerns the number of suppliers (one or two) included in the supply base and the capacity to be invested in each supplier. The pricing mechanism determines the timing of the price decisions, with the buyer making price commitments before suppliers exert cost-reduction efforts that may be renegotiated afterward. We find that symmetric capacity investment in suppliers and low price commitments (more likely to be renegotiated) are effective at fostering supplier competition, whereas asymmetric investment and high price commitments (less likely to be renegotiated) are better at motivating supplier effort. A complementary relationship exists between the supply base design and pricing mechanism: A more symmetric supply base should be combined with lower price commitments, leading to more renegotiation opportunities. This results in three possible sourcing structures: sole sourcing (investing capacity in a single supplier and forming price with ex ante commitments), symmetric dual sourcing (investing equal capacity in both suppliers and forming price with ex post negotiations), and asymmetric dual sourcing (investing positive but unequal capacities in two (ex ante identical) suppliers and forming price using both ex ante commitments and ex post (re)negotiations). We characterize the conditions for each structure and identify a strategic role of capacity investment..</description><author>Li, Cuihong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Implications of Demand Censoring in the Newsvendor Problem</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Besbes, Omar; Muharremoglu, Alp
We consider a repeated newsvendor problem in which the decision maker (DM) does not have access to the underlying demand distribution. The goal of this paper is to characterize the implications of demand censoring on performance. To that end, we compare the benchmark setting in which the DM has access to demand observations to a setting in which the DM may only rely on sales data. We measure performance in terms of regret: the difference between the cumulative costs of a policy and the optimal cumulative costs with knowledge of the demand distribution. Through upper and lower bounds, we characterize the optimal magnitude of the worst-case regret for the two settings, enabling one to isolate the implications of demand censoring. In particular, the results imply that the exploration-exploitation trade-off introduced by demand censoring is fundamentally different in the continuous and discrete demand cases, and that active exploration plays a much stronger role in the latter case. We further establish that in the discrete demand case, the need for active exploration almost disappears as soon as a lost sales indicator (that records whether demand was censored or not) becomes available, in addition to the censored demand samples.</description><author>Besbes, Omar; Muharremoglu, Alp</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Ties and User-Generated Content: Evidence from an Online Social Network</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shriver, Scott K.; Nair, Harikesh S.; Hofstetter, Reto
We exploit changes in wind speeds at surfing locations in Switzerland as a source of variation in users' propensity to post content about their surfing activity on an online social network. We exploit this variation to test whether users' online content-generation activity is codetermined with their social ties. Economically significant effects of this type can produce positive feedback that generates local network effects in content generation. When quantitatively significant, the increased content and tie density arising from the network effect induces more visitation and browsing on the site, which fuels growth by generating advertising revenue. We find evidence consistent with such network effects.</description><author>Shriver, Scott K.; Nair, Harikesh S.; Hofstetter, Reto</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Networks, Information Acquisition, and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Bing; Yang, Liyan
We analyze a rational expectations equilibrium model to explore the implications of information networks for the financial market. When information is exogenous, social communication improves market efficiency. However, social communication crowds out information production due to traders' incentives to "free ride" on informed friends and on a more informative price system. Overall, social communication hurts market efficiency when information is endogenous. The network effects on the cost of capital, liquidity, trading volume, and welfare are also sensitive to whether information is endogenous. Our analysis highlights the importance of information acquisition in examining the implications of information networks for financial markets.</description><author>Han, Bing; Yang, Liyan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tiers in One-Sided Matching Markets: Theory and Experimental Investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Yu; Haruvy, Ernan
The design of a matching market may affect behavior in prematch stages. In some settings, forward-looking agents might purchase low-priced properties with the intention of trading up. From a design standpoint, such behavior is undesirable. We investigate a tiered structure as a potential solution. Using a model that endogenizes prematch acquisition decisions, we show that tiers promote exchange while protecting the primary market. In the laboratory, we find that both firm revenue and total social surplus are improved by tiered matching, and the amount of improvement depends on the exchange mechanism the firm uses. We focus on two popular mechanisms deposit first and request first. We find that subjects are less likely to take advantage of the match under tier-free deposit first mechanism, possibly because of risk aversion. Thus, a tiered approach is more critical under the request first mechanism. We confirm that risk aversion partly explains deviations from theory.</description><author>Wang, Yu; Haruvy, Ernan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance Appraisals and the Impact of Forced Distribution-An Experimental Investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Johannes; Harbring, Christine; Sliwka, Dirk
A real-effort experiment is investigated in which supervisors have to rate the performance of individual workers who in turn receive a bonus payment based on these ratings. We compare a baseline treatment in which supervisors are not restricted in their rating behavior to a forced distribution system in which they have to assign differentiated grades. We find that productivity is significantly higher under a forced distribution by about 6% to 12%. However, the productivity effects are less clear cut when participants have prior experience with the baseline condition. Moreover, a forced distribution becomes detrimental when workers have access to a simple option to sabotage each other.</description><author>Berger, Johannes; Harbring, Christine; Sliwka, Dirk</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>