<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>MS7</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Buying Beauty: On Prices and Returns in the Art Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Renneboog, Luc; Spaenjers, Christophe
This paper investigates the price determinants and investment performance of art. We apply a hedonic regression analysis to a new data set of more than one million auction transactions of paintings and works on paper. Based on the resulting price index, we conclude that art has appreciated in value by a moderate 3.97% per year, in real U. S. dollar terms, between 1957 and 2007. This is a performance similar to that of corporate bonds-at much higher risk. A repeat-sales regression on a subset of the data demonstrates the robustness of our index. Next, quantile regressions document larger average price appreciations (and higher volatilities) in more expensive price brackets. We also find variation in historical returns across mediums and movements. Finally, we show that measures of high-income consumer confidence and art market sentiment predict art price trends.</description><author>Renneboog, Luc; Spaenjers, Christophe</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Payment Schemes on Inventory Decisions: The Role of Mental Accounting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Li; Koek, A. Guerhan; Tong, Jordan D.
Does the payment scheme have an effect on inventory decisions in the newsvendor problem? Keeping the net profit structure constant, we examine three payment schemes that can be interpreted as the newsvendor's order being financed by the newsvendor herself (scheme 0), by the supplier through delayed order payment (scheme S), and by the customer through advanced revenue (scheme C). In a laboratory study, we find that inventory quantities exhibit a consistent decreasing pattern in the order of schemes 0, S. and C, with the order quantities of scheme S being close to the expected-profit-maximizing solution. These observations are inconsistent with the expected-profit-maximizing model, contradict what a regular or hyperbolic time-discounting model would predict, and cannot be explained by the loss aversion model. Instead, they are consistent with a model that underweights the order-time payments, which can be explained by the "prospective accounting" theory in the mental accounting literature. A second study shows that the results hold even. if all physical payments are conducted at the same time, suggesting that the framing of the payment scheme is sufficient to induce the prospective accounting behavior. We further validate the robustness of our model under different profit conditions. Our findings contribute to the understanding of the psychological processes involved in newsvendor decisions and have implications for supply chain financing and contract design.</description><author>Chen, Li; Koek, A. Guerhan; Tong, Jordan D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>First-Party Content and Coordination in Two-Sided Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hagiu, Andrei; Spulber, Daniel
The strategic use of first-party content by two-sided platforms is driven by two key factors: the nature of buyer and seller expectations (favorable versus unfavorable) and the nature of the relationship between first-party content and third-party content (complements or substitutes). Platforms facing unfavorable expectations face an additional constraint: their prices and first-party content investment need to be such that low (zero) participation equilibria are eliminated. This additional constraint typically leads them to invest more (less) in first-party content relative to platforms facing favorable expectations when first-and third-party content are substitutes (complements). These results hold with both simultaneous and sequential entry of the two sides. With two competing platforms-incumbent facing favorable expectations and entrant facing unfavorable expectations-and multi-homing on one side of the market, the incumbent always invests (weakly) more in first-party content relative to the case in which it is a monopolist.</description><author>Hagiu, Andrei; Spulber, Daniel</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Knowledge Recombination Across Technological Boundaries: Scientists vs. Engineers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gruber, Marc; Harhoff, Dietmar; Hoisl, Karin
Building on the seminal work of Thomas J. Allen, we contribute to the emerging microlevel theory of knowledge recombination by examining how individual-level characteristics of inventors affect the breadth of their technological recombinations. Our data set combines information from 30,550 European patents with matched survey data obtained from 1,880 inventors. The analysis supports the view that inventors with a scientific education are more likely to generate patents that span technological boundaries (in our case, 30 broad, top-level technological domains) than inventors with an engineering degree. A doctoral degree is associated with increased recombination breadth for all groups of inventors. The breadth of an inventor's technological recombinations diminishes with increasing temporal distance to his education, but the differences between scientists and engineers persist over time. Our findings provide several new insights for research on inventors, the literature on organizational learning and innovation, and strategy research.</description><author>Gruber, Marc; Harhoff, Dietmar; Hoisl, Karin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing Strategic Inventories via Manufacturer-to-Consumer Rebates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arya, Anil; Mittendorf, Brian
Manufacturer-to-consumer rebates are a staple of modern supply chains. Such rebates are typically viewed as a means of price discrimination because of partial redemption by consumers. However, the proliferation of universally redeemed instant rebates suggests the practice may be motivated by additional considerations, an issue we tackle in this paper. Our results demonstrate that consumer rebates can be particularly useful when a supply chain encounters inefficiencies stemming from strategic inventory buildup by retailers. Wary of high wholesale prices, a retailer may hold excess inventory to convey a lower willingness to pay in future interactions and thereby strategically undercut future wholesale prices. As a retaliatory consequence, the manufacturer sets high near-term wholesale prices. The "pull" promotion from consumer rebates encourages more timely retail sales and in doing so undercuts (but does not eliminate) the retailer's strategic inventories. In other words, the introduction of consumer rebates can serve as an enticement for retailers to sell, not just for consumers to buy. Perhaps surprisingly, we find that the manufacturer, retailer, and consumers alike all benefit from the use of rebates, this despite the fact that the manufacturer uses the rebates in self interest and as a strategic weapon.</description><author>Arya, Anil; Mittendorf, Brian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Crashes, Correlated Illiquidity, and Portfolio Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Hong; Loewenstein, Mark
The recent financial crisis highlights the importance of market crashes and the subsequent market illiquidity for optimal portfolio selection. We propose a tractable and flexible portfolio choice model where market crashes can trigger switching into another regime with a different investment opportunity set. We characterize the optimal trading strategy in terms of coupled integro-differential equations and develop a quite general iterative numerical solution procedure. We conduct an extensive analysis of the optimal trading strategy. In contrast to standard portfolio choice models, changes in the investment opportunity set in one regime can affect the optimal trading strategy in another regime even in the absence of transaction costs. In addition, an increase in the expected jump size can increase stock investment even when the expected return remains the same and the volatility increases. Moreover, we show that misestimating the correlation between market crashes and market illiquidity can be costly to investors.</description><author>Liu, Hong; Loewenstein, Mark</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Discovery in the U.S. Treasury Market: Automation vs. Intermediation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Man, Kasing; Wang, Junbo; Wu, Chunchi
This paper examines the contribution to price discovery by electronic and voice-based trading systems in the U.S. Treasury market. Evidence shows that the electronic trading system has more price discovery and that trading automation increases the speed of incorporating information into prices. However, human trading generates significant price discovery, though its volume is low. The relative contribution of a trading system to price discovery depends on liquidity, volatility, volume, trade size, and order imbalance. The voice-based trading system contributes more to price discovery when trade size is large and liquidity is low. These findings provide important implications for the design of electronic markets for securities with different characteristics and trading environments.</description><author>Man, Kasing; Wang, Junbo; Wu, Chunchi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Clustering, Agency Costs and Operating Efficiency: Evidence from Nursing Home Chains</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lu, Susan F.; Wedig, Gerard J.
Models of horizontal integration typically describe a trade-off between multiunit efficiencies and managerial agency costs. In extreme cases where managers cannot be incented contractually, private ownership is thought to be the primary organizational substitute. In this paper we explore geographic clustering as an alternative strategy for controlling managerial agency costs within the chain form of organization. Clustering may facilitate scale efficiencies in both monitoring and supervision, resulting in reduced agency costs and improved application of the chain's business model. We test this hypothesis in the nursing home industry, which is characterized by managerial contract costs resulting from multitask models of production. We find that clustered nursing homes achieve higher quality, conditional on labor inputs and patient characteristics. The clustering effect is concentrated on reductions in minor/potential harm violations, which are difficult to observe without close monitoring. Several proxies for local organizational experience ("local learning") cannot account for our findings, which are robust to a variety of alternative clustering definitions and competing explanations based on gaming behavior. Further tests indicate that chains endogenously pursue clustering, presumably to realize the benefits of improved quality outcomes.</description><author>Lu, Susan F.; Wedig, Gerard J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Pitfalls of Subsystem Integration: When Less Is More</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erat, Sanjiv; Kavadias, Stylianos; Gaimon, Cheryl
In various industries end-product manufacturers acquire core subsystems from upstream technology provider firms and focus primarily on efficient end-product integration. We examine the strategic interactions between a technology firm that introduces a new subsystem and the respective end-product manufacturers ("integrators"). We analyze how the fraction of end-product functionalities prepackaged into the subsystem impacts the optimal introduction strategy and the relative value appropriation power across the industries. Offering a subsystem that performs many end-product functions has a dual effect on the provider's profits. On the positive side, the provider extracts a higher ease-of-use rent from the integrators because of the easier/cheaper integration. On the negative side, such subsystems may curtail the adopters' ability for competitive differentiation and render adoption less valuable. We discuss the role of subsystem functionality in value appropriation in technology markets, and we highlight the perils of subsystem overintegration.</description><author>Erat, Sanjiv; Kavadias, Stylianos; Gaimon, Cheryl</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Capacity Allocation to Customers Who Remember Past Service</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adelman, Daniel; Mersereau, Adam J.
We study the problem faced by a supplier deciding how to dynamically allocate limited capacity among a portfolio of customers who remember the fill rates provided to them in the past. A customer's order quantity is positively correlated with past fill rates. Customers differ from one another in their contribution margins, their sensitivities to the past, and in their demand volatilities. By analyzing and comparing policies that ignore goodwill with ones that account for it, we investigate when and how customer memory effects impact supplier profits. We develop an approximate dynamic programming policy that dynamically rationalizes the fill rates the firm provides to each customer. This policy achieves higher rewards than margin-greedy and Lagrangian policies and yields insights into how a supplier can effectively manage customer memories to its advantage.</description><author>Adelman, Daniel; Mersereau, Adam J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Biased Judgment in Censored Environments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feiler, Daniel C.; Tong, Jordan D.; Larrick, Richard P.
Some environments constrain the information that managers and decision makers can observe. We examine judgment in censored environments where a constraint, the censorship point, systematically distorts the observed sample. Random instances beyond the censorship point are observed at the censorship point, whereas uncensored instances are observed at their true value. Many important managerial decisions occur in censored environments, such as inventory, risk taking, and employee evaluation decisions. In this research, we demonstrate a censorship bias-individuals tend to rely too heavily on the observed censored sample, biasing their belief about the underlying population. We further show that the censorship bias is exacerbated for higher degrees of censorship, higher variance in the population, and higher variability in the censorship points. In four studies, we find evidence of the censorship bias across the domains of demand estimation and sequential risk taking. The bias causes individuals to make costly decisions and behave in an overly risk-averse manner.</description><author>Feiler, Daniel C.; Tong, Jordan D.; Larrick, Richard P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revenue Sharing and Information Leakage in a Supply Chain</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kong, Guangwen; Rajagopalan, Sampath; Zhang, Hao
This work explores the potential of revenue-sharing contracts to facilitate information sharing in a supply chain and mitigate the negative effects of information leakage. We consider a supplier who offers a revenue-sharing contract to two competing retailers, one of whom has private information about uncertain market potential and orders first. This order information may be leaked to the uninformed retailer by the supplier to realize higher profits. We show that the incentives of the supplier and retailers are better aligned under a revenue-sharing contract, as opposed to under a wholesale-price contract, reducing the supplier's incentive to leak. This is true for a wide range of wholesale prices and revenue-share percentages and is more likely when the revenue-share percentage is higher and when variation in demand is greater. Preventing information leakage may result in higher profits not only for the informed retailer and supplier but surprisingly even for the uninformed retailer. Our results are robust when the model is generalized along various dimensions.</description><author>Kong, Guangwen; Rajagopalan, Sampath; Zhang, Hao</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multiple-Unit Holdings Yield Attenuated Endowment Effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burson, Katherine; Faro, David; Rottenstreich, Yuval
Previous endowment effect experiments have examined circumstances in which people encounter a single unit of a good (e.g., one chocolate). We contrast single-unit treatments with multiple-unit treatments in which participants encounter several units of a good (e.g., five chocolates). We observe endowment effects of typical magnitude for singleton holdings but attenuated endowment effects for multiple-unit holdings. Moreover, endowment effects consistently arise for singletons even as the definition of a unit is altered. For instance, participants holding one piece of chocolate show an endowment effect of standard size, but so do participants holding one box of chocolates. Yet the box contains about 20 individual pieces of chocolate, and participants given that many separate pieces show a substantially attenuated endowment effect. We thus propose the property of "unit dependence": the definition of a unit can change, but contingent on any given definition, a pronounced endowment effect may emerge for singletons but not multiples.</description><author>Burson, Katherine; Faro, David; Rottenstreich, Yuval</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Diversity and Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Feng; Nagar, Venky
This study measures the performance of U.S. firms initiating same-sex domestic partnership benefit (SSDPB) policies. The results show that holding these firms upon their SSDPB initiation in a calendar portfolio earns a four-factor annualized excess return (alpha) of approximately 10% over the 1995-2008 sample period, beating 95% of all professional mutual funds in the United States. This finding is robust to several tests of reverse causality. SSDPB adopters also show significant improvement in operating performance relative to nonadopters.</description><author>Li, Feng; Nagar, Venky</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry Structure, Executive Pay, and Short-Termism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thanassoulis, John
This study outlines a new theory linking industry structure to optimal employment contracts and executive short-termism. Firms hire their executives using optimal contracts derived within a competitive labour market. To motivate effort, firms must use some variable remuneration. Such remuneration introduces a myopia problem: an executive would wish to inflate early expected earnings at some risk to future profits. To manage this short-termism, some bonus pay is deferred. Convergence in size among firms makes the cost of managing the myopia problem grow faster than the cost of managing the effort problem. Eventually, the optimal contract jumps from one deterring myopia to one tolerating myopia. Under some conditions, the industry partitions: the largest firms hire executives on contracts tolerant of myopia; smaller firms ensure myopia is ruled out.</description><author>Thanassoulis, John</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revenue Sharing in Airline Alliances</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Xing; Caldentey, Rene; Vulcano, Gustavo
We propose a two-stage game-theoretic approach to study the operations of an airline alliance in which independent carriers, managing different reservation and information systems, can collaboratively market and operate codeshare and interline itineraries. In the first-stage game, airlines negotiate fixed proration rates to share the revenues generated by such itineraries. In the second-stage game, airlines operate independent inventory control systems to maximize their own expected revenues. We derive a revenue-sharing rule that is (i) an admissible outcome of the first-stage negotiation, in the sense that no airline coalition has enough incentives to secede from the grand alliance, and (ii) efficient for the second-stage game, in the sense that the decentralized system can achieve the same revenues as a central planner managing the global alliance network. Our numerical study shows that the proposed proration rates can lead to a significant increase in revenues with respect to other rules commonly used in practice. Finally, because our proposal requires the disclosure of private demand information, we introduce a simple alternative rule that is based on public information. This heuristic performs remarkably well, becoming an interesting candidate to be pursued in practice.</description><author>Hu, Xing; Caldentey, Rene; Vulcano, Gustavo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Stock Selection and Performance of Buy-Side Analysts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Groysberg, Boris; Healy, Paul; Serafeim, George; Shanthikumar, Devin
Prior research on equity analysts focuses almost exclusively on those employed by sell-side investment banks and brokerage houses. Yet investment firms undertake their own buy-side research, and their analysts face different stock selection and recommendation incentives than their sell-side peers. We examine the selection and performance of stocks recommended by analysts at a large investment firm relative to those of sell-side analysts from mid-1997 to 2004. We find that the buy-side firm's analysts issue less optimistic recommendations for stocks with larger market capitalizations and lower return volatility than their sell-side peers, consistent with their facing fewer conflicts of interest and having a preference for liquid stocks. Tests with no controls for these effects indicate that annualized buy-side strong buy/buy recommendations underperform those for sell-side peers by 5.9% using market-adjusted returns and by 3.8% using four-factor model abnormal returns. However, these findings are driven by differences in the stocks recommended and their market capitalization. After controlling for these selection effects, we find no difference in the performance of the buy- and sell-side analysts' strong buy/buy recommendations.</description><author>Groysberg, Boris; Healy, Paul; Serafeim, George; Shanthikumar, Devin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Corporate Social Responsibility on Firm Value: The Role of Customer Awareness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Servaes, Henri; Tamayo, Ane
This paper shows that corporate social responsibility (CSR) and firm value are positively related for firms with high customer awareness, as proxied by advertising expenditures. For firms with low customer awareness, the relation is either negative or insignificant. In addition, we find that the effect of awareness on the CSR-value relation is reversed for firms with a poor prior reputation as corporate citizens. This evidence is consistent with the view that CSR activities can add value to the firm but only under certain conditions.</description><author>Servaes, Henri; Tamayo, Ane</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mechanism Design for Capacity Planning Under Dynamic Evolutions of Asymmetric Demand Forecasts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oh, Sechan; Ozer, Ozalp
This paper investigates the role of time in forecast information sharing and decision making under uncertainty. To do so, we provide a general framework to model the evolutions of forecasts generated by multiple decision makers who forecast demand for the same product. We also model the evolutions of forecasts when decision makers have asymmetric demand information and refer to it as the Martingale Model of Asymmetric Forecast Evolutions. This model helps us study mechanism design problems in a dynamic environment. In particular, we consider a supplier's (principal's) problem of eliciting credible forecast information from a manufacturer (agent) when both firms obtain asymmetric demand information for the end product over multiple periods. The supplier uses demand information to better plan for a capacity investment decision. When the supplier postpones building capacity and screening the manufacturer's private information, the supplier and the manufacturer can obtain more information and update their forecasts. This delay, however, may increase (respectively, decrease) the degree of information asymmetry between the two firms, resulting in a higher (respectively, lower) cost of screening. The capacity building cost may also increase because of a tighter deadline for building capacity. Considering all such trade-offs, the supplier has to determine (i) when to stop obtaining new demand information and build capacity, (ii) whether to offer a screening contract to credibly elicit private forecast information or to determine the capacity level without information sharing, (iii) how much capacity to build, and (iv) how to design the overall mechanism so that both firms benefit from this mechanism. This paper provides an answer to these questions. In doing so, we develop a new solution approach for a class of dynamic mechanism design problems. In addition, this paper provides a framework to quantify the option value of time for a strategic investment decision under the dynamic evolutions of asymmetric forecasts.</description><author>Oh, Sechan; Ozer, Ozalp</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competitive Price-Matching Guarantees: Equilibrium Analysis of the Availability Verification Clause Under Demand Uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nalca, Arcan; Boyaci, Tamer; Ray, Saibal
Price-matching guarantees involve a retailer matching the lower price of a competitor for an identical product. In reality, retailers often make such guarantees contingent on the verification of product availability at the competitor's location, and decline a price-match request if the product is not available there. This creates certain consternation on the part of customers. In this paper, we investigate the availability contingency strategy from the perspectives of both the retailers and the customers. Our analysis shows that availability contingency clauses intensify inventory competition between retailers and reinstitutes price competition, which is otherwise eliminated by unconditional price-matching guarantees. Consequently, despite what customers may think about the availability verification, it actually increases their surplus. On the other hand, such a clause reduces profits and, hence, is not the equilibrium strategy for retailers. Subsequently, we discuss how a likely customer behaviour pattern may be a plausible explanation regarding the use of the clause by the retailers in practice.</description><author>Nalca, Arcan; Boyaci, Tamer; Ray, Saibal</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry or Academia, Basic or Applied? Career Choices and Earnings Trajectories of Scientists</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Rajshree; Ohyama, Atsushi
We extend life cycle models of human capital investments by incorporating matching theory to examine the sorting pattern of heterogeneous scientists into different career trajectories. We link differences in physical capital investments and complementarities between basic and applied scientists across industry and academic settings to individual differences in scientist ability and preferences to predict an equilibrium matching of scientists to careers and to their earnings evolution. Our empirical analysis, using the National Science Foundation's Scientists and Engineers Statistical Data System database, is consistent with theoretical predictions of (i) sorting by ability into basic versus applied science among academic scientists, but not among industry scientists; and (ii) sorting by higher taste for nonmonetary returns into academia over industry. The evolution of an earnings profile is consistent with these sorting patterns: the earnings trajectories of basic and applied scientists are distinct from each other in academia but are similar in industry.</description><author>Agarwal, Rajshree; Ohyama, Atsushi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Publicizing Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Strobl, Guenter; Van Wesep, Edward D.
In most employment relationships, the employee's performance at the firm is privately, not publicly, observed. Firms can reward successful employees by publicizing their abilities, for example, via a job title, a glowing letter of recommendation, or a resume-worthy award. Firms that establish reputations for hiring young workers and promoting those who succeed lose good workers to competitors but can pay less to young, inexperienced workers in exchange. We find in a general equilibrium setting that firms with reputations for publicizing performance are able to pay less to employees at every level of tenure and thus earn economic profit, but that these firms will never be the most productive in the economy. For such equilibria to exist, the worker-firm match must be important, suggesting that this practice takes place only in human-capital-intensive industries.</description><author>Strobl, Guenter; Van Wesep, Edward D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Add-on Pricing by Asymmetric Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shulman, Jeffrey D.; Geng, Xianjun
This paper uses an analytical model to examine the consequences of add-on pricing when firms are both horizontally and vertically differentiated and there is a segment of boundedly rational consumers who are unaware of the add-on fees at the time of initial purchase. We find that consumers who know the add-on fees can be penalized-and increasingly so-by the existence of boundedly rational consumers. Our consideration of quality asymmetries on base goods and add-ons, plus the inclusion of boundedly rational consumers, leads to several novel findings regarding firm profits. When quality asymmetry is on base goods only and with boundedly rational consumers, add-on pricing can diminish profit for a qualitatively superior firm and increase profit for an inferior firm (i.e., a lose-win result), compared to when add-on pricing is prohibited or infeasible. When quality asymmetries exist on both base goods and add-ons and without boundedly rational consumers, the opposite win-lose result prevails. When quality asymmetries exist on both base goods and add-ons and with boundedly rational consumers, the result can be win-win, win-lose, or lose-win, depending on the magnitude of quality differentiation on add-ons.</description><author>Shulman, Jeffrey D.; Geng, Xianjun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Failure and Rescue in an Interbank Network</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rogers, L. C. G.; Veraart, L. A. M.
This paper is concerned with systemic risk in an interbank market, modelled as a directed graph of interbank obligations. This builds on the modelling paradigm of Eisenberg and Noe [Eisenberg L, Noe TH (2001) Systemic risk in financial systems. Management Sci. 47(2):236-249] by introducing costs of default if loans have to be called in by a failing bank. This immediately introduces novel and realistic effects. We find that, in general, many different clearing vectors can arise, among which there is a greatest clearing vector, arrived at by letting banks fail in succession until only solvent banks remain. Such a collapse should be prevented if at all possible. We then study situations in which consortia of banks may have the means and incentives to rescue failing banks. This again departs from the conclusions of the earlier work of Eisenberg and Noe, where in the absence of default losses there would be no incentive for solvent banks to rescue failing banks. We conclude with some remarks about how a rescue consortium might be constructed.</description><author>Rogers, L. C. G.; Veraart, L. A. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multistage Capital Budgeting with Delayed Consumption of Slack</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baiman, Stanley; Heinle, Mirko S.; Saouma, Richard
Capital budgeting frequently involves multiple stages at which firms can continue or abandon ongoing projects. In this paper, we study a project requiring two stages of investment. Failure to fund Stage 1 of the investment precludes investment in Stage 2, whereas failure to fund Stage 2 results in early termination. In contrast to the existing literature, we assume that the firm can limit the manager's informational rents with the early termination of the project. In this setting, we find that the firm optimally commits to a capital allocation scheme whereby it forgoes positive net present value (NPV) projects at Stage 1 (capital rationing), whereas at Stage 2, depending on the manager's previous report, it sometimes implements projects with a negative continuation NPV but in other situations forgoes implementing projects with positive continuation NPVs.</description><author>Baiman, Stanley; Heinle, Mirko S.; Saouma, Richard</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum and Organizational Risk Taking: Evidence from the National Football League</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lehman, David W.; Hahn, Jungpil
This study examines how momentum shapes organizational risk taking. We define momentum as a sustained and systematic trajectory in performance over time, and we argue that such trends impact interpretations of current performance as well as expectations of future performance. Drawing on the variable focus of attention model, we posit that momentum therefore directs the focus of organizational attention between concerns of aspirations, survival, and slack. Our conceptual model accounts for momentum that occurs within a performance period as well as that which occurs across periods. We propose that within- and across-period momentums are unique in terms of when and how each type impacts risk taking. We tested and found support for our hypotheses in the context of 22,603 play-by-play decisions made by the 32 teams of the National Football League during the 2000-2005 regular season games. Theoretical and practical implications are discussed.</description><author>Lehman, David W.; Hahn, Jungpil</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overcoming Resistance to Organizational Change: Strong Ties and Affective Cooptation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Battilana, Julie; Casciaro, Tiziana
We propose a relational theory of how change agents in organizations use the strength of ties in their network to overcome resistance to change. We argue that strong ties to potentially influential organization members who are ambivalent about a change (fence-sitters) provide the change agent with an affective basis to coopt them. This cooptation increases the probability that the organization will adopt the change. By contrast, strong ties to potentially influential organization members who disapprove of a change outright (resistors) are an effective means of affective cooptation only when a change diverges little from institutionalized practices. With more divergent changes, the advantages of strong ties to resistors accruing to the change agent are weaker, and may turn into liabilities that reduce the likelihood of change adoption. Analyses of longitudinal data from 68 multimethod case studies of organizational change initiatives conducted at the National Health Service in the United Kingdom support these predictions and advance a relational view of organizational change in which social networks operate as tools of political influence through affective mechanisms.</description><author>Battilana, Julie; Casciaro, Tiziana</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Class-Restricted Clustering and Microperturbation for Data Privacy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Xiao-Bai; Sarkar, Sumit
T he extensive use of information technologies by organizations to collect and share personal data has raised strong privacy concerns. To respond to the public's demand for data privacy, a class of clustering-based data masking techniques is increasingly being used for privacy-preserving data sharing and analytics. Although they address reidentification risks, traditional clustering-based approaches for masking numeric attributes typically do not consider the disclosure risk of categorical confidential attributes. We propose a new approach to deal with this problem. The proposed method clusters data such that the data points within a group are similar in the nonconfidential attribute values, whereas the confidential attribute values within a group are well distributed. To accomplish this, the clustering method, which is based on a minimum spanning tree (MST) technique, uses two risk-utility trade-off measures in the growing and pruning stages of the MST technique, respectively. As part of our approach we also propose a novel cluster-level microperturbation method for masking data that overcomes a common problem of traditional clustering-based methods for data masking, which is their inability to preserve important statistical properties such as the variance of attributes and the covariance across attributes. We show that the mean vector and the covariance matrix of the masked data generated using the microperturbation method are unbiased estimates of the original mean vector and covariance matrix. An experimental study on several real-world data sets demonstrates the effectiveness of the proposed approach.</description><author>Li, Xiao-Bai; Sarkar, Sumit</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyzing Screening Policies for Childhood Obesity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Yan; Goldhaber-Fiebert, Jeremy D.; Wein, Lawrence M.
Because of the health and economic costs of childhood obesity, coupled with studies suggesting the benefits of comprehensive (dietary, physical activity, and behavioral counseling) intervention, the U. S. Preventive Services Task Force recently recommended childhood screening and intervention for obesity beginning at age 6. Using a longitudinal data set consisting of the body mass index of 3,164 children up to age 18 and another longitudinal data set containing the body mass index at ages 18 and 40 and the presence or absence of disease (hypertension and diabetes) at age 40 for 747 people, we formulate and numerically solve-separately for boys and girls-a dynamic programming problem for the optimal biennial (i.e., at ages 2, 4, ... , 16) obesity screening thresholds. Unlike most screening problem formulations, we take a societal viewpoint, where the state of the system at each age is the population-wide probability density function of the body mass index. Compared to the biennial version of the task force's recommendation, the screening thresholds derived from the dynamic program achieve a relative reduction in disease prevalence of 3% at the same screening (and treatment) cost, or-because of the flatness of the disease versus screening trade-off curve-achieves the same disease prevalence at a 28% relative reduction in cost. Compared to the task force's policy, which uses the 95th percentile of body mass index (from cross-sectional growth charts tabulated by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention) as the screening threshold for each age, the dynamic programming policy treats mostly 16-year-olds (including many who are not obese) and very few males under 14 years old. Although our results suggest that adult hypertension and diabetes are minimized by focusing childhood obesity screening and treatment on older adolescents, the shortcomings in the available data and the narrowness of the medical outcomes considered prevent us from making a recommendation about childhood obesity screening policies.</description><author>Yang, Yan; Goldhaber-Fiebert, Jeremy D.; Wein, Lawrence M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competitive Incentives: Working Harder or Working Smarter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bracha, Anat; Fershtman, Chaim
Almost all jobs require a combination of cognitive effort and labor effort. This paper focuses on the effect that competitive incentive schemes have on the chosen combination of these two types of efforts. We use an experimental approach to show that competitive incentives may induce agents to work harder but not necessarily smarter. This effect was stronger for women.</description><author>Bracha, Anat; Fershtman, Chaim</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating Structural Models of Equilibrium and Cognitive Hierarchy Thinking in the Field: The Case of Withheld Movie Critic Reviews</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Alexander L.; Camerer, Colin F.; Lovallo, Dan
Film studios occasionally withhold movies from critics before their release. Because the unreviewed movies tend to be below average in quality, this practice provides a useful setting in which to test models of limited strategic thinking: Do moviegoers seem to realize that no review is a sign of low quality? A companion paper showed that in a set of all widely released movies in 2000-2009, cold opening produces a significant 20%-30% increase in domestic box office revenue, which is consistent with moviegoers overestimating quality of unreviewed movies (perhaps due to limited strategic thinking). This paper reviews those findings and provides two models to analyze this data: an equilibrium model and a behavioral cognitive hierarchy model that allows for differing levels of strategic thinking between moviegoers and movie studios. The behavioral model fits the data better, because moviegoer parameters are relatively close to those observed in experimental subjects. These results suggests that limited strategic thinking rather than equilibrium reasoning may be a better explanation for naive moviegoer behavior.</description><author>Brown, Alexander L.; Camerer, Colin F.; Lovallo, Dan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of CRM Outsourcing on Shareholder Value: A Contingency Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalaignanam, Kartik; Kushwaha, Tarun; Steenkamp, Jan-Benedict E. M.; Tuli, Kapil R.
One central business activity that companies increasingly outsource is the information systems (IS) function. Previous research has shown that outsourcing of back-office IS generally has a positive effect on shareholder value of the outsourcing firm. Much less is known about the performance implications of outsourcing of another important IS function, namely, front-office customer relationship management (CRM) systems, where the vendor uses its own personnel and software to perform several CRM tasks. Previous, largely anecdotal evidence shows that the performance implications of outsourcing CRM range from very negative to very positive. To address this unsatisfactory state of knowledge, we provide and empirically test a contingency perspective on the performance implications of outsourcing CRM processes. We do so using the event-study methodology. The results are largely consistent with our contingency model. CRM outsourcing is more beneficial to firms that are high on information technology capabilities and low on marketing capabilities, and less beneficial when it concerns presales CRM. Similarly, although vendor economic distance has a positive influence on the outsourcing firm's shareholder value, vendor cultural distance has a negative influence. These effects are in turn significantly moderated by the type of CRM process outsourced.</description><author>Kalaignanam, Kartik; Kushwaha, Tarun; Steenkamp, Jan-Benedict E. M.; Tuli, Kapil R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lens or Prism? Patent Citations as a Measure of Knowledge Flows from Public Research</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roach, Michael; Cohen, Wesley M.
This paper assesses the validity and accuracy of firms' backward patent citations as a measure of knowledge flows from public research by employing a newly constructed data set that matches patents to survey data at the level of the research and development lab. Using survey-based measures of the dimensions of knowledge flows, we identify sources of systematic measurement error associated with backward citations to both patent and nonpatent references. We find that patent citations reflect the codified knowledge flows from public research, but they appear to miss knowledge flows that are more private and contract based in nature, as well as those used in firm basic research. We also find that firms' patenting and citing strategies affect patent citations, making citations less indicative of knowledge flows. In addition, an illustrative analysis examining the magnitude and direction of measurement error bias suggests that measuring knowledge flows with patent citations can lead to substantial underestimation of the effect of public research on firms' innovative performance. Throughout our analyses we find that nonpatent references (e.g., journals, conferences, etc.), not the more commonly used patent references, are a better measure of knowledge originating from public research.</description><author>Roach, Michael; Cohen, Wesley M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Solving Constrained Consumption-Investment Problems by Simulation of Artificial Market Strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bick, Bjoern; Kraft, Holger; Munk, Claus
Utility-maximizing consumption and investment strategies in closed form are unknown for realistic settings involving portfolio constraints, incomplete markets, and potentially a high number of state variables. Standard numerical methods are hard to implement in such cases. We propose a numerical procedure that combines the abstract idea of artificial, unconstrained complete markets, well-known closed-form solutions in affine or quadratic return models, straightforward Monte Carlo simulation, and a standard iterative optimization routine. Our method provides an upper bound on the wealth-equivalent loss compared to the unknown optimal strategy, and it facilitates our understanding of the economic forces at play by building on closed-form expressions for the strategies considered. We illustrate and test our method on the life-cycle problem of an individual who receives unspanned labor income and cannot borrow or short sell. The upper loss bound is small, and our method performs well in comparison with two existing methods.</description><author>Bick, Bjoern; Kraft, Holger; Munk, Claus</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Individual vs. Aggregate Preferences: The Case of a Small Fish in a Big Pond</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Blackburn, Douglas W.; Ukhov, Andrey D.
We study the relationship between the risk preferences of individuals and the risk preferences of the aggregate economy. To emphasize the vast differences that can occur between individual and market preferences brought about through aggregation, we assume an economy consisting entirely of risk seekers. We show that such individuals can lead to an aggregate economy that is risk averse. The converse is also true. An aggregate economy that exhibits risk aversion does not imply an economy of individual risk averters. An economy demanding a risk premium can be formed from individuals who do not demand such compensation. Understanding the relationship between the preferences of individuals and the preferences of the aggregate economy is crucial for understanding the connection between the behavioral finance literature, which focuses on individual preferences, and the asset-pricing literature, which focuses on aggregate prices. We discuss empirical implications of these results.</description><author>Blackburn, Douglas W.; Ukhov, Andrey D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Dynamic Level-k Model in Sequential Games</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ho, Teck-Hua; Su, Xuanming
Backward induction is a widely accepted principle for predicting behavior in sequential games. In the classic example of the "centipede game," however, players frequently violate this principle. An alternative is a "dynamic level-k" model, where players choose a rule from a rule hierarchy. The rule hierarchy is iteratively defined such that the level-k rule is a best response to the level-(k - 1) rule, and the level-infinity rule corresponds to backward induction. Players choose rules based on their best guesses of others' rules and use historical plays to improve their guesses. The model captures two systematic violations of backward induction in centipede games, limited induction and repetition unraveling. Because the dynamic level-k model always converges to backward induction over repetition, the former can be considered to be a tracing procedure for the latter. We also examine the generalizability of the dynamic level-k model by applying it to explain systematic violations of backward induction in sequential bargaining games. We show that the same model is capable of capturing these violations in two separate bargaining experiments.</description><author>Ho, Teck-Hua; Su, Xuanming</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Services and the Business Models of Product Firms: An Empirical Analysis of the Software Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Suarez, Fernando F.; Cusumano, Michael A.; Kahl, Steven J.
Some product firms increasingly rely on service revenues as part of their business models. One possible explanation is that they turn to services to generate additional profits when their product industries mature and product revenues and profits decline. We explore this assumption by examining the role of services in the financial performance of firms in the prepackaged software products industry (Standard Industrial Classification code 7372) from 1990 to 2006. We find a convex, nonlinear relationship between a product firm's fraction of total sales coming from services and its overall operating margins. As expected, firms with a very high level of product sales are most profitable, and rising services are associated with declining profitability We find, however, that additional services start to have a positive marginal effect on the firm's overall profits when services reach a majority of a product firm's sales. We show that traditional industry maturity arguments cannot fully explain our data. It is likely that changes in both strategy and the business environment lead product firms to place more emphasis on services.</description><author>Suarez, Fernando F.; Cusumano, Michael A.; Kahl, Steven J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust Solutions of Optimization Problems Affected by Uncertain Probabilities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben-Tal, Aharon; den Hertog, Dick; De Waegenaere, Anja; Melenberg, Bertrand; Rennen, Gijs
In this paper we focus on robust linear optimization problems with uncertainty regions defined by phi-divergences (for example, chi-squared, Hellinger, Kullback-Leibler). We show how uncertainty regions based on phi-divergences arise in a natural way as confidence sets if the uncertain parameters contain elements of a probability vector. Such problems frequently occur in, for example, optimization problems in inventory control or finance that involve terms containing moments of random variables, expected utility, etc. We show that the robust counterpart of a linear optimization problem with phi-divergence uncertainty is tractable for most of the choices of phi typically considered in the literature. We extend the results to problems that are nonlinear in the optimization variables. Several applications, including an asset pricing example and a numerical multi-item newsvendor example, illustrate the relevance of the proposed approach.</description><author>Ben-Tal, Aharon; den Hertog, Dick; De Waegenaere, Anja; Melenberg, Bertrand; Rennen, Gijs</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Nonparametric Approach to Modeling Choice with Limited Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Farias, Vivek F.; Jagabathula, Srikanth; Shah, Devavrat
Choice models today are ubiquitous across a range of applications in operations and marketing. Real-world implementations of many of these models fire the formidable stumbling block of simply identifying the "right" model of choice to use. Because models of choice are inherently high-dimensional objects, the typical approach to dealing with this problem is positing, a priori, a parametric model that one believes adequately captures choice behavior. This approach can be substantially suboptimal in scenarios where one cares about using the choice model learned to make fine-grained predictions; one must contend with the risks of mis-specification and overfitting/underfitting. Thus motivated, we visit the following problem: For a "generic" model of consumer choice (namely, distributions over preference lists) and a limited amount of data on how consumers actually make decisions (such as marginal information about these distributions), how may one predict revenues from offering a particular assortment of choices? An outcome of our investigation is a nonparametric approach in which the data automatically select the right choice model for revenue predictions. The approach is practical. Using a data set consisting of automobile sales transaction data from a major U.S. automaker, our method demonstrates a 20% improvement in prediction accuracy over state-of-the-art benchmark models; this improvement can translate into a 10% increase in revenues from optimizing the offer set. We also address a number of theoretical issues, among them a qualitative examination of the choice models implicitly learned by the approach. We believe that this paper takes a step toward "automating" the crucial task of choice model selection.</description><author>Farias, Vivek F.; Jagabathula, Srikanth; Shah, Devavrat</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Engineering Trust: Reciprocity in the Production of Reputation Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Gary; Greiner, Ben; Ockenfels, Axel
Reciprocity in feedback giving distorts the production and content of reputation information in a market, hampering trust and trade efficiency. Guided by feedback patterns observed on eBay and other platforms, we run laboratory experiments to investigate how reciprocity can be managed by changes in the way feedback information flows through the system, leading to more accurate reputation information, more trust, and more efficient trade. We discuss the implications for theory building and for managing the redesign of market trust systems.</description><author>Bolton, Gary; Greiner, Ben; Ockenfels, Axel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Vertical Differentiation with Variety-Seeking Consumers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zeithammer, Robert; Thomadsen, Raphael
We analyze price and quality competition in a vertically differentiated duopoly in which consumers have a preference for variety. The preference for variety is a consequence of diminishing marginal utility for repeated experiences with the same product. We find consumer variety seeking can either soften or intensify price competition, depending on the difference in firm qualities and the strength of consumer preference for variety When the qualities are similar (or the consumer preference for variety is strong), prices and profits are higher than would be obtained in the absence of variety seeking. On the other hand, if qualities differ enough (or the preference for variety is weak), stronger preferences for variety are associated with more intense price competition and lower profits. When firms set their qualities before competing on price and the range of feasible qualities is restricted such that variety seeking softens competition, competing firms choose to minimally differentiate themselves from each other. The preference for variety can drive the firms to offer multiunit discounts, and the greater price flexibility from these discounts does not necessarily reduce profits relative to simple unit pricing.</description><author>Zeithammer, Robert; Thomadsen, Raphael</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing and Hedging with Discontinuous Functions: Quasi-Monte Carlo Methods and Dimension Reduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Xiaoqun; Tan, Ken Seng
Quasi-Monte Carlo (QMC) methods are important numerical tools in the pricing and hedging of complex financial instruments. The effectiveness of QMC methods crucially depends on the discontinuity and the dimension of the problem. This paper shows how the two fundamental limitations can be overcome in some cases. We first study how path-generation methods (PGMs) affect the structure of the discontinuities and what the effect of discontinuities is on the accuracy of QMC methods. The insight is that the discontinuities can be QMC friendly (i.e., aligned with the coordinate axes) or not, depending on the PGM. The PGMs that offer the best performance in QMC methods are those that make the discontinuities QMC friendly. The structure of discontinuities can affect the accuracy of QMC methods more significantly than the effective dimension. This insight motivates us to propose a novel way of handling the discontinuities. The basic idea is to align the discontinuities with the coordinate axes by a judicious design of a method for simulating the underlying processes. Numerical experiments demonstrate that the proposed method leads to dramatic variance reduction in QMC methods for pricing options and for estimating Greeks. It also reduces the effective dimension of the problem.</description><author>Wang, Xiaoqun; Tan, Ken Seng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Decision Stimuli for Risky Choice Experiments: An Adaptive Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cavagnaro, Daniel R.; Gonzalez, Richard; Myung, Jay I.; Pitt, Mark A.
Collecting data to discriminate between models of risky choice requires careful selection of decision stimuli. Models of decision making aim to predict decisions across a wide range of possible stimuli, but practical limitations force experimenters to select only a handful of them for actual testing. Some stimuli are more diagnostic between models than others, so the choice of stimuli is critical. This paper provides the theoretical background and a methodological framework for adaptive selection of optimal stimuli for discriminating among models of risky choice. The approach, called adaptive design optimization, adapts the stimulus in each experimental trial based on the results of the preceding trials. We demonstrate the validity of the approach with simulation studies aiming to discriminate expected utility, weighted expected utility, original prospect theory, and cumulative prospect theory models.</description><author>Cavagnaro, Daniel R.; Gonzalez, Richard; Myung, Jay I.; Pitt, Mark A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Experience Sampling and Graphical Displays on One's Investment Risk Appetite</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaufmann, Christine; Weber, Martin; Haisley, Emily
Financial professionals have a great deal of discretion concerning how to relay information about the risk of financial products to their clients. This paper introduces a new risk tool to communicate the risk of investment products, and it examines how different risk-presentation modes influence risk-taking behavior and investors' recall ability of the risk-return profile of financial products. We analyze four different ways of communicating risk: (i) numerical descriptions, (ii) experience sampling, (iii) graphical displays, and (iv) a combination of these formats in the "risk tool." Participants receive information about a risky and a risk-free fund and make an allocation between the two in an experimental investment portfolio. We find that risky allocations are elevated in both the risk tool and experience sampling conditions. Greater risky allocations in the risk tool condition are associated with decreased risk perception, increased confidence in the risky fund, and a lower estimation of the probability of a loss. In addition to these favorable perceptions of the risky fund, participants in the risk tool condition are more accurate on recall questions regarding the expected return and the probability of a loss. We find no evidence of greater dissatisfaction with returns in these conditions, and we observe a willingness to take on similar levels of risk in subsequent allocations.</description><author>Kaufmann, Christine; Weber, Martin; Haisley, Emily</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Earnings Effects of Entrepreneurial Experience: Evidence from the Semiconductor Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, Benjamin A.
Although previous studies have examined the rewards available to individuals inside entrepreneurial firms, entrepreneurial experience may provide rewards that are independent of the entrepreneurial context. Building on human capital theory, this study provides theoretical explanations for the effects of experience at a start-up on earnings across an individual's career and then examines these implications in the context of California's semiconductor industry Comparing the career trajectories of employees who join start-ups with a matched control group of comparable workers without start-up experience, I perform a counterfactual analysis and find that start-up experience in this context has a persistent positive effect on earnings that extend outside the entrepreneurial environment. The results from the matched sample are consistent with the development and revelation of valuable general human capital through entrepreneurial experience and suggest that the rewards to entrepreneurship are not limited to just the rewards available inside entrepreneurial firms.</description><author>Campbell, Benjamin A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Human Capital Investments and Employee Performance: An Analysis of IT Services Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bapna, Ravi; Langer, Nishtha; Mehra, Amit; Gopal, Ram; Gupta, Alok
The rapid pace of technological innovation necessitates that information technology ( IT) services firms continually invest in replenishing the skills of their key asset base, the human capital. We examine whether human capital investments directed toward employee training are effective in improving employee performance. Our rich employee level panel data set affords us the opportunity to link formal training with performance at the individual employee level. Using a dynamic panel model, we identify a significant positive impact of training on employee performance. A unit increase in training is linked to a 2.14% increase in an employee's performance. Interestingly, we find that in the IT sector, skills atrophy and consequently high-experience employees reap higher returns from training, which highlights the uniquely dynamic nature of IT knowledge and skills. We also find that general training that an employee can utilize outside the focal firm improves employee performance. However, specific training pertinent to the focal firm is not positively linked to performance. On the other hand, although domain and technical training both enhance employee performance individually, the interaction between the two suggests a substitutive relationship. Thus, our findings suggest that the value of training is conditional on a focused curricular approach that emphasizes a structured competency development program. Our findings have both theoretical and practical significance. Most important, they justify increased human capital investments to fuel future growth in this important component of the global economy.</description><author>Bapna, Ravi; Langer, Nishtha; Mehra, Amit; Gopal, Ram; Gupta, Alok</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Experiments for Estimating Preferences: An Adaptive Method of Eliciting Time and Risk Parameters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Toubia, Olivier; Johnson, Eric; Evgeniou, Theodoros; Delquie, Philippe
We present a method that dynamically designs elicitation questions for estimating risk and time preference parameters. Typically these parameters are elicited by presenting decision makers with a series of static choices between alternatives, gambles, or delayed payments. The proposed method dynamically (i.e., adaptively) designs such choices to optimize the information provided by each choice, while leveraging the distribution of the parameters across decision makers (heterogeneity) and capturing response error. We explore the convergence and the validity of our approach using simulations. The simulations suggest that the proposed method recovers true parameter values well under various circumstances. We then use an online experiment to compare our approach to a standard one used in the literature that requires comparable task completion time. We assess predictive accuracy in an out-of-sample task and completion time for both methods. For risk preferences, our results indicate that the proposed method predicts subjects' willingness to pay for a set of out-of-sample gambles significantly more accurately, while taking respondents about the same time to complete. For time preferences, both methods predict out-of-sample preferences equally well, while the proposed method takes significantly less completion time. For risk and time preferences, average completion time for our approach is approximately three minutes. Finally, we briefly review three applications that used the proposed methodology with various populations, and we discuss the potential benefits of the proposed methodology for research and practice.</description><author>Toubia, Olivier; Johnson, Eric; Evgeniou, Theodoros; Delquie, Philippe</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which U.S. Market Interactions Affect CEO Pay? Evidence from UK Companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gerakos, Joseph J.; Piotroski, Joseph D.; Srinivasan, Suraj
This paper examines how different types of interactions with U.S. markets by non-U.S. firms are associated 1 with higher levels of CEO pay, greater emphasis on incentive-based compensation, and smaller pay gaps with U.S. firms. Using a sample of CEOs of UK firms and using both broad cross-sectional and narrow event-window tests, we find that capital market relationship in the form of a U.S. exchange listing is related to higher UK CEO pay; however, the effect is similar when UK firms have a listing in any foreign country, implying a foreign listing effect not unique to the United States. Product market relationships measured by the extent of sales in the United States by UK companies are associated with higher pay, greater use of U.S.-style pay arrangements, and a reduction in the U.S. UK pay gap. The product market effect is incremental to the effect of a U.S. exchange listing, the extent of the firm's non-U.S. foreign market interactions, and the characteristics of the executive. The U.S. UK CEO pay gap reduces in UK firms that make U.S. acquisitions. Furthermore, the firm's use of a U.S. compensation consultant increases the sensitivity of UK pay practices to U.S. product market relationships.</description><author>Gerakos, Joseph J.; Piotroski, Joseph D.; Srinivasan, Suraj</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Competition with Consumer Confusion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chioveanu, Ioana; Zhou, Jidong
This paper proposes a model in which identical sellers of a homogeneous product compete in both prices and price frames (i.e., ways to present price information). Frame choices affect the comparability of price offers and may cause consumer confusion and lower price sensitivity. In equilibrium, firms randomize their frame choices to obfuscate price comparisons and sustain positive profits. The nature of the equilibrium depends on whether frame differentiation or frame complexity is more confusing. Moreover, an increase in the number of competitors induces firms to rely more on frame complexity and this may boost industry profits and lower consumer surplus.</description><author>Chioveanu, Ioana; Zhou, Jidong</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Missing Links: Referrer Behavior and Job Segregation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rubineau, Brian; Fernandez, Roberto M.
The importance of networks in labor markets is well known, and their job-segregating effects in organizations is a given. Conventional wisdom attributes this segregation to the homophilous nature of contact networks, and leaves little role for organizational influences. Yet employee referrals are necessarily initiated within a firm by employee referrers subject to organizational policies. We build theory regarding the role of referrers in the segregating effects of network recruitment. Using mathematical and computational models, we investigate how empirically documented referrer behaviors affect job segregation. We show that referrer behaviors can segregate jobs beyond the effects of homophilous network recruitment. Furthermore, and contrary to past understandings, we show that referrer behaviors can also mitigate most, if not all, of the segregating effects of network recruitment. Although largely neglected in previous labor market network scholarship, referrers are the missing links revealing opportunities for organizations to influence the effects of network recruitment.</description><author>Rubineau, Brian; Fernandez, Roberto M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Salesforce Compensation with Inventory Considerations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dai, Tinglong; Jerath, Kinshuk
We study a scenario in which a firm designs the compensation contract for a salesperson who exerts unobservable effort to increase the level of uncertain demand and, jointly, the firm also decides the inventory level to be stocked. We use a newsvendor-type model in which actual sales depend on the realized demand but are limited by the inventory available, and unfulfilled demand cannot be observed. In this setup, under the optimal contract, the agent is paid a bonus for meeting a sales quota. Our key result is that it may be optimal for the firm to stock more than the first-best inventory level, because this enables the firm to obtain a more precise indicator of the salesperson's effort. The possibility of stockouts due to limited inventory also leads to several counterintuitive results, including the following: (i) relative to when stockouts are not considered, it may be optimal for the firm to pay a higher bonus even though limited inventory constrains sales; (ii) as inventory becomes more expensive, thereby forcing the firm to lower its inventory, the firm may nevertheless pay the agent a higher bonus; and (iii) if there is a lower probability that the agent's effort exertion leads to high demand, rather than lowering inventory due to the lower sales potential, the firm may increase inventory.</description><author>Dai, Tinglong; Jerath, Kinshuk</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Smaller Menus Are Better: Variability in Menu-Setting Ability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldreich, David; Halaburda, Hanna
Are large menus better than small menus? Recent literature argues that individuals' apparent preference for smaller menus can be explained by their behavioral biases or informational limitations. These explanations imply that absent behavioral or informational effects, larger menus would be objectively better. However, in an important economic context-401(k) pension plans we find that larger menus are objectively worse than smaller menus, as measured by the maximum Sharpe ratio achievable. We propose a model in which menu setters differ in their ability to preselect the menu. We show that when the cost of increasing the menu size is sufficiently small, a lower-ability menu setter optimally offers more items in the menu than a higher-ability menu setter. Nevertheless, the menu optimally offered by a higher-ability menu setter remains superior. This results in a negative relation between menu size and menu quality: smaller menus are better than larger menus.</description><author>Goldreich, David; Halaburda, Hanna</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Invariant Probabilistic Sensitivity Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baucells, Manel; Borgonovo, Emanuele
In evaluating opportunities, investors wish to identify key sources of uncertainty. We propose a new way to measure how sensitive model outputs are to each probabilistic input (e.g., revenues, growth, idiosyncratic risk parameters). We base our approach on measuring the distance between cumulative distributions (risk profiles) using a metric that is invariant to monotonic transformations. Thus, the sensitivity measure will not vary by alternative specifications of the utility function over the output. To measure separation, we propose using either Kuiper's metric or Kolmogorov-Smirnov's metric. We illustrate the advantages of our proposed sensitivity measure by comparing it with others, most notably, the contribution-to-variance measures. Our measure can be obtained as a by-product of a Monte Carlo simulation. We illustrate our approach in several examples, focusing on investment analysis situations.</description><author>Baucells, Manel; Borgonovo, Emanuele</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Analysts' Forecasts Informative to the General Public?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altinkilic, Oya; Balashov, Vadim S.; Hansen, Robert S.
Contrary to the common view that analysts are important information agents, intraday returns evidence shows that announcements of analysts' forecast revisions release little new information, on average. Further cross-sectional evidence from returns around the announcements confirms that revisions are virtually information free. Daily announcement returns used in the literature appear to overstate the analyst's role as information agent, because forecast announcements are often issued directly after reports of significant news about the followed firm. The evidence reveals a sequential relationship between events and news and forecast revisions indicative of analyst piggybacking, not prophecy. These new findings about the most sought-after analyst reports broaden significantly the evidence indicating that price reactions to analysts' reports reveal little new information.</description><author>Altinkilic, Oya; Balashov, Vadim S.; Hansen, Robert S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When the Tail Wags the Dog: Industry Leaders, Limited Attention, and Spurious Cross-Industry Information Diffusion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cen, Ling; Chan, Kalok; Dasgupta, Sudipto; Gao, Ning
Within industry, stock returns of larger firms lead those of smaller firms, suggesting an intraindustry information diffusion process. Most industry leaders, however, have business segments in other industries (henceforth, minor-segment industries), whereas most small firms are pure players operating in one industry only. If investors cannot filter out the irrelevant information from the leaders' minor segments, the pure players will be mispriced due to spurious cross-industry information diffusion (SCIID). Consistent with the SCUD hypothesis, we document both a strong contemporaneous and a lead-lag relation in stock returns between firms from industry leaders' minor-segment industries and pure players in the industry leaders' major-segment industry. Our results are not due to potential missing common factors or economic relationships between pure. players and firms in the minor-segment industries.</description><author>Cen, Ling; Chan, Kalok; Dasgupta, Sudipto; Gao, Ning</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Does Rivals' Presence Affect Firms' Decision to Enter New Markets? Economic and Sociological Explanations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kocak, Ozgecan; Ozcan, Serden
Four distinct theoretical programs have examined market entry decisions of multiunit firms, advancing different explanations for the relationship between a firm's likelihood of entry into a geographical market and the number of rivals that are already present in the target market. Within the strategy literature, theory of strategic interactions explains that firms will want to establish a foothold in markets where their multimarket competitors are scarce, but avoid markets where there are many multimarket competitors. Within economic geography, positive externalities such as increase in demand explain firms' desire to locate close to their rivals whereas negative externalities such as competition explain their desire to avoid them. Within the ecological tradition, density dependence theory explains this relationship in terms of legitimation of an organizational form in a particular market and subsequently increased competition for resources there. Within new institutional theory, the presence of rivals is seen as a signal that a particular market is suitable for entry. Although generally quoted and mentioned in the literature, these four explanations have not been sufficiently separated to indicate whether these four mechanisms all operate simultaneously or whether one of them might account for the often found inverse-U-shaped relationship. Distinguishing firms with different strategies and using various moderators, we test the four explanations jointly and demonstrate their scope of operation.</description><author>Kocak, Ozgecan; Ozcan, Serden</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Consumer Attentiveness and Search Costs on Firm Quality Disclosure: A Competitive Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghosh, Bikram; Galbreth, Michael R.
Firms can invest to disclose quality information about their products to consumers, but consumers are not always perfectly attentive to these disclosures. Indeed, technologies such as digital video recorders have increased the ease with which disclosures can be avoided by consumers. Although such inattention may result in a consumer missing information from one or more competing firms, consumers who have missed disclosures might decide to search for quality information to become fully informed before making a purchase decision. In this paper we incorporate consumer attentiveness, as well as the related endogenous search decision, into a model of quality disclosure. Our results suggest that firms should disclose less quality information as the share of partially informed consumers (informed about one firm but not the other) increases, or as consumer search costs increase. We also provide insights into the potential impact of consumer trends toward lower attentiveness and lower search costs.</description><author>Ghosh, Bikram; Galbreth, Michael R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Video Rental Patterns Change as Consumers Move Online</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zentner, Alejandro; Smith, Michael; Kaya, Cuneyd
How will consumption patterns for popular and "long-tail" products change when consumers move from brick-and-mortar to Internet markets? We address this question using customer-level panel data obtained from a national video rental chain as it was closing many of its local stores. These data allow us to use the closure of a consumer's local video store as an instrument, breaking the inherent endogeneity between channel choice and product choice. Our results suggest that when consumers move from brick-and-mortar to online channels, they are significantly more likely to rent "niche" titles relative to "blockbusters." This suggests that a significant amount of niche product consumption online is due to the direct influence of the channel on consumer behavior, not just due to selection effects from the types of consumers who decide to use the Internet channel or the types of products that consumers decide to purchase online.</description><author>Zentner, Alejandro; Smith, Michael; Kaya, Cuneyd</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>License to Cheat: Voluntary Regulation and Ethical Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gino, Francesca; Krupka, Erin L.; Weber, Roberto A.
Although monitoring and regulation can be used to combat socially costly unethical conduct, their intended targets can often avoid regulation or hide their behavior. This surrenders at least part of the effectiveness of regulatory policies to firms' and individuals' decisions to voluntarily submit to regulation. We study individuals' decisions to avoid monitoring or regulation and thus enhance their ability to engage in unethical conduct. We conduct a laboratory experiment in which participants engage in a competitive task and can decide between having the opportunity to misreport their performance or having their performance verified by an external monitor. To study the effect of social factors on the willingness to be subject to monitoring, we vary whether participants make this decision simultaneously with others or sequentially, as well as whether the decision is private or public. Our results show that the opportunity to avoid being submitted to regulation produces more unethical conduct than situations in which regulation is either exogenously imposed or entirely absent.</description><author>Gino, Francesca; Krupka, Erin L.; Weber, Roberto A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Job Seekers Benefit from Contacts? A Direct Test with Contemporaneous Searches</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Obukhova, Elena; Lan, George
Although it is intuitively plausible that a job seeker benefits by using contacts in her job search, the literature is plagued by theoretical disagreements and inconclusive empirical evidence. Single-firm studies consistently find that job seekers applying through referrals achieve better labor-market outcomes than job seekers applying without referrals, but the evidence from job-seeker studies is mixed. To solve this puzzle, we clarify the distinction between having social capital and using contacts as a search method. We present theoretical reasons to suggest that the lack of an association between a job seeker's social capital and whether or not she uses social networks to search for a job should not be taken to imply that job seekers who use social networks to search for jobs do not benefit from using contacts. We exploit a strategic research setting, the school-to-work transition of 291 university graduates who engaged in 3,112 contemporaneous job searches, to show that although a job seeker's social capital may not affect whether or not she uses contacts to search for a job, using contacts as a job-search method does improve her job-search outcomes. We conclude by discussing the implications of our findings for the literature on job search and social networks.</description><author>Obukhova, Elena; Lan, George</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of New Product Introduction on Plant Productivity in the North American Automotive Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gopal, Anandasivam; Goyal, Manu; Netessine, Serguei; Reindorp, Matthew
Product launch-an event when a new product debuts for production in a plant-is an important phase in product development. But launches disrupt manufacturing operations, resulting in productivity losses. Using data from North American automotive plants from years 1999-2007, we estimate that a product launch entails an average productivity loss of 12%-15% at the plant level. This translates to a monetary loss of $42-$53 million per launch in lost productivity. We identify several ways to mitigate the decrease in productivity. Product (or mix) flexibility in the body shop is critical for reducing the productivity loss. A plant's past experiences with product launches as well as with manufacturing similar products (specifically, on the same platform as the launch product) temper the productivity losses even further. Nevertheless, there are subtle differences in the accrued learning with these two types of experiences: whereas the positive impact of platform experience persists over time, the learning accrued with launching other products in the same plant decays more quickly. Altogether, our results suggest that launching products at a flexible plant with appropriate platform experience could recover approximately $31 million per launch in lost productivity.</description><author>Gopal, Anandasivam; Goyal, Manu; Netessine, Serguei; Reindorp, Matthew</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"Nursevendor Problem": Personnel Staffing in the Presence of Endogenous Absenteeism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, Linda V.; Savin, Sergei; Savva, Nicos
The problem of determining nurse staffing levels in a hospital environment is a complex task because of variable patient census levels and uncertain service capacity caused by nurse absenteeism. In this paper, we combine an empirical investigation of the factors affecting nurse absenteeism rates with an analytical treatment of nurse staffing decisions using a novel variant of the newsvendor model. Using data from the emergency department of a large urban hospital, we find that absenteeism rates are consistent with nurses exhibiting an aversion to higher levels of anticipated workload. Using our empirical findings, we analyze a single-period nurse staffing problem considering both the case of constant absenteeism rate (exogenous absenteeism) as well as an absenteeism rate that is a function of the number of nurses scheduled (endogenous absenteeism). We provide characterizations of the optimal staffing levels in both situations and show that the failure to incorporate absenteeism as an endogenous effect results in understaffing.</description><author>Green, Linda V.; Savin, Sergei; Savva, Nicos</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>No-Arbitrage Taylor Rules with Switching Regimes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Haitao; Li, Tao; Yu, Cindy
We study the time-varying nature of U.S. monetary policies summarized by the Taylor rule based on a continuous-time regime-switching term structure model. In this model, the spot rate follows the Taylor rule and government bonds at different maturities are priced by no arbitrage. We allow the coefficients of the Taylor rule and the dynamics of inflation and output gap to be regime dependent and estimate the model using government bond yields. We find that the Fed is proactive in controlling inflation in one regime and accommodative for growth in another. Moreover, proactive monetary policies are associated with more stable inflation and output gap and therefore could have contributed to the Great Moderation. Our analysis also highlights the importance of switching regimes for term structure modeling. Without the regimes, inflation and output can explain less than 50% of the variations of bond yields. With the regimes, the two variables can explain more than 80% of the variations of bond yields.</description><author>Li, Haitao; Li, Tao; Yu, Cindy</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Coinsurance Within Business Groups: Evidence from Related Party Transactions in an Emerging Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jia, Nan; Shi, Jing; Wang, Yongxiang
Using novel transaction-level data on Chinese business groups, this study provides the first direct evidence of the coinsurance theory of business groups by investigating when different types of internal resources are transferred within a business group. We find that in Chinese business groups, a credit crunch experienced by the controlling shareholding firm (the "controller") of a publicly listed firm increases the loan-based related party transactions (RPTs) including loan guarantees and intercorporate loans provided by the listed firm to the controller. In turn, when the listed firm's performance dips, the controller and its son firms provide more support to the listed firm in the form of non-loan-based RPTs. These findings directly show the dynamic interactions of members within business groups.</description><author>Jia, Nan; Shi, Jing; Wang, Yongxiang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Simple Auctions for Supply Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duenyas, Izak; Hu, Bin; Beil, Damian R.
This paper studies an optimal procurement mechanism for a newsvendor-like problem where the buyer's (newsvendor's) purchase price of the supplies is not fixed, but determined through interaction with candidate suppliers. The buyer has priors on the suppliers' costs but does not know their costs exactly. Recent literature has shown how the buyer can implement the optimal procurement mechanism by announcing a revenue function (specifying a payment for each quantity the buyer may purchase), then auctioning off the supply contract with the specified revenue function. In this paper, we show that a simple modified version of the standard open-descending auction for a fixed quantity is also an optimal mechanism for obtaining supplies. What distinguishes this mechanism is its simplicity and familiarity for the suppliers-open-descending auctions are very easy to run and ubiquitous in practice, whereas auctioning supply contracts with a specified revenue function is much less observed and more difficult to explain to suppliers. Furthermore, we show that this simple mechanism can be easily generalized to ex ante asymmetric suppliers and a class of nonlinear production costs.</description><author>Duenyas, Izak; Hu, Bin; Beil, Damian R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Risk Spillovers Among Financial Institutions Around the Global Credit Crisis: Firm-Level Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Jian; Zhou, Yinggang
Using credit default swap data, we propose a novel empirical framework to identify the structure of credit risk networks across international major financial institutions around the recent global credit crisis. Specifically, we identify three groups of players, including prime senders, exchange centers, and prime receivers of credit risk information. Leverage ratios and, particularly, the short-term debt ratio appear to be significant determinants of the roles of financial institutions in credit risk transfer, while corporate governance indexes, size, liquidity, and asset write-downs are not significant. Our findings carry important implications for a new regulatory standard on capital subcharge and liquidity coverage ratio.</description><author>Yang, Jian; Zhou, Yinggang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Media, Aggregators, and the Link Economy: Strategic Hyperlink Formation in Content Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dellarocas, Chrysanthos; Katona, Zsolt; Rand, William
A defining property of the World Wide Web is a content site's ability to place virtually costless hyperlinks to third-party content as a substitute or complement to its own content. Costless hyperlinking has enabled new types of players, usually referred to as content aggregators, to successfully enter content ecosystems, attracting traffic and revenue by hosting links to the content of others. This, in turn, has sparked a heated controversy between content creators and aggregators regarding the legitimacy and costs/benefits of uninhibited free linking. To our knowledge, this work is the first to model the complex interplay between content and links in settings where a set of sites compete for traffic. We develop a series of analytical models that distill how hyperlinking affects the (a) incentives of content nodes to produce quality content versus link to third-party content, (b) profits of the various stakeholders, (c) average quality of content that becomes available to consumers, and (d) impact of content aggregators. Our results provide a nuanced view of the so-called link economy, highlighting both the beneficial consequences and the drawbacks of free hyperlinks for content creators and consumers.</description><author>Dellarocas, Chrysanthos; Katona, Zsolt; Rand, William</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tempus Fugit: Time Pressure in Risky Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kocher, Martin G.; Pahlke, Julius; Trautmann, Stefan T.
We study the effects of time pressure on risky decisions for pure gain prospects, pure loss prospects, and mixed prospects involving both gains and losses. In two experiments we find that time pressure has no effect on risk attitudes for gains, but increases risk aversion for losses. For mixed prospects, subjects become simultaneously more loss averse and more gain seeking under time pressure, depending on the framing of the prospects. The results suggest the importance of aspiration levels, and thus the overall probability to break even, under time pressure. We discuss the implications of our findings for decision-making situations that involve time pressure.</description><author>Kocher, Martin G.; Pahlke, Julius; Trautmann, Stefan T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investors' Heterogeneity and Implied Volatility Smiles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Tao
Heterogeneity in beliefs and time preferences among investors make stock volatility stochastic, even though the volatility of the underlying dividend is constant. Prices of the European options written on this stock admit closed-form solutions, hence their hedging deltas. The Black-Scholes implied volatility surface, which depends on wealth distribution, investors' beliefs, and time preferences, exhibits observed patterns that are widely documented in various options markets. Along with benchmark models, the model is calibrated weekly to the S&amp;P 500 index options from January 1996 to April 2006. It shows comparable performance to the stochastic volatility and jump model and outperforms the traders' rules and two no-arbitrage models (stochastic volatility, and stochastic volatility and stochastic interest rate) in terms of out-of-sample pricing errors.</description><author>Li, Tao</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning from My Success and from Others' Failure: Evidence from Minimally Invasive Cardiac Surgery</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diwas, K. C.; Staats, Bradley R.; Gino, Francesca
Learning from past experience is central to an organization's adaptation and survival. A key dimension of prior experience is whether an outcome was successful or unsuccessful. Although empirical studies have investigated the effects of success and failure in organizational learning, to date, the phenomenon has received little attention at the individual level. Drawing on attribution theory in psychology, we investigate how individuals learn from their own past experiences with both failure and success and from the experiences of others. For our empirical analyses, we use 10 years of data from 71 cardiothoracic surgeons who completed more than 6,500 procedures using a new technology for cardiac surgery. We find that individuals learn more from their own successes than from their own failures, but they learn more from the failures of others than from others' successes. We also find that individuals' prior successes and others' failures can help individuals overcome their inability to learn from their own failures. Together, these findings offer both theoretical and practical insights into how individuals learn directly from their prior experience and indirectly from the experiences of others.</description><author>Diwas, K. C.; Staats, Bradley R.; Gino, Francesca</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overconfidence in Newsvendor Orders: An Experimental Study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ren, Yufei; Croson, Rachel
Previous studies have shown that individuals make suboptimal decisions in a variety of supply chain and inventory settings. We hypothesize that one cause is that individuals are overconfident (in particular, overprecise) in their estimation of order variation. Previous work has shown theoretically that underestimating the variance of demand causes orders to deviate from optimal in predictable ways. We provide two experiments supporting this theoretical link. In the first, we elicit the precision of each individual's beliefs and demonstrate that overprecision significantly correlates with order bias. We find that overprecision explains almost one-third of the observed ordering mistakes and that the effect of overprecision is robust to learning and other dynamic considerations. In the second, we introduce a new technique to exogenously reduce overprecision. We find that participants randomly assigned to this treatment demonstrate less overprecision and less biased orders than do those in a control group.</description><author>Ren, Yufei; Croson, Rachel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Coproduct Technologies: Product Line Design and Process Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Ying-Ju; Tomlin, Brian; Wang, Yimin
The simultaneous production of different outputs (coproducts) is observed in the chemical, material, mineral, and semiconductor industries among others. Often, as with microprocessors, the outputs differ in quality in the vertical sense and firms classify the output into different grades (products). We analyze product line design and production for a firm operating a vertical coproduct technology. We examine how the product line and profit are influenced by the production cost and output distribution of the technology. We prove that production cost influences product line design in a fundamentally different manner for coproduct technologies than for uniproduct technologies where the firm can produce products independently. For example, with coproducts, the size and length of the product line can both increase in the production cost. Contrary to the oft-held view that variability is bad, we prove the firm benefits from a more variable output distribution if the production or classification cost is low enough.</description><author>Chen, Ying-Ju; Tomlin, Brian; Wang, Yimin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Blogs, Advertising, and Local-Market Movie Box Office Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gopinath, Shyam; Chintagunta, Pradeep K.; Venkataraman, Sriram
We measure the effects of pre- and postrelease blog volume, blog valence, and advertising on the performance of 75 movies in 208 geographic markets in the United States. We attribute the variation in blog effects across markets to differences in demographic characteristics of markets combined with differences across demographic groups in their access and exposure to blogs as well as their responsiveness conditional on access. We study the effects of prerelease factors on opening day box office performance and of pre- and postrelease factors on box office performance one month after release. Our estimation accounts for confounding factors in the measurement of these effects via the use of instrumental variables. We find considerable heterogeneity in the effects across consumer- and firm-generated media and across geographic markets, with gender, income, race, and age driving across-market differences. Release day performance is impacted most by prerelease blog volume and advertising, whereas postrelease performance is influenced by postrelease blog valence and advertising. Across markets, there is more variance in advertising and blog valence (postrelease) elasticities than there is in blog volume (prerelease) elasticities. We identify the top 20 markets in terms of their elasticities to each of these three instruments. Further, we classify markets in terms of their sensitivities across these three instruments to identify the most sensitive markets that studios can target with their limited release strategies. Finally, we characterize the extent to which studios could have improved their limited release strategies by identifying the overlap between the actual release markets and the most responsive ones. We find that at the time of first-release studios cover only 53% of the most responsive advertising markets and 44% of the most responsive markets to prerelease blog volume in their limited release</description><author>Gopinath, Shyam; Chintagunta, Pradeep K.; Venkataraman, Sriram</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>User-Generated Content and Bias in News Media</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yildirim, Pinar; Gal-Or, Esther; Geylani, Tansev
In this study, we investigate newspapers' decision to expand their product lines by adding online editions that incorporate user-generated content. We demonstrate that such product line extensions mitigate the extent of slanting in print media. The results also show that as the extent of discretion of users to generate online content increases, print versions of newspapers become more polarized. Furthermore, adding online editions results in reduced profits for newspapers as the additional product variants increase the intensity of competition in the market and the discretion awarded to users limits the ability of newspapers to extract rents from consumers.</description><author>Yildirim, Pinar; Gal-Or, Esther; Geylani, Tansev</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentives' Effect in Influenza Vaccination Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yamin, Dan; Gavious, Arieh
In the majority of developed countries, the level of influenza vaccination coverage in all age groups is suboptimal. Hence, the authorities offer different kinds of incentives for people to become vaccinated such as subsidizing immunization or placing immunization centers in malls to make the process more accessible. We built a theoretical epidemiological game model to find the optimal incentive for vaccination and the corresponding expected level of vaccination coverage. The model was supported by survey data from questionnaires about people's perceptions about influenza and the vaccination against it. Results suggest that the optimal magnitude of the incentives should be greater when less contagious seasonal strains of influenza are involved and greater for the nonelderly population rather than the elderly, and should rise as high as $57 per vaccinated individual so that all children between the ages of six months and four years will be vaccinated.</description><author>Yamin, Dan; Gavious, Arieh</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Acquisitions on the Performance of Existing Organizational Units in the Acquiring Firm: The Case of an Agribusiness Company</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mingo, Santiago
Companies frequently expand their production capacity through the acquisition of new organizational unit. This study analyzes how the performance of existing units is affected by the acquisition of another unit. The research focuses on three mechanisms: managerial distraction, resource transfer, and knowledge sharing. These mechanisms are studied in the context of existing units and acquired units with different levels of proximity and similarity between them. Using a detailed data set from an agribusiness company, empirical analysis shows that after an acquisition event there is a temporary decrease in the performance of existing units that are geographically proximate to the acquired unit. Data analysis also shows that after an acquisition event there is an increase in the performance of existing units that have similar characteristics to the acquired unit. In this latter case, the rate of increase in performance diminishes over time. This research demonstrates that the acquisition of an organizational unit can have differing dynamic effects on different parts of the organization.</description><author>Mingo, Santiago</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Influence of Software Process Maturity and Customer Error Reporting on Software Release and Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>August, Terrence; Niculescu, Marius Florin
Software producers are making greater use of customer error reporting to discover defects and improve the quality of their products. We study how software development differences among producers (e.g., varying levels of process maturity) and software class and functionality differences (e.g., operating system versus productivity software) affect how these producers coordinate software release timing and pricing to optimally harness error reporting contributions from users. In settings where prices are fixed, we characterize the optimal release time and demonstrate why in some cases it can actually be preferable to delay release when customer error reporting rates increase. The manner in which a firm's optimal release time responds to increases in software functionality critically hinges on whether the added functionality enhances or dilutes user error reporting; in both cases, the effect of added functionality on release timing can go in either direction, depending on both firm and product market characteristics. For example, when processing costs are relatively large compared with goodwill costs, firms with lower process maturity will release earlier when per-module error reporting contributions become diluted and release later when these contributions become enhanced. We also examine how a firm adapts price with changes in error reporting levels and software functionality, and finally, we provide implications of how beta testing influences release timing.</description><author>August, Terrence; Niculescu, Marius Florin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structural Estimation of Callers' Delay Sensitivity in Call Centers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aksin, Zeynep; Ata, Baris; Emadi, Seyed Morteza; Su, Che-Lin
We model the decision-making process of callers in call centers as an optimal stopping problem. After each waiting period, a caller decides whether to abandon a call or continue to wait. The utility of a caller is modeled as a function of her waiting cost and reward for service. We use a random-coefficients model to capture the heterogeneity of the callers and estimate the cost and reward parameters of the callers using the data from individual calls made to an Israeli call center. We also conduct a series of counterfactual analyses that explore the effects of changes in service discipline on resulting waiting times and abandonment rates. Our analysis reveals that modeling endogenous caller behavior can be important. when major changes (such as a change in service discipline) are implemented and that using a model with an exogenously specified abandonment distribution may be misleading.</description><author>Aksin, Zeynep; Ata, Baris; Emadi, Seyed Morteza; Su, Che-Lin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Margin Differences in Vertical Marketing Channels Lead to Contracts with Slotting Fees?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dhar, Tirtha
In this paper, we show that slotting fees can be part of an equilibrium solution if per-unit downstream margin is smaller than the per-unit upstream margin. In recent literature, a similar margin-based argument is made by Klein and Wright (2007), whereas intense downstream retail competition coupled with high upstream margin causes upstream manufacturers to offer slotting fees for promotional shelf space. In this paper, we generalize this argument and show that it is possible to have the margin-based argument without any downstream retail competition and competition between products within a retail chain. Interestingly we show that slotting fees will be larger if the products sold by a retailer are complements rather than substitutes. Using a model. of a channel bargaining game, we also provide the necessary and sufficient conditions for the existence of slotting fees and show that for contracts with slotting fees under full vertical coordination, upstream marginal cost functions need to be increasing. Broadly, our findings provide new insights into the strategic role of downstream product assortment on equilibrium-marketing-channel contracts with slotting fees.</description><author>Dhar, Tirtha</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrepreneurial Spawning and Firm Characteristics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Habib, Michel A.; Hege, Ulrich; Mella-Barral, Pierre
We analyze the implications of the decision to spawn or to retain a new product for the nature and evolution of the firm. In our model, a new product is spawned if the fit between the product and its parent firm organization is not adequate. We focus on the impact of the firm's history of spawning decisions on firm characteristics such as size, focus, profitability, and innovativeness, and analyze its role in shaping firm dynamics. In accordance with the empirical literature, our model predicts that older firms innovate less, spawn less, are more diversified and less profitable, and that firms with more valuable general or specialized resources innovate and spawn more. Echoing seemingly contradictory empirical findings, our model predicts that small, focused firms (large, diversified firms) innovate and spawn more, and are more profitable when sample heterogeneity is driven by the importance of organizational fit (the value of general resources).</description><author>Habib, Michel A.; Hege, Ulrich; Mella-Barral, Pierre</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Simultaneous vs. Sequential Group-Buying Mechanisms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Ming; Shi, Mengze; Wu, Jiahua
This paper studies the design of group-buying mechanisms in a two-period game where cohorts of consumers I arrive at a deal and make sign-up decisions sequentially. A firm can adopt either a sequential mechanism where the firm discloses to second-period arrivals the number of sign-ups accumulated in the first period, or a simultaneous mechanism where the firm does not post the number of first-period sign-ups and hence each cohort of consumers faces uncertainty about another cohort's size and valuations when making sign-up decisions. Our analysis shows that, compared with the simultaneous mechanism, the sequential mechanism leads to higher deal success rates and larger expected consumer surpluses. This result holds for a multiperiod extension and when the firm offers a price discount schedule with multiple breakpoints. Finally, when the firm can manage the sequence of arrivals, it should inform the smaller cohort of consumers first.</description><author>Hu, Ming; Shi, Mengze; Wu, Jiahua</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should Managers Use Team-Based Contests?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hua; Lim, Noah
When designing contests to motivate employees, should managers organize employees to compete in teams or as individuals? We develop a behavioral economics model that shows that if contestants are averse to being responsible for the team's loss, a team-based (TB) contest can yield higher effort than an individual-based (IB) contest. This prediction is contrary to those of standard economics models, which favor IB contests over TB contests. We test the competing predictions using laboratory economics experiments. The results show that when contestants do not know each other, average effort levels in the TB and TB contests are not different. When contestants are allowed to socialize with potential teammates before making effort decisions, TB contests yield higher effort relative to TB contests. We also show that the relative efficacy of TB contests is driven by contestants' aversion to letting their team down.</description><author>Chen, Hua; Lim, Noah</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Context-Dependent Preferences and Innovation Strategy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yuxin; Turut, Ozge
Disruptive innovations introduce a new performance dimension into a product category, but often suffer from inferior performance on key performance dimensions of their existing substitutes. Hence, the followers of these innovations face an important decision to make: they must choose to improve the new technology either on the key performance dimension shared with the old technology or on the new performance dimension. This paper investigates which path firms should choose when they face such a dilemma in the absence of any cost or capability issues. In doing so, we integrate customer response into the theory of technological evolution and allow preferences on the product choices to be context dependent. We show that context-dependent preferences may encourage the follower to improve the new technology on the new performance dimension. Later, we extend our game to a dynamic one and show that the context-dependent preferences may cause the pioneer to innovate less.</description><author>Chen, Yuxin; Turut, Ozge</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Person-Organization Discontinuity in Contract Perception: Why Corporations Can Get Away with Breaking Contracts But Individuals Cannot</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haran, Uriel
Most legal systems in the world follow the principle of corporate personhood, which grants organizations the same legal status as natural persons. Although debate over the notion of corporate personhood has been fierce, whether and how this principle is applied in people's beliefs and intuitions has yet to be empirically examined. This work addresses the gap in the literature, in the context of formal contracts. While contracts are typically seen as either morally binding promises or morally neutral business instruments, the data presented here show that contracts of individuals are associated more strongly with promises than are contracts of organizations. As a result, breach of contract by an individual is seen as a moral transgression. The same behavior by an organization, however, is viewed more as a legitimate business decision. This paper also finds that contractual obligations should be phrased in "promise" terms to eliminate this person organization discontinuity.</description><author>Haran, Uriel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Customer-Driven Misconduct: How Competition Corrupts Business Practices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bennett, Victor Manuel; Pierce, Lamar; Snyder, Jason A.; Toffel, Michael W.
Competition among firms yields many benefits but can also encourage firms to engage in corrupt or unethical activities. We argue that competition can lead organizations to provide services that customers demand but that violate government regulations, especially when price competition is restricted. Using 28 million vehicle emissions tests from more than 11,000 facilities, we show that increased competition is associated with greater inspection leniency, a service quality attribute that customers value but is illegal and socially costly. Firms with more competitors pass customer vehicles at higher rates and are more likely to lose customers whom they fail, suggesting that competition intensifies pressure on facilities to provide illegal leniency. We also show that, at least in markets in which pricing is restricted, firms use corrupt and unethical practices as an entry strategy.</description><author>Bennett, Victor Manuel; Pierce, Lamar; Snyder, Jason A.; Toffel, Michael W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Firm Financial Conditions Affect Product Quality and Pricing?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phillips, Gordon; Sertsios, Giorgo
We analyze the interaction of firm product quality and pricing decisions with financial distress and bankruptcy in the airline industry. We consider an airline's choices of quality and price as dynamic decisions that trade off current cash flows for future revenue. We examine how airline mishandled baggage, on-time performance, and pricing are related to financial distress and bankruptcy, controlling for the endogeneity of financial distress and bankruptcy. We find that an airline's quality decisions are differentially affected by financial distress and bankruptcy. Product quality decreases when airlines are in financial distress, consistent with financial distress reducing a firm's incentive to invest in quality. In contrast, in bankruptcy product quality increases relative to financial distress. In addition, we find that firms price more aggressively when in financial distress consistent with firms trying to increase short-term market share and revenues.</description><author>Phillips, Gordon; Sertsios, Giorgo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Competition Under Mixed Multinomial Logit Demand Functions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aksoy-Pierson, Margaret; Allon, Gad; Federgruen, Awi
In this paper, we postulate a general class of price competition models with mixed multinomial logit demand functions under affine cost functions. In these models, the market is partitioned into a finite set of market segments. We characterize the equilibrium behavior of this class of models in the case where each product in the market is sold by a separate, independent firm. We identify a simple and very broadly satisfied condition under which a pure Nash equilibrium exists and the set of Nash equilibria coincides with the solutions of the system of first-order-condition equations, a property of essential importance to empirical studies. This condition specifies that in every market segment, each firm captures less than 50% of the potential customer population when pricing at a specific level that, under the condition, is an upper bound for a rational price choice for the firm irrespective of the competitors' prices. We show that under a somewhat stronger, but still broadly satisfied, version of the above condition, a unique equilibrium exists. We complete the picture by establishing the existence of a Nash equilibrium, indeed a unique Nash equilibrium, for markets with an arbitrary degree of concentration, under sufficiently tight price bounds. We discuss how our results extend to a continuum of customer types. A discussion of the multiproduct case is included. The paper concludes with a discussion of implications for structural estimation methods.</description><author>Aksoy-Pierson, Margaret; Allon, Gad; Federgruen, Awi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Alleviating the Patient's Price of Privacy Through a Partially Observable Waiting List</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sandikci, Burhaneddin; Maillart, Lisa M.; Schaefer, Andrew J.; Roberts, Mark S.
In the United States, end-stage liver disease patients join a waiting list and then make accept/reject decisions for transplantation as deceased-donor organs are offered to them over time. These decisions are largely influenced by the patient's prospect for future offers, which can be ascertained most accurately by knowing the entire composition of the waiting list. Under the current transplantation system, however, the United Network for Organ Sharing (UNOS), in an effort to strike a balance between privacy and transparency, only publishes an aggregated version of the waiting list. However, it is not clear whether the published information is good enough (compared with perfect information) to help patients make optimal decisions that maximize their individual life expectancies. We provide a novel model of this accept/reject problem from an individual patient's perspective using a partially observed Markov decision process (POMDP) framework, which incorporates the imperfect waiting list information as published currently into the patient's decision making. We analyze structural properties of this model. In particular, we establish conditions that guarantee a monotone value function and a threshold-type optimal policy with respect to the partially observable rank state that captures the imperfect waiting list information. Furthermore, we develop an improved solution methodology to solve a generic POMDP model. This solution method guarantees, for any fixed grid, the best possible approximation to the optimal value function by solving linear programs to compute the optimal weights used for the approximation. Finally, we compare, in a clinically driven numerical study, the results of this model with those of an existing Markov decision process model that differs from our model in assuming the availability of perfect waiting list information. This comparison allows us to assess the quality of the published imperfect information as measured by a patient's so-called price of privacy (i.e., the opportunity loss in expected life days due to a lack of perfect waiting list information). Previous work estimates a significant loss in a patient's life expectancy, on average, when the patient has no waiting list information compared with full information. In this paper, we find that the currently published partial information is nearly sufficient to eliminate this loss, resulting in a negligible price of privacy and supporting current UNOS practice.</description><author>Sandikci, Burhaneddin; Maillart, Lisa M.; Schaefer, Andrew J.; Roberts, Mark S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Are Investors Willing to Pay to Customize Their Investment Product?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vrecko, Dennis; Langer, Thomas
Even though buy-and-hold (B&amp;H) investment strategies can take the risk tolerance of an investor into account by specifying a suitable stock proportion, the outcome profiles of B&amp;H strategies are restricted to a specific class of return distributions. For investors with particular risk preferences, further customization should thus provide additional value. The objective of this paper is to investigate the strength of preference for such customized distributions and to draw conclusions about the demand for personalized investment products. In two experimental studies, 256 participants could adjust the return distribution of an initially chosen B&amp;H investment by using an interactive software program. Our main finding is that most investors make extensive use of the customization option and many are willing to pay a substantial fee for this additional flexibility. We further find that the willingness to pay for customization is lower if the fee is integrated into the display of the return distribution, making its impact on final returns more obvious. We also observe that investors can be clustered into distinct subgroups via their adjustment patterns, but individually elicited prospect theory parameters are barely able to explain and predict these adjustments. As a robustness check, we also survey real investors at an investors fair to compare their preferences with those of our main pool of student subjects. We find that the willingness to pay for customization is slightly lower for these real investors and the main effect of fee integration is also less pronounced. In summary, we observe a strong willingness to pay for additional flexibility even though the actual benefits of customization vary markedly according to the individual. In many cases the accepted fees are so high that standard B&amp;H strategies stochastically dominate the customized distributions after fee integration.</description><author>Vrecko, Dennis; Langer, Thomas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consideration Set Formation with Multiproduct Firms: The Case of Within-Firm and Across-Firm Evaluation Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Lin; Dukes, Anthony
We consider a theoretical setting in which firms carry multiple products and consumers incur evaluation costs not only across firms but also within firms. Consumers judiciously decide the number of firms to include in their consideration sets as well as how many products from those firms. This decision depends on the relative trade-offs of evaluating an additional product and whether it is from a firm already included in the consideration set or from an entirely new firm. The composition of consumers' consideration set affects how firms compete in prices and in the number of products to offer. Contrary to previous literature, we find that firm differentiation can reduce firms' product lines and within-firm evaluation costs have either a positive or a negative effect on firms' prices. Interestingly, we show that within-firm evaluation costs and across-firm evaluation costs are different constructs. The number of products firms offer in equilibrium can exceed the socially optimal level if within-firm evaluation costs are significant.</description><author>Liu, Lin; Dukes, Anthony</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Hedge Funds Outperform Stocks and Bonds?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Brown, Stephen J.; Demirtas, K. Ozgur
H edge funds' extensive use of derivatives, short selling, and leverage and their dynamic trading strategies create significant nonnormalities in their return distributions. Hence, the traditional performance measures fail to provide an accurate characterization of the relative strength of hedge fund portfolios. This paper uses the utility-based nonparametric and parametric performance measures to determine which hedge fund strategies outperform the U. S. equity and/or bond markets. The results from the realized and simulated return distributions indicate that the long/short equity hedge and emerging markets hedge fund strategies outperform the U. S. equity market, and the long/short equity hedge, multistrategy, managed futures, and global macro hedge fund strategies dominate the U.S. Treasury market.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Brown, Stephen J.; Demirtas, K. Ozgur</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mixed Bundling in Two-Sided Markets in the Presence of Installed Base Effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chao, Yong; Derdenger, Timothy
We analyze mixed bundling in two-sided markets where installed base effects are present and find that the pricing structure deviates from traditional bundling as well as the standard two-sided markets literature-we determine prices on both sides fall with bundling. Mixed bundling acts as a price discrimination tool segmenting the market more efficiently. Consequently, as a by-product of this price discrimination, the two sides are better coordinated, and social welfare is enhanced. We show unambiguously that platform participations increase on both sides of the market. After theoretically evaluating the impact mixed bundling has on prices and welfare, we take the model predictions to data from the portable video game console market. We find empirical support for all theoretical predictions.</description><author>Chao, Yong; Derdenger, Timothy</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Implications of Hyperbolic Discounting for Optimal Pricing and Scheduling of Unpleasant Services That Generate Future Benefits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Plambeck, Erica L.; Wang, Qiong
People tend to lack the self-control to undergo an unpleasant service that would generate future benefits. This paper derives a tractable quasi-hyperbolic discounting model of that behavioral tendency (for a queueing system in which service time is short relative to the time horizon for its benefits). Planning in advance, people may naively overestimate their self-control. This paper shows how customers' lack of self-control and naivete affect optimal pricing and scheduling. The welfare-maximizing usage fee and the revenue-maximizing usage fee decrease with customers' lack of self-control. Charging for subscription, in addition to or instead of per use, increases revenue, especially when subscribers are naive. If the manager can charge for subscription or per use, subscription is optimal for revenue maximization, whereas usage-based pricing is optimal for welfare maximization. If customers are heterogeneous in their self-control and naivete, priority scheduling can dramatically increase welfare and revenue.</description><author>Plambeck, Erica L.; Wang, Qiong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ethnic Innovation and US Multinational Firm Activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foley, C. Fritz; Kerr, William R.
This paper studies the impact that ethnic innovators have on the global activities of U.S. firms by analyzing I detailed data on patent applications and on the operations of the foreign affiliates of U.S. multinational firms. The results indicate that increases in the share of a firm's innovation performed by inventors of a particular ethnicity are associated with increases in the share of that firm's affiliate activity in countries related to that ethnicity Ethnic innovators also appear to facilitate the disintegration of innovative activity across borders and to allow U.S. multinationals to form new affiliates abroad without the support of local joint venture partners.</description><author>Foley, C. Fritz; Kerr, William R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shouting to Be Heard in Advertising</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Simon P.; de Palma, Andre
Advertising competes for scarce consumer attention, so more profitable advertisers send more messages to break through the others' clutter. Multiple equilibria can arise: more messages in aggregate induce more "shouting to be heard," dissipating profit. Equilibria can involve a small range of loud shouters or large range of quiet whisperers. All advertisers prefer there to be less shouting. There is the largest diversity in message levels for a middling width of advertiser types: both very wide and very narrow widths have only one message per advertiser. The number of advertisers at each message level decreases with the level if the profit distribution is log-convex. Increasing the cost of sending messages can make all advertisers better off. A new technique is given for describing multiple equilibria, by determining how much examination is consistent with a given marginal advertiser.</description><author>Anderson, Simon P.; de Palma, Andre</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Pooling Purchases Lead to Higher Profits?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Bin; Duenyas, Izak; Beil, Damian R.
Consider two buyers facing uncertain demands who need to purchase a common critical component from a powerful sole-source supplier. If the two buyers pool their demands and purchase from the supplier as a single entity, will they necessarily earn higher profits than purchasing separately? We show that when a powerful supplier extracts profits from the buyers through optimal contract design, the demand variability reduction achieved by pooling can harm the buyers because it makes extracting profits easier for the supplier. We characterize cases when pooling is disadvantageous and also provide insights into when it is still advantageous. Our result is in contrast to the case where the price of the component is exogenous (typically assumed in most of the pooling literature), in which case pooling demands is always beneficial for the buyers.</description><author>Hu, Bin; Duenyas, Izak; Beil, Damian R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is It Better to Average Probabilities or Quantiles?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lichtendahl, Kenneth C.; Grushka-Cockayne, Yael; Winkler, Robert L.
We consider two ways to aggregate expert opinions using simple averages: averaging probabilities and averaging quantiles. We examine analytical properties of these forecasts and compare their ability to harness the wisdom of the crowd. In terms of location, the two average forecasts have the same mean. The average quantile forecast is always sharper: it has lower variance than the average probability forecast. Even when the average probability forecast is overconfident, the shape of the average quantile forecast still offers the possibility of a better forecast. Using probability forecasts for gross domestic product growth and inflation from the Survey of Professional Forecasters, we present evidence that both when the average probability forecast is overconfident and when it is underconfident, it is outperformed by the average quantile forecast. Our results show that averaging quantiles is a viable alternative and indicate some conditions under which it is likely to be more useful than averaging probabilities.</description><author>Lichtendahl, Kenneth C.; Grushka-Cockayne, Yael; Winkler, Robert L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Market Competition, Managerial Compensation, and Firm Size in Market Equilibrium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Subramanian, Ajay
We develop a tractable equilibrium model of competing firms in an industry to show how the distribution of firm qualities, moral hazard, and product market characteristics interact to affect firm size, managerial compensation, and market structure. Different determinants of product market competition have contrasting effects on firm size and managerial compensation. Although both firm size and managerial compensation increase with the entry cost, they increase with the elasticity of substitution if and only if firm size exceeds a high threshold but decrease if it is below a low threshold. Aggregate shocks to the firm productivity distribution affect incentives in our equilibrium framework. We show statistically and economically significant empirical support for several hypotheses derived from the theory that relates product market characteristics to managerial compensation, firm size, and the number of firms in the industry Different determinants of competition indeed have contrasting effects, as predicted by the theory.</description><author>Subramanian, Ajay</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Guilt by Association: Strategic Failure Prevention and Recovery Capacity Investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Sang-Hyun; Tomlin, Brian
We examine technological systems that display the following characteristics: (i) unplanned outages incur significant costs, (ii) the system experiences an outage if one or more of its subsystems fails, (iii) subsystem failures may occur simultaneously, and (iv) subsystem recovery requires specific resources and capabilities that are provided by different firms. Firms may invest in two measures to enhance system availability namely, failure prevention and recovery capacity. If recovery capacity investment is the only option, we find that the firms in a decentralized setting overinvest in capacity resulting in higher system availability but at a higher cost. If both investments can be made, we find that the firms underinvest in failure prevention and overinvest in recovery capacity That is, firms in a decentralized setting shift their focus from preventing failures to responding to failures. The net effect is lower system availability reversing the conclusion above. We also find that, unexpectedly, firms are more willing to let their subsystems fail if a joint failure is more likely to occur.</description><author>Kim, Sang-Hyun; Tomlin, Brian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Game-Theoretic Model of International Influenza Vaccination Coordination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mamani, Hamed; Chick, Stephen E.; Simchi-Levi, David
Influenza vaccination decisions in one country can influence the size of an outbreak in other countries due to interdependent risks from infectious disease transmission. This paper examines the inefficiency in the allocation of influenza vaccines that is due to interdependent risk of infection across borders and proposes a contractual mechanism to reduce such inefficiencies. The proposed contract is based on an epidemic model that accounts for intranational transmission and that from a source country where the dominant strain emerges. The contract reduces the overall financial burden of infection globally and improves the total number infected by seasonal influenza outbreaks. This is consistent with recent recommendations to improve pandemic preparedness. Numerical experiments demonstrate that the benefits of the contract can prevent millions of influenza cases and save tens of millions of dollars, and that the benefits are even greater when cross-border transmission is higher, even if cross-border transmission parameters have moderate estimation errors.</description><author>Mamani, Hamed; Chick, Stephen E.; Simchi-Levi, David</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrepreneurs Under Uncertainty: An Economic Experiment in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holm, Hakan J.; Opper, Sonja; Nee, Victor
This study reports findings from the first large-scale experiment investigating whether entrepreneurs differ 1 from other people in their willingness to expose themselves to various forms of uncertainty. A stratified random sample of 700 chief executive officers from the Yangzi delta region in China is compared to 200 control group members. Our findings suggest that in economic decisions, entrepreneurs are more willing to accept strategic uncertainty related to multilateral competition and trust. However, entrepreneurs do not differ from ordinary people when it comes to nonstrategic forms of uncertainty, such as risk and ambiguity.</description><author>Holm, Hakan J.; Opper, Sonja; Nee, Victor</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade Promotion Decisions Under Demand Uncertainty: A Market Experiment Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yuan, Hong; Gomez, Miguel I.; Rao, Vithala R.
In this paper, we examine trade promotion decisions in manufacturer-retailer channels where retailers face consumer demand uncertainty. We first present the theoretical analysis for two types of markets where trade promotion discounts are offered either as off-invoices or as scan-backs. We derive propositions by comparing wholesale and retail prices, retailer order quantities, and profits given the same trade promotion discount. Next, we extend the basic model so that the amount of trade promotion discount influences market expansion and solve for the optimal discount level. To test our theory, we then employ market experiments where we manipulate demand uncertainty and market expansion. Consistent with our theoretical predictions, we find that wholesale and retail prices are higher and retailer order quantities lower when the same amount of trade promotion discount is allocated to scan-backs versus off-invoices. In the market expansion condition, we find that manufacturers offer deeper discounts when trade promotions are allocated to off-invoices versus scan-backs. Overall, our research suggests that market experiments can shed light on trade promotion outcomes for which industry data are sparse or nonexistent.</description><author>Yuan, Hong; Gomez, Miguel I.; Rao, Vithala R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Loser's Curse: Decision Making and Market Efficiency in the National Football League Draft</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massey, Cade; Thaler, Richard H.
A question of increasing interest to researchers in a variety of fields is whether the biases found in judgment and decision-making research remain present in contexts in which experienced participants face strong economic incentives. To investigate this question, we analyze the decision making of National Football League teams during their annual player draft. This is a domain in which monetary stakes are exceedingly high and the opportunities for learning are rich. It is also a domain in which multiple psychological factors suggest that teams may overvalue the chance to pick early in the draft. Using archival data on draft-day trades, player performance, and compensation, we compare the market value of draft picks with the surplus value to teams provided by the drafted players. We find that top draft picks are significantly overvalued in a manner that is inconsistent with rational expectations and efficient markets, and consistent with psychological research.</description><author>Massey, Cade; Thaler, Richard H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring the Effect of Queues on Customer Purchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lu, Yina; Musalem, Andres; Olivares, Marcelo; Schilkrut, Ariel
We conduct an empirical study to analyze how waiting in queue in the context of a retail store affects customers' purchasing behavior. Our methodology combines a novel data set with periodic information about the queuing system (collected via video recognition technology) with point-of-sales data. We find that waiting in queue has a nonlinear impact on purchase incidence and that customers appear to focus mostly on the length of the queue, without adjusting enough for the speed at which the line moves. An implication of this finding is that pooling multiple queues into a single queue may increase the length of the queue observed by customers and thereby lead to lower revenues. We also find that customers' sensitivity to waiting is heterogeneous and negatively correlated with price sensitivity, which has important implications for pricing in a multiproduct category subject to congestion effects.</description><author>Lu, Yina; Musalem, Andres; Olivares, Marcelo; Schilkrut, Ariel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Emergence of Opinion Leaders in a Networked Online Community: A Dyadic Model with Time Dynamics and a Heuristic for Fast Estimation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lu, Yingda; Jerath, Kinshuk; Singh, Param Vir
We study the drivers of the emergence of opinion leaders in a networked community where users establish links to others, indicating their "trust" for the link receiver's opinion. This leads to the formation of a network, with high in-degree individuals being the opinion leaders. We use a dyad-level proportional hazard model with time-varying covariates to model the growth of this network. To estimate our model, we use Weighted Exogenous Sampling with Bayesian Inference, a methodology that we develop for fast estimation of dyadic models on large network data sets. We find that, in the Epinions network, both the widely studied "preferential attachment" effect based on the existing number of inlinks (i.e., a network-based property of a node) and the number and quality of reviews written (i.e., an intrinsic property of a node) are significant drivers of new incoming trust links to a reviewer (i.e., inlinks to a node). Interestingly, we find that time is an important moderator of these effects-intrinsic node characteristics are a stronger short-term driver of additional inlinks, whereas the preferential attachment effect has a smaller impact but it persists for a longer time. Our novel insights have important managerial implications for the design of online review communities.</description><author>Lu, Yingda; Jerath, Kinshuk; Singh, Param Vir</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Designing Buyback Contracts for Irrational But Predictable Newsvendors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker-Peth, Michael; Katok, Elena; Thonemann, Ulrich W.
One of the main assumptions in research on designing supply contracts is that decision makers act in a way that maximizes their expected profit. A number of laboratory experiments demonstrate that this assumption does not hold. Specifically, faced with uncertain demand, decision makers place orders that systematically deviate from the expected profit maximizing levels. We have added to this body of knowledge by demonstrating that ordering decisions also systematically depend on individual contract parameters and by developing a behavioral model that captures this systematic behavior. We proceed to test our behavioral model using laboratory experiments and use the data to derive empirical model parameters. We then test our approach in out-of-sample validation experiments that confirm that, indeed, contracts designed using the behavioral model perform better than contracts designed using the standard model.</description><author>Becker-Peth, Michael; Katok, Elena; Thonemann, Ulrich W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is There One Unifying Concept of Utility? An Experimental Comparison of Utility Under Risk and Utility Over Time</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abdellaoui, Mohammed; Bleichrodt, Han; l'Haridon, Olivier; Paraschiv, Corina
The nature of utility is controversial. Whereas decision theory commonly assumes that utility is context specific, applied and empirical decision analysis typically assumes one unifying concept of utility applicable to all decision problems. This controversy has hardly been addressed empirically because of the absence of methods to measure utility outside the context of risk. We introduce a method to measure utility over time and compare utility under risk and utility over time. We distinguish between gains and losses and also measure loss aversion. In two experiments we found that utility under risk and utility over time differed and were uncorrelated. Utility under risk was more curved than utility over time. Subjects were loss averse both for risk and for time, but loss aversion was more pronounced for risk. Loss aversion over risk and time were uncorrelated. This suggests that loss aversion, although important in both decision contexts, is volatile and subject to framing.</description><author>Abdellaoui, Mohammed; Bleichrodt, Han; l'Haridon, Olivier; Paraschiv, Corina</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insiders' Sales Under Rule 10b5-1 Plans and Meeting or Beating Earnings Expectations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shon, John; Veliotis, Stanley
We find that firms with insider sales executed under Rule 10b5-1 plans exhibit a higher likelihood of meeting or beating analysts' earnings expectations (MBE). This relation between MBE and plan sales is more pronounced for the plan sales of chief executive officers (CEOs) and chief financial officers (CEOs) and is nonexistent for other key insiders. The market reactions to firms that successfully meet or beat expectations are relatively positive compared with their peers that fail to do so. One interpretation of our results is that CEOs and CFOs who sell under these plans may be more likely to engage in strategic behavior to meet or beat expectations in an effort to maximize their proceeds from plan sales. However, readers should exercise caution in making inferences, because the potential presence of limit order transactions makes it difficult to unambiguously determine the direction of causality of the relation we document.</description><author>Shon, John; Veliotis, Stanley</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Customers Learn from Experience? Evidence from Retail Banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ater, Itai; Landsman, Vardit
We study customers' adoption and subsequent switching decisions with regard to a menu of three-part tariff plans offered by a commercial bank. Using a rich panel data set covering 70,510 fee-based checking accounts over 30 months, before and after the introduction of the plans, we find that most customers adopt non-cost-minimizing plans, preferring plans with large monthly allowances and high fixed payments. Furthermore, after adoption, customers who exceed their allowances and consequently pay overage fees are more likely to switch to plans with larger allowances than customers who do not experience such fees. Notably, after switching, these overage-paying customers pay higher monthly payments than before. In contrast, switching customers who did not pay overage payments before switching pay less after switching. Our findings, unlike those of previous research on experience-based learning, suggest that the behavior of experienced customers does not converge to the predictions of neoclassical models. We propose that "overage aversion,"which is closely related to loss aversion and mental accounting, is the most plausible explanation for our findings.</description><author>Ater, Itai; Landsman, Vardit</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset-Pricing Implications of Dividend Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Yan; Yang, Liyan
This paper establishes dividend volatility as a fundamental risk metric that prices assets. We theoretically incorporate dividend volatility clustering into a model in which narrow-framing investors are loss averse over fluctuations in the value of their investments. Our model shows that dividend volatility positively predicts future asset returns, with the predictive power increasing with the forecasting horizon; our model also sheds light on a variety of other asset-pricing phenomena. We further provide supporting empirical evidence that dividend volatility is indeed priced in the data. More specifically, aggregate dividend volatility predicts and is predicted by aggregate price-to-dividend ratios; aggregate dividend volatility predicts future aggregate market returns; and dividend volatility of portfolios sorted by size, book-to-market ratios, and past returns predicts future portfolio-level returns, respectively.</description><author>Li, Yan; Yang, Liyan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inventory Management for an Assembly System Subject to Supply Disruptions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeCroix, Gregory A.
We consider an assembly system with a single end product and a general assembly structure, where one or more of the component suppliers or (sub)assembly production processes is subject to random supply disruptions. We present a method for reducing the system to an equivalent system with some subsystems replaced by a series structure. This reduction simplifies the computation of optimal ordering policies and can also allow for comparison of disruption impacts across systems with different supply chain structures. We identify conditions under which a state-dependent echelon base-stock policy is optimal. Based on this result, we propose a heuristic policy for solving the assembly system with disruptions and test its performance in numerical trials. Using additional numerical trials, we explore a variety of strategic questions. For example, contrary to what is typically observed in systems without disruptions, we find that choosing a supplier with a longer lead time can sometimes yield lower system costs. We also find that backup supply is more valuable for a supplier with a shorter lead time than one with a longer lead time. In addition, because of component complementarities, we find that choosing suppliers whose disruptions are perfectly correlated yields lower system costs than choosing suppliers whose disruptions are independent, in contrast to the strategy that is typically preferred when choosing backup suppliers for a single product.</description><author>DeCroix, Gregory A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price-Quoting Strategies of an Upstream Supplier</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Bin; Beil, Damian R.; Duenyas, Izak
This paper studies an upstream supplier who quotes prices for a key component to multiple sellers that compete for an end-buyer's indivisible contract. At most one of the supplier's quotes may result in downstream contracting and hence produce revenue for her. We characterize the supplier's optimal price-quoting strategies and show that she will use one of two possible types of strategies, with her choice depending on the sellers' profit potentials relative to their uncertainties: secure, whereby she will always have business; or risky, whereby she may not have business. Addressing potential fairness concerns, we also study price-quoting strategies in which all sellers receive equal quotes. Finally, we show that the supplier's optimal mechanism resembles auctioning a single quote among the sellers. This paper can assist upstream suppliers in their pricing decisions and provides general insights into multitier supply chains' pricing dynamics.</description><author>Hu, Bin; Beil, Damian R.; Duenyas, Izak</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Risk Preferences in Pay-to-Bid Auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Platt, Brennan C.; Price, Joseph; Tappen, Henry
We analyze a new auction format in which bidders pay a fee each time they increase the auction price. Bidding fees are the primary source of revenue for the seller but produce the same expected revenue as standard auctions (assuming risk-neutral bidders). If risk-loving preferences are incorporated in the model, expected revenue increases. Our model predicts a particular distribution of ending prices, which we test against observed auction data. The degree of fit depends on how unobserved parameters are chosen; in particular, a slight preference for risk has the biggest impact in explaining auction behavior, suggesting that pay-to-bid auctions are a mild form of gambling.</description><author>Platt, Brennan C.; Price, Joseph; Tappen, Henry</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Organizational Decision Making: An Information Aggregation View</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Csaszar, Felipe A.; Eggers, J. P.
We study four information aggregation structures commonly used by organizations to evaluate opportunities: individual decision making, delegation to experts, majority voting, and averaging of opinions. Using a formal mathematical model, we investigate how the performance of each of these structures is contingent upon the breadth of knowledge within the firm and changes in the environment. Our model builds on work in the Carnegie tradition and in the group and behavioral decision-making literatures. We use the model to explore when delegation is preferable to other structures, such as voting and averaging. Our model shows that delegation is the most effective structure when there is diversity of expertise, when accurate delegation is possible, and when there is a good fit between the firm's knowledge and the knowledge required by the environment. Otherwise, depending on the knowledge breadth of the firm, voting or averaging may be the most effective structure. Finally, we use our model to shed light on which structures are more robust to radical environmental change and when crowd-based decision making may outperform delegation.</description><author>Csaszar, Felipe A.; Eggers, J. P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ad Revenue and Content Commercialization: Evidence from Blogs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Monic; Zhu, Feng
Many scholars argue that when incentivized by ad revenue, content providers are more likely to tailor their content to attract "eyeballs," and as a result, popular content may be excessively supplied. We empirically test this prediction by taking advantage of the launch of an ad-revenue-sharing program initiated by a major Chinese portal site in September 2007. Participating bloggers allow the site to run ads on their blogs and receive 50% of the revenue generated by these ads. After analyzing 4.4 million blog posts, we find that, relative to nonparticipants, popular content increases by about 13 percentage points on participants' blogs after the program takes effect. About 50% of this increase can be attributed to topics shifting toward three domains: the stock market, salacious content, and celebrities. Meanwhile, relative to nonparticipants, participants' content quality increases after the program takes effect. We also find that the program effects are more pronounced for participants with moderately popular blogs, and seem to persist after participants enroll in the program.</description><author>Sun, Monic; Zhu, Feng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Demand Uncertainty and Excess Supply in Commodity Contracting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Popescu, Dana G.; Seshadri, Sridhar
We examine how different characteristics of product demand and market impact the relative sales volume in the forward and spot markets for a commodity whose aggregate demand is uncertain. In a setting where either the forward contracts are binding quantity commitments between buyers and suppliers or the forward production takes place before the uncertainty in demand is resolved, we find that a combination of factors that include market concentration, demand risk, and price elasticity of demand will determine whether a commodity will be sold mainly through forward contracts or in the spot market. Previous findings in the literature show that when participants are risk neutral, the ratio of forward sales to spot sales is a function of market concentration alone; also, the lower the concentration, the higher this ratio. These findings hold under the assumption that demand is either deterministic or, if demand is uncertain, all production takes place after uncertainty is fully resolved and production plans can be altered instantaneously and costlessly. In our setting, however, we find that even a low level of demand risk can reverse the nature of supply in a highly competitive (low concentration) market, by shifting it from predominantly forward-driven to predominantly spot-driven supply. In markets with high concentration, the price elasticity of demand will determine whether the supply will be predominantly spot-driven or forward-driven. Our analysis suggests various new hypotheses on the structure of supply in commodity markets.</description><author>Popescu, Dana G.; Seshadri, Sridhar</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mixed Bundling of Two Independently Valued Goods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhargava, Hemant K.
This paper develops analytical results and insights for the mixed bundling problem of pricing a product line consisting of two component goods (with valuations distributed uniformly and independently in [0, a(1)] and [0, a(2)], respectively, with a(1) &lt; a(2)) and a bundle of the two goods. This setting has previously been considered analytically intractable. By deriving component good prices as exact algebraic functions of the optimal bundle price, I reduce the multiproduct pricing problem to a univariate nonlinear optimization problem in the bundle price. When the two component goods are sufficiently asymmetric in valuations, the optimal solution is partial mixed bundling (one component good is not sold separately), for which I derive exact conditions and optimal prices. An exact analytical solution is also given for mixed bundling of two information goods (component goods with zero marginal costs). For the general case, I derive a closed-form approximation of the optimal bundle price: P-B = 0.5724w(1) + 0.5695w(2) + 0.3516a(1) + 0.4889a(2) + 0.0054(a(2)/a(1))w(1)-0.0201(a(2)/a(1))w(2). The approximation is highly 'accurate (the resulting profit is within a percent of the exact optimal profit), efficient (instant solutions for specific problem instances), and useful in other applications where mixed bundling is a subproblem. I demonstrate this by applying the solution to the mixed bundle problem in a vertical channel where a retailer must bundle and price component goods from multiple independent manufacturers.</description><author>Bhargava, Hemant K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A "Meta-Analysis" of Multibrand, Multioutlet Channel Systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Eunkyu; Staelin, Richard; Yoo, Weon Sang; Du, Rex
In today's multibrand, multichannel marketplace, optimal channel design involves issues such as distribution intensity, channel exclusivity, vertical and horizontal coordination, and online offline mixed structures. We investigate how a firm's choice in these design issues affects its profitability under varying levels of brand and outlet differentiation. Our spatial model explicitly captures heterogeneous consumer preference for brand position, store location, and outlet type, under various consumer behavior assumptions. We apply this same underlying model to 10 different channel structures, deriving associated demand functions and equilibrium solutions. We perform a meta-analysis over the entire set of results to estimate a general model that summarizes the linkages among the factors shaping optimal channel structure decisions in a multibrand, multioutlet market. This general model efficiently describes the complex interactions of channel characteristics with industry structure and consumer characteristics, providing new findings as well as greater clarity to some results in the literature. A predictive analysis applied to additional channel structures exhibits strong generalizability in qualitative findings.</description><author>Lee, Eunkyu; Staelin, Richard; Yoo, Weon Sang; Du, Rex</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unpacking the Future: A Nudge Toward Wider Subjective Confidence Intervals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jain, Kriti; Mukherjee, Kanchan; Bearden, J. Neil; Gaba, Anil
Subjective probabilistic judgments in forecasting are inevitable in many real-life domains. A common way to obtain such judgments is to assess fractiles or confidence intervals. However, these judgments tend to be systematically overconfident. Further, it has proved particularly difficult to debias such forecasts and improve the calibration. This paper proposes a simple process that systematically leads to wider confidence intervals, thus reducing overconfidence. With a series of experiments, including with professionals, we show that unpacking the distal future into intermediate more proximal futures systematically improves calibration. We refer to this phenomenon as the time unpacking effect, find it is robust to different elicitation formats, and address the possible reasons behind it. We further show that this results in better overall forecasting performance when improved calibration is traded off against less sharpness, and that substantive benefits can be obtained even from just one level of time unpacking.</description><author>Jain, Kriti; Mukherjee, Kanchan; Bearden, J. Neil; Gaba, Anil</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Organization and Bargaining: Sales Process Choice at Auto Dealerships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bennett, Victor Manuel
This paper examines how firms' organizational form affects prices negotiated. Negotiated prices are one factor determining whether a vendor or customer captures the value from a transaction. Firms that systematically negotiate more effectively capture more value. Research has investigated individual- and market-level determinants of negotiation outcomes, but little has been done on the firm-level determinants of negotiated prices. I present a first look at one feature, sales process: whether salespeople handle the entire sale in parallel or customers begin with less experienced salespeople who can escalate difficult assignments. I model firms' choice of sales process as a biform game and test predictions of the model using a combination of transaction-level data on new car purchases in the United States and a unique survey of dealership management practices. I find that a serial process has implications consistent with improving firms' bargaining power and reducing customers' outside options.</description><author>Bennett, Victor Manuel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Geographic Constraints on Knowledge Spillovers: Political Borders vs. Spatial Proximity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Singh, Jasjit; Marx, Matt
Geographic localization of knowledge spillovers is a central tenet in multiple streams of research. However, prior work has typically examined this phenomenon considering only one geographic unit-country, state, or metropolitan area-at a time and has rarely accounted for spatial distance. We disentangle these multiple effects by using a regression framework employing choice-based sampling to estimate the likelihood of citation between random patents. We find both country and state borders to have independent effects on knowledge diffusion beyond what just geographic proximity in the form of metropolitan collocation or shorter within-region distances can explain. An identification methodology comparing inventor-added and examiner-added citation patterns points to an even stronger role of political borders. The puzzling state border effect remains robust on average across analyses, though it is found to have waned with time. The country effect has, in contrast, not only remained robust but even strengthened over time.</description><author>Singh, Jasjit; Marx, Matt</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contract Design with a Dominant Retailer and a Competitive Fringe</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kolay, Sreya; Shaffer, Greg
We show that under some conditions, quantity discounts and two-part tariffs are equivalent as mechanisms for channel coordination when an upstream firm sells its product in a downstream market that is characterized by a dominant retailer and a competitive fringe. We consider a setting in which discriminatory offers are feasible and a setting in which the same menu of options must be offered to all retailers. We find that the upstream firm's profit in both settings is independent of whether quantity discounts or two-part tariffs are used. The implication of this finding is that the firm's choice of contract design may turn on which one is easier to implement.</description><author>Kolay, Sreya; Shaffer, Greg</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Probability and Time Trade-Off</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baucells, Manel; Heukamp, Franz H.
Probability and time are integral dimensions of virtually any decision. To treat them together, we consider the prospect of receiving outcome x with a probability p at time t. We define risk and time distance, and show that if these two distances are traded off linearly, then preferences are characterized by three functions: a value function, a probability discount rate function, and a psychological distance function. The concavity of the psychological distance function explains the common ratio and common difference effects. A decreasing probability discount rate accounts for the magnitude effect. The discount rate and the risk premium depend on the shape of these three functions.</description><author>Baucells, Manel; Heukamp, Franz H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effect of Information Feedback on Bidder Behavior in Continuous Combinatorial Auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adomavicius, Gediminas; Curley, Shawn P.; Gupta, Alok; Sanyal, Pallab
Combinatorial auctions-in which bidders can bid on combinations of goods-can increase the economic efficiency of a trade when goods have complementarities. Recent theoretical developments have lessened the computational complexity of these auctions, but the issue of cognitive complexity remains an unexplored barrier for the online marketplace. This study uses a data-driven approach to explore how bidders react to the complexity in such auctions using three experimental feedback treatments. Using cluster analyses of the bids and the clicks generated by bidders, we find three stable bidder strategies across the three treatments. Further, these strategies are robust for separate experiments using a different setup. We also benchmark the continuous auctions against an iterative form of combinatorial auction-the combinatorial clock auction. The enumeration of the bidding strategies across different types of feedback, along with the analysis of their economic implications, is offered to help practitioners design better combinatorial auction environments.</description><author>Adomavicius, Gediminas; Curley, Shawn P.; Gupta, Alok; Sanyal, Pallab</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Forecasting Groups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lamberson, P. J.; Page, Scott E.
This paper characterizes the optimal composition of a group for making a combined forecast. In the model, individual forecasters have types defined according to a statistical criterion we call type coherence. Members of the same type have identical expected accuracy, and forecasters within a type have higher covariance than forecasters of different types. We derive the optimal group composition as a function of predictive accuracy, between- and within-type covariance, and group size. Group size plays a critical role in determining the optimal group: in small groups the most accurate type should be in the majority, whereas in large groups the type with the least within-type covariance should dominate.</description><author>Lamberson, P. J.; Page, Scott E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relicensing as a Secondary Market Strategy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oraiopoulos, Nektarios; Ferguson, Mark E.; Toktay, L. Beril
Secondary markets in the information technology industry, where used or refurbished equipment is traded, have been growing steadily. For original equipment manufacturers (OEMs) in this industry, the importance of secondary markets has grown in parallel, not only as a source of revenue, but also because of their impact on these firms' competitive advantage and market strategy. Recent articles in the press have severely criticized some OEMs who are perceived to be actively trying to eliminate the secondary market for their products. Other OEMs have policies that enhance their secondary markets. The goal of this paper is to understand how an OEM's incentives and optimal strategies vis-a-vis the secondary market are shaped contingent on her relative competitive advantage, product characteristics, and consumer preferences. The critical trade-off that we examine is whether the indirect benefit from maintaining an active secondary market (the resale value effect) can outweigh the potentially negative effect of the sales of used products at the expense of new product sales (the cannibalization effect). To that end, we develop a durable good model where the OEM can directly affect the resale value of her product through a relicensing fee charged to the buyer of the refurbished equipment. We analyze the OEM's strategy in both the monopoly and the duopoly cases, characterize the optimal relicensing fee set by the OEM, and draw conclusions on the conditions that favor stimulating or deterring the secondary market.</description><author>Oraiopoulos, Nektarios; Ferguson, Mark E.; Toktay, L. Beril</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Evaluation Costs in Strategic Factor Markets: The Implications for Competition and Organizational Design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ross, David Gaddis
This paper uses a formal model to study how evaluation costs affect competition for resources in strategic factor markets. It finds that relative scarcity may not always benefit resource sellers. Rather, when competition among resource investors passes a certain threshold intensity, miscoordination among investors increases to the point that sellers' expected profits decline. This paper extends the model to consider how investors organize to overcome managerial agency in resource evaluation. Two organizational designs are considered: (a) incentivization, wherein a lower-level manager is motivated by an incentive contract to evaluate resources for an investor, and (b) supervision, wherein evaluation is either handled directly or closely monitored by headquarters. The model suggests that competition among investors will be associated with a greater use of supervision and that investors using supervision will tend to make lower offers. This paper also finds that supervision will be more common when valuable resources are rare.</description><author>Ross, David Gaddis</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bias in White: A Longitudinal Natural Experiment Measuring Changes in Discrimination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rubineau, Brian; Kang, Yoon
Many professions are plagued by disparities in service delivery. Racial disparities in policing, mortgage lending, and healthcare are some notable examples. Because disparities can result from a myriad of mechanisms, crafting effective disparity mitigation policies requires knowing which mechanisms are active and which are not. In this study we can distinguish whether one mechanism-statistical discrimination-is a primary explanation for racial disparities in physicians' treatment of patients. In a longitudinal natural experiment using repeated quasi-audit studies of medical students, we test for within-cohort changes in disparities from medical student behaviors as they interact with white and black patient actors. We find significant increases in medical students' disparate behaviors by patient race between their first and second years of medical school. This finding is inconsistent with statistical discrimination predictions and challenges the idea that statistical discrimination is primarily responsible for racial disparities in patient care.</description><author>Rubineau, Brian; Kang, Yoon</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Now IT's Personal: Offshoring and the Shifting Skill Composition of the</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tambe, Prasanna; Hitt, Lorin M.
We combine new information technology (IT) offshoring and IT workforce microdata to investigate how the use of IT offshore captive centers is affecting the skill composition of the U. S. onshore IT workforce. The analysis is based on the theory that occupations involving tasks that are "tradable," such as tasks that require little personal communication or hands-on interaction with U. S.-based objects, are vulnerable to being moved offshore. Consistent with this theory, we find that firms that have offshore IT captive centers have 8% less of their onshore IT workforce involved in tradable occupations; those without offshore captive centers have increased the proportion of onshore employment in these same occupations by 3%. In addition, we find that hourly IT workers (e. g., IT contractors) are disproportionately employed in tradable jobs, and their onshore employment is 2%-3% lower in firms with offshore captive centers. These findings persist after considering different measures of employment composition, including controls for human capital, firm performance, domestic outsourcing, and whether firms choose to build or buy software. Instrumental variables and corroborating regressions suggest that our estimates are conservative-the magnitude of the effect generally rises after accounting for reverse causality and measurement error.</description><author>Tambe, Prasanna; Hitt, Lorin M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Broadening Focus: Spillovers, Complementarities, and Specialization in the Hospital Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clark, Jonathan R.; Huckman, Robert S.
The long-standing argument that focused operations outperform others stands in contrast to claims about the benefits of broader operational scope. The performance benefits of focus are typically attributed to reduced complexity, lower uncertainty, and the development of specialized expertise; the benefits of greater breadth are linked to the economies of scope achieved by sharing common resources, such as advertising or production capacity, across activities. Within the literature on corporate strategy, this tension between focus and breadth is reconciled by the concept of related diversification (i.e., a firm with multiple operating units, each specializing in distinct but related activities). We consider whether there are similar benefits to related diversification within an operating unit and examine the mechanism that generates these benefits. Using the empirical context of cardiovascular care within hospitals, we first examine the relationship between a hospital's level of specialization in cardiovascular care and the quality of its clinical performance on cardiovascular patients. We find that, on average, focus has a positive effect on quality performance. We then distinguish between positive spillovers and complementarities to examine (1) the extent to which a hospital's specialization in areas related to cardiovascular care directly impacts performance on cardiovascular patients (positive spillovers) and (2) whether the marginal benefit of a hospital's focus in cardiovascular care depends on the degree to which the hospital "cospecializes" in related areas (complementarities). In our setting, we find evidence of such complementarities in specialization.</description><author>Clark, Jonathan R.; Huckman, Robert S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local R&amp;D Strategies and Multilocation Firms: The Role of Internal Linkages</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alcacer, Juan; Zhao, Minyuan
This study looks at the role of internal linkages in highly competitive clusters. We argue that, in addition to serving as a mechanism for sourcing knowledge, strong internal linkages help firms increase internalization and create higher levels of technological interdependence across firm locations. Firms with strong networks of internal linkages are able to maintain tighter control over local innovation and reduce the risk that knowledge outflows will advantage competitors in clusters. Our empirical analysis of the global semiconductor industry shows that industry leaders intensify internal linkages across locations when they collocate with direct market competitors, but not when they collocate with innovators in the same technological field. We also find that internal linkages are associated with more knowledge flow within firms and less knowledge expropriation by collocated competitors. Our results suggest that future research in cluster innovation should consider the critical role of multilocation firms, their internal organization across clusters, and their responses to technological and market competition in clusters.</description><author>Alcacer, Juan; Zhao, Minyuan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Traditional and IS-Enabled Customer Acquisition on the Internet</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Jeonghye; Bell, David R.; Lodish, Leonard M.
Geographic variation in consumer use of Internet retailers is partly explained by variation in offline shopping costs. Explanations for geographic variation in the efficacy of different customer acquisition methods including traditional methods of offline word-of-mouth (WOM) and magazine advertising and information systems (IS)-enabled methods of online WOM and online search remain unexplored. We estimate a multivariate negative binomial distribution (NBD) model on zip code-level customer counts from a leading Internet retailer and provide new insights into factors explaining geographic variation in the success of these methods. First, we show that target customer density explains geographic variation over and above the impact due to the number of potential customers. Moreover, the effect of density is greatest for offline and online WOM acquisitions; this suggests that density contributes to contagion, connectivity, and a hypothesized "social multiplier." Second, when senders and recipients of WOM share consumption benefits, WOM is more powerful and compelling. We find that location-based convenience benefits have stronger effects on location-dependent offline WOM acquisitions than on location-independent online WOM acquisitions. Third, acquisition channels contribute differently to the total customer pool-offline WOM acquisitions are clustered, whereas magazine acquisitions are dispersed. Finally, separate click-to-conversion data from Coremetrics.com indicates that using the model-based predictions to target specific markets delivers a twofold improvement in actual click-to-order rates.</description><author>Choi, Jeonghye; Bell, David R.; Lodish, Leonard M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Impact of Performance-Based Contracting on Product Reliability: An Empirical Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guajardo, Jose A.; Cohen, Morris A.; Kim, Sang-Hyun; Netessine, Serguei
Using a proprietary data set provided by a major manufacturer of aircraft engines, we empirically investigate how product reliability is impacted by the use of two different types of after-sales maintenance support contracts: time and material contracts (T&amp;MC) and performance-based contracts (PBC). We offer a number of competing arguments based on the theory of incentives that establish why product reliability may increase or decrease under PBC. We build a two-stage econometric model that explicitly accounts for the endogeneity of contract choices, and find evidence of a positive and significant effect of PBC on product reliability. The estimation of our model indicates that product reliability is higher by 25%-40% under PBC compared to under T&amp;MC, once the endogeneity of contract choice is taken into account. Our results are consistent with two mechanisms for reliability improvement under PBC: more frequent scheduled maintenance and better care performed in each maintenance event.</description><author>Guajardo, Jose A.; Cohen, Morris A.; Kim, Sang-Hyun; Netessine, Serguei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Does the Variance of Product Ratings Matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Monic
This paper examines the informational role of product ratings. We build a theoretical model in which ratings can help consumers figure out how much they would enjoy the product. In our model, a high average rating indicates a high product quality, whereas a high variance of ratings is associated with a niche product, one that some consumers love and others hate. Based on its informational role, a higher variance would correspond to a higher subsequent demand if and only if the average rating is low. We find empirical evidence that is consistent with the theoretical predictions with book data from Amazon.com and BN.com. A higher standard deviation of ratings on Amazon improves a book's relative sales rank when the average rating is lower than 4.1 stars, which is true for 35% of all the books in our sample.</description><author>Sun, Monic</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>White Lies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erat, Sanjiv; Gneezy, Uri
In this paper we distinguish between two types of white lies: those that help others at the expense of the person telling the lie, which we term altruistic white lies, and those that help both others and the liar, which we term Pareto white lies. We find that a large fraction of participants are reluctant to tell even a Pareto white lie, demonstrating a pure lie aversion independent of any social preferences for outcomes. In contrast, a non-negligible fraction of participants are willing to tell an altruistic white lie that hurts them a bit but significantly helps others. Comparing white lies to those where lying increases the liar's payoff at the expense of another reveals important insights into the interaction of incentives, lying aversion, and preferences for payoff distributions. Finally, in line with previous findings, women are less likely to lie when it is costly to the other side. Interestingly though, we find that women are more likely to tell an altruistic lie.</description><author>Erat, Sanjiv; Gneezy, Uri</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing an Available-to-Promise Assembly System with Dynamic Short-Term Pseudo-Order Forecast</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Long; Xu, Susan H.; Ball, Michael O.
We study an order promising problem in a multiclass, available-to-promise (ATP) assembly system in the presence of pseudo orders. A pseudo order refers to a tentative customer order whose attributes, such as the likelihood of an actual order, order quantity, and confirmation timing, can change dynamically over time. A unit demand from any class is assembled from one manufactured unit and one inventory unit, where the manufactured unit takes one unit of capacity and needs a single period to produce. An accepted order must be filled before a positive delivery lead time. The underlying order acceptance decisions involve trade-offs between committing resources (production capacity and component inventory) to low-reward firm orders and reserving resources for high-reward orders. We develop a Markov chain model that captures the key characteristics of pseudo orders, including demand lumpiness, nonstationarity, and volatility. We then formulate a stochastic dynamic program for the ATP assembly system that embeds the Markov chain model as a short-term forecast for pseudo orders. We show that the optimal order acceptance policy is characterized by class prioritization, resource-imbalance-based rationing, and capacity-inventory-demand matching. In particular, the rationing level for each class is determined by a critical value that depends on the resource imbalance level, defined as the net difference between the production capacity and component inventory levels. Extensive numerical tests underscore the importance of the key properties of the optimal policy and provide operational and managerial insights on the value of the short-term demand forecast and the robustness of the optimal policy.</description><author>Gao, Long; Xu, Susan H.; Ball, Michael O.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling Purchasing Behavior with Sudden "Death": A Flexible Customer Lifetime Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bemmaor, Albert C.; Glady, Nicolas
T his study proposes a new customer lifetime model: the gamma/Gompertz distribution (G/G). The advantage of this model relative to the well-known Pareto distribution is twofold: (i) its probability density function can exhibit a mode at zero or an interior mode, and (ii) it can be skewed to the right or to the left. We combine the G/G with a negative binomial distribution (NBD) and obtain the moments of the distribution of the number of transactions over (0, T] and (T, T + T*]. Out of six data sets, the G/G/NBD model provides a notable improvement in the log-likelihood over the Pareto/NBD model in four data sets. It can indicate substantial differences in expected residual lifetimes compared to the Pareto/NBD and induce a retention rather than acquisition policy. On the average, the G/G/NBD exhibits slightly better forecasts of the mean number of transactions than the Pareto/NBD.</description><author>Bemmaor, Albert C.; Glady, Nicolas</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition Between Organizational Groups: Its Impact on Altruistic and Antisocial Motivations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goette, Lorenz; Huffman, David; Meier, Stephan; Sutter, Matthias
Firms are often organized into groups. Group membership has been shown empirically to have positive effects, in the form of increased prosocial behavior toward in-group members. This includes an enhanced willingness to engage in altruistic punishment of inefficient defection. Our paper provides evidence of a dark side of group membership. In the presence of cues of competition between groups, a taste for harming the out-group emerges: punishment ceases to serve a norm enforcement function, and instead, out-group members are punished harder and regardless of whether they cooperate or defect. Our results point to a mechanism that might help explain previous mixed results on the social value of punishment, and they contribute to understanding the sources of conflict between groups. They also point to an important trade-off for firms: introducing competition enhances within-group efficiency but also generates costly between-group conflict.</description><author>Goette, Lorenz; Huffman, David; Meier, Stephan; Sutter, Matthias</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hiring Cheerleaders: Board Appointments of "Independent" Directors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Lauren; Frazzini, Andrea; Malloy, Christopher J.
We provide evidence that firms appoint independent directors who are overly sympathetic to management, while still technically independent according to regulatory definitions. We explore a subset of independent directors for whom we have detailed, microlevel data on their views regarding the firm prior to being appointed to the board: sell-side analysts who are subsequently appointed to the boards of companies they previously covered. We find that boards appoint overly optimistic analysts who are also poor relative performers. The magnitude of the optimistic bias is large: 82.0% of appointed recommendations are strong buy/buy recommendations, compared with 56.9% for all other analyst recommendations. We also show that appointed analysts' optimism is stronger at precisely those times when firms' benefits are larger. Last, we find that appointing firms are more likely to have management on the board nominating committee, appear to be poorly governed, and increase earnings management and chief executive officer compensation following these board appointments.</description><author>Cohen, Lauren; Frazzini, Andrea; Malloy, Christopher J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Home Sweet Home: Entrepreneurs' Location Choices and the Performance of Their Ventures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahl, Michael S.; Sorenson, Olav
Entrepreneurs, even more than employees, tend to locate in regions in which they have deep roots ("home" regions). Here, we examine the performance implications of these choices. Whereas one might expect entrepreneurs to perform better in these regions because of their richer endowments of regionally embedded social capital, they might also perform worse if their location choices rather reflect a preference for spending time with family and friends. We examine this question using comprehensive data on Danish start-ups. Ventures perform better-survive longer and generate greater annual profits and cash flows-when located in regions in which their founders have lived longer. This effect appears substantial, similar in size to the value of prior experience in the industry (i.e., to being a spin-off).</description><author>Dahl, Michael S.; Sorenson, Olav</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Organizational Structure and the Limits of Knowledge Sharing: Incentive Conflict and Agency in Car Leasing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pierce, Lamar
This paper argues that conflicting incentives among managers may impede potential knowledge-sharing benefits from vertical integration. I study knowledge-based agency costs from vertical integration in car leasing, where manufacturer-owned captive lessors compete with independent lessors. Both organizational forms must acquire and integrate diffuse knowledge to accurately predict vehicle depreciation-a condition critical for profitability. Using a data set of 180,000 leases, I compare contracts of independent and captive lessors across car models, market conditions, and product life cycles. I find that managers in vertically integrated firms have conflicting incentives on whether to accurately and completely share proprietary knowledge, and show that these incentives appear to generate agency costs inconsistent with corporate profitability as managers selectively use and share knowledge for personal gain. The findings suggest that most knowledge benefits of vertical integration will be nullified when managerial interests are incompatible with the profit concerns of the firm.</description><author>Pierce, Lamar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Strategic Perils of Low Cost Outsourcing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feng, Qi; Lu, Lauren Xiaoyuan
The existing outsourcing literature has generally overlooked the cost differential and contract negotiations between manufacturers and suppliers (by assuming identical cost structures and adopting the Stackelberg framework). One fundamental question yet to be addressed is whether upstream suppliers' cost efficiency is always beneficial to downstream manufacturers in the presence of competition and negotiations. In other words, does low cost outsourcing always lead to a win-win outcome? To answer this question, we adopt a multiunit bilateral bargaining framework to investigate competing manufacturers' sourcing decisions. We analyze two supply chain structures: one-to-one channels, in which each manufacturer may outsource to an exclusive supplier; and one-to-two channels, in which each manufacturer may outsource to a common supplier. We show that, under both structures, low cost outsourcing may lead to a win-lose outcome in which the suppliers gain and the manufacturers lose. This happens because suppliers' cost advantage may backfire on competing manufacturers through two negative effects. First, a decrease of upstream cost weakens a manufacturer's bargaining position by reducing her disagreement payoff (i.e., her insourcing profit) because the competing manufacturer can obtain a low cost position through outsourcing. Second, in one-to-two channels, the common supplier's bargaining position is strengthened with a lower cost because his disagreement payoff increases (i.e., his profit from serving only one manufacturer increases). The endogeneity of disagreement payoffs in our model highlights the importance of modeling firm negotiations under competition. Moreover, we identify an interesting bargaining externality between competing manufacturers when they outsource to a common supplier. Because the supplier engages in two negotiations, his share of profit from the trade with one manufacturer affects the total surplus of the trade with the other manufacturer. Because of this externality, surprisingly, as a manufacturer's bargaining power decreases, her profit under outsourcing may increase and it may be more likely for her to outsource.</description><author>Feng, Qi; Lu, Lauren Xiaoyuan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Evidence-Based Incentive System for Medicare's End-Stage Renal Disease Program</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Donald K. K.; Zenios, Stefanos A.
Recent legislations directed Medicare to revamp its decades-old system for reimbursing dialysis treatments, with focus on the risk adjustment of payments and on the transition toward a pay-for-compliance system. To design an optimal payment system that incorporates these features, we develop an empirical method to estimate the structural parameters of the principal-agent model underlying Medicare's dialysis payment system. We use the model and parameter estimates to answer the following questions: Can a pay-for-compliance system based only on the intermediate performance measures currently identified by Medicare achieve first-best? How should patient outcomes be risk adjusted, and what welfare gains can be achieved by doing so? Our main findings are as follows: (1) the current set of intermediate measures identified by Medicare are not comprehensive enough for use alone in a pay-for-compliance system; (2) paying for risk-adjusted downstream outcomes instead of raw downstream outcomes can lengthen the hospital-free life of admitted patients by two weeks per patient per year without increasing Medicare expenditures.</description><author>Lee, Donald K. K.; Zenios, Stefanos A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reconceptualizing Stars: Scientist Helpfulness and Peer Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oettl, Alexander
It is surprising that the prevailing performance taxonomy for scientists (star versus nonstar) focuses only on individual output and ignores social behavior, because innovation is often characterized as a communal process. To develop a deeper understanding of the mechanisms by which scientists influence the productivity of others, I expand the traditional taxonomy of scientists that focuses solely on productivity and add a second, social dimension: helpfulness to others. Using a combination of academic paper publications and citations to capture scientist productivity and the receipt of academic paper acknowledgments to measure helpfulness, I examine the change in publishing output of the coauthors of 149 scientists that die. Coauthors of highly helpful scientists that die experience a decrease in output quality but not output quantity. Meanwhile, the deaths of high productivity scientists that are not highly helpful do not influence their coauthors' output. In addition, scientists who are helpful with conceptual feedback (critique and advice) have a larger impact on the performance of their coauthors than scientists who provide help with material access, scientific tools, or technical work. Within the context of evaluating scientific productivity, it may be time to update our conceptualization of a "star."</description><author>Oettl, Alexander</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Specialization and Variety in Repetitive Tasks: Evidence from a Japanese Bank</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Staats, Bradley R.; Gino, Francesca
Sustaining operational productivity in the completion of repetitive tasks is critical to many organizations' success. Yet research points to two different work-design-related strategies for accomplishing this goal: specialization to capture the benefits of repetition and variety (i.e., working on different tasks) to keep workers motivated and provide them opportunities to learn. In this paper, we investigate how these two strategies may bring different productivity benefits over time. For our empirical analyses, we use two and a half years of transaction data from a Japanese bank's home loan application-processing line. We find that over the course of a single day, specialization, as compared to variety, is related to improved worker productivity. However, when we examine workers' experience across a number of days, we find that variety helps improve worker productivity. Additionally, we show that part of this benefit results from workers' cumulative experience with changeovers. Our results highlight the need for organizations to transform specialization and variety into mutually reinforcing strategies rather than treating them as mutually exclusive. Overall, our paper identifies new ways to improve operational performance through the effective allocation of work.</description><author>Staats, Bradley R.; Gino, Francesca</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Advance Selling When Consumers Regret</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nasiry, Jayad; Popescu, Ioana
We characterize the effect of anticipated regret on consumer decisions and on firm profits and policies in an advance selling context where buyers have uncertain valuations. Advance purchases trigger action regret if valuations turn out to be lower than the price paid, whereas delaying purchase may cause inaction regret from missing a discount or facing a stockout. Consumers whom we describe as emotionally rational act strategically in response to the firm's policies and in anticipation of regret. In this context, regret explains two types of behavioral patterns: inertia (delayed purchase) and frenzies (buying early at negative surplus). We show how firms should optimally respond to consumer regret and also characterize a normative regret threshold above which they should not advance sell. Action regret reduces profits as well as the value of advance selling and booking limit policies for price-setting firms; inaction regret has the opposite effects. These effects are diminished by capacity constraints and are reversed for firms facing price pressure in the advance period (owing, e.g., to competition or market heterogeneity). Regret heterogeneity explains premium advance selling for the capacity-constrained firm, which may benefit from larger shares of regretful buyers. Finally, we show how the negative effects of regret on profits can be mitigated by regret-priming marketing campaigns and by offering refunds or options or allowing resales. Our results highlight the importance of assessing the relative strength of regret within and across market segments and of accounting for these factors in pricing and marketing policies.</description><author>Nasiry, Jayad; Popescu, Ioana</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Double Marginalization in Performance-Based Advertising: Implications and Solutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dellarocas, Chrysanthos
An important current trend in advertising is the replacement of traditional pay-per-exposure (pay-per-impression) pricing models with performance-based mechanisms in which advertisers pay only for measurable actions by consumers. Such pay-per-action (PPA) mechanisms are becoming the predominant method of selling advertising on the Internet. Well-known examples include pay-per-click, pay-per-call, and pay-per-sale. This work highlights an important, and hitherto unrecognized, side effect of PPA advertising. I find that, if the prices of advertised goods are endogenously determined by advertisers to maximize profits net of advertising expenses, PPA mechanisms induce firms to distort the prices of their goods (usually upward) relative to prices that would maximize profits in settings where advertising is sold under pay-per-exposure methods. Upward price distortions reduce both consumer surplus and the joint publisher advertiser profit, leading to a net reduction in social welfare. They persist in current auction-based PPA mechanisms, such as the ones used by Google, Yahoo!, and Microsoft. In the latter settings they also reduce publisher revenues relative to pay-per-exposure methods. I show that these phenomena constitute a form of double marginalization and discuss a number of enhancements to today's PPA mechanisms that restore equilibrium pricing of advertised goods to efficient levels, improving both consumer surplus as well as the publisher's expected profits.</description><author>Dellarocas, Chrysanthos</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Technology and Trademarks: Implications for Product Variety</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Guodong; Hitt, Lorin M.
This paper examines the relationship between information technology (IT) and trademarks. Using an 11-year panel data set (1987-1997) of IT capital Stock, trademark holdings, and other measures for 116 Fortune 1000 manufacturing firms, we find that IT contributes to higher trademark holdings. Further, we find evidence suggesting that firms with more IT capital tend to apply for more new trademarks and retire existing trademarks more quickly, leading to a shorter trademark life cycle. Because trademarks are mainly used by firms to communicate differences among similar products to the marketplace, these results suggest that the business value of IT can be realized in greater product variety.</description><author>Gao, Guodong; Hitt, Lorin M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Three-Way Complementarities: Performance Pay, Human Resource Analytics, and Information Technology</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aral, Sinan; Brynjolfsson, Erik; Wu, Lynn
We test for three-way complementarities among information technology (IT), performance pay, and human resource (HR) analytics practices. We develop a principal-agent model examining how these practices work together as an incentive system that produces a larger productivity premium when the practices are implemented in concert rather than separately. We assess our model by combining fine-grained data on human capital management (HCM) software adoption over 11 years with detailed survey data on incentive systems and HR analytics practices for 189 firms. We find that the adoption of HCM software is greatest in firms that have also adopted performance pay and HR analytics practices. Furthermore, HCM adoption is associated with a large productivity premium when it is implemented as a system of organizational incentives, but has less benefit when adopted in isolation. The system of three-way complements produces disproportionately greater benefits than pairwise interactions, highlighting the importance of including all three complements. Productivity increases significantly when the HCM systems "go live" but not when they are purchased, which can be years earlier. This helps rule out reverse causality as an explanation for our findings.</description><author>Aral, Sinan; Brynjolfsson, Erik; Wu, Lynn</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Transmission and the Bullwhip Effect: An Empirical Investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bray, Robert L.; Mendelson, Haim
The bullwhip effect is the amplification of demand variability along a supply chain: a company bullwhips if it purchases from suppliers more variably than it sells to customers. Such bullwhips (amplifications of demand variability) can lead to mismatches between demand and production and hence to lower supply chain efficiency. We investigate the bullwhip effect in a sample of 4,689 public U. S. companies over 1974-2008. Overall, about two-thirds of firms bullwhip. The sample's mean and median bullwhips, both significantly positive, respectively measure 15.8% and 6.7% of total demand variability. Put another way, the mean quarterly standard deviation of upstream orders exceeds that of demand by $20 million. We decompose the bullwhip by information transmission lead time. Estimating the bullwhip's information-lead-time components with a two-stage estimator, we find that demand signals firms observe with more than three-quarters' notice drive 30% of the bullwhip, and those firms observe with less than one-quarter's notice drive 51%. From 1974-1994 to 1995-2008, our sample's mean bullwhip dropped by a third.</description><author>Bray, Robert L.; Mendelson, Haim</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Signaling Quality via Queues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Debo, Laurens G.; Parlour, Christine; Rajan, Uday
We consider an M/M/1 queueing system with impatient consumers who observe the length of the queue before deciding whether to buy the product. The product may have high or low quality, and consumers are heterogeneously informed. The firm chooses a slow or (at a cost) a fast service rate. In equilibrium, informed consumers join the queue if it is below a threshold. The threshold varies with the quality of the good, so an uninformed consumer updates her belief about quality on observing the length of the queue. The strategy of an uninformed consumer has a "hole": she joins the queue at lengths both below and above the hole, but not at the hole itself. We show that if the prior probability the product has high quality and the proportion of informed consumers are both low, a high-quality firm may select a slower service rate than a low-quality firm. The queue can therefore be a valuable signaling device for a high-quality firm. Strikingly, in some scenarios, the high-quality firm may choose the slow service rate even if the technological cost of speeding up is zero.</description><author>Debo, Laurens G.; Parlour, Christine; Rajan, Uday</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational Herding in Microloan Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Juanjuan; Liu, Peng
Microloan markets allow individual borrowers to raise funding from multiple individual lenders. We use a unique panel data set that tracks the funding dynamics of borrower listings on Prosper.com, the largest microloan market in the United States. We find evidence of rational herding among lenders. Well-funded borrower listings tend to attract more funding after we control for unobserved listing heterogeneity and payoff externalities. Moreover, instead of passively mimicking their peers (irrational herding), lenders engage in active observational learning (rational herding); they infer the creditworthiness of borrowers by observing peer lending decisions and use publicly observable borrower characteristics to moderate their inferences. Counterintuitively, obvious defects (e.g., poor credit grades) amplify a listing's herding momentum, as lenders infer superior creditworthiness to justify the herd. Similarly, favorable borrower characteristics (e.g., friend endorsements) weaken the herding effect, as lenders attribute herding to these observable merits. Follow-up analysis shows that rational herding beats irrational herding in predicting loan performance.</description><author>Zhang, Juanjuan; Liu, Peng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Extroverted Firm: How External Information Practices Affect Innovation and Productivity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tambe, Prasanna; Hitt, Lorin M.; Brynjolfsson, Erik
We gather detailed data on organizational practices and information technology (IT) use at 253 firms to examine the hypothesis that external focus-the ability of a firm to detect and therefore respond to changes in its external operating environment-increases returns to IT, especially when combined with decentralized decision making. First, using survey-based measures, we find that external focus is correlated with both organizational decentralization, and IT investment. Second, we find that a cluster of practices including external focus, decentralization, and IT is associated with improved product innovation capabilities. Third, we develop and test a three-way complementarities model that indicates that the combination of external focus, decentralization, and IT is associated with significantly higher productivity in our sample. We also introduce a new set of instrumental variables representing barriers to IT-related organizational change and find that our results are robust when we account for the potential endogeneity of organizational investments. Our results may help explain why firms that operate in information-rich environments such as high-technology clusters or areas with high worker mobility have experienced especially high returns to IT investment and suggest a set of practices that some managers may be able to use to increase their returns from IT investments.</description><author>Tambe, Prasanna; Hitt, Lorin M.; Brynjolfsson, Erik</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When to "Fire" Customers: Customer Cost-Based Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shin, Jiwoong; Sudhir, K.; Yoon, Dae-Hee
The widespread adoption of activity-based costing enables firms to allocate common service costs to each customer, allowing for precise measurement of both the cost to serve a particular customer and the customer's profitability. In this paper, we investigate how pricing strategies based on customer cost information affects a firm's customer acquisition and retention dynamics, and ultimately its profit, using a two-period monopoly model with high-and low-cost customer segments. Although past purchase and cost information helps firms to increase profits through differential prices for good and bad customers in the second period ("price discrimination effect"), it can hurt firms because strategic forward-looking consumers may delay purchases to avoid higher future prices ("ratchet effect"). We find that when the customer cost heterogeneity is sufficiently large, it is optimal for firms to "fire" some of its high-cost customers, and customer cost-based pricing is profitable. Surprisingly, it is optimal to fire even some profitable customers. This result is robust even when the cost to serve is endogenous and determined by the consumer's choice of service level. We also shed insight on acquisition-retention dynamics, on when firms can improve their profitability by selectively firing known old "bad" customers, and on replacing the old "bad" customers with a mix of new "good" and "bad" customers.</description><author>Shin, Jiwoong; Sudhir, K.; Yoon, Dae-Hee</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamics of Rate-of-Return Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nezlobin, Alexander; Rajan, Madhav V.; Reichelstein, Stefan
Under rate-of-return regulation, a firm's product prices are constrained by the requirement that investors not earn more than an allowable return on the firm's assets. This paper examines the dynamic properties of the rate-of-return regulation process when the regulated firm periodically undertakes new capacity investments. Our analysis identifies prices that correspond to stationary values of the regulation process. It is shown that the underlying depreciation rules for property, plant, and equipment determine whether these stationary prices will be above, equal to, or below the long-run marginal cost of providing the regulated service. We provide conditions under which the rate-of-return regulation process is dynamically stable so that prices indeed converge to their stationary values. The overall efficiency of this regulation method is shown to depend on how well the applicable depreciation schedule matches the productivity pattern of the assets in use.</description><author>Nezlobin, Alexander; Rajan, Madhav V.; Reichelstein, Stefan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consistency Judgments, Embeddedness, and Relationship Outcomes in Interorganizational Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vinhas, Alberto Sa; Heide, Jan B.; Jap, Sandy D.
Past research has shown how outcomes in interorganizational relationships are influenced by the characteristics of the individual relationship in question. Focusing on relationships between suppliers and their organizational buyers, we augment this perspective by positing that relationship outcomes are also influenced by social comparison processes involving perceptions of a supplier's practices across comparable buyer relationships. Based on past research on embedded ties and institutional theory, we propose that the effect of these comparison processes depends on the nature of a buyer's existing interorganizational ties and on the norms that are brought to bear on the relationship in question. We test our propositions based on 788 observations of organizational buyers who have relationships with the same supplier. Our findings paint a complex, multilevel picture of the process by which relationship outcomes come about in interorganizational networks.</description><author>Vinhas, Alberto Sa; Heide, Jan B.; Jap, Sandy D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Sentiment and Analysts' Earnings Forecast Errors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hribar, Paul; McInnis, John
We correlate analysts' forecast errors with temporal variation in investor sentiment. We find that when sentiment is high, analysts' forecasts of one-year-ahead earnings and long-term earnings growth are relatively more optimistic for "uncertain" or "difficult-to-value" firms. Adding these forecast errors to a regression of stock returns on sentiment absorbs a sizable fraction of the explanatory power of sentiment for the cross section of future returns. This finding provides direct support for the notion that investor sentiment affects the earnings expectations of hard-to-value firms. Additional tests suggest that this bias in expectations is unlikely to be strategic in nature. Our results provide new insight into the mechanism through which investor sentiment affects returns.</description><author>Hribar, Paul; McInnis, John</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Party's Over: The Role of Earnings Guidance in Resolving Sentiment-Driven Overvaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Seybert, Nicholas; Yang, Holly I.
This paper shows that an important link between investor sentiment and firm. overvaluation is optimistic earnings expectations, and that management earnings guidance helps resolve sentiment-driven overvaluation. Using previously identified firm characteristics, we find that most of the negative returns to uncertain firms in months following high-sentiment periods fall within the three-day window around the issuance of management earnings guidance. Comparisons of guidance months to nonguidance months show that guidance issuance affects the magnitude and not just the daily distribution of negative returns. There is also some evidence of negative returns around earnings announcements for firms that previously issued guidance, suggesting that guidance does not entirely correct optimistic earnings expectations. To provide additional insight into the strength of the guidance effect, we show that the market reacts more strongly to surprises, particularly negative surprises, following high-sentiment periods. Finally, firms with higher transient institutional ownership are less likely to guide, and their guidance is less likely to contain bad news following high-sentiment periods, indicating that managers with a short-term focus are hesitant to correct optimistic market expectations.</description><author>Seybert, Nicholas; Yang, Holly I.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Accrual Anomaly: Risk or Mispricing?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, David; Hou, Kewei; Teoh, Siew Hong
We document considerable return comovement associated with accruals after controlling for other common factors. An accrual-based factor-mimicking portfolio has a Sharpe ratio of 0.16, higher than that of the market factor or the SMB and HML factors of Fama and French. According to rational frictionless asset pricing models, the ability of accruals to predict returns should come from the loadings on this accrual factor-mimicking portfolio. However, our tests indicate that it is the accrual characteristic rather than the accrual factor loading that predicts returns. These findings suggest that investors misvalue the accrual characteristic and cast doubt on the rational risk explanation.</description><author>Hirshleifer, David; Hou, Kewei; Teoh, Siew Hong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Madness? The Case of Mad Money</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engelberg, Joseph; Sasseville, Caroline; Williams, Jared
We use the popular television show Mad Money, hosted by Jim Cramer, to test theories of attention and limits to arbitrage. Stock recommendations on Mad Money constitute attention shocks to a large audience of individual traders. We find that stock recommendations lead to large overnight returns that subsequently reverse over the next few months. The spike-reversal pattern is strongest among small, illiquid stocks that are hard to arbitrage. Using daily Nielsen ratings as a direct measure of attention, we find that the overnight return is strongest when high-income viewership is high. We also find weak price effects among sell, recommendations. Taken together, the evidence supports the retail attention hypothesis of Barber and Odean (Barber, B., T. Odean. 2008. All that glitters: The effect of attention and news on the buying behavior of individual and institutional investors. Rev. Financial Stud. 21(2) 785-818) and illustrates the potential role of media in generating mispricing.</description><author>Engelberg, Joseph; Sasseville, Caroline; Williams, Jared</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bubbles and Information: An Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sutter, Matthias; Huber, Juergen; Kirchler, Michael
Asymmetric distribution of information, although omnipresent in real markets, is rarely considered in experimental economics. We study whether information about imminent future dividends can abate bubbles in experimental asset markets. We find that markets with asymmetrically informed traders have significantly smaller bubbles than markets with symmetrically informed or uninformed traders. Hence, fundamental values are better reflected in market prices-implying higher market efficiency-when some traders know more than others about future dividends. This suggests that bubbles are abated when traders know that a subset of them have an edge (in information) over others.</description><author>Sutter, Matthias; Huber, Juergen; Kirchler, Michael</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Initial Public Offerings as Lotteries: Skewness Preference and First-Day Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, T. Clifton; Hwang, Byoung-Hyoun
We find that initial public offerings (IPOs) with high expected skewness experience significantly greater first-day returns. The skewness effect is stronger during periods of high investor sentiment and is related to differences in skewness across industries as well as to time-series variation in the level of skewness in the market. IPOs with high expected skewness earn more negative abnormal returns in the following one to five years. High expected skewness is also associated with a higher fraction of small-sized trades on the first day of trading, which is consistent with a greater shift in holdings from institutions to individuals. The results suggest that first-day IPO returns are related to a preference for skewness.</description><author>Green, T. Clifton; Hwang, Byoung-Hyoun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Introduction to the Special Issue on Behavioral Economics and Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barber, Brad M.; Ho, Teck-Hua; Odean, Terrance
nan</description><author>Barber, Brad M.; Ho, Teck-Hua; Odean, Terrance</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Model of Casino Gambling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barberis, Nicholas
We show that prospect theory offers a rich theory of casino gambling, one that captures several features of actual gambling behavior. First, we demonstrate that for a wide range of preference parameter values, a prospect theory agent would be willing to gamble in a casino even if the casino offers only bets with no skewness and with zero or negative expected value. Second, we show that the probability weighting embedded in prospect theory leads to a plausible time inconsistency: at the moment he enters a casino, the agent plans to follow one particular gambling strategy; but after he starts playing, he wants to switch to a different strategy. The model therefore predicts heterogeneity in gambling behavior: how a gambler behaves depends on whether he is aware of the time inconsistency; and, if he is aware of it, on whether he can commit in advance to his initial plan of action.</description><author>Barberis, Nicholas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Personal Experience on Behavior: Evidence from Video-Rental Fines</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haselhuhn, Michael P.; Pope, Devin G.; Schweitzer, Maurice E.; Fishman, Peter
Personal experience matters. In a field setting with longitudinal data, we disentangle the effects of learning new information from the effects of personal experience. We demonstrate that experience with a fine, controlling for the effect of learning new information, significantly boosts future compliance. We also show that experience with a large fine boosts compliance more than experience with a small fine, but that the influence of experience with both large and small fines decays sharply over time.</description><author>Haselhuhn, Michael P.; Pope, Devin G.; Schweitzer, Maurice E.; Fishman, Peter</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Feedback, Self-Esteem, and Performance in Organizations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuhnen, Camelia M.; Tymula, Agnieszka
We examine whether private feedback about relative performance can mitigate moral hazard in competitive environments by modifying the agents' self-esteem. In our experimental setting, people work harder and expect to rank better when told that they may learn their ranking, relative to cases when feedback will not be provided. Individuals who ranked better than expected decrease output but expect a better rank in the future, whereas those who ranked worse than expected increase output but lower their future rank expectations. Feedback helps create a ratcheting effect in productivity, mainly because of the fight for dominance at the top of the rank hierarchy. Our findings suggest that organizations can improve employee productivity by changing the likelihood of feedback, the reference group used to calculate relative performance, and the informativeness of the feedback message.</description><author>Kuhnen, Camelia M.; Tymula, Agnieszka</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gender, Competition, and Managerial Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Price, Curtis R.
The purpose of this study is to investigate the use of competitive compensation between a manager and a worker in the laboratory. To this end, we impose a simple agency relationship between two groups of subjects termed managers and workers. The manager chooses a compensation scheme for the worker from either a piece rate or a tournament payment scheme and is paid based on the workers performance in the task. The results indicate that when given information about worker ability, male managers choose the tournament significantly less often for a female worker. On the other hand, when no information about worker ability is given to the manager, there is no difference in compensation choice for the worker, although male and female managers differ significantly in their own preferences for compensation scheme. We conjecture that these results are tied to the fact that there is a measurable stereotype that females are worse at the task relative to males, although further research is needed in this regard.</description><author>Price, Curtis R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aggregation and Manipulation in Prediction Markets: Effects of Trading Mechanism and Information Distribution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jian, Lian; Sami, Rahul
We conduct laboratory experiments on variants of market scoring rule prediction markets, under different information distribution patterns, to evaluate the efficiency and speed of information aggregation, as well as test recent theoretical results on manipulative behavior by traders. We find that markets structured to have a fixed sequence of trades exhibit greater accuracy of information aggregation than the typical form that has unstructured trade. In comparing two commonly used mechanisms, we find no significant difference between the performance of the direct probability-report form and the indirect security-trading form of the market scoring rule. In the case of the markets with a structured order, we find evidence supporting the theoretical prediction that information aggregation is slower when information is complementary. In structured markets, the theoretical prediction that there will be more delayed trading in complementary markets is supported, but we find no support for the prediction that there will be more bluffing in complementary markets. However, the theoretical predictions are not borne out in the unstructured markets.</description><author>Jian, Lian; Sami, Rahul</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Apologies as Signals: With Evidence from a Trust Game</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ho, Benjamin
Apologies are part of a social institution designed to restore frayed relationships not only in daily life but also in the domains of corporate governance, medical malpractice litigation, political reputation, organizational culture, etc. The theory shows that in a general class of moral hazard games with imperfect information about agents with two-dimensional type, apologies exhibit regular properties-e.g., apologies are more frequent in long relationships, early in relationships, and between better-matched partners. A variant of the trust game demonstrates that communication matters in a manner consistent with economic theory; specifically, the words "I am sorry" appear to select equilibrium behavior consistent with the theory's main predictions.</description><author>Ho, Benjamin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Imprecise Data Sets as a Source of Ambiguity: A Model and Experimental Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arad, Ayala; Gayer, Gabrielle
In many circumstances, evaluations are based on empirical data. However, some observations may be imprecise, meaning that it is not entirely clear what occurred in them. We address the question of how beliefs are formed in these situations. The individual in our model is essentially a "frequentist." He first makes a subjective judgment about the occurrence of the event for each imprecise observation. This may be any number between zero and one. He then evaluates the event by its "subjective" frequency of occurrence. Our model connects the method of processing imprecise observations with the individual's attitude toward ambiguity. An individual who in imprecise observations puts low (high) weight on the possibility that an event occurred is ambiguity averse (loving). An experiment supports the main assertions of the model: with precise data, subjects behave as if there were no ambiguity, whereas with imprecise data subjects turn out to be ambiguity averse.</description><author>Arad, Ayala; Gayer, Gabrielle</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prospect Theory, Liquidation, and the Disposition Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henderson, Vicky
There is a well-known intuition linking prospect theory with the disposition effect, the tendency of investors to sell assets that have risen in value rather than fallen. Recently, several authors have studied rigorous models in an attempt to formalize the intuition. However, some have found it difficult to predict a disposition effect while others produce a more extreme prediction where investors never voluntarily sell at a loss. We solve a model of asset liquidation where investors realize utility over gains and losses, and utility is concave over gains and convex over losses. Under the preferences of Tversky and Kahneman (Tversky, A., D. Kahneman. 1992. Advances in prospect theory: Cumulative representation of uncertainty. J. Risk Uncertainty 5(4) 297-323) and lognormal asset prices, investors exhibit a disposition effect as gains are realized at a greater rate than losses. Nonetheless, in contrast to the extant literature, we find that the investor will "give up" and sell at a loss when the asset has a sufficiently low Sharpe ratio.</description><author>Henderson, Vicky</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Paying to Be Nice: Consistency and Costly Prosocial Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gneezy, Ayelet; Imas, Alex; Brown, Amber; Nelson, Leif D.; Norton, Michael I.
Building on previous research in economics and psychology, we propose that the costliness of initial prosocial behavior positively influences whether that behavior leads to consistent future behaviors. We suggest that costly prosocial behaviors serve as a signal of prosocial identity and that people subsequently behave in line with that self-perception. In contrast, costless prosocial acts do not signal much about one's prosocial identity, so subsequent behavior is less likely to be consistent and may even show the reductions in prosocial behavior associated with licensing. The results of a laboratory experiment and a large field experiment converge to support our account.</description><author>Gneezy, Ayelet; Imas, Alex; Brown, Amber; Nelson, Leif D.; Norton, Michael I.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Split or Steal? Cooperative Behavior When the Stakes Are Large</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van den Assem, Martijn J.; van Dolder, Dennie; Thaler, Richard H.
We examine cooperative behavior when large sums of money are at stake, using data from the television game show Golden Balls. At the end of each episode, contestants play a variant on the classic prisoner's dilemma for large and widely ranging stakes averaging over $20,000. Cooperation is surprisingly high for amounts that would normally be considered consequential but look tiny in their current context, what we call a "big peanuts" phenomenon. Utilizing the prior interaction among contestants, we find evidence that people have reciprocal preferences. Surprisingly, there is little support for conditional cooperation in our sample. That is, players do not seem to be more likely to cooperate if their opponent might be expected to cooperate. Further, we replicate earlier findings that males are less cooperative than females, but this gender effect reverses for older contestants because men become increasingly cooperative as their age increases.</description><author>van den Assem, Martijn J.; van Dolder, Dennie; Thaler, Richard H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Behavioral Genetics of Behavioral Anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cesarini, David; Johannesson, Magnus; Magnusson, Patrik K. E.; Wallace, Bjorn
A number of recent papers have examined the environmental and genetic sources of individual differences in economic and financial decision making. Here we contribute to this burgeoning literature by extending it to a number of key behavioral anomalies that are thought to be of importance for consumption, savings, and portfolio selection decisions. Using survey-based evidence from more than 11,000 Swedish twins, we demonstrate that a number of anomalies such as, for instance, the conjunction fallacy, default bias, and loss aversion are moderately heritable, in contrast, our estimates imply that variation in common environment explains only a small share of individual differences. We also report suggestive evidence in favor of a shared genetic architecture between cognitive reflection and a subset of the studied anomalies. These results offer some support for the proposition that the heritable variation in behavioral anomalies is partly mediated by genetic variance in cognitive ability. Taken together with previous findings, our results underline the importance of genetic differences as a source of heterogeneity in economic and financial decision making.</description><author>Cesarini, David; Johannesson, Magnus; Magnusson, Patrik K. E.; Wallace, Bjorn</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Norms and Contracting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kessler, Judd B.; Leider, Stephen
We argue that contracts establish the norms of a relationship and that individuals incur disutility when deviating from these norms. In a laboratory experiment, we allow agents to make simple contracts before they play one of four games, and the most effective contract always includes an unenforceable "handshake" agreement to take the first-best action. In three games, a contract with only this handshake agreement is (at least weakly) optimal. The handshake is particularly effective in games with strategic complements. Our results highlight an explanation for contractual incompleteness: establishing a norm can effectively substitute for weak enforceable restrictions.</description><author>Kessler, Judd B.; Leider, Stephen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Gender Composition on Team Performance and Decision Making: Evidence from the Field</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Apesteguia, Jose; Azmat, Ghazala; Iriberri, Nagore
We investigate whether the gender composition of teams affects their economic performance. We study a large business game, played in groups of three, in which each group takes the role of a general manager. There are two parallel competitions, one involving undergraduates and the other involving MBA students. Our analysis shows that teams formed by three women are significantly outperformed by all other gender combinations, both at the undergraduate and MBA levels. Looking across the performance distribution, we find that for undergraduates, three-women teams are outperformed throughout, but by as much as 0.47 of a standard deviation of the mean at the bottom and by only 0.09 at the top. For MBA students, at the top, the best performing group is two men and one woman. The differences in performance are explained by differences in decision making. We observe that three-women teams are less aggressive in their pricing strategies, invest less in research and development, and invest more in social sustainability initiatives than does any other gender combination.</description><author>Apesteguia, Jose; Azmat, Ghazala; Iriberri, Nagore</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Case-Based Model of Probability and Pricing Judgments: Biases in Buying and Selling Uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brenner, Lyle A.; Griffin, Dale W.; Koehler, Derek J.
We integrate a case-based model of probability judgment with prospect theory to explore asset pricing under uncertainty. Research within the "heuristics and biases" tradition suggests that probability judgments respond primarily to case-specific evidence and disregard aggregate characteristics of the class to which the case belongs, resulting in predictable biases. The dual-system framework presented here distinguishes heuristic assessments of value and evidence strength from deliberative assessments that incorporate prior odds and likelihood ratios following Bayes' rule. Hypotheses are derived regarding the relative sensitivity of judged probabilities, buying prices, and selling prices to case- versus class-based evidence. We test these hypotheses using a simulated stock market in which participants can learn from experience and have incentives for accuracy. Valuation of uncertain assets is found to be largely case based even in this economic setting; however, consistent with the framework's predictions, distinct patterns of miscalibration are found for buying prices, selling prices, and probability judgments.</description><author>Brenner, Lyle A.; Griffin, Dale W.; Koehler, Derek J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Multimethod Approach to Identifying Norms and Normative Expectations Within a Corporate Hierarchy: Evidence from the Financial Services Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burks, Stephen V.; Krupka, Erin L.
We use an incentive-compatible economic experiment and surveys in the field at a large financial services firm to identify the norms for on-the-job behavior among financial advisers and their leaders, and the normative expectations each group has of the other. We examine whistle-blowing on a peer, an incentive clash between serving the client and earning commissions, and a dilemma about fiduciary responsibility to a client. We find patterns of agreement among advisers, among leaders, and between the two groups, that are consistent with company guidelines identified ex ante. However, we also find measurable differences between what leaders expect and the actual norms of advisers. When there is such a mismatch we are able to distinguish mis-communication from ethical disagreement between leaders and advisers. Finally, we show that when advisers' personal ethical opinions do not match group norms, this mismatch is correlated with job dissatisfaction and lying for money in a second experiment.</description><author>Burks, Stephen V.; Krupka, Erin L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Penny Wise, Dollar Foolish: Buy-Sell Imbalances On and Around Round Numbers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Holden, Craig W.; Jacobsen, Stacey
This paper provides evidence that stock traders focus on round numbers as cognitive reference points for value. Using a random sample of more than 100 million stock transactions, we find excess buying (selling) by liquidity demanders at all price points one penny below (above) round numbers. Further, the size of the buy-sell imbalance is monotonic in the roundness of the adjacent round number (i.e., largest adjacent to integers, second-largest adjacent to half-dollars, etc.). Conditioning on the price path, we find much stronger excess buying (selling) by liquidity demanders when the ask falls (bid rises) to reach the integer than when it crosses the integer. We discuss and test three explanations for these results. Finally, 24-hour returns also vary by price point, and buy-sell imbalances are a major determinant of that variation across price points. Buying (selling) by liquidity demanders below (above) round numbers yield losses approaching $1 billion per year.</description><author>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Holden, Craig W.; Jacobsen, Stacey</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fighting City Hall: Entry Deterrence and Technology Upgrades in Cable TV Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Seamans, Robert C.
This article investigates how private firms respond to potential entry from public firms. This paper uses a data set of over 3,000 U.S. cable TV systems to present evidence consistent with entry deterrence. incumbent cable TV firms upgrade faster when located in markets with a potential municipal entrant. However, the same systems are then slower to offer new products enabled by the upgrade, suggesting upgrades in these markets occur for strategic reasons. Incumbent cable systems also upgrade faster in response to municipal entry threats than to private entry threats. Understanding how private firms respond to potential entry from public firms is especially important in light of recent U.S. government entry into several industries.</description><author>Seamans, Robert C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Constant Proportion Debt Obligations: A Postmortem Analysis of Rating Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gordy, Michael B.; Willemann, Soren
In its complexity and its vulnerability to market volatility, the constant proportion debt obligation (CPDO) might be viewed as the poster child for the excesses of financial engineering in the credit market. This paper examines the CPDO as a case study in model risk in the rating of complex structured products. We demonstrate that the models used by Standard and Poor's (S&amp;P) and Moody's fail in-sample specification tests even during the precrisis period and in particular understate the kurtosis of spread changes. Because stochastic volatility is the most natural explanation for the excess kurtosis, we estimate an extended version of the S&amp;P model with stochastic volatility and find that the volatility-of-volatility is large and significant. An implication is that agency model-implied probabilities of attaining high spread levels were biased downward, which in turn biased the rating upward. We conclude with larger lessons for the rating of complex products and for modeling credit risk in general.</description><author>Gordy, Michael B.; Willemann, Soren</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cutting in Line: Social Norms in Queues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allon, Gad; Hanany, Eran
Although the norm in many retail banks is to serve customers on a first-come, first-served basis, some customers try to cut the line, usually by providing an excuse for their urgency. In other queues, however, this behavior is considered unacceptable and is aggressively banned. In all of these cases, customer exhibit strategies that have not yet been explored in the operations literature: they choose whether or not to cut the line and must also decide whether to accept or reject such intrusions by others. This paper derives conditions for the emergence of such behavior in equilibrium among the customers themselves, i.e., when the queue manager is not involved in granting priorities and the customers have to use community enforcement to sustain such equilibria.</description><author>Allon, Gad; Hanany, Eran</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Calendar Cycles, Infrequent Decisions, and the Cross Section of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jagannathan, Ravi; Marakani, Srikant; Takehara, Hitoshi; Wang, Yong
We show that when investors review their consumption and investment plans infrequently at different points in time with interim information flows, the standard consumption-based capital asset pricing model (CCAPM) will continue to hold only at those points in time when all investors review their plans. Stylized facts suggest that the end of the tax year is a candidate for one such points in time. Therefore, we should expect more support for the CCAPM during the period surrounding the end of the tax year, i.e., the fourth and first quarters in Japan where the tax year ends in December, and the first and second quarters in the United Kingdom where the tax year ends in April. Our empirical findings are consistent with these expectations.</description><author>Jagannathan, Ravi; Marakani, Srikant; Takehara, Hitoshi; Wang, Yong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Density Forecasting of Intraday Call Center Arrivals Using Models Based on Exponential Smoothing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Taylor, James W.
A key input to the call center staffing process is a forecast for the number of calls arriving. Density forecasts of arrival rates are needed for analytical call center models, which assume Poisson arrivals with a stochastic arrival rate. Density forecasts of call volumes can be used in simulation models and are also important for the analysis of outsourcing contracts. A forecasting method, which has previously shown strong potential, is Holt-Winters exponential smoothing adapted for modeling the intraday and intraweek cycles in intraday data. To enable density forecasting of the arrival volume and rate, we develop a Poisson count model, with gamma distributed arrival rate, which captures the essential features of this exponential smoothing method. The apparent stationary level in our data leads us to develop versions of the new model for series with stationary levels. We evaluate forecast accuracy up to two weeks ahead using data from three organizations. We find that the stationary level models improve prediction beyond approximately two days ahead, and that these models perform well in comparison with sophisticated benchmarks. This is confirmed by the results of a call center simulation model, which demonstrates the use of arrival rate density forecasting to support staffing decisions.</description><author>Taylor, James W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sequential Sampling with Economics of Selection Procedures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chick, Stephen E.; Frazier, Peter
Sequential sampling problems arise in stochastic simulation and many other applications. Sampling is used to infer the unknown performance of several alternatives before one alternative is selected as best. This paper presents new economically motivated fully sequential sampling procedures to solve such problems, called economics of selection procedures. The optimal procedure is derived for comparing a known standard with one alternative whose unknown reward is inferred with sampling. That result motivates heuristics when multiple alternatives have unknown rewards. The resulting procedures are more effective in numerical experiments than any previously proposed procedure of which we are aware and are easily implemented. The key driver of the improvement is the use of dynamic programming to model sequential sampling as an option to learn before selecting an alternative. It accounts for the expected benefit of adaptive stopping policies for sampling, rather than of one-stage policies, as is common in the literature.</description><author>Chick, Stephen E.; Frazier, Peter</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bayesian Dynamic Pricing Policies: Learning and Earning Under a Binary Prior Distribution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harrison, J. Michael; Keskin, N. Bora; Zeevi, Assaf
Motivated by applications in financial services, we consider a seller who offers prices sequentially to a stream of potential customers, observing either success or failure in each sales attempt. The parameters of the underlying demand model are initially unknown, so each price decision involves a trade-off between learning and earning. Attention is restricted to the simplest kind of model uncertainty, where one of two demand models is known to apply, and we focus initially on performance of the myopic Bayesian policy (MBP), variants of which are commonly used in practice. Because learning is passive under the MBP (that is, learning only takes place as a by-product of actions that have a different purpose), it can lead to incomplete learning and poor profit performance. However, under one additional assumption, a constrained variant of the myopic policy is shown to have the following strong theoretical virtue: the expected performance gap relative to a clairvoyant who knows the underlying demand model is bounded by a constant as the number of sales attempts becomes large.</description><author>Harrison, J. Michael; Keskin, N. Bora; Zeevi, Assaf</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multiattribute One-Switch Utility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tsetlin, Ilia; Winkler, Robert L.
The one-switch property states that the preference between any two lotteries switches at most once as wealth increases. Working within the expected utility framework, we extend the one-switch notion to the multiattribute case and identify the families of multiattribute utility functions that are one-switch. We then show that all multiattribute one-switch utility functions can be approximated by a sum of two multiattribute exponential utilities (sumex utility). Finally, we discuss how the one-switch property, when appropriate, can simplify the assessment of multiattribute utility.</description><author>Tsetlin, Ilia; Winkler, Robert L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing Delegated Search Over Design Spaces</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erat, Sanjiv; Krishnan, Vish
Organizations increasingly seek solutions to their open-ended design problems by employing a contest approach in which search over a solution space is delegated to outside agents. We study this new class of problems, which are costly to specify, pose credibility issues for the focal firm, and require finely tuned awards for meeting the firm's needs. Through an analytical model, we examine the relationship between problem specification, award structure, and breadth of solution space searched by outside agents toward characterizing how a firm should effectively manage such open-ended design contests. Our results independently establish and offer a causal explanation for an interesting phenomenon observed in design contests-clustering of searchers in specific regions of the solution space. The analysis also yields a cautionary finding-although the breadth of search increases with number of searchers, the relationship is strongly sublinear (logarithmic). Finally, from the practical perspective of managing the delegated search process, our results offer rules of thumb on how many and what size awards should be offered, as well as the extent to which firms should undertake problem specification, contingent on the nature (open-endedness and uncertainty) of the design problem solution being delegated to outside agents.</description><author>Erat, Sanjiv; Krishnan, Vish</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Leasing Greener Than Selling?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agrawal, Vishal V.; Ferguson, Mark; Toktay, L. Beril; Thomas, Valerie M.
Based on the proposition that leasing is environmentally superior to selling, some firms have adopted a leasing strategy and others promote their existing leasing programs as environmentally superior to "green" their image. The argument is that because a leasing firm retains ownership of the off-lease units, it has an incentive to remarket them or invest in designing a more durable product, resulting in a lower volume of new production and disposal. However, leasing might be environmentally inferior because of the direct control the firm has over the off-lease products, which may prompt the firm to remove them from the market to avoid cannibalizing the demand for new products. Motivated by these issues, we adopt a life-cycle environmental impact perspective and analytically investigate if leasing can be both more profitable and have a lower total environmental impact. We find that leasing can be environmentally worse despite remarketing all off-lease products and greener than selling despite the mid-life removal of off-lease products. Our analysis also provides insights for environmental groups and entities that use different approaches to improve the environmental performance of business practices. We show that imposing disposal fees or encouraging remanufacturing, under some conditions, can actually lead to higher environmental impact. We also identify when educating consumers to be more environmentally conscious can improve the relative environmental performance of leasing.</description><author>Agrawal, Vishal V.; Ferguson, Mark; Toktay, L. Beril; Thomas, Valerie M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Chasing a Moving Target: Exploitation and Exploration in Dynamic Environments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Posen, Hart E.; Levinthal, Daniel A.
A common justification for organizational change is that the circumstances in which the organization finds itself have changed, thereby eroding the value of utilizing existing knowledge. On the surface, the claim that organizations should adapt by generating new knowledge seems obvious and compelling. However, this standard wisdom overlooks the possibility that the reward to generating new knowledge may itself be eroded if change is an ongoing property of the environment. This observation in turn suggests that environmental change is not a self-evident call for strategies of greater exploration. Indeed, under some conditions the appropriate response to environmental change is a renewed focus on exploiting existing knowledge and opportunities. We develop a computational model based on the canonical multiarmed bandit formulation of exploration and exploitation. We endeavor to understand the mechanisms by which environmental change acts to make purposeful efforts at organizational adaptation less (or more) valuable.</description><author>Posen, Hart E.; Levinthal, Daniel A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing Kernels with Stochastic Skewness and Volatility Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chabi-Yo, Fousseni
I derive pricing kernels in which the market volatility is endogenously determined. Using the Taylor expansion series of the representative investor's marginal utility, I show that the price of market volatility risk is restricted by the investor's risk aversion and skewness preference. The risk aversion is estimated to be between two and five and is significant. The price of the market volatility is negative. Consistent with economic theory, I find that the pricing kernel decreases in the market index return and increases in market volatility. The projection of the estimated pricing kernel onto a polynomial function of the market return produces puzzling behaviors, which can be observed in the pricing kernel and absolute risk aversion functions. The inclusion of additional terms in the Taylor expansion series of the investor's marginal utility produces a pricing kernel function of market stochastic volatility, stochastic skewness, and stochastic kurtosis. The prices of risk of these moments are restricted by the investor's risk aversion, skewness preference, and kurtosis preference. The prices of risk of these moments should not be confused with the price of risk of powers of the market return, such as coskewness and cokurtosis.</description><author>Chabi-Yo, Fousseni</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Compensation and Pay-Performance Sensitivity in a Continuous-Time Principal-Agent Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ju, Nengjiu; Wan, Xuhu
This paper studies the optimal contract between risk-neutral shareholders and a constant relative risk-aversion manager in a continuous-time model. Several interesting results are obtained. First, the optimal compensation is increasing but concave in output value if the manager is more risk averse than a log-utility manager. Second, when the manager has a log utility, a linear contract is optimal when there is no explicit lower bound on the compensation, and an option contract is optimal when there is an explicit lower bound. Third, optimal effort is stochastic (state dependent). Fourth, consistent with empirical findings and contrary to standard agency theory predictions, the relationship between pay-performance sensitivity and firm performance and that between pay-performance sensitivity and firm risk can be nonmonotonic.</description><author>Ju, Nengjiu; Wan, Xuhu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Management Insights</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorman, Michael F.
nan</description><author>Gorman, Michael F.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Transaction-Level Analysis of Spatial Arbitrage: The Role of Habit, Attention, and Electronic Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Overby, Eric; Clarke, Jonathan
Despite the central role of arbitrage in finance and economic theory, there is limited evidence of the factors that create and eliminate arbitrage opportunities, how often arbitrage occurs, and how profitable it is. We address these gaps via a transaction-level analysis of spatial arbitrage in the wholesale automotive market. We investigate why arbitrage opportunities are created by analyzing how sellers choose where to sell vehicles. We find that the attention sellers pay to the distribution of a vehicle is negatively related to the probability that it is arbitraged. Arbitrage occurs in approximately 1% of transactions, although electronic trading is making arbitrage less prevalent by improving buyer/seller matching across locations. Arbitrage yields a 5.6% return on average, although arbitrageurs take a loss 14% of the time. Our results contribute to the literature on arbitrage, the effect of attention allocation on market outcomes, and the effect of information technology on market efficiency.</description><author>Overby, Eric; Clarke, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beyond the Glass Ceiling: Does Gender Matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, Renee B.; Funk, Patricia
A large literature documents that women are different from men in their choices and preferences, but little is known about gender differences in the boardroom. If women must be like men to break the glass ceiling, we might expect gender differences to disappear among directors. Using a large survey of directors, we show that female and male directors differ systematically in their core values and risk attitudes, but in ways that differ from gender differences in the general population. These results are robust to controlling for differences in observable characteristics. Consistent with findings for the population, female directors are more benevolent and universally concerned but less power oriented than male directors. However, in contrast to findings for the population, they are less tradition and security oriented than their male counterparts. They are also more risk loving than male directors. Thus, having a woman on the board need not lead to more risk-averse decision making.</description><author>Adams, Renee B.; Funk, Patricia</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the Rolodex Matter? Corporate Elite's Small World and the Effectiveness of Boards of Directors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nguyen, Bang Dang
This paper investigates the impact of social ties on the effectiveness of boards of directors. When the chief executive officer (CEO) and a number of directors belong to the same social networks, the CEO is less likely to be dismissed for poor performance. The results are robust to different measures of performance and networks, and consistent after controlling for CEO ability and connected boards' superior information. Although being ousted is costly for all CEOs-who must then devote time to finding new employment and only succeed in 62% of cases-socially connected CEOs are more likely to find new and better employment after a forced departure. Evidence from this paper suggests that close social ties between board members and CEOs impact the workings of the board of directors.</description><author>Nguyen, Bang Dang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Keynes Meets Markowitz: The Trade-Off Between Familiarity and Diversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyle, Phelim; Garlappi, Lorenzo; Uppal, Raman; Wang, Tan
We develop a model of portfolio choice to nest the views of Keynes, who advocates concentration in a few familiar assets, and Markowitz, who advocates diversification. We use the concepts of ambiguity and ambiguity aversion to formalize the idea of an investor's "familiarity" toward assets. The model shows that for any given level of expected returns, the optimal portfolio depends on two quantities: relative ambiguity across assets and the standard deviation of the expected return estimate for each asset. If both quantities are low, then the optimal portfolio consists of a mix of familiar and unfamiliar assets; moreover, an increase in correlation between assets causes an investor to increase concentration in familiar assets (flight to familiarity). Alternatively, if both quantities are high, then the optimal portfolio contains only the familiar asset(s), as Keynes would have advocated. In the extreme case in which both quantities are very high, no risky asset is held (nonparticipation).</description><author>Boyle, Phelim; Garlappi, Lorenzo; Uppal, Raman; Wang, Tan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Inattention and the Market Impact of Summary Statistics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilbert, Thomas; Kogan, Shimon; Lochstoer, Lars; Ozyildirim, Ataman
We show that U.S. stock and Treasury futures prices respond sharply to recurring stale information releases: In particular, we identify a unique macroeconomic series-the U.S. Leading Economic Index (R) (LET)-which is released monthly and constructed as a summary statistic of previously released inputs. We show that a front-running strategy that trades S&amp;P 500 futures in the direction of the announcement a day before its release and then trades in the opposite direction of the announcement following its release generates an average annual return of close to 8%. These patterns are more pronounced for high beta stocks, for stocks that are more difficult to arbitrage, and during times when investors' sensitivity to firm-specific stale information is high. Treasury futures exhibit similar, albeit less pronounced, price patterns. Other measures of information arrival, such as price volatility and volume, spike following the release. These empirical findings suggest that some investors are inattentive to the stale nature of the information included in the LEI releases, instead interpreting it as new information, and thereby causing temporary yet significant mispricing.</description><author>Gilbert, Thomas; Kogan, Shimon; Lochstoer, Lars; Ozyildirim, Ataman</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Cultural Differences Between Contracting Parties Matter? Evidence from Syndicated Bank Loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Yafeh, Yishay
We investigate whether cultural differences between professional decision makers affect financial contracts in a large data set of international syndicated bank loans. We find that more culturally distant lead banks offer borrowers smaller loans at a higher interest rate and are more likely to require third-party guarantees. These effects do not disappear following repeated interaction between borrower and lender and are economically sizable: A one-standard-deviation increase in cultural distance, approximately the distance between Canada and the United States or between Japan and South Korea, is associated with a 6.5 basis point higher loan spread; the loan spread increases by about 23 basis points if the bank-firm match involves culturally more distant parties, for example, from Japan and the United States. We also find that cultural differences not only affect the relation between borrower and lender, but also hamper risk sharing between participant banks and culturally distant lead banks.</description><author>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Yafeh, Yishay</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumption Externality and Yield Uncertainty in the Influenza Vaccine Supply Chain: Interventions in Demand and Supply Sides</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arifoglu, Kenan; Deo, Sarang; Iravani, Seyed M. R.
We study the impact of yield uncertainty (supply side) and self-interested consumers (demand side) on the inefficiency in the influenza vaccine supply chain. Previous economic studies, focusing on demand side, find that the equilibrium demand is always less than the socially optimal demand because self-interested individuals do not internalize the social benefit of protecting others via reduced infectiousness (positive externality). In contrast, we show that the equilibrium demand can be greater than the socially optimal demand after accounting for the limited supply due to yield uncertainty and manufacturer's incentives. The main driver for this result is a second (negative) externality: Self-interested individuals ignore that vaccinating people with high infection costs is more beneficial for the society when supply is limited. We show that the extent of the negative externality can be reduced through more efficient and less uncertain allocation mechanisms. To investigate the relative effectiveness of government interventions on supply and demand sides under various demand and supply characteristics, we construct two partially centralized scenarios where the social planner (i.e., government) intervenes either on the demand side or the supply side, but not both. We conduct an extensive numerical analysis.</description><author>Arifoglu, Kenan; Deo, Sarang; Iravani, Seyed M. R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>