<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Review of Financial Studies7</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Prospect theory and mean-variance analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, H.; Levy, M.
The experimental results of prospect theory (PT) reveal suggest that investors make decisions based on change of wealth rather than total wealth, that preferences are S-shaped with a risk-seeking segment, and that probabilities are subjectively distorted. This article shows that while PT's findings are in sharp contradiction to the foundations of mean-variance (MV) analysis, counterintuitively, when diversification between assets is allowed, the MV and PT-efficient sets almost coincide. Thus one can employ the MV optimization algorithm to construct PT-efficient portfolios.</description><author>Levy, H.; Levy, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Technical analysis and liquidity provision</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kavajecz, K. A.; Odders-White, E. R.
The apparent conflict between the level of resources dedicated to technical analysis by practitioners and academic theories of market efficiency is a long-standing puzzle. We explore a previously unexamined feature of technical analysis-namely its relation to liquidity provision. We demonstrate that support and resistance levels coincide with peaks in depth on the limit order book and moving average forecasts reveal information about the relative position of depth on the book. Furthermore, we show that these relationships stem from technical rules locating depth already in place on the limit order book.</description><author>Kavajecz, K. A.; Odders-White, E. R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank competition and credit standards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ruckes, M.
This article offers an explanation for the substantial variation of credit standards and price competition among banks over the business cycle. As the economic outlook improves, the average default probabilities of borrowers decline. This affects the profitability of screening and causes bank screening intensity to display an inverse U-shape as a function of economic prospects. Low screening activity in expansions creates intense price competition among lenders and loans are extended to lower-quality borrowers. As the economic outlook worsens, price competition diminishes, and credit standards tighten significantly. Deposit insurance may contribute to the countercyclical variation of credit standards.</description><author>Ruckes, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of corporate capital structure and investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cantillo, M.
This article uses a general equilibrium framework to explore the origins and limitations of financial intermediaries. In the model, investors have a generic lending technology that they can improve at a cost. Those who upgrade become intermediaries to exploit their advantage. However, conflicts with depositors will limit the banks' market presence, and they will only lend to moderately endowed firms while bondholders will finance cash-rich corporations. The article also analyzes the extent to which investors adopt the superior lending technique, the nature of bank competition, and how corporate and bank conditions affect interest rates and investment.</description><author>Cantillo, M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why does book building drive out auction methods of IPO issuance? Evidence from Japan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kutsuna, K.; Smith, R.
We examine Japan's 1997 introduction of book building as an alternative to a previously required hybrid auction method. Despite higher cost for some issuers, all issuers in Japan now select book building. Book building enables more accurate valuation of firms, but gains from accurate valuation are partly redistributive. Thus book building can drive auction-method offerings from the market even if it yields no aggregate benefit. Compared to the auction regime, book building reduces issue costs for large issuers. Auctioning is less costly for small issuers, but appears to foreclose some small firms from issuing. The aggregate costs of book building and auctioning are similar.</description><author>Kutsuna, K.; Smith, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of voting rights to majority shareholders: Evidence from dual-class stock unifications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hauser, S.; Lauterbach, B.
We study 84 dual-class. stock unifications, where superior vote shareholders gave up their superior voting status (all firm stocks became "one share one vote") and received (in most cases) compensation in the form of additional shares. Unifications are essentially intrafirm transactions of voting rights, and afford observation of the intrafirm-assessed price of vote. The price of vote in unifications (1) increases with the percentage vote lost by the majority shareholders, (2) is higher in family-controlled firms, (3) decreases with institutional investor holdings, and (4) is similar to the "outside" price of vote implicit in the market prices of stocks.</description><author>Hauser, S.; Lauterbach, B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board composition, board effectiveness, and the observed form of takeover bids</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bange, M. M.; Mazzeo, M. A.
We show that bidding firms consider target board characteristics when deciding takeover offer types and initial offer premiums. We study a sample of 436 proposed negotiated mergers and bypass offers. Firms with individuals holding the titles of both chief executive officer (CEO) and board chair are more likely to receive bypass offers. These offers are more likely to be successful and generate higher target shareholder gains over the takeover offer period. When the target's board is independent, the target is less likely to receive a high premium and the offer is less likely to succeed.</description><author>Bange, M. M.; Mazzeo, M. A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Losing money on arbitrage: Optimal dynamic portfolio choice in markets with arbitrage opportunities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, J.; Longstaff, F. A.
We derive the optimal investment policy of a risk-averse investor in a market where there is a textbook arbitrage opportunity, but where liabilities must be secured by collateral. We find that it is often optimal to underinvest in the arbitrage by taking a smaller position than collateral constraints allow. Even when the optimal policy is followed, the arbitrage portfolio typically experiences losses before the final convergence date. In fact, its initial performance may be indistinguishable from that of a conventional portfolio with a poor track record. These results have important implications for the role of arbitrageurs in financial markets.</description><author>Liu, J.; Longstaff, F. A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Adverse selection and the required return</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garleanu, N.; Pedersen, L. H.
An important feature of financial markets is that securities are traded repeatedly by asymmetrically informed investors. We study how current and future adverse selection affect the required return. We find that the bid-ask spread generated by adverse selection is not a cost, on average, for agents who trade, and hence the bid-ask spread does not directly influence the required return. Adverse selection contributes to trading-decision distortions, however, implying allocation costs, which affect the required return. We explicitly derive the effect of adverse selection on required returns, and show how our result differs from models that consider the bid-ask spread to be an exogenous cost.</description><author>Garleanu, N.; Pedersen, L. H.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Family values and the star phenomenon: Strategies of mutual fund families</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nanda, V.; Wang, Z. J.; Zheng, L.
We examine the extent to which a fund's cash flows are affected by the stellar performance of other funds in its family-and consequences of such spillovers. We show that star performance results in greater cash inflow to the fund and to other funds in its family. Moreover, families with higher variation in investment strategies across funds are shown to be more likely to generate star performance. We argue that spillovers may induce lower ability families to pursue star-creating strategies. Consistent with our conjecture, families with high variation in investment strategies across funds significantly underperform low-variation families.</description><author>Nanda, V.; Wang, Z. J.; Zheng, L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock return predictability and asset pricing models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avramov, D.
This article develops an asset allocation framework that incorporates prior beliefs about the extent of stock return predictability explained by asset pricing models. We find that when prior beliefs allow even minor deviations from pricing model implications, the resulting asset allocations depart considerably from and substantially outperform allocations dictated by either the underlying models or the sample evidence on return predictability. Under a wide range of beliefs about model pricing abilities, asset allocations based on conditional models outperform their unconditional counterparts that exclude return predictability.</description><author>Avramov, D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital budgeting in multidivision firms: Information, agency, and incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernardo, A. E.; Cai, H. B.; Luo, J. A.
We examine optimal capital allocation and managerial compensation in a firm with two investment projects (divisions) each run by a risk-neutral manager who can provide (i) (unverifiable) information about project quality and (ii) (unverifiable) access to value-enhancing, but privately costly resources. The optimal managerial compensation contract offers greater performance pay and a lower salary when managers report that their project is higher quality. The firm generally underinvests in capital and managers underutilize resources (relative to first-best). We also derive cross-sectional predictions about the sensitivity of investment in one division to the quality of investment opportunities in the other division, and the relative importance of division-level and firm-level performance-based pay in managerial compensation contracts.</description><author>Bernardo, A. E.; Cai, H. B.; Luo, J. A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The overseas listing decision: New evidence of proximity preference</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarkissian, S.; Schill, M. J.
Using a cross section of effectively the entire universe of overseas listings across world markets, we examine the market preferences of firms listing their stock abroad. We find that geographic, economic, cultural, and industrial proximity play the dominant role in the choice of overseas listing venue. Contrary to the notion that firms maximize international portfolio diversification gains in listing abroad, cross-listing activity is more common across markets for which diversification gains are relatively low. Our findings imply that the same proximity constraints that are believed to lead to "home bias" in investment portfolio decisions also exert a profound influence on financing decisions.</description><author>Sarkissian, S.; Schill, M. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are IPOs really underpriced?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Purnanandam, A. K.; Swaminathan, B.
While IPOs have been underpriced by more than 10% during the past two decades, we find that in a sample of more than 2,000 IPOs from 1980 to 1997, the median IPO was significantly overvalued at the offer price relative to valuations based on industry peer price multiples. This overvaluation ranges from 14% to 50% depending on the peer matching criteria. Cross-sectional regressions show that "overvalued" IPOs provide high first-day returns, but low long-run risk-adjusted returns. These overvalued IPOs have lower profitability, higher accruals, and higher analyst growth forecasts than "undervalued" IPOs. Ex post, the projected high growth of overvalued IPOs fails to materialize, while their profitability declines from pre-IPO levels. These results suggest IPO investors are deceived by optimistic growth forecasts and pay insufficient attention to profitability in valuing IPOs.</description><author>Purnanandam, A. K.; Swaminathan, B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Underpricing and market power in uniform price auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kremer, I.; Nyborg, K. G.
In uniform auctions, buyers choose demand schedules as strategies and pay the same "market clearing" price for units awarded. Despite the widespread use of these auctions, the extant theory shows that they are susceptible to arbitrarily large underpricing. We make a realistic modification to the theory by letting prices, quantities, and bids be discrete. We show that underpricing can be made arbitrarily small by choosing a sufficiently small price tick size and a sufficiently large quantity multiple. We also show how one might improve revenues by modifying the allocation rule. A trivial change in the design can have a dramatic impact on prices. Our conclusions are robust to bidders being capacity constrained. Finally, we examine supply uncertainty robust equilibria.</description><author>Kremer, I.; Nyborg, K. G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wealth, information acquisition, and portfolio choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peress, J.
I solve (with an approximation) a Grossman-Stiglitz economy tinder general preferences, thus allowing for wealth effects. Because information generates increasing returns, decreasing absolute risk aversion, in conjunction with the availability of costly information, is sufficient to explain why wealthier households invest a larger fraction of their wealth in risky assets. One no longer needs to resort to decreasing relative risk aversion, an empirically questionable assumption. Furthermore, I show how to distinguish empirically between these two explanations. Finally, I find that the availability of costly information exacerbates wealth inequalities.</description><author>Peress, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Differences of opinion, short-sales constraints, and market crashes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, H.; Stein, J. C.
We develop a theory of market crashes based on differences of opinion among investors. Because of short-sales constraints, bearish investors do not initially participate in the market and their information is not revealed in prices. However, if other previously bullish investors bail out of the market, the originally bearish group may become the marginal "support buyers,'' and more will be learned about their signals. Thus accumulated hidden information comes out during market declines. The model explains a variety of stylized facts about crashes and also makes a distinctive new prediction-that returns will be more negatively skewed conditional on high trading volume.</description><author>Hong, H.; Stein, J. C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Order preferencing and market quality on US equity exchanges</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peterson, M. A.; Sirri, E. R.
We present a detailed view of market quality in the presence of preferencing arrangements. A unique dataset provides the opportunity to measure trading costs of marketable orders and fill rates and ex post costs of limit orders across trading venues. For market orders, we find the primary exchange provides the lowest execution costs. However, the preferencing exchanges are no worse than, and in most cases better than, the nonpreferencing regional exchanges. For limit orders, the regionals execute limit orders more frequently than the primary market and with an ex post execution cost that is not very different from the primary market.</description><author>Peterson, M. A.; Sirri, E. R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity-based competition for order flow</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parlour, C. A.; Seppi, D. J.
We present a microstructure model of competition for order flow between exchanges based on liquidity provision. We find that neither a pure limit order market (PLM) nor a hybrid specialist/limit order market (HM) structure is competition-proof. A PLM can always be supported in equilibrium as the dominant market (i.e., where the hybrid limit book is empty), but an HM can also be supported, for some market parameterizations, as the dominant market. We also show the possible coexistence of competing markets. Order preferencing-that is, decisions about where orders are routed when investors are indifferent-is a key determinant of market viability. Welfare comparisons show that competition between exchanges can increase as well as reduce the cost of liquidity.</description><author>Parlour, C. A.; Seppi, D. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market making with costly monitoring: An analysis of the SOES controversy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foucault, T.; Roell, A.; Sandas, P.
This article presents a model of information monitoring and market making in a dealership market. We model how intensively dealers monitor public information to avoid being picked off by professional day traders when monitoring is costly. Price competition among dealers is hampered by their incentives to share monitoring costs. The risk of being picked off by the day traders makes dealers more competitive. The interaction between these effects determines whether a firm quote rule improves trading costs and price discovery. Our empirical results support the prediction that professional day traders prefer stocks with small spreads, but offer less support for the prediction that their trading leads to wider spreads.</description><author>Foucault, T.; Roell, A.; Sandas, P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of covariance risk and pricing anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moskowitz, T. J.
This article examines the link between several well-known asset pricing "anomalies" and the covariance structure of returns. I find size, book-to-market, and momentum strategies exhibit a strong, weak, and negligible relation to covariance risk, respectively. A size factor helps predict future volatility and covariation, improving the efficiency of investment strategies. Moreover, its premium rises following increases in both its volatility and covariation with other assets. These effects are amplified in recessions. No such relations exist for book-to-market or momentum. These findings may shed light on explanations for these premia and present a challenging set of facts for future theory.</description><author>Moskowitz, T. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk adjustment and trading strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, D. H.; Conrad, J.; Dittmar, R. F.
We assess the profitability of momentum strategies using a stochastic discount factor approach. In unconditional tests, approximately half of the strategies' profitability is explained. In conditional tests we see a further slight decline in profits. We argue that the risk of these strategies should be increasing in the market risk premium. Empirically, while their risk measures estimated relative to the stochastic discount factor behave as predicted, market betas do not; thus capital asset pricing model (CAPM)-like benchmarks may lead to incorrect inferences. Given that our nonparametric risk adjustment explains roughly half of momentum strategy profits, we cannot rule out the possibility of residual mispricing.</description><author>Ahn, D. H.; Conrad, J.; Dittmar, R. F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stochastic discount factor bounds with conditioning information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferson, W. E.; Siegel, A. F.
Hansen and Jagannathan (1991) (hereafter HJ) derive restrictions on the volatility of stochastic discount factors that price a given set of returns. This article studies the sampling properties of HJ bounds that use conditioning information. One approach is to multiply the returns by the lagged variables. We also study optimized HJ bounds with conditioning information from Gallant, Hansen, and Tauchen (1990) and based on portfolios derived in Ferson and Siegel (2001). We document striking finite-sample biases in the HJ bounds, where the bounds reject asset-pricing models too often. We provide a useful bias correction. We also evaluate asymptotic standard errors for the bounds from Hansen, Heaton, and Luttmer (1995).</description><author>Ferson, W. E.; Siegel, A. F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Delta-hedged gains and the negative market volatility risk premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, G.; Kapadia, N.
We investigate whether the volatility risk premium is negative by examining the statistical properties of delta-hedged option portfolios (buy the option and hedge with stock). Within a stochastic volatility framework, we demonstrate a correspondence between the sign and magnitude of the volatility risk premium and the mean delta-hedged portfolio returns. Using a sample of S&amp;P 500 index options, we provide empirical tests that have the following general results. First, the delta-hedged strategy underperforms zero. Second, the documented underperformance is less for options away from the money. Third, the underperformance is greater at times of higher volatility. Fourth, the volatility risk premium significantly affects delta-hedged gains, even after accounting for jump fears. Our evidence is supportive of a negative market volatility risk premium.</description><author>Bakshi, G.; Kapadia, N.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global integration in primary equity markets: The role of US banks and</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ljungqvist, A. P.; Jenkinson, T.; Wilhelm, W. J.
We examine the costs and benefits of the global integration of initial public offering (IPO) markets associated with the diffusion of U.S. underwriting methods in the 1990s. Bookbuilding is becoming increasingly popular outside the United States and typically costs twice as much as a fixed-price offer. However, on its own, bookbuilding only leads to lower underpricing when conducted by U.S. banks and/or targeted at U.S. investors. For most issuers, the gains associated with lower underpricing outweighed the additional costs associated with hiring U.S. banks or marketing in the United States. This suggests a quality/price trade-off contrasting with the findings of Chen and Ritter, particularly since non-U.S. issuers raising US$20 million-US$80 million also typically pay a 7% spread when U.S. banks and investors are involved.</description><author>Ljungqvist, A. P.; Jenkinson, T.; Wilhelm, W. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic equilibrium with liquidity constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Detemple, J.; Serrat, A.
This article studies an intertemporal economy with liquidity constrained and unconstrained individuals. We use a stopping time approach to solve the finite horizon-constrained consumption portfolio problem with constant relative risk aversion and to examine the structure of equilibrium. The impact of the constraint on the optimal consumption and the financing portfolio is assessed. The equilibrium state price density is related to the exercise boundary of an American-style contingent claim with nonlinear payoff. This stopping time characterization enables us to prove the existence of an equilibrium and can be implemented numerically. Properties of equilibrium bond and stock returns are examined.</description><author>Detemple, J.; Serrat, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Underwriter certification and Japanese seasoned equity issues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooney, J. W.; Kato, H. K.; Schallheim, J. S.
In sharp contrast to results in the United States, the average stock price response to an announcement of a seasoned equity issue in Japan is positive. Offer prices in Japan, unlike the United States, are announced several days before the beginning of the subscription period and incorporate a substantial discount. We suggest that the positive announcement effects in Japan are consistent with the underwriter's certification of the issuing firm's value. We characterize the underwriter's risk as a put option and find a positive association between the underwriter's risk and the announcement returns, as well as other results consistent with underwriter certification.</description><author>Cooney, J. W.; Kato, H. K.; Schallheim, J. S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of trading halts in monitoring a specialist market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edelen, R.; Gervais, S.
When a collection of specialists organize as an exchange, each can reap net private benefits at the expense of the exchange by quoting a privately optimal pricing schedule. Coordination makes all specialists and customers better off, but requires a system of monitoring and punishment that breaks down when information asymmetries between the exchange and a specialist are high. The specialist may then seek a temporary trading halt to alleviate unjustified punishment, or the exchange may halt trading to prevent the quoting of damaging privately optimal pricing schedules. We test this theory on a sample of NYSE halts. As predicted, we find a significant increase, in estimated information asymmetry immediately preceding trading halts.</description><author>Edelen, R.; Gervais, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial compensation and the market reaction to bank loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almazan, A.; Suarez, J.
This article considers why a manager would choose to submit himself to the discipline of bank monitoring. This issue is analyzed within the context of a model where the manager enjoys private benefits, which can be restricted by the monitor, and is optimally compensated by shareholders. Within this setting we find that managers will submit to monitoring when they receive favorable private information. This result is consistent with event study evidence that suggests that the market has a favorable view of financing choices that increase monitoring.</description><author>Almazan, A.; Suarez, J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt maturity and the effects of growth opportunities and liquidity risk on leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, S. A.
I test the hypothesis that short debt maturity attenuates the negative effect of growth opportunities on leverage. Using simultaneous equations with leverage and maturity endogenous, I find strong support for an economically significant attenuation effect. The negative effect of growth opportunities on leverage for firms with all shorter-term debt is less than one-sixth as large as the effect for firms with all longer-term debt. Short maturity also increases liquidity risk, however, which negatively affects leverage. The results suggest that firms trade off the cost of underinvestment problems against the cost of liquidity risk when choosing short maturity.</description><author>Johnson, S. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal contracts in a continuous-time delegated portfolio management problem</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hui, O. Y.
This article studies the contracting problem between an individual investor and a professional portfolio manager in a continuous-time principal-agent framework. Optimal contracts are obtained in closed form. These contracts are of a symmetric form and suggest that a portfolio manager should receive a fixed fee, a fraction of the total assets under management, plus a bonus or a penalty depending upon the portfolio's excess return relative to a benchmark portfolio. The appropriate benchmark portfolio is an active index that contains risky assets where the number of shares invested in each asset can vary over time, rather than a passive index in which the number of shares invested in each asset remains constant over time.</description><author>Hui, O. Y.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Employee reload options: Pricing, hedging, and optimal exercise</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dybvig, P. H.; Loewenstein, M.
Reload options, call options granting new options on exercise, are popularly used in compensation. Although the compound option feature may seem complicated, there is a distribution-free dominant policy of exercising reload options whenever they are in the money. The optimal policy implies general formulas for numerical valuation. Simpler formulas for valuation and hedging follow from Black-Scholes assumptions with or without continuous dividends. Time vesting affects the optimal policy, but numerical results indicate that it is nearly optimal to exercise in the money whenever feasible. The results suggest that reload options produce similar incentives as employee stock options and share grants.</description><author>Dybvig, P. H.; Loewenstein, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock return characteristics, Skew laws, and the differential pricing of individual equity options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, G.; Kapadia, N.; Madan, D.
This article provides several new insights into the economic sources of skewness. First, we document the differential pricing of individual equity options versus the market index and relate it to variations in return skewness. Second, we show. how risk aversion introduces skewness in the risk-neutral density. Third, we derive laws that decompose individual return skewness into a systematic component and an idiosyncratic component. Empirical analysis of OEX options and 30 stocks demonstrates that individual risk-neutral distributions differ from that of the market index by being far less negatively skewed. This article explains the presence and evolution of risk-neutral skewness over time and in the cross section of individual stocks.</description><author>Bakshi, G.; Kapadia, N.; Madan, D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Auctions vs. bookbuilding and the control of underpricing in hot IPO markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Derrien, F.; Womack, K. L.
Market returns before the offer price is set affect the amount and variability of initial public offering (IPO) underpricing. Thus an important question is "What IPO procedure is best adapted for controlling underpricing in "hot" versus "cold" market conditions?" The French stock market offers a unique arena for empirical research on this topic, since three substantially different issuing mechanisms (auctions, bookbuilding, and fixed price) are used there. Using 1992-1998 data, we find that the auction mechanism is associated with less underpricing and lower variance of underpricing. We show that the auction procedure's ability to incorporate more information from recent market conditions into the IPO price is an important reason.</description><author>Derrien, F.; Womack, K. L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of lockups in initial public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brav, A.; Gompers, P. A.
In a sample of 2,794 initial public offerings (IPOs), we test three potential explanations for the existence of IPO lockups: lockups serve as (i) a signal of firm quality, (ii) a commitment device to alleviate moral hazard problems, or (iii) a mechanism for underwriters to extract additional compensation from the issuing firm. Our results support the commitment hypothesis. Insiders of firms that are associated with greater potential for moral hazard lockup their shares for a longer period of time. Insiders of firms that have experienced larger excess returns, are backed by venture capitalists, or go public with high-quality underwriters are more likely to be released from the lockup restrictions.</description><author>Brav, A.; Gompers, P. A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incomplete consumption risk sharing and currency risk premiums</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarkissian, S.
This article studies the impact of imperfect consumption risk sharing across countries on the formation of time-varying risk premiums in the foreign exchange market and on their cross-sectional differences. These issues are addressed within the framework of the Constantinides and Duffie (1996) model applied to a multicountry world. The article shows that the cross-country variance of consumption growth rates is counter-cyclical and that this feature of consumption data is mildly helpful for currency pricing. In particular, unlike the standard CCAPM, the new model is able to generate currency risk premiums at lower values of risk aversion and provide certain explanatory power for cross-sectional differences in currency returns.</description><author>Sarkissian, S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information technology and financial services competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hauswald, R.; Marquez, R.
We analyze how two dimensions of technological progress affect competition in financial services. While better technology may result in improved information processing, it might also lead to low-cost or even free access to information through, for example, informational spillovers. In the context of credit screening, we show that better access to information decreases interest rates and the returns from screening. However, an improved ability to process information increases interest rates and bank profits. Hence predictions regarding financial claims' pricing hinge on the overall effect ascribed to technological progress. Our results generalize to other financial markets where informational asymmetries drive profitability, such as insurance and securities markets.</description><author>Hauswald, R.; Marquez, R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Greener pastures and the impact of dynamic institutional preferences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bennett, J. A.; Sias, R. W.; Starks, L. T.
Although institutional investors have a preference for large capitalization stocks, over time they have shifted their preferences toward smaller, riskier securities. These changes in aggregate preferences have arisen primarily from changes in the preferences of each class of institution, rather than changes in the importance of different classes. Evidence also suggests that recent growth in institutional investment combined with this shift in preferences helps explain why markets in general, and smaller stocks in particular, have exhibited greater firm-specific risk and liquidity in recent years. Additional analyses suggest that institutional investors moved toward smaller securities because such securities offer "greener pastures".</description><author>Bennett, J. A.; Sias, R. W.; Starks, L. T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-subsidies, external financing constraints, and the contribution of the internal capital market to firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Billett, M. T.; Mauer, D. C.
We examine the link between the excess value of a diversified firm and the value of its internal capital market. Subsidies to small financially constrained segments with good relative investment opportunities significantly increase excess value, while transfers of resources from segments with good relative investment opportunities significantly decrease excess value. Of interest is that subsidies to small financially constrained segments with poor relative investment opportunities also significantly increase excess value. However, there is little evidence that this result depends on the diversity of a firm's investment opportunities. We conclude that financing constraints drive the relationship between the internal capital market and firm value.</description><author>Billett, M. T.; Mauer, D. C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real flexibility and financial structure: An empirical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>MacKay, P.
I examine the empirical relation between real flexibility and financial structure. I test whether real flexibility increases debt capacity by lowering default risk and making assets more marketable or decreases debt capacity by facilitating risk shifting and asset substitution. I measure real flexibility as the sensitivity of marginal production and investment decisions to variations in the economic environment. I find that financial leverage is negatively related to production flexibility but positively related to investment flexibility. This split in results suggests that although asset substitution facilitated by investment flexibility can be prevented contractually, risk shifting facilitated by production flexibility is intractable.</description><author>MacKay, P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxes and corporate finance: A review</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, J. R.
This article reviews tax research related to domestic and multinational capital structure, payout policy, compensation policy, risk management, and organizational form. For each topic, the theoretical arguments explaining how taxes can affect corporate decision making and firm value are reviewed, followed by a summary of the related empirical evidence and a discussion of unresolved issues. Tax research generally supports the hypothesis that high tax rate firms pursue policies that provide tax benefits. Many issues remain unresolved, however, including understanding whether tax effects are of first-order importance, why firms do not pursue tax benefits more aggressively, and whether corporate actions are affected by investor-level taxes.</description><author>Graham, J. R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price discovery and trading after hours</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barclay, M. J.; Hendershott, T.
We examine the effects of trading after hours on the amount and timing of price discovery over the 24-hour day. A high volume of liquidity trade facilitates price discovery. Thus prices are more efficient and more information is revealed per hour during the trading day than after hours. However, the low trading volume after hours generates significant, albeit inefficient, price discovery. Individual trades contain more information after hours than during the day. Because information asymmetry declines over the day, price changes are larger, reflect more private information, and are less noisy before the open than after the close.</description><author>Barclay, M. J.; Hendershott, T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informal financial networks: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garmaise, M. J.; Moskowitz, T. J.
We develop a model of informal financial networks and present corroborating evidence by studying the role of property brokers in the U.S. commercial real estate market. Our model demonstrates that service intermediaries, who do not themselves supply loans, can facilitate their clients' access to finance through informal relationships with lenders. Empirically we find that, controlling for endogenous broker selection, hiring a broker strikingly increases the probability of obtaining bank finance. Our results demonstrate that even in the United States, with its well-developed capital markets, informal networks play an important role in controlling access to finance.</description><author>Garmaise, M. J.; Moskowitz, T. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional liquidity needs and the structure of monitored finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Winton, A.
A financial institution that finances and monitors firms learns private information about these firms. When the institution seeks funds to meet its own liquidity needs, it faces adverse selection ("liquidity") costs that increase with the risk of its claims on these firms. The institution can reduce its liquidity costs by holding debt rather than equity. Conversely, except in a limited setting resembling venture capital, firms that depend on monitored finance prefer to give the monitoring institution debt rather than equity. Institutions with less frequent or less severe liquidity needs have greater appetite for equity and for the debt of more risky borrowers. These predictions are consistent with general patterns of monitored finance.</description><author>Winton, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium investment strategies and output price behavior: A real-options approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aguerrevere, F. L.
The effects of competitive interactions on investment decisions and on the dynamics of the price of a nonstorable commodity are studied in a model of incremental investment with time to build and operating flexibility. I find that an increase in uncertainty may encourage firms to increase their capacity. Furthermore, I show that it may be optimal to invest in additional capacity during periods in which part of the operational capacity is not being utilized. The impact of competition on the properties of the endogenous output price is dramatic. For example, I find that price volatility may be increasing in the number of competitors in the industry.</description><author>Aguerrevere, F. L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Raids, rewards, and reputations in the market for managerial talent</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fee, C. E.; Hadlock, C. J.
We find that executives who jump to chief executive officer (CEO) positions at new employers come from firms that exhibit above-average stock price performance. This relationship is more pronounced for more senior executives. No such relationship exists for jumps to non-CEO positions. Stock options and restricted stock do not appear to significantly affect the likelihood of jumping ship, but the existence of an "heir apparent" on the management team increases the likelihood that executives will leave for non-CEO positions elsewhere. Hiring grants used to attract managers are correlated with the equity position forfeited at the prior employer and with the prior employer's performance.</description><author>Fee, C. E.; Hadlock, C. J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Statistical arbitrage and securities prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bondarenko, O.
This article introduces the concept of a statistical arbitrage opportunity (SAO). In a finite-horizon economy, a SAO is a zero-cost trading strategy for which (i) the expected payoff is positive, and (ii) the conditional expected payoff in each Final state of the economy is nonnegative. Unlike a pure arbitrage opportunity, a SAO can have negative payoffs provided that the average payoff in each final state is nonnegative. If the pricing kernel in the economy is path independent, then no SAOs can exist. Furthermore, ruling out SAOs imposes a novel martingale-type restriction on the dynamics of securities prices. The important properties of the restriction are that it (1) is model-free, in the sense that it requires no parametric assumptions about the true equilibrium model, (2) can be tested in samples affected by selection biases, such as the peso problem, and (3) continues to hold when investors' beliefs are mistaken. The article argues that one can use the new restriction to empirically resolve the joint hypothesis problem present in the traditional tests of the efficient market hypothesis.</description><author>Bondarenko, O.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Return distributions and improved tests of asset pricing models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vorkink, K.
We compare and contrast some existing ordinary least squares (OLS)- and generalized method of moments (GMM)-based tests of asset pricing models with a new more general test. This new test is valid under the assumption that returns are elliptically distributed, a necessary and sufficient assumption of the linear capital asset pricing model (CAPM). This new test fails to reject the CAPM on a dataset of stocks sorted by market valuations, whereas similar tests constructed from OLS and GMM estimation methods reject the linear CAPM. We also find that outliers reduce the OLS-estimated mispricing of the linear CAPM on monthly returns sorted by previous performance, that is, momentum. Monte Carlo evidence supports superior size and power properties of the new test relative to OLS- and GMM-based tests.</description><author>Vorkink, K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonlinear mean reversion in the short-term interest rate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, C. S.
Using a new Bayesian method for the analysis of diffusion processes, this article finds that the nonlinear drift in interest rates found in a number of previous studies can be confirmed only under prior distributions that are best described as informative. The assumption of stationarity, which is common in the literature, represents a nontrivial prior belief about the shape of the drift function. This belief and the use of "flat" priors contribute strongly to the finding of nonlinear mean reversion. Implementation of an approximate Jeffreys prior results in virtually no evidence for mean reversion in interest rates unless stationarity is assumed. Finally, the article documents that nonlinear drift is primarily a feature of daily rather than monthly data, and that these data contain a transitory element that is not reflected in the volatility of longer-maturity yields.</description><author>Jones, C. S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial development and financing constraints: International evidence from the structural investment model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Love, I.
This article provides evidence that financial development impacts growth by reducing financing constraints that would otherwise distort efficient allocation of investment. The financing constraints are inferred from the investment Euler equation by assuming that the firm's stochastic discount factor is a function of the firm's financial position (specifically, the stock of liquid assets). The magnitude of the changes in the cost of capital is twice as large in a country with a low level of financial development as in a country with an average level of financial development. The size effect, business cycles, and legal environment effects are also considered.</description><author>Love, I.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A new approach to measuring financial contagion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bae, K. H.; Karolyi, G. A.; Stulz, R. M.
This article proposes a new approach to evaluate contagion in financial markets. Our measure of contagion captures the coincidence of extreme return shocks across countries within a region and across regions. We characterize the extent of contagion, its economic significance, and its determinants using a multinomial logistic regression model. Applying our approach to daily returns of emerging markets during the 1990s, we find that contagion is predictable and depends on regional interest rates, exchange rate changes, and conditional stock return volatility. Evidence that contagion is stronger for extreme negative returns than for extreme positive returns is mixed.</description><author>Bae, K. H.; Karolyi, G. A.; Stulz, R. M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fundamental properties of bond prices in models of the short-term rate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mele, A.
This article develops restrictions that arbitrage-constrained bond prices impose on the short-term rate process in order to be consistent with given dynamic properties of the term structure of interest rates. The central focus is the relationship between bond prices and the short-term rate volatility. In both scalar and multidimensional diffusion settings, typical relationships between bond prices and volatility are generated by joint restrictions on the risk-neutralized drift functions of the state variables and convexity of bond prices with respect to the short-term rate. The theory is illustrated by several examples and is partially extended to accommodate the occurrence of jumps and default.</description><author>Mele, A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Term structure dynamics in theory and reality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dai, Q. A.; Singleton, K.
This article is a critical survey of models designed for pricing fixed-income securities and their associated term structures of market yields. Our primary focus is on the interplay between the theoretical specification of dynamic term structure models and their empirical fit to historical changes in the shapes of yield curves. We begin by overviewing the dynamic term structure models that have been fit to treasury or swap yield curves and in which the risk factors follow diffusions, jump-diffusion, or have "switching regimes." Then the goodness-of-fit of these models is assessed relative to their abilities to (i) match linear projections of changes in yields onto the slope of the yield curve; (ii) match the persistence of conditional volatilities, and the shapes of term structures of unconditional volatilities, of yields; and (iii) to reliably price caps, swaptions, and other fixed-income derivatives. For the case of defaultable securities we explore the relative fits to historical yield spreads.</description><author>Dai, Q. A.; Singleton, K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The design of financial policies in corporate spin-offs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mehrotra, V.; Mikkelson, W.; Partch, M.
We examine differences in financial leverage between parent and spun-off firms that emerge from corporate spin-offs. Our tests control for past financing choices and the costs of adjusting capital structure, factors that can obscure cross-sectional patterns among firms' target leverage ratios. We find that firms that emerge from spin-offs with more financial leverage have a higher cash flow return on assets, lower variability of industry operating income, and a greater proportion of fixed assets. The positive relation between profitability and the use of financial level-age, in a setting that is free of pecking order effects, is particularly important because it contrasts with existing evidence. Our results indicate that the ability to cover debt payments and default-related costs are important determinants of the use of financial leverage, as implied by the trade-off theory of capital structure. We find no evidence that managerial incentives or governance characteristics affect the difference in leverage ratios in firms that emerge from spin-offs.</description><author>Mehrotra, V.; Mikkelson, W.; Partch, M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structuring international cooperative ventures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Noe, T. H.; Rebello, M. J.; Shrikhande, M. M.
We examine the effect of bargaining power and informational asymmetry on the design of international cooperative ventures in the presence of restrictions on equity participation and investment. When the bargaining advantage rests with the multinational, equity participation restrictions can increase the profits to domestic firms and encourage suboptimal investment policies. Overinvestment occurs when the multinational's bargaining advantage is reinforced by an informational advantage, while underinvestment occurs when the domestic firm possesses the informational advantage. In contrast, when the bargaining advantage rests with the domestic firm, equity participation restrictions do not affect investment levels.</description><author>Noe, T. H.; Rebello, M. J.; Shrikhande, M. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How firms should hedge</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, G. W.; Toft, K. B.
Substantial academic research explains why firms should hedge, but little work has addressed how firms should hedge. We assume that firms can experience costly states of nature and derive optimal hedging strategies using vanilla derivatives (e.g., forwards and options) and custom "exotic" derivative contracts for a value-maximizing firm facing both hedgable (price) and unhedgable (quantity) risks. Customized exotic derivatives are typically better than vanilla contracts when correlations between prices and quantities are large in magnitude and when quantity risks are substantially greater than price risks. Finally, we discuss how our model may be applied in practice.</description><author>Brown, G. W.; Toft, K. B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock return predictability: A Bayesian model selection perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, K. J. M.
Attempts to characterize stock return predictability have resulted in little consensus on the important conditioning variables, giving rise to model uncertainty and data snooping fears. We introduce a new methodology that explicitly incorporates model uncertainty by comparing all possible models simultaneously and in which the priors are calibrated to reflect economically meaningful information. Our approach minimizes data snooping given the information set and the priors. We compare the prior views of a skeptic and a confident investor. The data imply posterior probabilities that are in general more supportive of stock return predictability than the priors for both types of investors.</description><author>Cremers, K. J. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An isomorphism between asset pricing models with and without linear habit formation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schroder, M.; Skiadas, C.
We show an isomorphism between optimal portfolio selection or competitive equilibrium models with utilities incorporating linear habit formation, and corresponding models without habit formation. The isomorphism can be used to mechanically transform known solutions not involving habit formation to corresponding solutions with habit formation. For example, the Constantinides (1990) and Ingersoll (1992) solutions are mechanically obtained from the familiar Merton solutions for the additive utility case, without recourse to a Bellman equation or first-order conditions. More generally, recent solutions to portfolio selection problems with recursive utility and a stochastic investment opportunity set are readily transformed to novel solutions of corresponding problems with utility that combines recursivity with habit formation. The methodology also applies in the context of Hindy-Huang-Kreps (1992) preferences, where our isomorphism shows that the solution obtained by Hindy and Huang (1993) can be mechanically transformed to Dybvig's (1995) solution to the optimal consumption-investment problem with consumption ratcheting.</description><author>Schroder, M.; Skiadas, C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International asset allocation with regime shifts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, A.; Bekaert, G.
Correlations between international equity market returns tend to increase in highly volatile bear markets, which has led some to doubt the benefits of international diversification. This article solves the dynamic portfolio choice problem of a U.S. investor faced with a time-varying investment opportunity set modeled using a regime-switching process which may be characterized by correlations and volatilities that increase in bad times. International diversification is still valuable with regime changes and currency hedging imparts further benefit. The costs of ignoring the regimes are small for all-equity portfolios but increase when a conditionally risk-free asset can be held.</description><author>Ang, A.; Bekaert, G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading and pricing in upstairs and downstairs stock markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Booth, G. G.; Lin, J. C.; Martikainen, T.; Tse, Y.
We provide empirical evidence on the economic benefits of negotiating trades in the upstairs trading room of brokerage firms relative to the downstairs market. Using Helsinki Stock Exchange data, we find that upstairs trades tend to have lower information content and lower price impacts than downstairs trades. This is consistent with the hypotheses that the upstairs market is better at pricing uninformed liquidity trades and that upstairs brokers can give better prices to their customers if they know the unexpressed demands of other customers. We find that these economic benefits depend on price discovery occurring in the downstairs market.</description><author>Booth, G. G.; Lin, J. C.; Martikainen, T.; Tse, Y.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price formation and market quality when the number and presence of insiders is unknown</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schnitzlein, C. R.
In most models of market microstructure tractability requires that all market participants know the number (and presence) of competing insiders. I drop this assumption in experimental asset markets. Outcomes are qualitatively consistent with theoretical models when the number of insiders is disclosed prior to trade. When it is not, insiders use the timing and size of trades interactively to hide from the dealers and each other, dealers have difficulty identifying insider trades, and liquidity patterns do not differ as a function of the number of insiders. In general, insider behavior has strategic dimensions not admitted in Kyle (1985) and extensions.</description><author>Schnitzlein, C. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The informational role of stock and option volume</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, K.; Chung, Y. P.; Fong, W. M.
This article analyzes the intraday interdependence of order flows and price movements for actively traded NYSE stocks and their Chicago Board Options Exchange (CBOE)-traded options. Stock net trade volume (buyer-initiated volume minus seller-initiated volume) has strong predictive ability for stock and option quote revisions, but option net trade volume has no incremental predictive ability. This suggests that informed investors initiate trades in the stock market but not in the option market. On the other hand, both stock and option quote revisions have predictive ability for each other. Thus, while information in the stock market is contained in both quote revisions and trades, information in the option market is contained only in quote revisions.</description><author>Chan, K.; Chung, Y. P.; Fong, W. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic volume-return relation of individual stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Llorente, G.; Michaely, R.; Saar, G.; Wang, J.
We examine the dynamic relation between return and volume of individual stocks. Using a simple model in which investors trade to share risk or speculate on private information, we show that returns generated by risk-sharing trades tend to reverse themselves, while returns generated by speculative trades tend to continue themselves. We test this theoretical prediction by analyzing the relation between daily volume and first-order return autocorrelation for individual stocks listed on the NYSE and AMEX. We find that the cross-sectional variation in the relation between volume and return autocorrelation is related to the extent of informed trading in a manner consistent with the theoretical prediction.</description><author>Llorente, G.; Michaely, R.; Saar, G.; Wang, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentive-compatible contracts for the sale of information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Biais, B.; Germain, L.
An informed financial institution can trade on private information and also sell it to clients through a managed fund. To provide an incentive for the informed agent to trade in the interest of her client, the optimal contract requires that she be compensated as an increasing function of the profits of the fund. The optimal contract is also designed to limit the aggressiveness of the sum of the fund's trade and the proprietary trade. This reduces information revelation and thus leads to greater overall trading profits than if the informed agent only conducted proprietary trades.</description><author>Biais, B.; Germain, L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nondiscriminating foreclosure and voluntary liquidating costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, K.; Young, L.; Zhou, Y. Q.
Since liquidation and bankruptcy are costly, researchers have tried to find out why the claimants of a troubled firm do not work out a deal to avoid these costs. In this article we show that if a creditor has to deal with multiple borrowers who might default, it may be optimal for the creditor to randomly reject requests for a loan workout. We further demonstrate that the optimal acceptance rate used by a creditor is positively related to the liquidating cost and negatively related to the default benefit. Our model is particularly relevant when analyzing the default decisions of mortgage borrowers and small business owners.</description><author>Wang, K.; Young, L.; Zhou, Y. Q.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial innovation and information: The role of derivatives when a market for information exists</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, M.
We study the effects of financial innovation in a model of endogenous information acquisition. We deter-mine the conditions under which the introduction of a derivative written on an existing stock increases or decreases the incentive to purchase information. We show that financial innovation produces some effects which hold across informational structures and others which differ. The former coincide with the few empirical results that are robust in the literature (effects on prices, risk premia, and volatility), while the latter coincide with the ones that differ experiment by experiment (effects on volume, correlation between volume and volatility, and market informational efficiency).</description><author>Massa, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition, adverse selection, and information dispersion in the banking industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marquez, R.
Proprietary information generated through the process of lending can impact the structure of the banking industry. With more competing banks, borrower-specific information becomes more disperse, as each bank becomes informed about a smaller pool of borrowers. This reduces banks' screening ability. creating an inefficiency as more tow-quality borrowers obtain financing. Incumbent banks' information advantage may also create difficulties for potential entrants, so that entry should be easier in markets with high borrower turnover or where entrants have specific expertise in evaluating credit risks. We draw implications for whether financial deregulation is likely to increase borrowers' surplus, and what patterns of entry might be observed.</description><author>Marquez, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why new issues and high-accrual firms underperform: The role of analysts' credulity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Teoh, S. H.; Wong, T. J.
We find that analysts' forecast errors are predicted by past accounting accruals (adjustments to cash flows to obtain reported earnings) among both equity issuers and nonissuers. Analysts are more optimistic for the subsequent four years for issuers reporting higher issue-year accruals. The predictive power is greater for discretionary accruals than nondiscretionary accruals and is independent of the presence of an underwriting affiliation. Predicted forecast errors from accruals significantly explain the long-term underperformance of new issuers. The predictability of forecast errors among nonissuers suggests that analysts' credulity about accruals management more generally contributes to market inefficiency.</description><author>Teoh, S. H.; Wong, T. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk arbitrage in takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornelli, F.; Li, D. D.
This article studies the role of risk arbitrageurs in takeovers and the source of their advantage. We show how the presence of arbitrageurs affects the value of the target shares, since arbitrageurs are more likely to tender. Therefore an arbitrageur has the informational advantage of knowing he bought shares. In equilibrium, the number of arbitrageurs buying shares and the price they pay are deter-mined endogenously. We also present several empirical implications, including the relationship among trading volume, takeover premium, liquidity of the shares, and the number of risk arbitrageurs investing in one particular deal.</description><author>Cornelli, F.; Li, D. D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal portfolio selection with transaction costs and finite horizons</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, H.; Loewenstein, M.
We examine the optimal trading strategy for a CRRA investor who maximizes the expected utility of wealth on a finite date and faces transaction costs. Closed-form solutions are obtained when this date is uncertain. We then show a sequence of analytical solutions converge to the solution to the problem with a deterministic finite horizon. Consistent with the common life-cycle investment advice, the optimal trading strategy is found to be horizon dependent and largely buy and hold. Moreover, it might be optimal for the investor in our model not to buy any stock, even when the risk premium is positive. Further analysis of the optimal policy is also provided.</description><author>Liu, H.; Loewenstein, M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are the Fama and French factors global or country specific?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, J. M.
This article examines whether country-specific or global versions of Fama and French's three-factor model better explain time-series variation in international stock returns. Regressions for portfolios and individual stocks indicate that domestic factor models explain much more time-series variation in returns and generally have lower pricing errors than the world factor model. In addition, decomposing the world factors into domestic and foreign components demonstrates that the addition of foreign factors to domestic models leads to less accurate in-sample and out-of-sample pricing. Practical applications of the three-factor model, such as cost of capital calculations and performance evaluations, are best performed on a country-specific basis.</description><author>Griffin, J. M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic factors do influence aggregate stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Flannery, M. J.; Protopapadakis, A. A.
Stock market returns are significantly correlated with inflation and money growth. The impact of real macroeconomic variables on aggregate equity returns has been difficult to establish, perhaps because their effects are neither linear nor time invariant. We estimate a GARCH model of daily equity returns, where realized returns and their conditional volatility depend on 17 macro series' announcements. We find six candidates for priced factors: three nominal (CPI, PPI, and a Monetary Aggregate) and three real (Balance of Trade, Employment Report, and Housing Starts). Popular measures of overall economic activity, such as Industrial Production or GNP are not represented.</description><author>Flannery, M. J.; Protopapadakis, A. A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of leverage on bidding behavior: Theory and evidence from the FCC auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Clayton, M. J.; Ravid, S. A.
This is an exploration of how bidding behavior of firms in various auctions is affected by their capital structure. The theoretical model considers a first-price sealed bid and an English auction. We find that as debt levels increase, firms tend to reduce their bids. The lower bids give the competition incentives to reduce their bids as well, These results are investigated empirically using data from the 1994-1995 FCC spectrum auctions. Consistent with the theoretical model, higher debt levels of the bidding firm and of the competition tend to lead to lower bids. Additional determinants of bidding behavior in these auctions are also analyzed.</description><author>Clayton, M. J.; Ravid, S. A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option exercise games: An application to the equilibrium investment strategies of firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grenadier, S. R.
Under the standard real options approach to investment under uncertainty, agents formulate optimal exercise strategies in isolation and ignore competitive interactions. However, in many real-world asset markets, exercise strategies cannot be determined separately. but must be formed as part of a strategic equilibrium. This article provides a tractable approach for deriving equilibrium investment strategies in a continuous-time Cournot-Nash framework. The impact of competition on exercise strategies is dramatic. For example, while standard real options models emphasize that a valuable "option to wait" leads firms to invest only at large positive net present values, the impact of competition drastically erodes the value of the option to wait and leads to investment at very near the zero net present value threshold.</description><author>Grenadier, S. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discussion of "Underreaction to self-selected news events"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Titman, S.
nan</description><author>Titman, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferson, W.
nan</description><author>Ferson, W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Introduction to Review of Financial Studies conference on market frictions and behavioral finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heaton, J.; Korajczyk, R.
nan</description><author>Heaton, J.; Korajczyk, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robustness and pricing with uncertain growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cagetti, M.; Hansen, L. P.; Sargent, T.; Williams, N.
We study how decision-makers' concerns about robustness affect prices and quantities in a stochastic growth model. In the model economy, growth rates in technology are altered by infrequent large shocks and continuous small shocks. An investor observes movements in the technology level but cannot perfectly distinguish their sources. Instead the investor solves a signal extraction problem. We depart from most of the macroeconomics and finance literature by presuming that the investor treats the specification of technology evolution as an approximation. To promote a decision rule that is robust to model misspecification. an investor acts as if a malevolent player threatens to perturb the actual data-generating process relative to his approximating model. We study how a concern about robustness alters asset prices. We show that the dynamic evolution of the risk-return trade-off is dominated by movements in the growth-state probabilities and that the evolution of the dividend-price ratio is driven primarily by the capital-technology ratio.</description><author>Cagetti, M.; Hansen, L. P.; Sargent, T.; Williams, N.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discussion of "Robustness and pricing with uncertain growth"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maenhout, P. J.
nan</description><author>Maenhout, P. J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why don't issuers get upset about leaving money on the table in IPOs?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loughran, T.; Ritter, J. R.
One of the puzzles regarding initial public offerings (IPOs) is that issuers rarely get upset about leaving substantial amounts of money on the table, defined as the number of shares sold times the difference between the first-day closing market price and the offer price. The average IPO leaves $9.1 million on the table. This number is approximately twice as large as the fees paid to investment bankers and represents a substantial indirect cost to the issuing firm. We present a prospect theory model that focuses on the covariance of the money left on the table and wealth changes. Our reasoning also provides an explanation for a second puzzling pattern: much more money is left on the table following recent market rises than after market falls. This results in an explanation of hot issue markets. We also offer a new explanation for why IPOs are underpriced.</description><author>Loughran, T.; Ritter, J. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discussion of "Why don't issuers get upset about leaving money on the table in IPOs?"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Daniel, K.
nan</description><author>Daniel, K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Online investors: Do the slow die first?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barber, B. M.; Odean, T.
We analyze 1,607 investors who switched from phone-based to online trading during the 1990s. Those who switch to online trading perform well prior to going online, beating the market by more than 2% annually. After going online, they trade more actively, more speculatively, and less profitably than before-tagging the market by more than 3% annually. Reductions in market frictions (lower trading costs, improved execution speed, and greater ease of access) do not explain these findings. Overconfidence-augmented by self-attribution bias and the illusions of knowledge and control-can explain the increase in trading and reduction in performance of online investors.</description><author>Barber, B. M.; Odean, T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Underreaction to self-selected news events: The case of stock splits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ikenberry, D. L.; Ramnath, S.
An emerging literature looking at self-selected, corporate news events concludes that markets appear to underreact to news. Recent theoretical articles have explored why or how underreaction might occur. However, the notion of underreaction is contentious. We revisit this issue by focusing on one of the most simple of corporate transactions, the stock split. Prior studies that report abnormal return drifts subsequent to splits do not appear to be spurious, nor a consequence of misspecified benchmarks. Using recent cases, we report a drift of 9% in the year following a split announcement. We consider fundamental operating performance as a source of the underreaction and find that splitting firms have an unusually low propensity to experience a contraction in future earnings. Further, analysts' earnings forecasts are comparatively low at the time of the split announcement and revise sluggishly over time. Together these results are consistent with the notion of market underreaction to the information in corporate news events.</description><author>Ikenberry, D. L.; Ramnath, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum and autocorrelation in stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lewellen, J.
This article studies momentum in stock returns, focusing on the role of industry, size, and book-to-market (B/M) factors. Size and B/M portfolios exhibit momentum as strong as that in individual stocks and industries. The size and B/M portfolios are well diversified, so momentum cannot be attributed to firm- or industry-specific returns. Further, industry, size, and B/M portfolios are negatively autocorrelated and cross-serially correlated over intermediate horizons. The evidence suggests that stocks covary "too strongly" with each other. I argue that excess covariance, not underreaction, explains momentum in the portfolios.</description><author>Lewellen, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discussion of "Momentum and autocorrelation in stock returns"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, J.; Hong, H.
nan</description><author>Chen, J.; Hong, H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competing theories of financial anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brav, A.; Heaton, J. B.
We compare two competing theories of financial anomalies: "behavioral" theories built on investor irrationality, and "rational structural uncertainty" theories built on incomplete information about the structure of the economic environment. We find that although the theories relax opposite assumptions of the rational expectations ideal, their mathematical and predictive similarities make them difficult to distinguish. Even if irrationality generates financial anomalies, their disappearance still may hinge on rational learning-that is, on the ability of rational arbitrageurs and their investors to reject competing rational explanations for observed price patterns.</description><author>Brav, A.; Heaton, J. B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discussion of "Competing theories of financial anomalies"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Bondt, W.
nan</description><author>De Bondt, W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sidelined investors, trading-generated news, and security returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, H. H.; Coval, J. D.; Hirshleifer, D.
This article studies information blockages and the asymmetric release of information in a security market with fixed setup costs of trading. In this setting, "sidelined" investors may delay trading until price movements validate their private signals. Trading thereby internally generates the arrival of further news to the market. This leads to (1) negative skewness following price run-ups and positive skewness following price rundowns (even though the model is ex ante symmetric), (2) a lack of correspondence between large price changes and the arrival of external information, and (3) increases in volatility following large price changes.</description><author>Cao, H. H.; Coval, J. D.; Hirshleifer, D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discussion of "Sidelined investors, trading-generated news, and security returns"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Veronesi, P.
nan</description><author>Veronesi, P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Partial adjustment or stale prices? Implications from stock index and futures return autocorrelations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, D. H.; Boudoukh, J.; Richardson, M.; Whitelaw, R. F.
We investigate the relation between returns on stock indices and their corresponding futures contracts to evaluate potential explanations for the pervasive yet anomalous evidence of positive, short-horizon portfolio autocorrelations, Using a simple theoretical framework, we generate empirical implications for both microstructure and partial adjustment models. The major findings are (i) return autocorrelations of indices are generally positive even though futures contracts have autocorrelations close to zero, and (ii) these autocorrelation differences are maintained under conditions favorable for spot-futures arbitrage and are most prevalent during low-volume periods. These results point toward microstructure-based explanations and away from explanations based on behavioral models.</description><author>Ahn, D. H.; Boudoukh, J.; Richardson, M.; Whitelaw, R. F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical analysis of personal bankruptcy and delinquency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gross, D. B.; Souleles, N. S.
This article uses a new dataset of credit card accounts to analyze credit card delinquency, personal bankruptcy, and the stability of credit risk models. We estimate duration models for default and assess the relative importance of different variables in predicting default. We investigate how the propensity to default has changed over time, disentangling the two leading explanations for the recent increase in default rates-a deterioration in the risk composition of borrowers versus an increase in borrowers' willingness to default due to declines in default costs. Even after controlling for risk composition and economic fundamentals, the propensity to default significantly increased between 1995 and 1997. Standard default models missed an important time-varying default factor, consistent with a decline in default costs.</description><author>Gross, D. B.; Souleles, N. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor activism and financial market structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Noe, T. H.
This article investigates investor activism when there are a number of strategic investors that are capable of intervening in corporate governance. These strategic investors can monitor and/or trade in anonymous financial markets. In equilibrium, a core group of monitoring investors emerges endogenously to curtail managerial opportunism. These core activists both intervene and trade aggressively. Although the smallest investors are passive, there is no monotonic relationship between the size of preexisting shareholdings and activism. In fact, among those investors who choose activism, those with the smallest holdings are the most aggressive.</description><author>Noe, T. H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quadratic term structure models: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, D. H.; Dittmar, R. F.; Gallant, A. R.
This article theoretically explores the characteristics underpinning quadratic term structure models (QTSMs), which designate the yield on a bond as a quadratic function of underlying state variables. We develop a comprehensive QTSM, which is maximally flexible and thus encompasses the features of several diverse models including the double square-root model of Longstaff (1989), the univariate quadratic model of Beaglehole and Tenney (1992), and the squared-autoregressive-independent-variable nominal term structure (SAINTS) model of Constantinides (1992). We document a complete classification of admissibility and empirical identification for the QTSM, and demonstrate that the QTSM can overcome limitations inherent in affine term structure models (ATSMs). Using the efficient method of moments of Gallant and Tauchen (1996). we test the empirical performance of the model in determining bond prices and compare the performance to the ATSMs. The results of the goodness-of-fit tests suggest that the QTSMs outperform the ATSMs in explaining historical bond price behavior in the United States.</description><author>Ahn, D. H.; Dittmar, R. F.; Gallant, A. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing interest rate derivatives: A general approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chacko, G.; Das, S.
The relationship between affine stochastic processes and bond pricing equations in exponential term structure models has been well established. We connect this result to the pricing of interest rate derivatives. If the term structure model is exponential affine, then there is a linkage between the bond pricing solution and the prices of many widely traded interest rate derivative securities. Our results apply to m-factor processes with n diffusions and I jump processes. The pricing solutions require at most a single numerical integral, making the model easy to implement. We discuss many options that yield solutions using the methods of the article.</description><author>Chacko, G.; Das, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing trade-off and pecking order predictions about dividends and debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, E. F.; French, K. R.
Confirming predictions shared by the trade-off and pecking order models, more profitable firms and firms with fewer investments have higher dividend payouts. Confirming the pecking order model but contradicting the trade-off model, more profitable firms are less levered. Firms with more investments have less market leverage, which is consistent with the trade-off model and a complex pecking order model. Firms with more investments have lower long-term dividend payouts, but dividends do not vary to accommodate short-term variation in investment. As the pecking order model predicts, short-term variation in investment and earnings is mostly absorbed by debt.</description><author>Fama, E. F.; French, K. R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When are real options exercised? An empirical study of mine closings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moel, A.; Tufano, P.
In this article, we study a well-known real option: the opening and closing of mines. Using a new database that tracks the annual opening and closing decisions of 285 developed North American gold mines in the period 1988-1997, we find that the real options model is a useful descriptor of mines' opening and shutting decisions. In addition, we find that the decision whether to shut a mine is related to firm-specific managerial factors not normally considered within a strict real options model.</description><author>Moel, A.; Tufano, P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Persistence and reversal in herd behavior: Theory and application to the decision to go public</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nelson, L.
We model rational herd behavior when the underlying value changes over time, with payoffs that are either dependent or independent of the underlying value. We show that herding does not last forever and is not monotone in signal quality. High correlation among agents' actions does not necessarily imply herding. This suggests alternative empirical methods are needed to detect herding. The model has many applications, including the IPO decision in which payoffs are state dependent. The model implies that the decision to go public is more likely associated with herding than the decision to delay an IPO.</description><author>Nelson, L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The investor recognition hypothesis in a dynamic general equilibrium: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shapiro, A.
This article analyzes a dynamic general equilibrium under a generalization of Merton's (1987) investor recognition hypothesis. A class of informationally constrained investors is assumed to implement only a particular trading strategy. The model implies that, all else being equal, a risk premium on a less visible stock need not be higher than that on a more visible stock with a lower volatility-contrary to results derived in a static mean-variance setting. A consumption-based capital asset pricing model (CAPM) augmented by the generalized investor recognition hypothesis emerges as a viable contender for explaining the cross-sectional variation in unconditional expected equity returns.</description><author>Shapiro, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-sectional and time-series determinants of momentum returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jegadeesh, N.; Titman, S.
Portfolio strategies that buy stocks with high returns over the previous 3-12 months and sell stocks with low returns over this same time period perform well over the following 12 months. A recent article by Conrad and Kaul (1998) presents striking evidence suggesting that the momentum profits are attributable to cross-sectional differences in expected returns rather than to any time-series dependence in returns. This article shows that Conrad and Kaul reach this conclusion because they do not take into account the small sample biases in their tests and bootstrap experiments. Our unbiased empirical tests indicate that cross-sectional differences in expected returns explain very little, if any, of the momentum profits.</description><author>Jegadeesh, N.; Titman, S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the limit order routing decision matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Battalio, R.; Greene, J.; Hatch, B.; Jennings, R.
We examine the impact deciding to route limit orders away from the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) has on three dimensions of execution quality with methodologies controlling for market conditions and order submission strategies. Overall differences in limit order execution quality between regional stock exchanges and the NYSE are small, suggesting that the order routing decision may not affect retail limit order traders substantively. Conditioning on the distance between the limit order's price and prevailing quotes, however reveals systematic differences in execution quality. This implies that brokers can strategically route limit orders to improve retail limit order execution quality.</description><author>Battalio, R.; Greene, J.; Hatch, B.; Jennings, R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The informational efficiency of the corporate bond market: An intraday analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hotchkiss, E. S.; Ronen, T.
Using a unique dataset based on daily and hourly high-yield bond transaction prices, we find the informational efficiency of corporate bond prices is similar to that of the underlying stocks. We find that stocks do not lead bonds in reflecting firm-specific information. We further examine price behavior around earnings news and find that information is quickly incorporated into both bond and stock prices, even at short return horizons. Finally, we find that measures of market quality are no poorer for the bonds in our sample than for the underlying stocks.</description><author>Hotchkiss, E. S.; Ronen, T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate bond valuation and hedging with stochastic interest rates and endogenous bankruptcy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, V. V.; Carpenter, J. N.
This paper analyzes corporate bond valuation and optimal call and default rules when interest rates and firm value are stochastic. It then uses the results to explain the dynamics of hedging. Bankruptcy rules are important determinants of corporate bond sensitivity to interest rates and firm value. Although endogenous and exogenous bankruptcy models can be calibrated to produce the same prices, they can have very different hedging implications. We show that empirical results on the relation between corporate spreads and Treasury rates provide evidence on duration, and we find that the endogenous model explains the empirical patterns better than do typical exogenous models.</description><author>Acharya, V. V.; Carpenter, J. N.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The long-term performance of corporate bonds (and stocks) following seasoned equity offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eberhart, A. C.; Siddique, A.
Previous studies document negative long-term abnormal stock returns following seasoned equity offering (SEO) issuances and conclude that markets are inefficient. Other studies, however, argue that these results are a manifestation of risk mismeasurement (i.e., the bad-model problem), not market inefficiency. We test the efficient market hypothesis (EMH) and avoid the bad-model problem by examining the long-term performance of our sample firms' bonds and stocks following their SEOs. Our results are inconsistent with the EMH. We also provide evidence that SEOs transfer wealth from shareholders to bondholders because SEOs reduce default risk.</description><author>Eberhart, A. C.; Siddique, A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On mutual fund investment styles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, L. K. C.; Chen, H. L.; Lakonishok, J.
Most mutual funds adopt investment styles that cluster around a broad market benchmark. Few funds take extreme positions away from the index, but those who do are more likely to favor growth stocks and past winners. The bias toward glamour and the tendency of poorly performing value funds to shift styles may reflect agency and behavioral considerations. After adjusting for style, there is evidence that growth managers on average outperform value managers. Though a fund's factor loadings and its portfolio characteristics generally yield similar conclusions about its style, an approach using portfolio characteristics predicts fund returns better.</description><author>Chan, L. K. C.; Chen, H. L.; Lakonishok, J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulating access to international large-value payment systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holthausen, C.; Ronde, T.
This article studies access regulation to international large-value payment systems when banking supervision is national. We focus on the choice between net and real-time gross settlement. As a novel feature, the communication between the public authorities is endogenized. It is shown that the national authorities' incentives are not perfectly aligned concerning the settlement method. Therefore public regulation fails to implement the first-best access criteria. Banks prefer net settlement too often due to limited liability. Still, if banks have superior information about their counterparties, private involvement in access regulation is desirable as it reveals information to the public authorities.</description><author>Holthausen, C.; Ronde, T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The asymmetric relation between initial margin requirements and stock market volatility across bull and bear markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hardouvelis, G. A.; Theodossiou, P.
Higher initial margin requirements are associated with lower subsequent stock market volatility during normal and bull periods, but show no relationship during bear periods. Higher margins are also negatively related to the conditional mean of stock returns, apparently because they reduce systemic risk. We conclude that a prudential rule for setting margins (or other regulatory restrictions) is to lower them in sharply declining markets in order to enhance liquidity and avoid a depyramiding effect in stock prices, but subsequently raise them and keep them at the higher level in order to prevent a future pyramiding effect.</description><author>Hardouvelis, G. A.; Theodossiou, P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Demand curves and the pricing of money management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, S. E. K.; Musto, D. K.
One reason why funds charge different prices to their investors is that they face different demand curves. One source of differentiation is asset retention: Performance-sensitive investors migrate from worse to better prospects, taking their performance sensitivity with them. In the cross-section we show that past attrition significantly influences the current pricing of retail but not institutional funds. In time-series we show that the repricing of retail funds after merging in new shareholders is predicted by the estimated effect on its demand curve. This result is robust to other influences on repricing, including asset and account-size changes.</description><author>Christoffersen, S. E. K.; Musto, D. K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fee speech: Signaling, risk-sharing, and the impact of fee structures on investor welfare</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Das, S. R.; Sundaram, R. K.
The fee structure used to compensate investment advisers is central to the study of fund design, and affects investor welfare in at least three ways: (i) by influencing the portfolio-selection incentives of the adviser, (ii) by affecting risk-sharing between adviser and investor, and (iii) through its use as a signal of quality by superior investment advisers. In this paper, we describe a model in which all of these features are present, and use it to compare two popular and contrasting forms of fee contracts, the "fulcrum" and the "incentive" types, from the standpoint of investor welfare. While the former has some undeniably attractive features (that have, in particular, been used by regulators to justify its mandatory use in a mutual fund context), we find surprisingly that it is the latter that is often more attractive from the standpoint of investor welfare. Our model is a flexible one; our conclusions are shown to be robust to many extensions of interest. The results are also extended to consider unrestricted fee structures and competitive markets for fund managers.</description><author>Das, S. R.; Sundaram, R. K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual fund survivorship</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carhart, M. M.; Carpenter, J. N.; Lynch, A. W.; Musto, D. K.
This article provides a comprehensive study of survivorship issues using the mutual fund data of Carhart (1997). We demonstrate theoretically that when survival depends on multiperiod performance, the survivorship bias in average performance typically increases with the sample length. This is empirically relevant because evidence suggests a multiyear survival rule for U.S. mutual funds. In the data we find the annual bias increases from 0.07% for 1-year samples to 1% for samples longer than 15 years. We find that survivor conditioning weakens evidence of performance persistence. Finally, we explain how survivor conditioning affects the relation between performance and fund characteristics.</description><author>Carhart, M. M.; Carpenter, J. N.; Lynch, A. W.; Musto, D. K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comparing financial systems.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thakor, A. V.
nan</description><author>Thakor, A. V.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An analysis of default correlations and multiple defaults</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhou, C. S.
Evaluating default correlations or the probabilities of default by more than one firm is an important task in credit analysis, derivatives pricing, and risk management. However, default correlations cannot be measured directly, multiple-default modeling is technically difficult, and most existing credit models cannot be applied to analyze multiple defaults. This article develops a first-passage-time model, providing an analytical formula for calculating default correlations that is easily implemented and conveniently used for a variety of financial applications. The model also provides a theoretical justification for several empirical regularities in the credit risk literature.</description><author>Zhou, C. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial constraints and stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lamont, O.; Polk, C.; Saa-Requejo, J.
We test whether the impact of financial constraints on firm value is observable in stock returns. We form portfolios of firms based on observable characteristics related to financial constraints and test for common variation in stock returns. Financially constrained firms' stock returns move together over time, suggesting that constrained firms are subject to common shocks. Constrained firms have low average stock returns in our 1968-1997 sample of growing manufacturing firms. We find no evidence that the relative performance of constrained firms reflects monetary policy, credit conditions, or business cycles.</description><author>Lamont, O.; Polk, C.; Saa-Requejo, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The price of a smile: Hedging and spanning in option markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buraschi, A.; Jackwerth, J.
The volatility smile changed drastically around the crash of 1987, and new option pricing models have been proposed to accommodate that change. Deterministic volatility models allow for more flexible volatility surfaces but refrain from introducing additional risk factors. Thus, options are still redundant securities. Alternatively, stochastic models introduce additional risk factors, and options are then needed for spanning of the pricing kernel. We develop a statistical test based on this difference in spanning. Using daily S&amp;P 500 index options data from 1986-1995, our tests suggest that both in- and out-of-the-money options are needed for spanning. The findings are inconsistent with deterministic volatility models but are consistent with stochastic models that incorporate additional priced risk factors, such as stochastic volatility, interest rates, or jumps.</description><author>Buraschi, A.; Jackwerth, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Technological innovation and initial public offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maksimovic, V.; Pichler, P.
This article shows how both technological and competitive risks affect the timing of private and initial public offerings in an emerging industry. Early private financing occurs in industries that are perceived to be risky, with high development costs and low probability of being displaced by technologically superior rivals. Early public financing occurs in industries perceived to be viable, with low development costs and low probability of displacement. Due to feedback effects between financial and product markets, the value of investors proprietary information is greater in private than in initial public offerings. This has implications for underpricing.</description><author>Maksimovic, V.; Pichler, P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Underpricing and entrepreneurial wealth losses in IPOs: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Habib, M. A.; Ljungqvist, A. P.
We model owners as solving a multidimensional problem when taking their firms public. Owners can affect the level of underpricing through the choices they make in promoting an issue, such as which underwriter to hire or on what exchange to list. The benefits of reducing underpricing in this way depend on the owners' participation in the offering and the magnitude of the dilution they suffer on retained shares, We argue that the extent to which owners trade off underpricing and promotion is determined by the minimization of their wealth losses. Evidence from a sample of U.S. initial public offering confirms our empirical predictions.</description><author>Habib, M. A.; Ljungqvist, A. P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal portfolio choice and the valuation of illiquid securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longstaff, F. A.
Traditional models of portfolio choice assume that investors can continuously trade unlimited amounts of securities. In reality, investors face liquidity constraints. I analyze a model where investors are restricted to trading strategies that are of bounded variation. An investor facing this type of illiquidity behaves very differently from an unconstrained investor. A liquidity-constrained investor endogenously acts as if facing borrowing and short-selling constraints, and one may take riskier positions than in liquid markets. I solve for the shadow cost of illiquidity and show that large price discounts can be sustained in a rational model.</description><author>Longstaff, F. A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Value-at-risk-based risk management: Optimal policies and asset prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basak, S.; Shapiro, A.
This article analyzes optimal, dynamic portfolio and wealth/consumption policies of utility maximizing investors who must also manage market-risk exposure using Value-at-Risk (VaR). We find that VaR risk managers often optimally choose a larger exposure to risky assets than non-risk managers and consequently incur larger losses when losses occur. We suggest an alternative risk-management model, based on the expectation of a loss, to remedy the shortcomings of VaR. A general-equilibrium analysis reveals that the presence of VaR risk managers amplifies the stock-market volatility at times of down markets and attenuates the volatility at times of up markets.</description><author>Basak, S.; Shapiro, A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficient trading strategies in the presence of market frictions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jouini, E.; Kallal, H.
We provide a price characterization of efficient contingent claims-that is, chosen by at least a rational agent-in multiperiod economies with market frictions. Frictions include market incompleteness, transaction costs, short-selling, and borrowing costs. We characterize the inefficiency cost of a trading strategy-its required investment minus the largest amount necessary to obtain the same utility level-and we propose a measure of portfolio performance. We show that arbitrage bounds cannot be tightened based on efficiency without restricting preferences or endowments. We observe common investment strategies becoming inefficient with market frictions and others rationalized by them.</description><author>Jouini, E.; Kallal, H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The risk in hedge fund strategies: Theory and evidence from trend followers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fung, W.; Hsieh, D. A.
Hedge fund strategies typically generate option-like returns. Linear-factor models using benchmark asset indices have difficulty explaining them. Following the suggestions in Glosten and Jagannathan (1994), this article shows how to model hedge fund returns by focusing on the popular "trend-following" strategy. We use lookback straddles to model trend-following strategies, and show that they can explain trend-following funds' returns better than standard asset indices. Though standard straddles lead to similar empirical results, lookback straddles are theoretically closer to the concept of trend following. Our model should be useful in the design of performance benchmarks for trend-following funds.</description><author>Fung, W.; Hsieh, D. A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial markets and corporate finance: Selected papers of Michael J. Brennan.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dimson, E.
nan</description><author>Dimson, E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global diversification, growth, and welfare with imperfectly integrated markets for goods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dumas, B.; Uppal, R.
In this article we examine the effect of the imperfect mobility of goods on international risk sharing and, through that, on the investment in risky projects, welfare, and growth. Our main result is that the welfare gain from integration of financial markets is not greatly reduced by the presence of goods market imperfections, modeled as a cost of transferring goods from one country to the other. We also find that the gain is nonmonotonic with respect to investors' risk aversion and the aggregate volatility of output growth. The policy implication to be drawn is that financial market integration is a worthwhile goal to pursue even when full goods mobility has not been achieved.</description><author>Dumas, B.; Uppal, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The use of foreign currency derivatives and firm market value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allayannis, G.; Weston, J. P.
This article examines the use of foreign currency derivatives (FCDs) in a sample of 720 large U.S. nonfinancial firms between 1990 and 1995 and its potential impact on firm value. Using Tobin's Q as a proxy for firm value, we find a positive relation between firm value and the use of FCDs. The hedging premium is statistically and economically significant for firms with exposure to exchange rates and is on average 4.87% of firm value. We also find some evidence consistent with the hypothesis that hedging causes an increase in firm value.</description><author>Allayannis, G.; Weston, J. P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International competition and exchange rate shocks: A cross-country industry analysis of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, J. M.; Stulz, R. M.
This article systematically examines the importance of exchange rate movements and industry competition for stock returns. Common shocks to industries across countries are more important than competitive shocks due to changes in exchange rates. Weekly exchange rate shacks explain almost nothing of the relative performance of industries. Using returns measured over longer horizons, the importance of exchange rate shocks increases slightly and the importance of industry common shocks increases more substantially. Both industry and exchange rate shocks are more important for industries that produce internationally traded goods, but the importance of these shocks is economically small for these industries as well.</description><author>Griffin, J. M.; Stulz, R. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium positive interest rates: A unified view</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jin, Y.; Glasserman, P.
This article develops precise connections among two general approaches to building interest rate models: a general equilibrium approach using a pricing kernel and the Heath, Jarrow, and Morton framework based on specifying forward rate volatilities and the market price of risk. The connections exploit the observation that a pricing kernel is uniquely determined by its drift. Through these connections we provide, for any arbitrage-free term structure model, a representative-consumer real production economy supporting that term structure model in equilibrium. We put particular emphasis on models in which interest rates remain positive. By modeling the dynamics of the drift of the pricing kernel, we construct a new family of Markovian-positive interest rate models.</description><author>Jin, Y.; Glasserman, P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dynamics of the forward interest rate curve with stochastic string shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Santa-Clara, P.; Sornette, D.
This article offers a new class of models for the term structure of forward interest rates. We allow each instantaneous forward rate to be driven by a different stochastic shock, but constrain the shocks so that the forward rate curve is kept continuous. We term the shocks to the forward curve "stochastic string shocks" and construct then as solutions to stochastic partial differential equations. This article offers a variety of parameterizations that can produce, with parsimony, any correlation pattern among forward rates of different maturities. We derive the no-arbitrage condition on the drift of forward rates shocked by stochastic strings and show how to price interest rate derivatives. Although derivatives can be easily priced, they can be perfectly hedged only by trading in an infinite number of bonds of all maturities. We show that the strings model is consistent with any panel dataset of bond prices, and does not require the addition of error terms in econometric models. Finally, we empirically calibrate some versions of the model and price the delivery option embedded in long bond futures. We show that the delivery option is much more valuable in string models than in a similar one-factor model. This is due to the greater variety of shapes of the term structure that string models can produce, which induces more changes in the cheapest-to-deliver bond.</description><author>Santa-Clara, P.; Sornette, D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuing American options by simulation: A simple least-squares approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longstaff, F. A.; Schwartz, E. S.
This article presents a simple yet powerful new approach for approximating the value of American options by simulation. The key to this approach is the use of least squares to estimate the conditional expected payoff to the optionholder from continuation. This makes this approach readily applicable in path-dependent and multifactor situations where traditional finite difference techniques cannot be used. We illustrate this technique with several realistic examples including valuing an option when the underlying asset follows a jump-diffusion process and valuing an American swaption in a 20-factor suing model of the term structure.</description><author>Longstaff, F. A.; Schwartz, E. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are insider trades informative?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lakonishok, J.; Lee, I.
We examine insider trading activities of all companies traded on the NYSE, AMEX, and Nasdaq during the 1975-1995 period. In general, very little market movement is observed when insiders trade and when they report their trades to the SEC. Insiders in aggregate are contrarian investors. However, they predict market movements better than simple contrarian strategies. Insiders also seem to be able to predict cross-sectional stock returns. The result, however, is driven by insider's ability to predict returns in smaller firms. In addition, informativeness of insiders' activities is coming from purchases, while insider selling appears to have no predictive ability.</description><author>Lakonishok, J.; Lee, I.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the nature of the risks and the source of the rewards to momentum investing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grundy, B. D.; Martin, J. S.
Buying recent winners and shorting recent losers guarantees time-varying factor exposures in accordance with the performance of common risk factors during the ranking period. Adjusted for this dynamic risk exposure, momentum profits are remarkably stable across subperiods of the entire post-1926 era. Factor models can explain 95% of winner or loser return variability, but cannot explain their mean returns. Momentum strategies which base winner or loser status on stock-specific return components are more profitable than those based on total returns. Neither industry effects nor cross-sectional differences in expected returns are the primary cause of the momentum phenomenon.</description><author>Grundy, B. D.; Martin, J. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning to be overconfident</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gervais, S.; Odean, T.
We develop a multiperiod market model describing both the process by which traders learn about their ability and how a bias in this learning can create overconfident traders. A trader in our model initially does not know his own ability. He infers this ability from his successes and failures. In assessing his ability the trader takes too much credit for his successes. This leads him to become overconfident. A trader's expected level of overconfidence increases in the early stages of his career. Then, with more experience, he comes to better recognize his own ability. The patterns in trading volume, expected profits, price volatility, and expected prices resulting from this endogenous overconfidence are analyzed.</description><author>Gervais, S.; Odean, T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The determinants of asymmetric volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, G. J.
Volatility in equity markets is asymmetric: contemporaneous return and conditional return volatility are negatively correlated. In this article I develop an asymmetric volatility model where dividend growth and dividend volatility are the two state variables of the economy. The model allows both the leverage effect and the volatility feedback effect, the two popular explanations of asymmetry. The model is estimated by the simulated method of moments. I find that both the leverage effect and volatility feedback are important determinants of asymmetric volatility, and volatility feedback is significant both statistically and economically.</description><author>Wu, G. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank power and cash holdings: Evidence from Japan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pinkowitz, L.; Williamson, R.
Using industrial firms from the United States, Germany, and Japan, we examine the effect of bank power on cash holdings. We show that Japanese firms hold more cash than U.S. or German firms. We also document that Japanese cash balances are affected by the monopoly power of banks. During periods with powerful banks, firms' high cash holdings are consistent with banks extracting rents. When banks weakened, Japanese cash levels became more like U.S. firms. We conclude that strong Japanese banks persuade firms to hold large cash balances. This is contrary to widely held beliefs about the Japanese governance system.</description><author>Pinkowitz, L.; Williamson, R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantitative asset pricing implications of endogenous solvency constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alvarez, F.; Jermann, U. J.
We study the asset pricing implications of an economy where solvency constraints are endogenously determined to deter agents from defaulting while allowing as much risk sharing as possible. We solve analytically for efficient allocations and for the corresponding asset prices, portfolio holdings, and solvency constraints for a simple example. Then we calibrate a more general model to U.S. aggregate as well as idiosyncratic income processes. We find equity premia, risk premia for long-term bonds, and Sharpe ratios of magnitudes similar to the U.S. data for low risk aversion and a low time-discount factor.</description><author>Alvarez, F.; Jermann, U. J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price impact asymmetry of block trades: An institutional trading explanation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saar, G.
This article develops a theoretical model to explain the permanent price impact asymmetry between buyer- and seller-initiated block trades (the permanent price impact of buys is larger than that of sells). The model shows how the trading strategy of institutional portfolio managers creates a difference between the information content of buys and sells. The main implication of the model is that the history of price performance influences the asymmetry: the longer the run-up in a stock's price, the less the asymmetry. The intensity of institutional trading and the frequency of information events affect the asymmetry differently depending on recent price performance.</description><author>Saar, G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational beliefs and security design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garmaise, M.
This article studies the security-design problem of a cash-constrained firm facing investors with diverse beliefs. Investor "rational beliefs" are modeled as varying and yet rational in the sense of Kurz (1994a). With two investors, optimal designs are similar under rational beliefs and rational expectations. With many investors, however, optimal securities under rational beliefs maximize investor differences of opinion, while under rational expectations optimal designs minimize disagreements. We demonstrate that the common practice of issuing multiple securities backed by a single asset is optimal under rational beliefs but not under rational expectations. Researching market beliefs can create substantial value for firms.</description><author>Garmaise, M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does the spirit of capitalism affect stock market prices?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smith, W. T.
Bakshi and Chen (1996b) suggest that the spirit of capitalism affects stock prices by increasing society's aversion to risk. In this article, I show that the way in which the spirit of capitalism impinges upon asset prices depends on the interaction of impatience, willingness to substitute over time, and ordinal preferences between consumption and status, in addition to risk aversion. I develop a general model that charts the channels through which the spirit of capitalism affects asset prices. An increase in the capitalist spirit may increase or decrease risk aversion, and may actually decrease the prices of risky assets.</description><author>Smith, W. T.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disentangling the dividend information in splits: A decomposition using conditional event-study methods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nayak, S.; Prabhala, N. R.
While folklore in finance holds that split valuation effects are due to dividend increases associated with splits, little is known about magnitudes of dividend and nondividend components of split announcement effects. We find that splits and dividends are indeed informational substitutes, a notion we characterize more precisely, but a significant portion of split valuation effects, 46% according to our estimates, cannot be attributed to dividend information in splits. Our techniques extend the literature on conditional event-study methods and we illustrate their practical value in testing hypotheses and analyzing data not amenable to analysis by standard procedures.</description><author>Nayak, S.; Prabhala, N. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The many faces of information disclosure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boot, A. W. A.; Thakor, A. V.
In this article we ask: what kind of information and how much of it should firms voluntarily disclose? Three types of disclosures are considered. One is information that complements the information available only to informed investors (to-be-processed complementary information). The second is information that is orthogonal to that which any investor can acquire and thus complements the information available to all investors (preprocessed complementary information). And the third is information that substitutes for the information of the informed investors in that it reveals to all what was previously known only by the informed (substitute information). Our main results are as follows. First, in equilibrium, all types of firms voluntarily disclose all three types of information. Second, in contrast to the existing literature, complementary information disclosure by firms strengthens investors' private incentives to acquire information. Substitute information disclosure weakens private information acquisition incentives. Third, while complementary information disclosure has an ambiguous effect on financial innovation incentives, substitute information disclosure weakens those incentives.</description><author>Boot, A. W. A.; Thakor, A. V.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information flow and pricing errors: A unified approach to estimation and testing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>George, T. J.; Hwang, C. Y.
This study examines whether rates of information flow differ between trading and non-trading periods, and whether the variances of pricing errors differ at the open and close of trading. The approach improves on existing methods by allowing for correlation between pricing errors and information flow, and by conducting inferences at the individual security level. The daytime rate of information flow is about seven times the overnight rate, and the variances of pricing errors at the open are not different from those at the close of trading. This evidence differs from existing results based on return variance ratios.</description><author>George, T. J.; Hwang, C. Y.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing asset pricing anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brennan, M. J.; Xia, Y. H.
The optimal portfolio strategy is developed for an investor who has detected an asset pricing anomaly but is not certain that the anomaly is genuine rather than merely apparent. The analysis takes account of the fact that the parameters of both the underlying asset pricing model and the anomalous returns are estimated rather than known. The value that an investor would place on the ability to invest to exploit the apparent anomaly is also derived and illustrative calculations are presented for the Fama and French SMB and HML portfolios, whose returns are anomalous relative to the CAPM.</description><author>Brennan, M. J.; Xia, Y. H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership and control of german corporations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Franks, J.; Mayer, C.
In a study of the ownership of German corporations, we find a strong relation between board turnover and corporate performance, little association of concentrations of ownership with managerial disciplining, and only limited evidence that pyramid structures can be used for control purposes. The static relationship of ownership to control in Germany is therefore similar to the United Kingdom and the United States. However, there are marked differences in dynamic relations involving transfers of ownership. There is an active market in share blocks giving rise to changes in control, but the gains are limited and accrue solely to the holders of large blocks, not to minority investors. We provide evidence of low overall benefits to control changes and the exploitation of private benefits of control.</description><author>Franks, J.; Mayer, C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Efficient asset management: A practical guide to stock portfolio optimization and asset allocation.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ma, T. S.
nan</description><author>Ma, T. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected returns and habit persistence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Y. M.
Using a consumption-based asset pricing model with infinite-horizon nonlinear habit formation, Campbell and Cochrane (1999) show that low consumption in surplus of habit should forecast high expected returns. This article argues that the finite-horizon linear habit model also implies an inverse relation between expected returns and surplus consumption. This article also presents empirical evidence, which indicates that expected returns on stocks and bonds vary with surplus consumption implied by the habit models. The volatility of returns and the reward to volatility are also related to surplus consumption. However, less than 30% of the predictable variation of expected returns, using standard lagged information variables, is attributed to surplus consumption.</description><author>Li, Y. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exposure and markups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allayannis, G.; Ihrig, J.
This article examines how to properly specify and test for factors that affect exchange-rate exposure. Starting from theoretical underpinnings and a sample of U.S. manufacturing industries between 1979 and 1995, we find that 4 of 18 industry groups are significantly exposed to exchange-rate movements through the effect of industry competitive structure, export share, and imported input share. On average, a 1% appreciation of the dollar decreases the return of the average industry by 0.13%. Consistent with our model's predictions, as an industry's markups fall (rise), its exchange-rate exposure increases (decreases).</description><author>Allayannis, G.; Ihrig, J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of debt financing on entry and exit in a duopoly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lambrecht, B. M.
This article investigates the interaction between market entry, company foreclosure, and capital structure in a duopoly. We find that the order in which firms foreclose is determined not only by differences in firm-specific factors, but also by common economic factors, such as the interest rate and the market profit volatility. We extend the exit model by allowing financially distressed firms to renegotiate their debt contracts through a one-off debt exchange offer. We find that firms with high bankruptcy costs or with prospects of profit improvement can get bigger reductions on their debt repayments. Investigating market entry, we find that financial vulnerability of the incumbent induces earlier entry.</description><author>Lambrecht, B. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The endogeneity of managerial compensation in firm valuation: A solution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Palia, D.
Much of the empirical literature that has examined the functional relationship between firm value and managerial ownership levels assumes that managerial ownership levels are exogenous and are the only component of managerial compensation related to firm performance. This assumption is contrary to the theoretical and empirical literature wherein managerial compensation is endogenously determined and includes both shares and options. Using instruments for managerial compensation and panel data to control for unobservable heterogeneity in the firm's contracting environment, we estimate a system of simultaneous equations. We find that firms are in equilibrium when they endogenously set their chief executive officer's compensation.</description><author>Palia, D.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Adverse selection and competitive market making: Empirical evidence from a limit order market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sandas, P.
This article presents a new methodology for testing economic restrictions on the price schedules offered in a limit order book that are based on (i) break-even conditions for marginal limit orders and (ii) rational updating conditions for order book revisions over time. Using order flow data from the Stockholm Stock Exchange, I find strong evidence of insufficient depth in the limit order books relative to the theoretical predictions. An extended model, which allows the model parameters to depend on market conditions, captures some of the systematic variation in the observed order book depth.</description><author>Sandas, P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An examination of changes in specialists' posted price schedules</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kavajecz, K. A.; Odders-White, E. R.
New York Stock Exchange specialists disseminate information to market participants by displaying price schedules consisting of bid prices, ask prices, bid depths, and ask depths. We examine how specialists update these price schedules in a simultaneous equations model. We find that changes in the best prices and depths on the limit order book have a significant impact on the posted price schedule, while the effects of transactions and order activity are secondary. Furthermore, we show that specialists revise prices and depths differently, but find no evidence that they revise the price schedule in response to changes in inventory.</description><author>Kavajecz, K. A.; Odders-White, E. R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Familiarity breeds investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huberman, G.
Shareholders of a Regional Bell Operating Company (RBOC) tend to live in the area which it serves, and an RBOC's customers tend to hold its shares rather than other RBOCs' equity. The geographic bias of the RBOC investors is closely related to the general tendency of households' portfolios to be concentrated, of employees' tendency to own their employers' stocks in their retirement accounts, and to the home country bias in the international arena. Together, these phenomena provide competing evidence that people invest in the familiar while often ignoring the principles of portfolio theory.</description><author>Huberman, G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-border investing with tax arbitrage: The case of German dividend tax credits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McDonald, R. L.
German dividends typically carry a tax credit which makes the dividend worth 42.86% more to a taxable German shareholder than to a tax-exempt or foreign shareholder. This results in a penalty for foreign investors who buy and hold German dividend-paying stocks. I document that, as a result of the credit, the ex-day drop exceeds the dividend by more than one-half of the tax credit, and show that futures and option prices embed more than one-half of the tax credit. The existence of the credit creates opportunities for cross-border tax arbitrage-in which foreign holders of German stock transfer the dividend to German shareholders-and implies that it is tax efficient for foreign investors to hold derivatives rather than investing directly in German stocks. The empirical findings are consistent with costly tax arbitrage activity by German investors, who face tax risk due to antiarbitrage rules. Since dividend tax credits exist in many other countries, the findings are potentially of broad interest.</description><author>McDonald, R. L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal consumption and investment with capital gains taxes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dammon, R. M.; Spatt, C. S.; Zhang, H. H.
This article characterizes optimal dynamic consumption and portfolio decisions in the presence of capital gains taxes and short-sale restrictions, The optimal decisions are a function of the investor's age, initial portfolio holdings, and tax basis. Our results capture the trade-off between the diversification benefits and tax costs of trading over an investor's lifetime. The incentive to rediversify the portfolio is inversely related to the size of the embedded gain and investor's age. Contrary to standard financial advice, the optimal equity holding increases well into an investor's lifetime in our model due to the forgiveness of capital gains taxes at death.</description><author>Dammon, R. M.; Spatt, C. S.; Zhang, H. H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading volume: Definitions, data analysis, and implications of portfolio theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lo, A. W.; Wang, J.
We examine the implications of portfolio theory for the cross-sectional behavior of equity trading volume. Two-fund separation theorems suggest a natural definition for trading activity: share turnover. If two-fund separation holds, share turnover must be identical for all securities. If (K + 1)-fund separation holds, we show that turnover satisfies an approximately linear K-factor structure. These implications are examined empirically using individual weekly turnover data for NYSE and AMEX securities from 1962 to 1996. We find strong evidence against two-fund separation, and a principal-components decomposition suggests that turnover is well approximated by a two-factor linear model.</description><author>Lo, A. W.; Wang, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The significance of the market portfolio</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Athanasoulis, S. G.; Shiller, R. J.
Arguments for creating a marker to allow trading the portfolio of all endowments in the entire world, the "market portfolio " are considered. This world share market would represent a radical innovation, since at the present time only a small fraction of world endowments are traded. Using a stochastic endowment economy where preferences are mean variance, it is shown that creating such a market may be justified in terms of its contribution to social welfare. It is also argued that creating a market for world shares is attractive for certain reasons of robustness and simplicity.</description><author>Athanasoulis, S. G.; Shiller, R. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The design of bank loan contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorton, G.; Kahn, J.
The unique characteristics of bank loans emerge endogenously to enhance efficiency in a model of renegotiation between a borrower and a lender in which there is the potential for moral hazard on each side of the relationship. Firm risk is endogenous and renegotiated interest rates on the debt need not be monotone in firm risk. The initial terms of the debt are not set to price default risk but rather are set to efficiently balance bargaining power in later renegotiation. Loan pricing may be nonlinear, involving initial transfers either from the borrower to the bank or from the bank to the borrower.</description><author>Gorton, G.; Kahn, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The term structure of interest rates as a random field</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldstein, R. S.
Forward rate dynamics are modeled as a random field. In contrast to multifactor models, random field models offer a parsimonious description of term structure dynamics, while eliminating the self-inconsistent practice of recalibration. The form of the drift of the instantaneous forward rate process necessary to preclude arbitrage under the risk-neutral measure is obtained. Forward risk-adjusted measures are identified and used to price a bond option when the forward volatility structure depends on the square root of the current spot rate. Several classes of tractable random field models are presented.</description><author>Goldstein, R. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The opportunity for conspiracy in asset markets organized with dealer intermediaries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cason, T. N.
This article reports an asset market experiment in which asymmetrically informed traders transact through competing dealers. Dealers face a classic adverse selection problem, because some traders have private information regarding the asset value while other traders are uninformed. When dealers cannot communicate outside the market, they price the asset competitively and the market is generally informationally efficient. When dealers communicate privately between periods, they collude successfully to widen spreads and increase profit. Another treatment permits traders to post limit orders, while still allowing dealers to communicate. Limit orders restore informational efficiency and narrow spreads but cause dealers to earn negative trading profits.</description><author>Cason, T. N.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcy priority for bank deposits: A contract theoretic explanation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Birchler, U. W.
Over the past decade several countries, including the US, have introduced or redesigned legislation that confers priority in bankruptcy upon all or some bank deposits. We argue that in the presence of contracting costs such rules can increase efficiency. We first show in a private information model that a borrower can reduce overall costs of finance by letting informationally heterogeneous lenders choose between junior and senior debt. In particular, we find that debt priorities reduce socially wasteful information gathering by investors. We then argue why, particularly in banking, legal standardization of debt priorities may be superior to bilateral private arrangements.</description><author>Birchler, U. W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank reputation, bank commitment, and the effects of competition in credit markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dinc, I. S.
This article discusses the effects of credit market competition on a bank's incentive to keep its commitment to lend to a borrower when the borrower's credit quality deteriorates. It is shown that, unlike in the borrower's commitment problem to keep borrowing from the same bank in "good" times, the increased competition may strengthen a bank's incentive to keep its commitment. Banks offer loans with commitment to the highest quality borrowers but, when faced with competition from bond markets, they also give these loans to lower quality borrowers. An increase in the number of banks has a nonmonotonic effect; new banks reinforce a bank's incentive only if there are small number of banks.</description><author>Dinc, I. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic responses of incumbents to new entry: The effect of ownership structure, capital structure, and focus</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khanna, N.; Tice, S.
We examine how certain firm- and market-specific characteristics affect incumbent firms' responses to new entry into their local markets. Data comes from the discount department store industry where Wal-Mart entered a large number of markets in a short period of time. Consistent with existing research, larger and more profitable incumbents respond more aggressively to Wal-Mart's entry while more highly levered incumbents respond less aggressively. Also, there is evidence that incumbent managers fight harder (possibly overinvest) when their job is at greater risk and high managerial ownership appears to reduce this agency problem. Incumbent firms behave differently in markets under attack by Wal-Mart than in markets not yet threatened, suggesting that some of the documented responses are specific to Wal-Mart's entry.</description><author>Khanna, N.; Tice, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the recoverability of preferences and beliefs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cuoco, D.; Zapatero, F.
We examine the extent to which an investor's tastes and beliefs can be jointly recovered from knowledge of his/her consumption choice. More precisely, we assume that the investor's preferences admit an expected utility representation, but with subjective (unknown) probabilities, and investigate what joint restrictions can be placed on utility functions and beliefs. If the investor draws utility from intertemporal consumption, we show that the set of utility functions and beliefs that are consistent with a given consumption choice can be characterized by a martingale condition. In the Markovian case, this characterization can be restated in terms of a Riccati differential equation that must be satisfied by the investor's relative risk aversion function. To each solution of this differential equation is associated a unique utility function and a unique set of beliefs supporting the given consumption choice. Moreover, we show that the differential equation has at most one solution in the class of utility functions displaying infinite absolute risk aversion at the origin. Thus, preferences (and associated beliefs) can be uniquely recovered within this class.</description><author>Cuoco, D.; Zapatero, F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recovering risk aversion from option prices and realized returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jackwerth, J. C.
A relationship exists between aggregate risk-neutral and subjective probability distributions and risk aversion functions. We empirically derive risk aversion functions implied by option prices and realized returns on the S&amp;P500 index simultaneously. These risk aversion functions dramatically change shapes around the 1987 crash: Precrash, they are positive and decreasing in wealth and largely consistent with standard assumptions made in economic theory. Postcrash, they are partially negative and partially increasing and irreconcilable with those assumptions. Mispricing in the option market is the most likely cause. Simulated trading strategies exploiting this mispricing show excess returns, even after accounting for the possibility of further crashes, transaction costs, and hedges against the downside risk.</description><author>Jackwerth, J. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government intervention and adverse selection costs in foreign exchange markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Naranjo, A.; Nimalendran, M.
An important group of traders in the foreign exchange market is governments who often adhere to a foreign exchange rate policy of occasional interventions with otherwise floating rates. In this article we provide a theoretical model and empirical evidence that government foreign exchange interventions create significant adverse selection problems for dealers. In particular, our model shows that the adverse selection component of the Foreign exchange spread is positively related to the variance of unexpected intervention and that expected intervention has no impact on the spread. After controlling for inventory and order processing costs, we find that bid-ask spreads increase with U.S. dollar and German deutsche mark foreign exchange rate intervention during the period 1976-1994. Furthermore, when the intervention is decomposed into expected and unexpected components, we find a statistically and economically significant increase in spreads with the variance of unexpected intervention, while expected intervention has no significant impact on spreads.</description><author>Naranjo, A.; Nimalendran, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric volatility and risk in equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekaert, G.; Wu, G. J.
It appears that volatility in equity markets is asymmetric: returns and conditional volatility are negatively correlated. We provide a unified framework to simultaneously investigate asymmetric volatility at the firm and the market level and to examine two potential explanations of the asymmetry: leverage effects and volatility feedback. Our empirical application uses the market portfolio and portfolios with different leverage constructed from Nikkei 225 stocks. We reject the pure leverage model of Christie (1982) and find support for a volatility feedback story. Volatility feedback at the firm level is enhanced by strong asymmetries in conditional covariances. Conditional betas do not show significant asymmetries, We document the risk premium implications of these findings.</description><author>Bekaert, G.; Wu, G. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation of bankrupt firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilson, S. C.; Hotchkiss, E. S.; Ruback, R. S.
This study compares the market value of firms that reorganize in bankruptcy with estimates of value based on management's published cash flow projections. We estimate firm values using models that have been shown in other contexts to generate relatively precise estimates of value. We find that these methods generally yield unbiased estimates of value, but the dispersion of valuation errors is very wide-the sample ratio of estimated value to market value varies from less than 20% to greater than 250%. Cross-sectional analysis indicates that the variation in these errors is related to empirical proxies for claimholders' incentives to overstate or understate the firm's value.</description><author>Gilson, S. C.; Hotchkiss, E. S.; Ruback, R. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuing American put options using Gaussian quadrature</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sullivan, M. A.
This article develops an efficient and accurate method for numerical evaluation of the integral equation which defines the American put option value function. Numerical integration using Gaussian quadrature and function approximation using Chebyshev polynomials are combined to evaluate recursive expectations and produce an approximation of the option value function in two dimensions, across stock prices and over time to maturity. A set of such solutions results in a multidimensional approximation that is extremely accurate and very quick to compute. The method is an effective alternative to finite difference methods, the binomial model, and various analytic approximations.</description><author>Sullivan, M. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of bank regulation and management compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>John, K.; Saunders, A.; Senbet, L. W.
We show that concentrating bank regulation on bank capital ratios may be ineffective in controlling risk taking. We propose, instead, a more direct mechanism of influencing bank risk-taking incentives, in which the FDIC insurance premium scheme incorporates incentive features of top-management compensation. With this scheme, we show that bank owners choose an optimal management compensation structure that induces first-best value-maximizing investment choices by a bank's management. We explicitly characterize the parameters of the optimal management compensation structure and the fairly priced FDIC insurance premium in the presence of a single or multiple sources of agency problems.</description><author>John, K.; Saunders, A.; Senbet, L. W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging and liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mello, A. S.; Parsons, J. E.
This article develops a model for evaluating alternative hedging strategies for financially constrained firms. A key advantage of the model is the ability to capture the intertemporal effects of hedging on the firm's financial situation. We characterize the optimal hedge. A wide range of alternative hedging strategies can be specified and the model allows us to determine in each case if the hedging strategy raises or lowers firm value and by how much. We show that hedging firm value, hedging cash flow from operations and hedging sales revenue are not optimal. The article highlights the fact that every hedging strategy comes packaged with a burrowing strategy which requires careful consideration.</description><author>Mello, A. S.; Parsons, J. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do firms choose their lenders? An empirical investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cantillo, M.; Wright, J.
This article investigates which companies finance themselves through intermediaries and which borrow directly from arm's length investors. Our empirical results show that large companies with abundant cash and collateral tap credit markets directly; these markers cater to safe and profitable industries, and are most active when riskless rates or intermediary earnings are low; We show that determinants of lender selection sharpen during investment downturns and that there are substantial asymmetries in the way firms enter and exit capital markets. These results support a theoretical framework where intermediaries have batter reorganizational skills but a higher opportunity cost of capital than bondholders.</description><author>Cantillo, M.; Wright, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are there economies of scale in underwriting fees? Evidence of rising external financing costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altinkilic, O.; Hansen, R. S.
This study examines the behavior of spreads paid in firm underwritten seasoned common stock offerings and straight bond offerings. Estimates indicate that up to 85% of the spread is variable cost and that the marginal spread is rising. Further, offerings that are likely to require greater underwriting services encounter higher marginal spreads. These findings are consistent with there being a family of U-shaped spreads, with lower quality offerings priced on higher spreads, unlike the economics of scale view of spreads. They agree with the views that underwriters provide valuable services and that the marginal cost of external finance is rising.</description><author>Altinkilic, O.; Hansen, R. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Excess funds and agency problems: An empirical study of incremental cash disbursements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lie, E.
This study investigates the excess funds hypothesis using samples of special dividends, regular dividend increases, and self-tender offers. All three types of firms tend to have funds in excess of industry norms before the events. The excess funds are largely nonrecurring for special dividend and self-tender offer firms and recurring for regular dividend increase firms. The analysis of the stock price reaction suggests that large incremental disbursements mitigate the agency problem associated with excess funds. In particular, the stock price reaction is positively related to excess funds for self-tender offers and large special dividends, but not for regular dividend increases (which tend to be smaller) or small special dividends.</description><author>Lie, E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial analysis and corporate strategy.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemla, G.
nan</description><author>Chemla, G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium mispricing in a capital market with portfolio constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basak, S.; Croitoru, B.
This article develops a general equilibrium, continuous time model where portfolio constraints generate mispricing between redundant securities. Constrained consumption-portfolio optimization techniques are adapted to incorporate redundant, possibly mispriced securities. Under logarithmic preferences, we provide explicit conditions for mispricing and closed-form expressions for all economic quantities. Existence of an equilibrium where mispricing occurs with positive probability is verified in a specific case. In a more general setting, we demonstrate the necessity of mispricing for equilibrium when agents are heterogeneous enough. The construction of a representative agent with stochastic weights allows us to characterize prices and allocations, given mispricing occurs.</description><author>Basak, S.; Croitoru, B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPOs and long-term relationships: An advantage of book building</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sherman, A. E.
There is a global trend in initial public offerings toward the increased use of book building. Relative to other methods such as auctions, a key feature of book building is that the underwriter has total discretion in allocating shares, allowing allocations to be based on long-term relationships between underwriters and investors. in a multiperiod model with endogenous (and costly) information acquisition, I show that the underwriter's ability to lower underpricing depends largely on its ability to favor regular uninformed investors. One implication is that the hybrid book building/open offer method, which is becoming increasingly popular internationally, will lead to higher underpricing than straight book building.</description><author>Sherman, A. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prices, liquidity, and the information content of trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koski, J. L.; Michaely, R.
We investigate the effect of asymmetric information on prices and liquidity by analyzing trades, quotes, spreads, and depths. Information content should increase with trade size and the information asymmetry of the trading period. Results show that price and liquidity effects are significantly associated with information content as measured by both trade size and timing relative to information events. Results are stronger for purchases than sales. Quoted prices are better measures of information effects than transaction prices, because they control for bid-ask bounce. Finally, trades that a priori contain no information have no impact on prices and liquidity, despite their large size.</description><author>Koski, J. L.; Michaely, R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic debt restructuring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Noe, T. H.; Wang, J.
We analyze a distressed firm indebted to many creditors. The firm's owners have the option of choosing the sequence of restructuring negotiations with the creditors. We show that sequencing flexibility is beneficial to firm owners, and that the optimal sequencing of restructuring negotiations involves exploiting the firm's liabilities to some creditors so as to moderate the demands of others. Moderately distressed firms will eschew renegotiations with creditors in strong bargaining positions. Severely distressed firms will extract concessions from all creditors. In this case, owners can gain if they can credibly commit to conditional restructuring agreements that link the concessions of one creditor to concessions by others.</description><author>Noe, T. H.; Wang, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Toeholds, bid jumps, and expected payoffs in takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Betton, S.; Eckbo, B. E.
We estimate sequentially outcome probabilities and expected payoffs associated with first, second, and final bids in a large sample of tender offer contests. Rival bids arrive quickly and produce large bid jumps. Greater bidder toeholds (prebid ownership of target shares) reduce the probability of competition and target resistance and are associated with both lower bid premiums and lower prebid target stock price runups. The expected payoff to target shareholders is increasing in the bid premium and in the probability of competition, bur decreasing in the bidder's toehold. The initial bidder's expected payoff is significantly positive in the "rival-bidder-win" outcome, in part reflecting gains from the pending toehold sale. Despite these dramatic toehold effects, only half of the initial bidders acquire toeholds.</description><author>Betton, S.; Eckbo, B. E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing models: Implications for expected returns and portfolio selection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>MacKinlay, A. C.; Pastor, L.
When a risk factor is missing from an asset pricing model, the resulting mispricing is embedded within the residual covariance matrix. Exploiting this phenomenon leads to expected return estimates that are more stable and precise than estimates delivered by standard methods. Portfolio selection can also be improved. At an extreme, optimal portfolio weights are proportional to expected returns when no factors are observable. We find that such portfolios perform well in simulations and in out-of-sample comparisons.</description><author>MacKinlay, A. C.; Pastor, L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulatory and legal pressures and the costs of Nasdaq trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schultz, P.
The Nasdaq market came under intense pressure from regulators and class-action lawsuits following allegations of tacit collusion by Christie and Schultz (1994). This article examines the changes in transaction costs on the Nasdaq from January 1993 through June 1996 using 16 million trades in 30 stocks. Effective spreads cannot be estimated during 1995 and 1996 because time-stamps of trades and quotes cannot be matched. However, the autocovariance spread estimator of Roll (1984) works well with intraday data over this period. This spread estimator reveals that trading costs declined significantly for 29 of the 30 stocks over 1993-1996.</description><author>Schultz, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The interaction between product market and financing strategy: The role of venture capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hellmann, T.; Puri, M.
Venture capital financing is widely believed to be influential for new innovative companies. We provide empirical evidence that venture capital financing is related to product market strategies and outcomes of start-ups. Using a unique hand-collected database of Silicon Valley high-tech start-ups we find that innovator firms are more likely to obtain venture capital than imitator firms. Venture capital is also associated with a significant reduction in the time to bring a product to market, especially for innovators. Our results suggest significant interrelations between investor types and product market dimensions, and a role of venture capital for innovative companies.</description><author>Hellmann, T.; Puri, M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The private placement of debt and outside equity as an information revelation mechanism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Habib, M. A.; Johnsen, D. B.
We view debt and outside equity as serving to elicit credible information from different specialists about the value of an enterprise in its various uses. The equity valuation specialist provides a price forecast for equity that reveals information about the value of the enterprise in its primary use. The debt valuation specialist provides a price forecast for debt that reveals information about the value of the enterprise in its alternative use. The prices forecast by the valuation specialists credibly reveal their private information because they are required to buy the associated claims at the forecast prices, thereby bonding their valuations.</description><author>Habib, M. A.; Johnsen, D. B.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price discovery in auction markets: A look inside the black box</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Madhavan, A.; Panchapagesan, V.
Opening mechanisms play a crucial role in information aggregation following the overnight nontrading period. This article examines the process of price discovery at the New York Stock Exchange single-price opening auction. We develop a theoretical model to explain the determinants of the opening price and test the model using order-level data. We show that the presence of designated dealers facilitates price discovery relative to a fully automated call auction market. This is consistent with specialists extracting information from observing the evolution of the limit order book. In addition, the specialist's opening trade reflects noninformational factors such as price stabilization requirements.</description><author>Madhavan, A.; Panchapagesan, V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt valuation, renegotiation, and optimal dividend policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fan, H.; Sundaresan, S. M.
The valuation of debt and equity, reorganization boundaries, and firm's optimal dividend policies are studied in a framework where we model strategic interactions between debt holders and equity holders in a game-theoretic setting which can accommodate varying bargaining powers to the two claimants. Two formulations of reorganization are presented: debt-equity swaps and strategic debt service resulting from negotiated debt service reductions. We study the effects of bond covenants on payout policies and distinguish liquidity-induced defaults from strategic defaults. We derive optimal equity issuance and payout policies. The debt capacity of the firm and the optimal capital structure are characterized.</description><author>Fan, H.; Sundaresan, S. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forcing firms to talk: Financial disclosure regulation and externalities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Admati, A. R.; Pfleiderer, P.
We analyze a model of voluntary disclosure by firms and the desirability of disclosure regulation, In our model disclosure is costly, it has private and social value, and its precision is endogenous. We show that (i) a convexity in the value of disclosure can lead to a discontinuity in the disclosure policy; (ii) the Nash equilibrium of a voluntary disclosure game is often socially inefficient; (iii) regulation mat requires a minimal precision level sometimes but not always improves welfare; (iii) the same is true for subsidies that change the perceived cost of disclosures; and (iv) neither regulation method dominates the other.</description><author>Admati, A. R.; Pfleiderer, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock market risk and return: An equilibrium approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Whitelaw, R. F.
Empirical evidence that expected stock returns are weakly related to volatility at the market level appears to contradict the intuition that risk and return are positively related. We investigate this issue in a general equilibrium exchange economy characterized by a regime-switching consumption process with time-varying transition probabilities between regimes. When estimated using consumption data, the model generates a complex, nonlinear and time-varying relation between expected returns and volatility, duplicating the salient features of the risk/return trade-off in the data. The results emphasize the importance of time-varying investment opportunities and highlight the perils of relying on intuition from static models.</description><author>Whitelaw, R. F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do call prices and the underlying stock always move in the same direction?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, G.; Cao, C.; Chen, Z. W.
This article empirically analyzes some properties shared by all one-dimensional diffusion option models. Using S&amp;P 500 options, we find that sampled intraday (or interday) call (put) prices often go down (up) even as the underlying price goes up, and call and put prices often increase, or decrease, together. Our results are valid after controlling for time decay and market microstructure effects. Therefore one-dimensional diffusion option models cannot be completely consistent with observed option price dynamics; options are nor redundant securities, nor ideal hedging instruments-puts and the underlying asset prices may go down together.</description><author>Bakshi, G.; Cao, C.; Chen, Z. W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A closed-form GARCH option valuation model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heston, S. L.; Nandi, S.
This paper develops a closed-form option valuation formula for a spot asset whose variance follows a GARCH (p, q) process that can be correlated with the returns of the spot asset. It provides the first readily computed option formula for a random volatility model that can be estimated and implemented solely on the basis of observables. The single lag version of this model contains Heston's (1993) stochastic volatility model as a continuous-time limit. Empirical analysis on S&amp;P500 index options shows that the out-of-sample valuation errors from the single lag Version of the GARCH model are substantially lower than the ad hoc Black-Scholes model of Dumas, Fleming and Whaley (1998) that uses a separate implied volatility for each option to fit to the smirk/smile in implied volatilties. The GARCH model remains superior even though the parameters of the GARCH model are held constant and volatility is filtered from the history of asset prices while the ad hoc Black-Scholes model is updated every period. The improvement is largely due to the ability of the GARCH model to simultaneously capture the correlation of volatility with spot returns and the path dependence in volatility.</description><author>Heston, S. L.; Nandi, S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Client discretion, switching costs, and financial innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharyya, S.; Nanda, V.
We analyze the incentives of investment banks to develop innovative products. We show that client characteristics and market structure affect these incentives significantly. Investment banks with larger market shares have greater incentives to innovate and smaller banks are likely to share their innovations with the largest bank. Innovation incentives increase in volatile environments and regulatory scrutiny actually encourages loophole exploitation activity. Our predictions are consistent with stylized facts and the analysis has broad testable implications for innovative activity in other markets similarly characterized by a lack of comprehensive protection for intellectual property rights, for example, the software industry.</description><author>Bhattacharyya, S.; Nanda, V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market making, prices, and quantity limits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dupont, D.
This article develops a model of spread and depth setting under asymmetric information where the equilibrium depth is proportionally more sensitive than the spread to changes in the degree of information asymmetry. The analysis uses a one-period model in which a risk-neutral, monopolistic market maker faces a price-sensitive liquidity trader and a better informed trader who is alternatively risk neutral and risk averse. The equilibrium depth can take values ranging from 0 to infinity, depending on the information asymmetry, the asset volatility, and the strength of the liquidity demand. while the spread remains positive and finite.</description><author>Dupont, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Active portfolio management: A quantitative approach to providing superior returns and controlling risk, 2nd edition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Connor, G.
nan</description><author>Connor, G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Derivatives: A PowerPlus picture book.</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hagerty, K.
nan</description><author>Hagerty, K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>