<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Review of Financial Studies1</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:07:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Global Dollar Credit and Carry Trades: A Firm-Level Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bruno, Valentina; Shin, Hyun Song
We conduct a firm-level analysis of borrowing in US dollars by nonfinancial corporates from outside the United States. We find that emerging market firms with already high cash holdings are more likely to issue US dollar-denominated bonds, especially during periods when the dollar carry trade is more favorable. The proceeds of the dollar bond issuance add to the firm's cash holdings more than other sources of funds. The evidence points to financial decisions that resemble carry trades, rather than to precautionary borrowing in anticipation of future financing needs.</description><author>Bruno, Valentina; Shin, Hyun Song</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Asset Pricing Approach to Liquidity Effects in Corporate Bond Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bongaerts, Dion; de Jong, Frank; Driessen, Joost
We use an asset pricing approach to compare the effects of the liquidity level and liquidity risk on expected U.S. corporate bond returns. Using signed transaction data, we estimate effective transaction costs for bond portfolios by a repeat-sales method. We find that the liquidity level and exposure to equity market liquidity risk affect expected bond returns. In contrast, exposure to corporate bond liquidity shocks carries an economically negligible risk premium. A simulation study shows that it is unlikely that our results are driven by measurement error in betas or multicollinearity. We present a simple theoretical model that explains these findings.</description><author>Bongaerts, Dion; de Jong, Frank; Driessen, Joost</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign Cash: Taxes, Internal Capital Markets, and Agency Problems (vol 30, pg 1490, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harford, Jarrad; Wang, Cong; Zhang, Kuo
nan</description><author>Harford, Jarrad; Wang, Cong; Zhang, Kuo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Short-Selling Threats on Incentive Contracts: Evidence from an Experiment (vol 30, pg 1627, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Angelis, David; Grullon, Gustavo; Michenaud, Sebastien
nan</description><author>De Angelis, David; Grullon, Gustavo; Michenaud, Sebastien</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Does Risk Management Influence Production Decisions? Evidence from a Field Experiment (vol 30, pg 1935, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cole, Shawn; Gine, Xavier; Vickery, James
nan</description><author>Cole, Shawn; Gine, Xavier; Vickery, James</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Differences of Opinion and International Equity Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dumas, Bernard; Lewis, Karen K.; Osambela, Emilio
We develop an international financial market model in which domestic and foreign residents differ in their beliefs about the information content in public signals. We determine how informational advantages of domestic investors in the interpretation of home public signals affect equity markets. We evaluate the ability of our model to generate four international-finance anomalies: (i) the co-movement of returns and capital flows, (ii) home-equity preference, (iii) the dependence of firm returns on home and foreign factors, and (iv) abnormal returns around foreign firm cross-listing in the home market. Their relationships with empirical differences-of-opinion proxies are consistent with the model.</description><author>Dumas, Bernard; Lewis, Karen K.; Osambela, Emilio</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Retail Short Selling and Stock Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kelley, Eric K.; Tetlock, Paul C.
Using proprietary data on millions of trades by retail investors, we provide the first large-scale evidence that retail short selling predicts negative stock returns. Aportfolio that mimics weekly retail shorting earns an annualized risk-adjusted return of 9%. The predictive ability of retail short selling lasts for one year and is not subsumed by institutional short selling. In contrast to institutional shorting, retail shorting best predicts returns in small stocks and those that are heavily bought by other retail investors. Our findings are consistent with retail short sellers having unique insights into the retail investor community and small firms' fundamentals.</description><author>Kelley, Eric K.; Tetlock, Paul C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pre-market Trading and IPO Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Chun; Chiang, Yao-Min; Qian, Yiming; Ritter, Jay R.
Studying the only mandatory pre-IPO market in the world-Taiwan's Emerging Stock Market (ESM)-we document that pre-market prices are very informative about post-market prices and that informativeness increases with a stock's liquidity. The ESM price-earnings ratio shortly before an initial public offering explains about 90% of the variation in the offer price-earnings ratio. However, the average IPO underpricing level remains high, at 55%, suggesting that agency problems between underwriters and issuers can lead to excessive underpricing, even with little valuation uncertainty. Also, regulations impact the relative bargaining power of players and therefore IPO pricing.</description><author>Chang, Chun; Chiang, Yao-Min; Qian, Yiming; Ritter, Jay R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inflation Bets on the Long Bond</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Harrison; Sraer, David; Yu, Jialin
The liquidity premium theory of interest rates predicts that the Treasury yield curve steepens with inflation uncertainty as investors demand larger risk premiums to hold long-term bonds. By using the dispersion of inflation forecasts to measure this uncertainty, we find the opposite. Since the prices of long-term bonds move more with inflation than short-term ones, investors also disagree and speculate more about long-maturity payoffs with greater uncertainty. Shorting frictions, measured by using Treasury lending fees, then lead long maturities to become overpriced and the yield curve to flatten. We estimate this inflation-betting effect using time variation in inflation disagreement and Treasury supply.</description><author>Hong, Harrison; Sraer, David; Yu, Jialin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mind the Gap: The Difference between US and European Loan Rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berg, Tobias; Saunders, Anthony; Steffen, Sascha; Streitz, Daniel
We analyze pricing differences between U.S. and European syndicated loans over the 19922014 period. We explicitly distinguish credit lines from term loans. For credit lines, U.S. borrowers pay significantly higher spreads, but lower fees, resulting in similar total costs of borrowing in both markets. Credit line usage is more cyclical in the United States, which provides a rationale for the pricing structure difference. For term loans, we analyze the channels of the cross-country loan price differential and document the importance of: the composition of term loan borrowers and the loan supply by institutional investors and foreign banks.</description><author>Berg, Tobias; Saunders, Anthony; Steffen, Sascha; Streitz, Daniel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Capital and Dividend Externalities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Le, Hanh T.; Shin, Hyun Song
Dividend payouts erode equity capital and affect the relative value of claims on a bank. Through this channel, when banks have contingent claims on each other, one bank's capital policy affects the equity value and risk of default for other banks. When such externalities are strong, bank capital becomes a public good, whereby the private equilibrium features excessive dividends and inefficient recapitalization relative to the efficient policy that maximizes total banking sector equity. We relate these implications to the observed bank behaviour during the crisis of 2007-2009.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Le, Hanh T.; Shin, Hyun Song</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Law and Finance Matter: Lessons from Externally Imposed Courts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, James R.; Cookson, J. Anthony; Heimer, Rawley Z.
This paper provides novel evidence on the real and financial market effects of legal institutions. Our analysis exploits persistent and externally imposed differences in court enforcement that arose when the U.S. Congress assigned state courts to adjudicate contracts on a subset of Native American reservations. Using area-specific data on small business lending, we find that reservations assigned to state courts, which enforce contracts more predictably than tribal courts, have stronger credit markets. Moreover, the law-driven component of credit market development is associated with significantly higher per capita income, with stronger effects in sectors that depend more on external financing.</description><author>Brown, James R.; Cookson, J. Anthony; Heimer, Rawley Z.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fundamental Analysis and the Cross-Section of Stock Returns: A Data-Mining Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yan, Xuemin; Zheng, Lingling
We construct a "universe" of over 18,000 fundamental signals from financial statements and use a bootstrap approach to evaluate the impact of data mining on fundamental-based anomalies. We find that many fundamental signals are significant predictors of cross-sectional stock returns even after accounting for data mining. This predictive ability is more pronounced following high-sentiment periods and among stocks with greater limits to arbitrage. Our evidence suggests that fundamental-based anomalies, including those newly discovered in this study, cannot be attributed to random chance, and they are better explained by mispricing. Our approach is general and we also apply it to past return-based anomalies.</description><author>Yan, Xuemin; Zheng, Lingling</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aggregation of Information About the Cross Section of Stock Returns: A Latent Variable Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Light, Nathaniel; Maslov, Denys; Rytchkov, Oleg
We propose a new approach for estimating expected returns on individual stocks from a large number of firm characteristics. We treat expected returns as latent variables and apply the partial least squares (PLS) estimator that filters them out from the characteristics under an assumption that the characteristics are linked to expected returns through one or few common latent factors. The estimates of expected returns constructed by our approach from 26 firm characteristics generate a wide cross-sectional dispersion of realized returns and outperform estimates obtained by alternative techniques. Our results also provide evidence of commonality in asset pricing anomalies.</description><author>Light, Nathaniel; Maslov, Denys; Rytchkov, Oleg</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which Alpha?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barillas, Francisco; Shanken, Jay
A common approach to comparing asset pricing models involves a competition in pricing test-asset returns. In contrast, we show that for models with traded factors, when the comparison is framed appropriately in terms of success in pricing both the test-asset and factor returns, the extent to which each model is able to price the factors in the other model is what matters for model comparison. Test assets are irrelevant based on several prominent criteria. For models with nontraded factors, test assets are relevant for model comparison insofar as they are needed to identify factor-mimicking portfolio returns.</description><author>Barillas, Francisco; Shanken, Jay</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Does Risk Management Influence Production Decisions? Evidence from a Field Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cole, Shawn; Gine, Xavier; Vickery, James
Weather is a key source of income risk, especially in emerging market economies. This paper uses a randomized controlled trial involving Indian farmers to study how an innovative rainfall insurance product affects production decisions. We find that insurance provision induces farmers to invest more in higher-return but rainfall-sensitive cash crops, particularly among educated farmers. This shift in behavior occurs ex ante, when realized monsoon rainfall is still uncertain. Our results suggest that financial innovation can mitigate the real effects of uninsured production risk.</description><author>Cole, Shawn; Gine, Xavier; Vickery, James</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Freedom of Information Act and the Race Toward Information Acquisition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gargano, Antonio; Rossi, Alberto G.; Wermers, Russ
We document a little-known source of information exploited by sophisticated institutional investors: the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), a law that allows for the disclosure of previously unreleased information by the U.S. Government. Through FOIA requests, we identify several sophisticated institutional investors, chiefly hedge funds, that request information from the FDA. We explore the type of information commonly requested by funds and the types of firms that are targets of FDA-FOIA requests and show that FOIA requests allow these investors to generate abnormal returns. Thus, we illustrate a detailed mechanism through which costly information becomes incorporated into market prices.</description><author>Gargano, Antonio; Rossi, Alberto G.; Wermers, Russ</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mispricing Factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stambaugh, Robert F.; Yuan, Yu
A four-factor model with two "mispricing" factors, in addition to market and size factors, accommodates a large set of anomalies better than notable four-and five-factor alternative models. Moreover, our size factor reveals a small-firm premium nearly twice usual estimates. The mispricing factors aggregate information across 11 prominent anomalies by averaging rankings within two clusters exhibiting the greatest return co-movement. Investor sentiment predicts the mispricing factors, especially their short legs, consistent with a mispricing interpretation and the asymmetry in ease of buying versus shorting. A three-factor model with a single mispricing factor also performs well, especially in Bayesian model comparisons.</description><author>Stambaugh, Robert F.; Yuan, Yu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bribes and Firm Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zeume, Stefan
I exploit the passage of the U.K. Bribery Act 2010 as a shock to U.K. firms' cost of doing business. Around the Act's passage, U.K. firms operating in high-corruption countries experience a drop in firm value, while their non-U.K. competitors in these countries encounter an increase. U.K. firms respond to the Act by reducing the expansion of their subsidiary network into perceptively corrupt countries. Moreover, their sales and merger and acquisition (M&amp;A) activity in such countries declines. In sum, bribes facilitate doing business in certain countries. Imposing unilateral antibribery regulations on some firms benefits their unregulated competitors.</description><author>Zeume, Stefan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign Cash: Taxes, Internal Capital Markets, and Agency Problems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harford, Jarrad; Wang, Cong; Zhang, Kuo
When the fraction of a firm's cash held overseas is greater, its shareholders value that cash lower. This goes beyond a pure tax effect: the repatriation tax friction disrupts the firm's internal capital market, distorting its investment policy. Firms underinvest domestically and overinvest abroad. Our findings are more pronounced when firms are subject to higher repatriation tax rates, higher costs of borrowing, and more agency problems. Overall, our evidence suggests that a combination of taxes, financing frictions, and agency problems leads to a valuation discount for foreign cash and documents real effects of how foreign earnings are taxed.</description><author>Harford, Jarrad; Wang, Cong; Zhang, Kuo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extending Industry Specialization through Cross-Border Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fresard, Laurent; Hege, Ulrich; Phillips, Gordon
We investigate the role of industry specialization in horizontal cross-border mergers and acquisitions. We find that acquirers from more specialized industries in a country are more likely to buy foreign targets in countries that are less specialized in these same industries. The role of industry specialization in foreign acquisitions is more prevalent when contracting inefficiencies and exporting costs limit arm's-length relationships. The economic gains in cross-border deals are larger when specialized acquirers purchase assets in less specialized industries. These results are consistent with an internalization motive for foreign acquisitions, through which acquirers can apply localized intangibles on foreign assets.</description><author>Fresard, Laurent; Hege, Ulrich; Phillips, Gordon</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Short-Selling Threats on Incentive Contracts: Evidence from an Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Angelis, David; Grullon, Gustavo; Michenaud, Sebastien
This paper examines the effects of a shock to the stock-price formation process on the design of executive incentive contracts. We find that an exogenous removal of short-selling constraints causes firms to convexify compensation payoffs by granting relatively more stock options to their managers. We also find that treated firms adopt new antitakeover provisions. These results suggest that when firms face the threat of bear raids, they incentivize managers to take actions that mitigate the adverse effects of unrestrained short selling. Overall, this paper provides causal evidence that financial markets affect incentive contract design.</description><author>De Angelis, David; Grullon, Gustavo; Michenaud, Sebastien</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing and New Product Decisions of Private and Publicly Traded Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phillips, Gordon M.; Sertsios, Giorgo
We exploit Medicare national coverage reimbursement approvals as a quasi-natural experiment to investigate how the financing decisions of private and publicly traded firms respond to changes in investment opportunities. We find that publicly traded companies increase their external financing and their subsequent product introductions by more than private companies in response to national coverage approvals. Private equity financing is the primary source of the increased financing for public firms. We show that the stock characteristics of publicly traded firms, such as liquidity and price informativeness, and product market competition are important factors in explaining their financing advantage.</description><author>Phillips, Gordon M.; Sertsios, Giorgo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Impact of Financial Leverage on the Incidence and Severity of Product Failures: Evidence from Product Recalls</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kini, Omesh; Shenoy, Jaideep; Subramaniam, Venkat
We study the impact of the financial condition of firms on firms' ability to produce safer products that result in fewer recalls. Using a variety of tests, including two quasi-natural experiments that result in exogenous negative industry cash-flow shocks, we find that firms with higher leverage or distress likelihood have a greater probability of a product recall. These firms also face more frequent and severe recalls. Further, firms with more debt due at the onset of the financial crisis experience a greater likelihood and frequency of recalls. We conclude that a firm's financial condition has real effects that impact product safety.</description><author>Kini, Omesh; Shenoy, Jaideep; Subramaniam, Venkat</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shaped by Booms and Busts: How the Economy Impacts CEO Careers and Management Styles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schoar, Antoinette; Zuo, Luo
We show that economic conditions when managers enter the labor market have long-run effects on their career paths and managerial styles. Managers who began their careers during recessions become CEOs more quickly, but at smaller firms. They also have more conservative styles, such as lower investment in capital expenditures and research and development, more cost cutting, and lower leverage and working capital needs. These recession effects appear to be largely driven by the characteristics of the CEO's first job (recession CEOs tend to start in smaller or private firms), which suggests that the early work environment is important to the formation and selection of managers.</description><author>Schoar, Antoinette; Zuo, Luo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition and Ownership Structure of Closely Held Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bena, Jan; Xu, Ting
We study how product market competition affects firms' ownership structures using a large sample of closely held firms in eighteen European countries. We show that firms operating in more competitive environments have lower inside ownership and that the stakes of their outside shareholders are more dispersed. These results are explained by competition increasing the need to raise external equity and reducing private control benefits. Our findings suggest that, by changing corporate ownership structure, competition mitigates incentive misalignment among shareholders, leading to better firm performance and gains in economic efficiency.</description><author>Bena, Jan; Xu, Ting</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distracted Shareholders and Corporate Actions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kempf, Elisabeth; Manconi, Alberto; Spalt, Oliver
Investor attention matters for corporate actions. Our new identification approach constructs firm-level shareholder "distraction" measures, by exploiting exogenous shocks to unrelated parts of institutional shareholders' portfolios. Firms with "distracted" shareholders are more likely to announce diversifying, value-destroying, acquisitions. They are also more likely to grant opportunistically timed CEO stock options, more likely to cut dividends, and less likely to fire their CEO for bad performance. Firms with distracted shareholders have abnormally low stock returns. Combined, these patterns are consistent with a model in which the unrelated shock shifts investor attention, leading to a temporary loosening of monitoring constraints.</description><author>Kempf, Elisabeth; Manconi, Alberto; Spalt, Oliver</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spillovers Inside Conglomerates: Incentives and Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duchin, Ran; Goldberg, Amir; Sosyura, Denis
Using hand-collected data on divisional managers at conglomerates, we find that a change in industry pay in one division generates spillovers on managerial pay in other divisions of the same firm. These spillovers arise only within the boundaries of a conglomerate. The intra-firm spillovers increase when conglomerates have excess cash and when managers have more influence over its distribution, but decline in the presence of strong governance. These spillovers are associated with weaker performance and lower firm value. Our evidence is consistent with simultaneous cross-subsidization via managerial compensation and capital budgets and suggests that these practices arise in similar firms.</description><author>Duchin, Ran; Goldberg, Amir; Sosyura, Denis</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Toxic Arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foucault, Thierry; Kozhan, Roman; Tham, Wing Wah
Short-lived arbitrage opportunities arise when prices adjust with a lag to new information. They are toxic because they expose dealers to the risk of trading at stale quotes. Hence, theory implies that more frequent toxic arbitrage opportunities and faster responses to these opportunities should impair liquidity. We provide supporting evidence using data on triangular arbitrage. As predicted, illiquidity is higher on days when the fraction of toxic arbitrage opportunities and arbitrageurs' relative speed are higher. Overall, our findings suggest that the price efficiency gain of high-frequency arbitrage comes at the cost of increased adverse selection risk.</description><author>Foucault, Thierry; Kozhan, Roman; Tham, Wing Wah</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Size Discovery</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duffie, Darrell; Zhu, Haoxiang
Size-discovery mechanisms allow large quantities of an asset to be exchanged at a price that does not respond to price pressure. Primary examples include "workup" in Treasury markets, "matching sessions" in corporate bond and CDS markets, and block-trading "dark pools" in equity markets. By freezing the execution price and giving up on market-clearing, size-discovery mechanisms overcome concerns by large investors over their price impacts. Price-discovery mechanisms clear the market, but cause investors to internalize their price impacts, inducing costly delays in the reduction of position imbalances. We show how augmenting a price-discovery mechanism with a size-discovery mechanism improves allocative efficiency.</description><author>Duffie, Darrell; Zhu, Haoxiang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dynamics of Market Efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rosch, Dominik M.; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; van Dijk, Mathijs A.
We study the dynamics of high-frequency market efficiency measures. We provide evidence that these measures comove across stocks and with each other, suggesting the existence of a systematic market efficiency component. In vector autoregressions, we show that shocks to funding liquidity (the TED spread), hedge fund assets under management, and a proxy for algorithmic trading are significantly associated with systematic market efficiency. Thus, stock market efficiency is prone to systematic fluctuations, and, consistent with recent theories, events and policies that impact funding liquidity can affect the aggregate degree of price efficiency.</description><author>Rosch, Dominik M.; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; van Dijk, Mathijs A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Need for Speed? Exchange Latency and Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Menkveld, Albert J.; Zoican, Marius A.
A faster exchange does not necessarily improve liquidity. On the one hand, speed enables a high-frequency market maker (HFM) to update quotes faster on incoming news. This reduces payoff risk and thus lowers the competitive bid-ask spread. On the other hand, HFM price quotes are more likely to meet speculative high-frequency bandits, and thus are less likely to meet liquidity traders. This raises the spread. The net effect of exchange speed depends on a security's news-to-liquidity-trader ratio.</description><author>Menkveld, Albert J.; Zoican, Marius A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Stocks Real Assets? Sticky Discount Rates in Stock Markets (vol 30, pg 539, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Katz, Michael; Lustig, Hanno; Nielsen, Lars
nan</description><author>Katz, Michael; Lustig, Hanno; Nielsen, Lars</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Anatomy of the CDS Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oehmke, Martin; Zawadowski, Adam
Using novel position and trading data for single-name corporate credit default swaps (CDSs), we provide evidence that CDS markets emerge as "alternative trading venues" serving a standardization and liquidity role. CDS positions and trading volume are larger for firms with bonds fragmented into many separate issues and with heterogeneous contractual terms. Whereas hedging motives are associated with trading volume in the bond and CDS markets, speculative trading concentrates in the CDS. Cross-market arbitrage links the CDS and bond market via the basis trade, compressing the negative CDS-bond basis and reducing price impact in the bond market.</description><author>Oehmke, Martin; Zawadowski, Adam</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Design of Financial Securities: Empirical Evidence from Private-Label RMBS Deals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Begley, Taylor A.; Purnanandam, Amiyatosh
We study the key drivers of security design in the residential mortgage-backed security (RMBS) market during the run-up to the subprime mortgage crisis. We show that deals with a higher level of equity tranche have a significantly lower delinquency rate conditional on observable loan characteristics. The effect is concentrated within pools with a higher likelihood of asymmetric information between deal sponsors and potential buyers of the securities. Further, securities sold from high-equity-tranche deals command higher prices conditional on their credit ratings. Overall, our results show that the goal of security design in this market was not only to exploit regulatory arbitrage, but also to mitigate information frictions that were pervasive in this market.</description><author>Begley, Taylor A.; Purnanandam, Amiyatosh</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Policies with Permanent and Transitory Shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Decamps, Jean-Paul; Gryglewicz, Sebastian; Morellec, Erwan; Villeneuve, Stephane
We model the financing, cash holdings, and hedging policies of a firm facing financing frictions and subject to permanent and transitory cash flow shocks. The permanent and transitory shocks generate distinct, sometimes opposite, effects on corporate policies. We use the model to develop a rich set of empirical predictions. In our model, correlated permanent and transitory shocks imply less risk, lower cash savings, and a drop in the value of credit lines. The composition of cash-flow shocks affects the cash-flow sensitivity of cash, which can be positive or negative. Optimal hedging of permanent and transitory shocks may involve opposite positions.</description><author>Decamps, Jean-Paul; Gryglewicz, Sebastian; Morellec, Erwan; Villeneuve, Stephane</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Junior Inherit? Refinancing and the Blocking Power of Second Mortgages</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bond, Philip; Elul, Ronel; Garyn-Tal, Sharon; Musto, David K.
In most U.S. states, mortgage seniority follows time priority: older mortgages are paid first. This potentially impedes refinancing of senior mortgages because replacement mortgages are junior unless the existing junior lienholders consent to resubordination. We exploit legal variation across states to provide evidence that time priority reduces refinancing, especially of smaller mortgages (suggesting a significant fixed cost of obtaining resubordination) and of mortgages close to the conforming loan limit. On the contrary, we find evidence that time priority renders second mortgages more valuable to lenders, increasing the likelihood that a borrower obtains a second mortgage.</description><author>Bond, Philip; Elul, Ronel; Garyn-Tal, Sharon; Musto, David K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Asset Redeployability Channel: How Uncertainty Affects Corporate Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, Hyunseob; Kung, Howard
This paper examines how uncertainty affects corporate investment under varying degrees of asset redeployability. We develop new measures of asset redeployability by accounting for the usability of assets within and across industries. We identify plausibly exogenous shocks to economic uncertainty by using major economic and political events. We find that after an increase in uncertainty, firms using less redeployable capital reduce investment more. More redeployable assets exhibit higher recovery rates and are traded more actively in secondary markets. Overall, our results suggest that frictions in redeploying assets affect liquidation values and therefore make firms cautious about investment decisions under uncertainty.</description><author>Kim, Hyunseob; Kung, Howard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Being Surprised by the Unsurprising: Earnings Seasonality and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Tom Y.; Hartzmark, Samuel M.; Solomon, David H.; Soltes, Eugene F.
We present evidence consistent with markets failing to properly price information in seasonal earnings patterns. Firms with historically larger earnings in one quarter of the year ("positive seasonality quarters") have higher returns when those earnings are usually announced. Analysts have more positive forecast errors in positive seasonality quarters, consistent with the returns being driven by mistaken earnings estimates. We show that investors appear to overweight recent lower earnings following positive seasonality quarters, leading to pessimistic forecasts in the subsequent positive seasonality quarter. The returns are not explained by risk-based explanations, firm-specific information, increased volume, or idiosyncratic volatility.</description><author>Chang, Tom Y.; Hartzmark, Samuel M.; Solomon, David H.; Soltes, Eugene F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Actual Share Repurchases, Price Efficiency, and the Information Content of Stock Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Busch, Pascal; Obernberger, Stefan
We examine the impact of actual share repurchases on stock prices using several measures of price efficiency and manually collected data on U.S. repurchases. We find that share repurchases make prices more efficient and reduce idiosyncratic risk. Further analyses reveal that the effects are primarily driven by repurchases in down markets. We conclude that share repurchases help to maintain accurate stock prices by providing price support at fundamental values. We find no evidence that managers use share repurchases to manipulate stock prices when selling their equity holdings or exercising stock options.</description><author>Busch, Pascal; Obernberger, Stefan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Risky Is Consumption in the Long-Run? Benchmark Estimates from a Robust Estimator</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dew-Becker, Ian
The long-run standard deviation (LRSD) of consumption growth is a key moment in determining risk premiums under Epstein-Zin preferences. Standard estimators of the LRSD are biased downward and have poor confidence interval coverage, making them overreject the long-run risk model. This paper studies a new estimator with smaller bias and accurate confidence intervals. Standard long-run risk calibrations are still rejected in the data. The LRSD of consumption growth in the postwar sample is estimated to be 2.5% per year with an upper bound to the 95% confidence interval of 4.9%. These values can be taken as benchmarks for future calibrations.</description><author>Dew-Becker, Ian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Individual Investor Activity and Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahlquist, Magnus; Martinez, Jose Vicente; Soderlind, Paul
We examine the daily activity and performance of a large panel of individual investors from Sweden's Premium Pension System. We find that active investors earn higher returns and risk-adjusted returns than do inactive investors. A performance decomposition analysis reveals that most outperformance by active investors is the result of active investors successfully timing mutual funds and asset classes. While activity is beneficial for some investors, extreme flows out of mutual funds affect funds' net asset values negatively for all investors. Financial advisors, by contributing to coordinate investments and redemptions, exacerbate these negative effects.</description><author>Dahlquist, Magnus; Martinez, Jose Vicente; Soderlind, Paul</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Prices and Risk Sharing in Open Economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stathopoulos, Andreas
This paper proposes a two-country model that features time-varying heterogeneity in conditional risk aversion across countries, endogenously arising from the interaction between external habit formation and preference home bias. The model generates high international correlation of state prices along with modest cross-country consumption growth correlation and matches the empirical disconnect between exchange rate changes and consumption growth rate differentials. The key mechanism is endogenous time variation in conditional consumption growth volatility: the conditionally less risk averse country insures the more risk averse one, offsetting cross-country heterogeneity in conditional risk aversion and leading to significant international comovement in marginal utility growth.</description><author>Stathopoulos, Andreas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Currency Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Menkhoff, Lukas; Sarno, Lucio; Schmeling, Maik; Schrimpf, Andreas
We assess the properties of currency value strategies based on real exchange rates. We find that real exchange rates have predictive power for the cross-section of currency excess returns. However, adjusting real exchange rates for key country-specific fundamentals (productivity, the quality of export goods, net foreign assets, and output gaps) better isolates information related to the currency risk premium. In turn, the resultant measure of currency value displays considerably stronger predictive power for currency excess returns. Finally, the predictive information content in our currency value measure is distinct from that embedded in popular currency strategies, such as carry and momentum.</description><author>Menkhoff, Lukas; Sarno, Lucio; Schmeling, Maik; Schrimpf, Andreas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Pricing When 'This Time Is Different'</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Johannes, Michael; Lochstoer, Lars A.
Recent evidence suggests that younger people update beliefs in response to aggregate shocks more than older people. We embed this generational learning bias in an equilibrium model in which agents have recursive preferences and are uncertain about exogenous aggregate dynamics. The departure from rational expectations is statistically modest, but generates high average risk premiums varying at generational frequencies, a positive relation between past returns and agents' future return forecasts, and substantial and persistent over-and undervaluation. Consistent with the model, the price-dividend ratio is empirically more sensitive to macroeconomic shocks when the fraction of young in the population is higher.</description><author>Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Johannes, Michael; Lochstoer, Lars A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Stocks Real Assets? Sticky Discount Rates in Stock Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Katz, Michael; Lustig, Hanno; Nielsen, Lars
Local stock markets adjust sluggishly to changes in local inflation. When the local rate of inflation increases, local investors subsequently earn lower real returns on local stocks, but not on local bonds or foreign stocks, suggesting that local stock market investors use sticky long-run nominal discount rates that are too low when inflation increases because they are slow to update the inflation expectations in discount rates. Small amounts of stickiness in inflation expectations suffice to match the real stock return predictability induced by inflation in the data. We also consider other explanations, such as nominal cash flow extrapolation.</description><author>Katz, Michael; Lustig, Hanno; Nielsen, Lars</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-Run and Long-Run Consumption Risks, Dividend Processes, and Asset Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Jun; Zhang, Harold H.
We examine the implications of short-run and long-run consumption risks on the momentum and long-term contrarian profits and the value premium in a unified economic framework. By introducing time-varying firm cash flow exposures to the short-run and long-run shocks in consumption growth, we find the otherwise standard intertemporal asset pricing model goes a long way toward generating the momentum and long-term contrarian profits and the value premium. The model also reproduces the size effect, the pairwise correlations between the profitabilities of these investment strategies, and the performance of the standard CAPM and the consumption CAPM in explaining these well-documented return behaviors.</description><author>Li, Jun; Zhang, Harold H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Is the Consumption-CAPM Missing? An Information-Theoretic Framework for the Analysis of Asset Pricing Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghosh, Anisha; Julliard, Christian; Taylor, Alex P.
We consider asset pricing models in which the SDF can be factorized into an observable component and a potentially unobservable one. Using a relative entropy minimization approach, we nonparametrically estimate the SDF and its components. Empirically, we find the SDF has a business-cycle pattern and significant correlations with market crashes and the Fama-French factors. Moreover, we derive novel bounds for the SDF that are tighter and have higher information content than existing ones. We show that commonly used consumption-based SDFs correlate poorly with the estimated one, require high risk aversion to satisfy the bounds and understate market crash risk.</description><author>Ghosh, Anisha; Julliard, Christian; Taylor, Alex P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetries and Portfolio Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dahlquist, Magnus; Farago, Adam; Tedongap, Romeo
We examine the portfolio choice of an investor with generalized disappointment-aversion preferences who faces log returns described by a normal-exponential model. We derive a three-fund separation strategy: the investor allocates wealth to a risk-free asset, a standard mean-variance efficient fund, and an additional fund reflecting return asymmetries. The optimal portfolio is characterized by the investor's endogenous effective risk aversion and implicit asymmetry aversion. In empirical applications, we find that disappointment aversion is associated with much larger asymmetry aversion than are standard preferences. Our model explains patterns in popular portfolio advice across both risk appetites and investment horizons.</description><author>Dahlquist, Magnus; Farago, Adam; Tedongap, Romeo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring Systemic Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Pedersen, Lasse H.; Philippon, Thomas; Richardson, Matthew
We present an economic model of systemic risk in which undercapitalization of the financial sector as a whole is assumed to harm the real economy, leading to a systemic risk externality. Each financial institution's contribution to systemic risk can be measured as its systemic expected shortfall (SES), that is, its propensity to be undercapitalized when the system as a whole is undercapitalized. SES increases in the institution's leverage and its marginal expected shortfall (MES), that is, its losses in the tail of the system's loss distribution. We demonstrate empirically the ability of components of SES to predict emerging systemic risk during the financial crisis of 2007-2009.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Pedersen, Lasse H.; Philippon, Thomas; Richardson, Matthew</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>SRISK: A Conditional Capital Shortfall Measure of Systemic Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brownlees, Christian; Engle, Robert F.
We introduce SRISK to measure the systemic risk contribution of a financial firm. SRISK measures the capital shortfall of a firm conditional on a severe market decline, and is a function of its size, leverage and risk. We use the measure to study top financial institutions in the recent financial crisis. SRISK delivers useful rankings of systemic institutions at various stages of the crisis and identifies Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac, Morgan Stanley, Bear Stearns, and Lehman Brothers as top contributors as early as 2005-Q1. Moreover, aggregate SRISK provides early warning signals of distress in indicators of real activity.</description><author>Brownlees, Christian; Engle, Robert F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nothing Special About Banks: Competition and Bank Lending in Britain, 1885-1925</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Braggion, Fabio; Dwarkasing, Narly; Moore, Lyndon
We investigate the impact of increasing bank concentration on bank loan contracts in a lightly regulated environment that allows us to abstract from possible confounding effects of regulation and focus on the "pure" effects of competition on bank lending. We study over 30,000 British bank loans over the period 1885 to 1925. Borrowers in counties with high bank concentration received smaller loans and posted more collateral than borrowers in other counties. In high concentration counties, the quality of loan applicants improved, suggesting that banks restricted credit, not that the quality of loan applicants had worsened.</description><author>Braggion, Fabio; Dwarkasing, Narly; Moore, Lyndon</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dynamics of Investment, Payout and Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lambrecht, Bart M.; Myers, Stewart C.
We develop a dynamic agency model of a public corporation. Managers underinvest because of risk aversion. They smooth rents and payout. They do not exploit interest tax shields fully. The interactions of investment, debt, and payout decisions can change drastically depending on managers' preferences. Managers with power utility set investment, debt, and payout proportional to the firm's net worth, generating a constant (possibly negative) net debt ratio. With exponential utility, investment decisions are separated from decisions about debt and payout. More profitable firms become cash cows, and less profitable firms accumulate debt, as in a pecking-order model.</description><author>Lambrecht, Bart M.; Myers, Stewart C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Professional Norms in the Banking Industry Favor Risk-taking?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohn, Alain; Fehr, Ernst; Marechal, Michel Andre
In recent years, the banking industry has witnessed several cases of excessive risk-taking that frequently have been attributed to problematic professional norms. We conduct experiments with employees from several banks in which we manipulate the saliency of their professional identity and subsequently measure their risk aversion in a real stakes investment task. If bank employees are exposed to professional norms that favor risk-taking, they should become more willing to take risks when their professional identity is salient. We find, however, that subjects take significantly less risk, challenging the view that the professional norms generally increase bank employees' willingness to take risks.</description><author>Cohn, Alain; Fehr, Ernst; Marechal, Michel Andre</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Are Modifications of Securitized Loans Beneficial to Investors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maturana, Gonzalo
Loan modification is widely discussed as an alternative to foreclosure, but little research has focused on quantifying its effect on loan performance. I quantify this effect early in the housing crisis by exploiting exogenous variation in the incentives to modify securitized nonagency loans. An additional modification reduces loan losses by 35.8% relative to the average loss; this reduction suggests that the marginal benefit of modification likely exceeded the marginal cost. Consistent with the idea that high-income borrowers may be better equipped to withstand bad economic times, I find that modifications are especially beneficial when borrowers have larger loans.</description><author>Maturana, Gonzalo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Quantitative Easing on Bank Lending Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rodnyansky, Alexander; Darmouni, Olivier M.
Banks' exposure to large-scale asset purchases, as measured by the relative prevalence of mortgage-backed securities on their books, affects lending following unconventional monetary policy shocks. Using a difference-in-differences identification strategy, this paper finds strong effects of the first and third round of quantitative easing (QE1 and QE3) on credit. Highly affected commercial banks increase lending by 2% to 3% relative to their counterparts. QE2 had no significant impact, consistent with its exclusive focus on Treasuries sparsely held by banks. Overall, banks respond heterogeneously, and the type of asset being targeted is central to QE.</description><author>Rodnyansky, Alexander; Darmouni, Olivier M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endogenous Leverage and Advantageous Selection in Credit Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nenov, Plamen T.
I study asset price amplification in an asymmetric information model. Entrepreneurs issue debt to finance investments in a physical asset. They have private information about their success probabilities. For a given debt level, higher asset prices require entrepreneurs to invest more of their own funds. This makes bad entrepreneurs more reluctant to mimic good ones; as a result, good entrepreneurs increase their equilibrium leverage and invest more, and this amplifies the initial asset price increase. This model generates predictions about the credit market that are qualitatively consistent with existing evidence.</description><author>Nenov, Plamen T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contingent Capital, Tail Risk, and Debt-Induced Collapse</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Nan; Glasserman, Paul; Nouri, Behzad; Pelger, Markus
We study the design and incentive effects of contingent convertible debt. With contingent convertibles, the endogenous bankruptcy boundary can be at either of two levels: one with lower default risk or one at which default precedes conversion. An increase in debt moves the firm from the first regime to the second, a phenomenon we call debt-induced collapse. Setting the conversion trigger sufficiently high avoids this hazard. Given this condition, we investigate the effect of contingent capital and debt maturity on optimal capital structure, debt overhang, and asset substitution. We calibrate the model to large banks during the financial crisis.</description><author>Chen, Nan; Glasserman, Paul; Nouri, Behzad; Pelger, Markus</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk-Based Capital Requirements for Banks and International Trade</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demir, Banu; Michalski, Tomasz K.; Ors, Evren
We test the trade finance channel of exports by controlling for the bank credit channel. Using Turkey's July 2012 adoption of Basel II as a quasi-natural experiment, we examine whether shocks to trade financing costs affect exports. With data for 16,662 Turkish exporters shipping 2,888 different products to 158 countries, we find that the share of letters-of-credit-based exports decreases (increases) when the associated risk weights for counterparty exposure increase (decrease) after the adoption of Basel II. However, growth of firm-product-country-level exports remains unaffected. Trade financing might have a lesser role in exports than previously suggested by the previous literature.</description><author>Demir, Banu; Michalski, Tomasz K.; Ors, Evren</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Speculation and the Term Structure of Interest Rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barillas, Francisco; Nimark, Kristoffer P.
We develop and estimate a tractable equilibrium term structure model populated with rational but heterogeneously informed traders that take on speculative positions to exploit what they perceive to be inaccurate market expectations about future bond prices. The speculative motive is an important driver of trading volume. Yield dynamics due to speculation are (1) statistically distinct from classical term structure components due to risk premiums and expectations about future short rates and are orthogonal to public information available to traders in real time and (2) quantitatively important, accounting for a substantial fraction of the variation of long maturity U.S. bond yields.</description><author>Barillas, Francisco; Nimark, Kristoffer P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>De Facto Seniority, Credit Risk, and Corporate Bond Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bao, Jack; Hou, Kewei
We study the effect of a bond's place in its issuer's maturity structure on credit risk. Using a structural model as motivation, we argue that bonds due relatively late in their issuers' maturity structure have greater credit risk than do bonds due relatively early. Empirically, we find robust evidence that these later bonds have larger yield spreads and greater comovement with equity and that the magnitude of the effects is consistent with model predictions for investment-grade bonds. Our results highlight the importance of bond-specific credit risk for understanding corporate bond prices.</description><author>Bao, Jack; Hou, Kewei</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economic Effects of a Borrower Bailout: Evidence from an Emerging Market (hhx073, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gine, Xavier; Kanz, Martin
nan</description><author>Gine, Xavier; Kanz, Martin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit-Induced Boom and Bust</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Di Maggio, Marco; Kermani, Amir
This paper exploits the federal preemption of national banks in 2004 from local laws against predatory lending to gauge the effect of the supply of credit on the real economy. First, the preemption regulation resulted in an 11% increase in annual lending in the 2004-2006 period, which is associated with a 3.3% rise in annual house price growth rate and a 2.2% expansion of employment in nontradable sectors. This was followed by a sharp decline in subsequent years. Furthermore, we show that the increase in the supply of credit reduced delinquencies during boom years, but increased them in bust years.</description><author>Di Maggio, Marco; Kermani, Amir</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Strategic Underreporting of Bank Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Begley, Taylor A.; Purnanandam, Amiyatosh; Zheng, Kuncheng
We show that banks significantly underreport the risk in their trading book when they have lower equity capital. Specifically, a decrease in a bank's equity capital results in substantially more violations of its self-reported risk levels in the following quarter. Underreporting is especially frequent during the critical periods of high systemic risk and for banks with larger trading operations. We exploit a discontinuity in the expected benefit of underreporting present in Basel regulations to provide further support for a causal link between capital-saving incentives and underreporting. Overall, we show that banks' self-reported risk measures become least informative precisely when they matter the most.</description><author>Begley, Taylor A.; Purnanandam, Amiyatosh; Zheng, Kuncheng</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loan Sales and Bank Liquidity Management: Evidence from a US Credit Register</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Irani, Rustom M.; Meisenzahl, Ralf R.
We examine how banks use loan sales to manage liquidity during periods of marketwide stress and the associated spillovers to market prices. We track the dynamics of loan share ownership in the secondary market using data from a U.S. supervisory register of syndicated loans. Controlling for loan quality using loan-year fixed effects, we find that banks reliant on wholesale funding were more likely to exit syndicates through sales during 2007/08. This effect is stronger for banks dependent on short-term funding and holding fewer liquid securities. In addition, secondary market prices decrease significantly more for loans funded by liquidity-strained banks.</description><author>Irani, Rustom M.; Meisenzahl, Ralf R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Excessive Is Banks' Maturity Transformation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Segura, Anatoli; Suarez, Javier
We quantify the gains from regulating maturity transformation in a model of banks that finance long-term assets with nontradable debt. Banks choose the amount and maturity of their debt by trading off investors' preferences for short maturities with the risk of systemic crises. Pecuniary externalities make unregulated debt maturities inefficiently short. In calibrating the model to eurozone banking data for 2006, we find that lengthening the average maturity of wholesale debt from 2.8 to 3.3 months would produce welfare gains with a present value of euro 105 billion, while the lengthening induced by the NSFR would be too drastic.</description><author>Segura, Anatoli; Suarez, Javier</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Managers Give Hometown Labor an Edge?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yonker, Scott E.
In line with the psychological theory of place attachments, managers favor hometown workers over others. Consistent with this prediction, I find that following periods of industry distress, establishments located near CEOs' childhood homes experience fewer employment and pay reductions and are less likely to be divested relative to other firm establishments. While it is not possible to directly test whether this employment bias destroys firm value, managers only implement these policies when governance is weak, suggesting that this favoritism is suboptimal. Together, these results provide direct evidence of employee favoritism and show that idiosyncratic manager styles impact corporate employment decisions.</description><author>Yonker, Scott E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Within-Firm Pay Inequality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mueller, Holger M.; Ouimet, Paige P.; Simintzi, Elena
Financial regulators and investors have expressed concerns about high pay inequality within firms. Using a proprietary data set of public and private firms, this paper shows that firms with higher pay inequality-relative wage differentials between top-and bottom-level jobs-are larger and have higher valuations and stronger operating performance. Moreover, firms with higher pay inequality exhibit larger equity returns and greater earnings surprises, suggesting that pay inequality is not fully priced by the market. Our results support the notion that differences in pay inequality across firms are a reflection of differences in managerial talent.</description><author>Mueller, Holger M.; Ouimet, Paige P.; Simintzi, Elena</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash Holdings and Labor Heterogeneity: The Role of Skilled Labor</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghaly, Mohamed; Dang, Viet Anh; Stathopoulos, Konstantinos
Firms differ in their dependence on skilled labor and face labor adjustment costs that increase with their workers' skill level. We show that firms with a higher share of skilled workers, and thus less flexibility to adjust their labor demand in response to cash flow shocks, hold more precautionary cash. The effect of labor skills on cash holdings is more pronounced for financially constrained firms and varies with exogenous differences in firing and hiring costs. We address endogeneity concerns by using subsamples of firms with reasonably similar characteristics, propensity score matching, and a quasi-experimental shock to labor markets.</description><author>Ghaly, Mohamed; Dang, Viet Anh; Stathopoulos, Konstantinos</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor-Force Heterogeneity and Asset Prices: The Importance of Skilled Labor</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Belo, Frederico; Li, Jun; Lin, Xiaoji; Zhao, Xiaofei
Previous studies have identified a negative relation between firms' hiring rates and future stock returns in the cross-section. We document that this relation is significantly steeper in industries that rely relatively more on high-skill workers than low-skill workers. A long-short portfolio sorted on firm-level hiring rate earns an average annual return of 8.6% in high-skill industries, and only 0.9% in low-skill industries. Moreover, this pattern is not explained by the standard CAPM. These findings are consistent with a neoclassical model with labor force heterogeneity and labor market frictions if it is more costly to replace high-skill than low-skill workers.</description><author>Belo, Frederico; Li, Jun; Lin, Xiaoji; Zhao, Xiaofei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bid-Ask Spreads, Trading Networks, and the Pricing of Securitizations (vol 30, pg 3048, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hollifield, Burton; Neklyudov, Artem; Spatt, Chester
nan</description><author>Hollifield, Burton; Neklyudov, Artem; Spatt, Chester</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mortgages and Monetary Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garriga, Carlos; Kydland, Finn E.; Sustek, Roman
Mortgages are long-term loans with nominal payments. Consequently, in incomplete asset markets, monetary policy can affect housing investment and the economy through the cost of new mortgage borrowing and real payments on outstanding debt. These channels, distinct from the traditional real rate channel, are embedded in a general equilibrium model. The transmission mechanism is stronger under adjustable-rate mortgages compared with fixed-rate mortgages. Further, persistent monetary policy shocks affecting the level of the nominal yield curve have larger real effects compared with transitory shocks. Persistently higher inflation gradually benefits homeowners under FRMs, but hurts them immediately under ARMs.</description><author>Garriga, Carlos; Kydland, Finn E.; Sustek, Roman</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Small Bank Comparative Advantages in Alleviating Financial Constraints and Providing Liquidity Insurance over Time</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; Bouwman, Christa H. S.; Kim, Dasol
We use novel monthly survey data from 1993 to 2012 on small business managerial perceptions of financial constraints and other conditions, matched with information on banks in their local markets. The data suggest that small banks have comparative advantages in alleviating these constraints. These advantages tend to be greater during adverse economic conditions and do not appear to decrease or increase secularly. Small banks also appear to have comparative advantages in providing liquidity insurance to small business customers of large banks experiencing liquidity shocks during financial crises. Our findings suggest a source of social costs from ongoing consolidation of the banking industry.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; Bouwman, Christa H. S.; Kim, Dasol</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonlinear Shrinkage of the Covariance Matrix for Portfolio Selection: Markowitz Meets Goldilocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ledoit, Olivier; Wolf, Michael
Markowitz (1952) portfolio selection requires an estimator of the covariance matrix of returns. To address this problem, we promote a nonlinear shrinkage estimator that is more flexible than previous linear shrinkage estimators and has just the right number of free parameters (i.e., the Goldilocks principle). This number is the same as the number of assets. Our nonlinear shrinkage estimator is asymptotically optimal for portfolio selection when the number of assets is of the same magnitude as the sample size. In backtests with historical stock return data, it performs better than previous proposals and, in particular, it dominates linear shrinkage.</description><author>Ledoit, Olivier; Wolf, Michael</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International Corporate Diversification and Financial Flexibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jang, Yeejin
If the location of firm operations is relevant for financing, multinationals should have easier access to different foreign sources of funding relative to domestic firms. I document that U.S. multinationals are more likely to borrow from a foreign bank and to issue international bonds than are U.S. domestic firms. Multinationals are less affected than domestic firms by capital market dislocations because of greater funding flexibility. Using the 2007-2009 financial crisis as a capital supply shock, I find that multinationals relied more on foreign funding sources in bank loans and consequently reduced domestic investment less than did domestic firms.</description><author>Jang, Yeejin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Management with Supply Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, Heitor; Hankins, Kristine Watson; Williams, Ryan
Purchase obligations are forward contracts with suppliers and are used more broadly than traded commodity derivatives. This paper is the first to document that these contracts are a risk management tool and have a material impact on corporate hedging activity. Firms that expand their risk management options following the introduction of steel futures contracts substitute financial hedging for purchase obligations. Contracting frictions, such as bargaining power and settlement risk, as well as potential hold-up issues associated with relationship-specific investment, affect the use of purchase obligations in the cross-section, as well as how firms respond to the introduction of steel futures.</description><author>Almeida, Heitor; Hankins, Kristine Watson; Williams, Ryan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Authority, Consensus, and Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chakraborty, Archishman; Yilmaz, Bilge
Management-aligned boards exchange precise information with management and make efficient decisions. But when agency conflicts are important, management-aligned boards may not maximize shareholder value. Even if management controls all decisions and the board only provides advice, optimal boards may withhold information. This creates inefficiencies. But agency costs fall because management is induced to obey the board. When the board can directly veto management proposals, shareholders are better off. Optimal boards should then be more shareholder-aligned. Shareholder value is further enhanced if shareholders can veto management and also commit to revealing the board's information. Optimal boards should then be perfectly shareholder-aligned.</description><author>Chakraborty, Archishman; Yilmaz, Bilge</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Simple Estimation of Bid-Ask Spreads from Daily Close, High, and Low Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abdi, Farshid; Ranaldo, Angelo
We propose a new method to estimate the bid-ask spread when quote data are not available. Compared to other low-frequency estimates, this method utilizes a wider information set, namely, readily available close, high, and low prices. In the absence of end-of-day quote data, this method generally provides the highest cross-sectional and average time-series correlations with the TAQ effective spread benchmark. Moreover, it delivers the most accurate estimates for less liquid stocks. Our estimator has many potential applications, including an accurate measurement of transaction cost, systematic liquidity risk, and commonality in liquidity for U.S. stocks dating back almost one century.</description><author>Abdi, Farshid; Ranaldo, Angelo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Impact or Trading Volume: Why Is the Amihud (2002) Measure Priced?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lou, Xiaoxia; Shu, Tao
The return premium associated with the Amihud (2002) measure is generally considered a liquidity premium that compensates for price impact. We find that the pricing of the Amihud measure is not attributable to the construction of the return-to-volume ratio intended to capture price impact, but is driven by the trading volume component. Additionally, the high-frequency price impact and spread benchmarks are priced only in January and do not explain the pricing of the trading volume component of the Amihud measure. Additional analyses suggest that the volume effect on stock return is likely caused by mispricing, not by compensation for illiquidity.</description><author>Lou, Xiaoxia; Shu, Tao</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Hedging Affect Firm Value? Evidence from a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilje, Erik P.; Taillard, Jerome P.
We exploit an exogenous change in basis risk in the oil and gas industry to analyze the channels through which hedging affects firm value. Using a difference-in-differences framework, we find that firms affected by a basis risk shock reduce investment, have lower valuations, sell assets, and reduce debt. Our findings are driven by firms with ex ante high leverage. Overall, our results provide evidence that reducing the probability of financial distress and underinvestment risk are first-order channels through which hedging affects firm value.</description><author>Gilje, Erik P.; Taillard, Jerome P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Market Competition and Industry Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bustamante, M. Cecilia; Donangelo, Andres
This paper studies how expected returns interact with product market competition. The model predicts that (1) competition erodes markups, such that firms are more exposed to systematic risk; (2) the threat of entry by new firms lowers exposure to systematic risk of incumbents; and (3) higher industry aggregate risk represents a barrier to entry, such that riskier industries become less competitive. We provide empirical evidence consistent with these three channels and for an overall negative relation between returns and competition. We also consider a sample selection correction for publicly listed firms and use it to construct an alternative concentration measure.</description><author>Bustamante, M. Cecilia; Donangelo, Andres</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rational Opacity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Monnet, Cyril; Quintin, Erwan
We present an environment in which long-term investors sometimes choose to restrict how much fundamental information they receive about the value of their investment to preserve its liquidity in secondary markets. When and only when there is a risk that secondary markets may be shallow, more information can reduce the expected payoff of agents who need to cash out early. Even given direct and costless control over information design, stakeholders choose to incentivize managers to withhold interim information. In such an environment, imposing transparency can lower investment and welfare.</description><author>Monnet, Cyril; Quintin, Erwan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Characteristics that Provide Independent Information about Average</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, Jeremiah; Hand, John R. M.; Zhang, X. Frank
We take up Cochrane's (2011) challenge to identify the firm characteristics that provide independent information about average U.S. monthly stock returns by simultaneously including 94 characteristics in Fama-MacBeth regressions that avoid overweighting microcaps and adjust for data-snooping bias. We find that while 12 characteristics are reliably independent determinants in non-microcap stocks from 1980 to 2014 as a whole, return predictability sharply fell in 2003 such that just two characteristics have been independent determinants since then. Outside of microcaps, the hedge returns to exploiting characteristics-based predictability also have been insignificantly different from zero since 2003.</description><author>Green, Jeremiah; Hand, John R. M.; Zhang, X. Frank</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Returns to Hedge Fund Activism: An International Study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becht, Marco; Franks, Julian; Grant, Jeremy; Wagner, Hannes F.
This paper provides evidence on the incidence, characteristics, and performance of activist engagements across countries. We find that the incidence of activism is greatest with high institutional ownership, particularly for U.S. institutions. We use a sample of 1,740 activist engagements across 23 countries and find that almost one-quarter of engagements are by multi-activists engaging the same target. These engagements perform strikingly better than single activist engagements. Engagement outcomes, such as board changes and takeovers, vary across countries and significantly contribute to the returns to activism. Japan is an exception, with high initial expectations and low outcomes. (JEL G32)</description><author>Becht, Marco; Franks, Julian; Grant, Jeremy; Wagner, Hannes F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity Vesting and Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex; Fang, Vivian W.; Lewellen, Katharina A.
This paper links the CEO's concerns for the current stock price to reductions in real investment. We identify short-term concerns using the amount of stock and options scheduled to vest in a given quarter. Vesting equity is associated with a decline in the growth of research and development and capital expenditure, positive analyst forecast revisions, and positive earnings guidance, within the same quarter. More broadly, by introducing a measure of incentives that is determined by equity grants made several years prior, and thus unlikely driven by current investment opportunities, we provide evidence that CEO contracts affect real decisions.</description><author>Edmans, Alex; Fang, Vivian W.; Lewellen, Katharina A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Takeover Defense Indices Measure Takeover Deterrence?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Schonlau, Robert J.; Wehrly, Eric W.
Many researchers use the G-index or E-index to measure firms' takeover defenses. Others argue that these indices are not related to firms' takeover likelihoods. We find that, unlike their raw values, the instrumented versions of these indices are significantly and negatively related to acquisition likelihood. The difference between the raw and instrumented results indicates that the G-index and E-index include an endogenous component and highlights the importance of accounting for endogeneity in tests that use takeover indices to measure takeover deterrence. We provide data on new instruments that researchers can use to address these issues.</description><author>Karpoff, Jonathan M.; Schonlau, Robert J.; Wehrly, Eric W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real Effects of Lending Relationships on Innovative Firms and Inventor Mobility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hombert, Johan; Matray, Adrien
We study how relationship lending determines the financing of innovation. Exploiting a negative shock to relationships, we show that it reduces the number of innovative firms, especially those that depend more on relationship lending such as small, opaque firms. This credit supply shock leads to reallocation of inventors whereby young and productive inventors leave small firms and move out of geographical areas where lending relationships are hurt. Overall, our results show that credit markets affect both the level of innovation activity and the distribution of innovative human capital across the economy.</description><author>Hombert, Johan; Matray, Adrien</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Forces and CEO Pay: Shocks to CEO Demand Induced by IPOWaves</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nickerson, Jordan
I develop a simple competitive equilibrium model and derive the prediction that CEO pay-size elasticity increases when more firms compete for an inelastic supply of managers. Using industry-level IPO waves as a proxy for increased competition for CEOs, I find that pay-size elasticity increases by 6% with a one-standard-deviation increase in IPO activity. This effect is stronger in specialized industries. In addition, increased IPO activity leads to a greater likelihood of executive transitions between firms. These findings indicate that market forces play a key role in the determination of CEO pay.</description><author>Nickerson, Jordan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Independent Director Departures Predict Future Bad Events?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fahlenbrach, Rudiger; Low, Angie; Stulz, Rene M.
Following surprise independent director departures, affected firms have worse stock and operating performance, are more likely to restate earnings, face shareholder litigation, suffer from an extreme negative return event, and make worse mergers and acquisitions. The announcement returns to surprise director departures are negative, suggesting that the market infers bad news from surprise departures. We use exogenous variation in independent director departures triggered by director deaths to test whether surprise independent director departures cause these negative outcomes or whether an anticipation of negative outcomes is responsible for the surprise director departure. Our evidence is more consistent with the latter.</description><author>Fahlenbrach, Rudiger; Low, Angie; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intellectual Property Rights Protection, Ownership, and Innovation: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fang, Lily H.; Lerner, Josh; Wu, Chaopeng
Using a difference-in-differences approach, we study how intellectual property right (IPR) protection affects innovation in China in the years around the privatizations of state-owned enterprises (SOEs). Innovation increases after SOE privatizations, and this increase is larger in cities with strong IPR protection. Our results support theoretical arguments that IPR protection strengthens firms' incentives to innovate and that private sector firms are more sensitive to IPR protection than SOEs.</description><author>Fang, Lily H.; Lerner, Josh; Wu, Chaopeng</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Determines Entrepreneurial Outcomes in Emerging Markets? The Role of Initial Conditions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ayyagari, Meghana; Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Maksimovic, Vojislav
We study how institutions influence start-up characteristics of firms and how these characteristics predict entrants' growth trajectories over the early firm life cycle. Using census data from India, we find that greater financial development is associated with higher entry rates and smaller-sized entrants. Following entry, however, large and small entrants grow at the same rates across states with different institutions or industries with differing reliance on external finance. The impact of access to finance is greater on start-up size and entry rates than on the subsequent growth of firms during the early life cycle.</description><author>Ayyagari, Meghana; Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Maksimovic, Vojislav</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Does Personal Bankruptcy Law Affect Startups?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cerqueiro, Geraldo; Fabiana Penas, Maria
We exploit state-level changes in the amount of personal wealth individuals can protect under Chapter 7 to analyze the effect of debtor protection on the financing structure and performance of a representative panel of U.S. startups. The effect of increasing debtor protection depends on the entrepreneur's level of wealth. Firms owned by mid-wealth entrepreneurs whose assets become fully protected suffer a reduction in credit availability, employment, operating efficiency, and survival rates. We find no such negative effects for low-wealth and high-wealth owners. Our results are consistent with theories that predict that asset protection in bankruptcy leads to a redistribution of credit.</description><author>Cerqueiro, Geraldo; Fabiana Penas, Maria</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Where's the Kink? Disappointment Events in Consumption Growth and Equilibrium Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delikouras, Stefanos
I propose a consumption-based asset pricing model with disappointment aversion to investigate the link between downside consumption risk and expected returns across asset markets. I find that the disappointment model can explain 95% of the cross-sectional variation in size/ book-to-market portfolios and more than 80% of the variation in the joint sample of stocks, bonds, and commodity futures. I also show that the performance of the disappointment model is comparable to that of the Fama-French three-factor specification, regardless of the sample frequency (annual, quarterly). Overall, my results indicate that disappointment aversion considerably improves the fit of consumption-based asset pricing models.</description><author>Delikouras, Stefanos</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fraudulent Income Overstatement on Mortgage Applications During the Credit Expansion of 2002 to 2005</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mian, Atif; Sufi, Amir
Treating fraudulently overstated income on mortgage applications as true income can lead to incorrect conclusions on the nature of the mortgage credit supply expansion toward marginal borrowers from 2002 to 2005. A positive gap between zip-code-level income growth calculated from mortgage applications and income growth from the IRS likely reflects mortgage fraud, not an improvement in home-buyer income. In support of the credit supply view, mortgage credit for home purchase expanded significantly more in low-credit-score neighborhoods on both the extensive and intensive margins from 2002 to 2005, even though these neighborhoods deteriorated on many measures of income prospects.</description><author>Mian, Atif; Sufi, Amir</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Housing Demand During the Boom: The Role of Expectations and Credit Constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Landvoigt, Tim
I use a life-cycle model of housing demand to infer expectations about house prices and home equity requirements for the housing boom of the 2000s from observed household choices. Expectations and credit constraints are separately identified from the intensive and extensive margins of housing demand. The main results are that (1) expected price growth was close to average long-run growth, (2) home equity requirements were lax initially, but tightened after the bust, and (3) subjective uncertainty about future price growth was large. Given the option to default on mortgage debt, greater price uncertainty leads to higher optimal household leverage.</description><author>Landvoigt, Tim</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Political Economy of Financial Innovation: Evidence from Local Governments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Perignon, Christophe; Vallee, Boris
We investigate the development of an innovative and high-risk type of borrowing for local governments, known as structured loans. Using transaction data for more than 2,700 local governments in France, we show that the adoption of these instruments is more frequent for politicians from highly indebted local governments, from politically contested areas, and during political campaigns. Taking on structured loans helps incumbents win a reelection, and initially allows them to maintain lower taxes. Our findings illustrate how financial innovation can amplify principal-agent problems within the political system.</description><author>Perignon, Christophe; Vallee, Boris</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Aggregated Returns Disclosure Increase Portfolio Risk Taking?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beshears, John; Choi, James J.; Laibson, David; Madrian, Brigitte C.
Many experiments have found that participants take more investment risk if they see less frequent returns, portfolio-level returns (rather than each individual asset's returns), or longhorizon (rather than one-year) historical return distributions. In contrast, we find that such information aggregation treatments do not affect total equity investment when we make the investment environment more realistic than in prior experiments. Previously documented aggregation effects are not robust to changes in the risky asset's return distribution or to the introduction of a multiday delay between portfolio choice and return realizations.</description><author>Beshears, John; Choi, James J.; Laibson, David; Madrian, Brigitte C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Long-Term Contracting with Learning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Zhiguo; Wei, Bin; Yu, Jianfeng; Gao, Feng
We introduce uncertainty into Holmstrom and Milgrom (1987) to study optimal long-term contracting with learning. In a dynamic relationship, the agent's shirking not only reduces current performance, but also increases the agent's information rent due to the persistent belief manipulation effect. We characterize the optimal contract using the dynamic programming technique in which information rent is the unique state variable. In the optimal contract, the optimal effort is front-loaded and stochastically decreases over time. Furthermore, the optimal contract exhibits an option-like feature in that incentives increase after good performance. Implications about managerial incentives and asset management compensations are discussed.</description><author>He, Zhiguo; Wei, Bin; Yu, Jianfeng; Gao, Feng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Mind Is a Terrible Thing to Change: Confirmatory Bias in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pouget, Sebastien; Sauvagnat, Julien; Villeneuve, Stephane
This paper studies the impact of the confirmatory bias on financial markets. We propose a model in which some traders may ignore new evidence inconsistent with their favorite hypothesis regarding the state of the world. The confirmatory bias provides a unified rationale for several existing stylized facts, including excess volatility, excess volume, and momentum. It also delivers novel predictions for which we find empirical support using data on analysts' earnings forecasts: traders update beliefs depending on the sign of past signals and previous beliefs, and, at the stock level, differences of opinion are larger when past signals have different signs.</description><author>Pouget, Sebastien; Sauvagnat, Julien; Villeneuve, Stephane</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Causal Effect of Stop-Loss and Take-Gain Orders on the Disposition Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fischbacher, Urs; Hoffmann, Gerson; Schudy, Simeon
We investigate whether automatic selling devices causally reduce investors' disposition effect (DE) in a laboratory experiment. Investors can actively buy and sell assets. Investors in the treatment group use stop-loss and take-gain options to automatically sell assets. In addition, we introduce a reminder condition that reminds investors about their selling plan if a limit is hit. Results show that the automatic selling device treatment significantly reduces the DEs, but the reminder treatment does not. Thus, the opportunity to ex ante commit to automatically selling at a loss causally reduces the disposition effect.</description><author>Fischbacher, Urs; Hoffmann, Gerson; Schudy, Simeon</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Choice and Amplification of Financial Crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahnert, Toni; Kakhbod, Ali
We propose an amplification mechanism of financial crises based on the information choices of investors. Information acquisition makes investors more likely to act against their prior. Deteriorating public news under an initially strong (weak) prior increases (reduces) the value of private information and induces more (less) information acquisition. Deteriorating public news increases the probability of a crisis, since the initially strong (weak) prior induces no attacks (attacks). This effect is amplified with endogenous information choices. To enhance financial stability, a policy maker affects information acquisition via taxes and subsidies. We derive and discuss testable implications for the magnitude of amplification.</description><author>Ahnert, Toni; Kakhbod, Ali</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>External Habit in a Production Economy: A Model of Asset Prices and Consumption Volatility Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Andrew Y.
A standard real business-cycle model with external habit and capital adjustment costs matches a long list of asset price and business-cycle moments: equity, firm value, and risk-free rate volatility; the equity premium; excess return predictability; consumption growth predictability; basic moments of consumption, output, and investment; among others. The model also generates endogenous consumption volatility risk. Precautionary savings motives make consumption sensitive to shocks in bad times, leading to countercyclical volatility, even with homoscedastic technology shocks. Habit acts as countercyclical leverage, which amplifies this channel. Habit also implies high risk aversion, which amplifies the stock price response.</description><author>Chen, Andrew Y.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Information Content of a Nonlinear Macro-Finance Model for Commodity Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khan, Saqib; Khokher, Zeigham; Simin, Timothy
State-of-the-art term structure models of commodity prices have serious difficulties extrapolating the prices of long-maturity futures contracts from short-dated contracts. This situation is problematic for valuing real commodity-linked assets. We estimate a nonlinear four-factor continuous time model of commodity price dynamics. The model nests many previous specifications. To estimate the model, we use crude oil prices and inventories. The inventory data and nonlinear price dynamics have a large impact on oil price forecasts. The additional factor in our model compared with current three-factor models has a significant impact on model-implied long-maturity futures prices.</description><author>Khan, Saqib; Khokher, Zeigham; Simin, Timothy</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Segmentation and Differential Reactions of Local and Foreign Investors to Analyst Recommendations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jia, Chunxin; Wang, Yaping; Xiong, Wei
This paper uses segmented dual-class shares of Chinese firms-Ashares traded in mainland China by local investors and H shares traded in Hong Kong by foreign investors-to document a rich pattern in the differential reactions of local and foreign investors to analyst recommendations. This pattern reveals that social connections between analysts and investors affect investor reactions to analyst recommendations. Because of the investors' differential reactions, analyst recommendations may exacerbate, rather than attenuate, the market segmentation between the two share classes. (JEL G02, G15)</description><author>Jia, Chunxin; Wang, Yaping; Xiong, Wei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bid-Ask Spreads, Trading Networks, and the Pricing of Securitizations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hollifield, Burton; Neklyudov, Artem; Spatt, Chester
The Financial Industry Regulatory Authority began collecting transaction data from broker-dealers in 2011 as a step toward enhancing its understanding of securitization markets. We use transaction data to document the importance of the interdealer network structure to market quality. Some dealers are relatively central in the network and trade with many dealers, while others are peripheral. Core dealers receive relatively lower and less dispersed spreads than peripheral dealers. We develop a model in which core and peripheral dealers trade with different customer clienteles and argue that the presence of relatively sophisticated customers in securitization markets explains these facts. (JEL G12, G14, G23)</description><author>Hollifield, Burton; Neklyudov, Artem; Spatt, Chester</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Sharing and Contagion in Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cabrales, Antonio; Gottardi, Piero; Vega-Redondo, Fernando
We investigate the socially optimal design of financial networks, that allows to tackle the trade-off between risk sharing and contagion. We identify conditions on the shock distribution under which full integration or maximal segmentation is optimal. We also show that, under different conditions, the optimal network displays different levels of strength of linkages to other firms or intermediate degrees of segmentation. In the latter case, the individual and social incentives to establish linkages are not necessarily aligned. When firms face heterogeneous distributions of risks, they should optimally form linkages only with firms facing risks of the same kind. (JEL D85, C72, G21)</description><author>Cabrales, Antonio; Gottardi, Piero; Vega-Redondo, Fernando</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tax Rates and Corporate Decision-making</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, John R.; Hanlon, Michelle; Shevlin, Terry; Shroff, Nemit
We survey companies and find that many use incorrect tax rate inputs into important corporate decisions. Specifically, many companies use an average tax rate (the GAAP effective tax rate, ETR) to evaluate incremental decisions, rather than using the theoretically correct marginal tax rate. We find evidence consistent with behavioral biases (heuristics, salience) and managers' educational backgrounds affecting these choices. We estimate the economic consequences of using the theoretically incorrect tax rate and find that using the ETR for capital structure decisions leads to suboptimal leverage choices and using the ETR in investment decisions makes firms less responsive to investment opportunities. (JEL H25, G31, M00, G02 and M41)</description><author>Graham, John R.; Hanlon, Michelle; Shevlin, Terry; Shroff, Nemit</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economic Effects of Public Financing: Evidence from Municipal Bond Ratings Recalibration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adelino, Manuel; Cunha, Igor; Ferreira, Miguel A.
We show that municipalities' financial constraints can have a significant impact on local employment and growth. We identify these effects by exploiting exogenous upgrades in U.S. municipal bond ratings caused by Moody's recalibration of its ratings scale in 2010. We find that local governments increase expenditures because their debt capacity expands following a rating upgrade. These expenditures have an estimated local income multiplier of 1.9 and a cost per job of $20,000 per year. Our findings suggest that debt-financed increases in government spending can improve economic conditions during recessions. (JEL E24, G24, G28, H74)</description><author>Adelino, Manuel; Cunha, Igor; Ferreira, Miguel A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Sharing and Rating Manipulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Liberti, Jose Maria; Sturgess, Jason
We show that banks manipulate borrowers' credit ratings before sharing them with competing banks. Using a unique feature on the timing of information disclosure of a public credit registry, we disentangle the effect of manipulation from learning of credit ratings. We show that banks downgrade high-quality borrowers for which they have positive private information to protect their informational rents. Banks also upgrade low-quality borrowers with multiple lenders to avoid creditor runs. Our results suggest that credit ratings manipulation limits the positive effects of credit registries' information disclosure on credit allocation. (JEL G2; G14; G38)</description><author>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Liberti, Jose Maria; Sturgess, Jason</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gender and Connections among Wall Street Analysts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fang, Lily Hua; Huang, Sterling
We examine how alumni ties with corporate boards differentially affect male and female analysts' job performance and career outcomes. Connections improve analysts' forecasting accuracy and recommendation impact, but the effect is two to three times as large for men as for women. Connections also contribute to analysts' likelihood of being voted by institutional investors as "star" analysts, but act as a partial substitute to performance for men, while a complement to performance for women. Our evidence indicates that men benefit more than women from connections in both job performance and the subjective evaluation by others. (JEL G24, J16, J24)</description><author>Fang, Lily Hua; Huang, Sterling</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Information Content of a Nonlinear Macro-Finance Model for Commodity Prices (vol 30, pg 2818, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khan, Saqib; Khokher, Zeigham; Simin, Timothy
nan</description><author>Khan, Saqib; Khokher, Zeigham; Simin, Timothy</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond Market Exposures to Macroeconomic and Monetary Policy Risks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Song, Dongho
The paper estimates a model that allows for shifts in the aggressiveness of monetary policy and time variation in the distribution of macroeconomic shocks. These model features induce variations in the cyclical properties of inflation and the riskiness of bonds. The estimation identifies inflation as procyclical from the late 1990s, when the economy shifted toward aggressive monetary policy and experienced procyclical macroeconomics shocks. Since bonds hedge stock market risks when inflation is procylical, the stock-bond return correlation turned negative in the late 1990s. The risks of encountering countercyclical inflation in the future could lead to an upward-sloping yield curve, like in the data.</description><author>Song, Dongho</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>It Depends on Where You Search: Institutional Investor Attention and Underreaction to News</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben-Rephael, Azi; Da, Zhi; Israelsen, Ryan D.
We propose a direct measure of abnormal institutional investor attention (AIA) using news searching and news reading activity for specific stocks on Bloomberg terminals. AIA is highly correlated with institutional trading measures and related to, but different from, other investor attention proxies. Contrasting AIA with retail attention measured by Google search activity, we find that institutional attention responds more quickly to major news events, leads retail attention, and facilitates permanent price adjustment. The well-documented price drifts following both earnings announcements and analyst recommendation changes are driven by announcements to which institutional investors fail to pay sufficient attention. (JEL D83, G02, G12, G14, G23)</description><author>Ben-Rephael, Azi; Da, Zhi; Israelsen, Ryan D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxation and Dividend Policy: The Muting Effect of Agency Issues and Shareholder Conflicts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacob, Martin; Michaely, Roni
Using proprietary data on the entire spectrum of ownership structure and exact tax status of investors and firms, we examine how dividend taxation affects payout. Utilizing an exogenous shock to dividend taxation, we show that absent any frictions, dividend taxation has a large impact on payout. As agency issues and shareholder conflicts increase, owners' tax preferences have significantly smaller impact on payout. Three mechanisms reduce the dividend-tax sensitivity: Coordination among owners, heterogeneity in tax preferences, and diverging objectives between managers and owners. Altogether, taxation has a first-order impact on payout, but agency issues and shareholder conflicts mute its impact substantially. (JEL G30, G35, H24, H25)</description><author>Jacob, Martin; Michaely, Roni</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pension Fund Asset Allocation and Liability Discount Rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andonov, Aleksandar; Bauer, Rob M. M. J.; Cremers, K. J. Martijn
The unique regulation of U.S. public pension funds links their liability discount rate to the expected return on assets, which gives them incentives to invest more in risky assets in order to report a better funding status. Comparing public and private pension funds in the United States, Canada, and Europe, we find that U.S. public pension funds act on their regulatory incentives. U.S. public pension funds with a higher level of underfunding per participant, as well as funds with more politicians and elected plan participants serving on the board, take more risk and use higher discount rates. The increased risk-taking by U.S. public funds is negatively related to their performance.</description><author>Andonov, Aleksandar; Bauer, Rob M. M. J.; Cremers, K. J. Martijn</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Demand for High-Beta Stocks: Evidence from Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Susan E. K.; Simutin, Mikhail
Prior studies have documented that pension plan sponsors often monitor a fund's performance relative to a benchmark. We use a first-difference approach to show that in an effort to beat benchmarks, fund managers controlling large pension assets tend to increase their exposure to high-beta stocks, while aiming to maintain tracking errors around the benchmark. The findings support theoretical conjectures that benchmarking can lead managers to tilt their portfolio toward high-beta stocks and away from low-beta stocks, which can reinforce observed pricing anomalies.</description><author>Christoffersen, Susan E. K.; Simutin, Mikhail</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fund Flows and Market States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Franzoni, Francesco; Schmalz, Martin C.
This paper establishes a new empirical fact: Mutual funds' flow-performance sensitivity is a hump-shaped function of aggregate risk-factor realizations. Explanations based on extant theories can explain only a fraction of the pattern. We thus develop a new parsimonious model. It assumes Bayesian investors who are uncertain about the degree to which fund returns are exposed to systematic risk. Fund performance is then less informative about manager skill when factor realizations are larger in absolute value. The data also support the out-of-sample prediction that the hump shape is more pronounced for funds with more uncertain risk loadings.</description><author>Franzoni, Francesco; Schmalz, Martin C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Market Competition in a World of Cross-Ownership: Evidence from Institutional Blockholdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Jie; Huang, Jiekun
We analyze the effects of institutional cross-ownership of same-industry firms on product market performance and behavior. Our results show that cross-held firms experience significantly higher market share growth than do non-cross-held firms. We establish causality by relying on a difference-in-differences approach based on the quasi-natural experiment of financial institution mergers. We also find evidence suggesting that institutional cross-ownership facilitates explicit forms of product market collaboration (such as within-industry joint ventures, strategic alliances, or within-industry acquisitions) and improves innovation productivity and operating profitability. Overall, our evidence indicates that cross-ownership by institutional blockholders offers strategic benefits by fostering product market coordination.</description><author>He, Jie; Huang, Jiekun</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Deflation Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fleckenstein, Matthias; Longstaff, Francis A.; Lustig, Hanno
We study the nature of deflation risk by extracting the objective distribution of inflation from the market prices of inflation swaps and options. We find that the market expects inflation to average about 2.5% over the next 30 years. Despite this, the market places substantial weight on deflation scenarios in which prices significantly decline over extended horizons. The market prices the economic tail risk of deflation similarly to other types of tail risks, such as corporate default or catastrophic insurance losses. We find that deflation risk is strongly negatively correlated with outcomes in the financial markets and with consumer confidence.</description><author>Fleckenstein, Matthias; Longstaff, Francis A.; Lustig, Hanno</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Family Status and Social Security Claiming Options Shape Optimal Life Cycle Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hubener, Andreas; Maurer, Raimond; Mitchell, Olivia S.
We show how optimal household decisions regarding work, retirement, saving, portfolio allocations, and life insurance are shaped by the complex financial options embedded in U.S. Social Security rules and uncertain family transitions. Our life cycle model predicts sharp consumption drops on retirement, an age-62 peak in claiming rates, and earlier claiming by wives versus husbands and single women. Moreover, life insurance is mainly purchased on men's lives. Our model, which takes Social Security rules seriously, generates wealth and retirement outcomes that are more consistent with the data, in contrast to earlier and less realistic models.</description><author>Hubener, Andreas; Maurer, Raimond; Mitchell, Olivia S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Whom Do You Trust?: Investor-Advisor Relationships and Mutual Fund Flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kostovetsky, Leonard
I provide a measure for the value that investors place on trust and relationships in asset management by examining mutual fund flows around announced changes in the ownership of fund management companies. I find a decline in flows of around 7% of fund assets in the year following the announcement date, resulting primarily from fund outflows. Retail investors and investors in funds with higher expense ratios are most responsive to ownership changes, providing evidence that such investors appear to place a significant value on trust and are more likely to respond to a relationship disruption by withdrawing their assets.</description><author>Kostovetsky, Leonard</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating Security Betas Using Prior Information Based on Firm Fundamentals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cosemans, Mathijs; Frehen, Rik; Schotman, Peter C.; Bauer, Rob
We propose a hybrid approach for estimating beta that shrinks rolling window estimates toward firm-specific priors motivated by economic theory. Our method yields superior forecasts of beta that have important practical implications. First, unlike standard rolling window betas, hybrid betas carry a significant price of risk in the cross-section even after controlling for characteristics. Second, the hybrid approach offers statistically and economically significant out-of-sample benefits for investors who use factor models to construct optimal portfolios. We show that the hybrid estimator outperforms existing estimators because shrinkage toward a fundamentals-based prior is effective in reducing measurement noise in extreme beta estimates.</description><author>Cosemans, Mathijs; Frehen, Rik; Schotman, Peter C.; Bauer, Rob</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Attention</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sicherman, Nachum; Loewenstein, George; Seppi, Duane J.; Utkus, Stephen P.
This paper investigates financial attention using novel panel data on daily investor online account logins. We find support for selective attention to portfolio information. Account logins fall by 9.5% after market declines. Investors also pay less attention when the VIX volatility index is high. The level of attention and the attention/return correlation are strongly related to investor demographics (gender, age) and financial position (wealth, holdings). Using a new statistical decomposition, we show how aggregate and individual household trading are related to investor attention.</description><author>Sicherman, Nachum; Loewenstein, George; Seppi, Duane J.; Utkus, Stephen P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Corporate Value of (Corrupt) Lobbying</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borisov, Alexander; Goldman, Eitan; Gupta, Nandini
We examine whether the stock market considers corporate lobbying to be value enhancing, using an event that potentially limited the ability of firms to lobby but was exogenous to their characteristics and prior lobbying decisions. The results show that this exogenous shock negatively affects the value of firms that lobby. In particular, we estimate that a firm that spends $100,000 more on lobbying in the 3 years before the shock ( where sample average lobbying expenses are about $4 million), experiences a loss of about $1.2 million in shareholder value on average. We also examine the channels through which lobbying may create value for firms.</description><author>Borisov, Alexander; Goldman, Eitan; Gupta, Nandini</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does it Pay to Invest in Art? A Selection-Corrected Returns Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korteweg, Arthur; Kraeussl, Roman; Verwijmeren, Patrick
This paper shows the importance of correcting for sample selection when investing in illiquid assets that trade endogenously. Using a sample of 32,928 paintings that sold repeatedly between 1960 and 2013, we find an asymmetric V-shaped relation between sale probabilities and returns. Adjusting for the resulting selection bias reduces average annual index returns from 8.7% to 6.3%, lowers Sharpe ratios from 0.27 to 0.11, and materially impacts portfolio allocations. Investing in a broad portfolio of paintings is not attractive, but targeting specific styles or top-selling artists may add value. The methodology naturally extends to other asset classes.</description><author>Korteweg, Arthur; Kraeussl, Roman; Verwijmeren, Patrick</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Borrowing High versus Borrowing Higher: Price Dispersion and Shopping Behavior in the US Credit Card Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stango, Victor; Zinman, Jonathan
We document substantial cross-individual dispersion in U.S. credit card borrowing costs, even after controlling for borrower risk and card characteristics. That remaining dispersion arises because cross-lender pricing heterogeneity generates dispersion in annual percentage rate (APR) offers to borrowers, and borrowers vary in shopping intensity. Our empirics match administrative data to self-reported card shopping intensity and use instruments suggested by fair lending law to account for the endogeneity between APRs and search. The results show that shoppers versus nonshoppers pay APRs as different as those paid by borrowers in the best versus worst credit score deciles. We discuss implications for policy and practice.</description><author>Stango, Victor; Zinman, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Pricing When Traders Sell Extreme Winners and Losers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>An, Li
This study investigates the asset pricing implications of a newly documented refinement of the disposition effect, characterized by investors being more likely to sell a security when the magnitude of their gains or losses on it increases. I find that stocks with both large unrealized gains and large unrealized losses outperform others in the following month (trading strategy monthly alpha = 0.5-1%, Sharpe ratio = 1.5). This supports the conjecture that these stocks experience higher selling pressure, leading to lower current prices and higher future returns. Overall, this study provides new evidence that investors' trading behavior can aggregate to affect equilibrium price dynamics.</description><author>An, Li</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity Market Misvaluation, Financing, and Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Warusawitharana, Missaka; Whited, Toni M.
We estimate a dynamic investment model in which firms finance with equity, cash, or debt. Misvaluation affects equity values, and firms optimally issue and repurchase overvalued and undervalued shares. The funds flowing to and from these activities come from investment, dividends, or net cash. The model fits a broad set of data moments in large heterogeneous samples and across industries. Our parameter estimates imply that misvaluation induces larger changes in financial policies than investment. The investment responses are strongest for small firms but nonetheless modest. Managers' rational responses to misvaluation increase shareholder value by up to 4%.</description><author>Warusawitharana, Missaka; Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividends as Reference Points: A Behavioral Signaling Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, Malcolm; Mendel, Brock; Wurgler, Jeffrey
We outline a dividend signaling model that features investors who are averse to dividend cuts. Managers with strong unobservable cash earnings pay high dividends but retain enough to be likely not to fall short next period. The model is consistent with a Lintner partial-adjustment model, modal dividend changes of zero, stronger market reactions to dividend cuts than increases, comparatively infrequent and irregular repurchases, and a mechanism that does not depend on public destruction of value, which managers reject in surveys. New tests involve stronger reactions to changes from longer-maintained dividend levels and reference point currencies of American Depository Receipt dividends.</description><author>Baker, Malcolm; Mendel, Brock; Wurgler, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disclosure Standards and the Sensitivity of Returns to Mood</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bushee, Brian J.; Friedman, Henry L.
We provide evidence that higher-quality disclosure standards are associated with stock returns that are less sensitive to noise driven by investors' moods. We identify return-mood sensitivity (RMS) based on the association between index returns and urban cloudiness, a source of short-term variation in mood. Based on a stylized model, we predict and find evidence consistent with higher-quality disclosure standards reducing RMS by tilting susceptible investors' trades toward information and by facilitating sophisticated investors' arbitrage. Our findings suggest that disclosure standards play an important role in enhancing price efficiency by reducing noise in returns, particularly noise related to investors' short-term moods.</description><author>Bushee, Brian J.; Friedman, Henry L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust Bayesian Portfolio Choices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Evan W.; Cheng, Ai-Ru
We propose a Bayesian-averaging portfolio choice strategy with excellent out-of-sample performance. Every period a new model is born that assumes means and covariances are constant over time. Each period we estimate model parameters, update model probabilities, and compute robust portfolio choices by taking into account model uncertainty, parameter uncertainty, and non-stationarity. The portfolio choices achieve higher out-of-sample Sharpe ratios and certainty equivalents than rolling window schemes, the 1/N approach, and other leading strategies do on a majority of 24 datasets.</description><author>Anderson, Evan W.; Cheng, Ai-Ru</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mortgage Risk and the Yield Curve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malkhozov, Aytek; Mueller, Philippe; Vedolin, Andrea; Venter, Gyuri
We study feedback from the risk of outstanding mortgage-backed securities (MBS) on the level and volatility of interest rates. We incorporate supply shocks resulting from changes in MBS duration into a parsimonious equilibrium dynamic term structure model and derive three predictions that are strongly supported in the data: (1) MBS duration positively predicts nominal and real excess bond returns, especially for longer maturities; (2) the predictive power of MBS duration is transitory in nature; and (3) MBS convexity increases interest rate volatility, and this effect has a hump-shaped term structure.</description><author>Malkhozov, Aytek; Mueller, Philippe; Vedolin, Andrea; Venter, Gyuri</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Spillovers, Gains from Trade, and Interventions in Frozen Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Camargo, Braz; Kim, Kyungmin; Lester, Benjamin
We study government interventions in markets suffering from adverse selection. Importantly, asymmetric information prevents both the realization of gains from trade and the production of information that is valuable to other market participants. We find a fundamental tension in maximizing welfare: while some intervention is required to restore trading, too much intervention depletes trade of its informational content. We characterize the optimal policy that balances these two considerations, and explore how it depends on features of the environment. Our model can be used to study a program introduced in 2009 to restore information production in the market for legacy assets.</description><author>Camargo, Braz; Kim, Kyungmin; Lester, Benjamin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Secondary Market Liquidity and Security Design: Theory and Evidence from ABS Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Friewald, Nils; Hennessy, Christopher A.; Jankowitsch, Rainer
We develop and empirically test a theory of optimal security design under adverse selection accounting for strategic trading by uninformed investors who will liquidate a security in secondary markets only if their idiosyncratic carrying costs exceed the security's expected trading loss. Such investors demand primary market discounts equaling expected carrying costs borne plus trading losses incurred. Issuers minimize the total illiquidity discount by splitting cash-flow into tranched debt claims with liquidity predicted to increase with seniority, while the optimal number of tranches increases with underlying cash-flow risk. Empirical tests confirm our model predictions.</description><author>Friewald, Nils; Hennessy, Christopher A.; Jankowitsch, Rainer</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Buying High and Selling Low: Stock Repurchases and Persistent Asymmetric Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bond, Philip; Zhong, Hongda
Share prices generally fall when a firm announces a seasoned equity offering (SEO). A standard explanation is that an SEO communicates negative information to investors. We show that if repeated capital market transactions are possible, this same asymmetry of information between firms and investors implies that some firms also repurchase shares in equilibrium. A subset of these firms directly profit from repurchases, while other firms repurchase in order to improve the terms of a subsequent SEO. The possibility of repurchases reduces both SEOs and investment. Overall, our analysis highlights the importance of analyzing SEOs and repurchases in a unified framework.</description><author>Bond, Philip; Zhong, Hongda</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Production Flexibility, Product Markets, and Capital Structure Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reinartz, Sebastian J.; Schmid, Thomas
We examine how production flexibility affects financial leverage. A worldwide sample of energy utilities allows us to apply direct measures for production flexibility based on their power plants. We find that production flexibility increases financial leverage. For identification, we exploit privatizations and deregulations of electricity markets, geographical variations in natural resources, the technological evolution of gas-fired power plants, and differences in electricity prices and recapitalization cost across regions. Production flexibility affects financial leverage via the channels of reduced expected cost of financial distress and higher present value of tax shields. The relative importance of these channels depends on firms' profitability.</description><author>Reinartz, Sebastian J.; Schmid, Thomas</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Out-of-the-Money CEOs: Private Control Premium and Option Exercises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fos, Vyacheslav; Jiang, Wei
When a proxy contest is looming, the rate at which CEOs exercise options to sell (hold) the resulting shares slows down by 80% (accelerates by 60%), consistent with their desire to maintain or strengthen voting rights when facing challenges. Such deviations are closely aligned with features unique to proxy contests, such as the record dates and nomination status, and are more pronounced when the private benefits are higher or when the voting rights are more crucial. The distortions suggest that incumbents value their stocks higher than the market price when voting rights are valuable for defending control.</description><author>Fos, Vyacheslav; Jiang, Wei</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Institutional Ownership on Payout Policy: Evidence from Index Thresholds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Crane, Alan D.; Michenaud, Sebastien; Weston, James P.
We show that higher institutional ownership causes firms to pay more dividends. Our identification relies on a discontinuity in ownership around Russell index thresholds. Our estimates indicate that a one-percentage-point increase in institutional ownership causes a $7 million (8%) increase in dividends. We also find differences in shareholder proposals and voting patterns that suggest that even nonactivist institutions play an important role in monitoring firm behavior. The effect of institutional ownership on dividends is stronger for firms with higher expected agency costs.</description><author>Crane, Alan D.; Michenaud, Sebastien; Weston, James P.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateral, Taxes, and Leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Shaojin; Whited, Toni M.; Wu, Yufeng
We quantify the importance of collateral versus taxes for firms' capital structures. We estimate a dynamic model in which a taxable firm seeks financing for investment, and a dynamic contracting environment motivates endogenous collateral constraints. Optimal leverage stays a safe distance from the constraint, balancing the tax benefit of debt with the cost of lost financial flexibility. We estimate this flexibility cost to be 7.2% of firm assets, a percentage that is comparable to the tax benefit. Models with different tax rates fit the data equally well, and leverage responds to the tax rate only when taxes are low.</description><author>Li, Shaojin; Whited, Toni M.; Wu, Yufeng</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive Compensation Incentives Contingent on Long-Term Accounting Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Zhi; Wang, Lingling
The percentage of S&amp;P 500 firms using multiyear accounting-based performance (MAP) incentives for CEOs increased from 16.5% in 1996 to 43.3% in 2008. The use and design of MAP incentives depend on the signal quality of accounting versus stock performance, shareholder horizons, strategic imperatives, and board independence. After the technology bubble, option expensing, and the publicity of option backdating, firms increasingly use stock-based MAP plans to replace options, resulting in changes in pay structure, but not in pay level. While firms respond to the evolving contracting environment, they consider firm characteristics and shareholder preferences and do not blindly follow the trend.</description><author>Li, Zhi; Wang, Lingling</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rare Booms and Disasters in a Multisector Endowment Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tsai, Jerry; Wachter, Jessica A.
Why do value stocks have higher average returns than growth stocks, despite having lower risk? Why do these stocks exhibit positive abnormal performance, while growth stocks exhibit negative abnormal performance? This paper offers a rare-event-based explanation that can also account for the high equity premium and volatility of the aggregate market. The model explains other puzzling aspects of the data, such as joint patterns in time-series predictablity of aggregate market and value and growth returns, long periods in which growth outperforms value, and the association between positive skewness and low realized returns.</description><author>Tsai, Jerry; Wachter, Jessica A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring Liquidity in Bond Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schestag, Raphael; Schuster, Philipp; Uhrig-Homburg, Marliese
In the literature, there is no consensus on a common approach to measure bond liquidity. This paper is the first to comprehensively compare all commonly employed liquidity measures based on intraday and daily data for the U.S. corporate bond market. We find that high-frequency measures based on intraday data are very strongly correlated, implying that previous results should be robust regarding the chosen measure. Most low-frequency proxies based on daily data generally also measure transaction costs well. However, three proxies clearly take the lead: Corwin and Schultz's (2012) high-low spread estimator, Roll's (1984) measure, and Hasbrouck's (2009) Gibbs measure.</description><author>Schestag, Raphael; Schuster, Philipp; Uhrig-Homburg, Marliese</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dynamics of Crises and the Equity Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Branger, Nicole; Kraft, Holger; Meinerding, Christoph
It is a major challenge for asset pricing models to generate a high equity premium and a low risk-free rate while imposing realistic consumption dynamics. To address this issue, our paper proposes a novel pricing channel: we allow for consumption drops that can spark an economic crisis. This new feature generates a large equity premium even if possible consumption drops are of moderate size. In turn, our model also matches the consumption data of 42 countries along several dimensions. In particular, our approach generates a realistic number of crises that have realistic durations and involve clustering of moderate consumption drops.</description><author>Branger, Nicole; Kraft, Holger; Meinerding, Christoph</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Durable Goods, Inflation Risk, and Equilibrium Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eraker, Bjorn; Shaliastovich, Ivan; Wang, Wenyu
High expected inflation is known to predict low future real growth. We show that, relative to nondurable goods sectors of the economy, such predictability is significantly more pronounced in durable sectors. Consistent with this macroeconomic evidence, the equity returns of durable goods-producing firms have a larger negative exposure to expected inflation risks. We estimate a two-good recursive utility model that features persistent growth fluctuations and inflation nonneutrality for durable and nondurable consumption. Our model can quantitatively account for the levels and volatilities of bond and equity prices, and correlations of equity returns with bond returns and with expected inflation.</description><author>Eraker, Bjorn; Shaliastovich, Ivan; Wang, Wenyu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Cross-Section of Expected Returns: Where We Stand Today</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karolyi, G. Andrew
The Review of Financial Studies has among its missions the facilitation and promotion of a vigorous academic debate across unsettled questions in finance. This special section of Volume 29, Number 1 consists of three studies on the cross-section of expected returns. To what extent are our inferences about certain anomalous patterns in the cross-section of expected returns related to biases and inefficiencies in our testing procedures? Are all factor discoveries equally important? Do some proposed factors subsume the explanatory power of others? Is the after-trading-cost performance of some anomalies more resilient than that of others?</description><author>Karolyi, G. Andrew</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>... and the Cross-Section of Expected Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harvey, Campbell R.; Liu, Yan; Zhu, Heqing
Hundreds of papers and factors attempt to explain the cross-section of expected returns. Given this extensive data mining, it does not make sense to use the usual criteria for establishing significance. Which hurdle should be used for current research? Our paper introduces a new multiple testing framework and provides historical cutoffs from the first empirical tests in 1967 to today. A new factor needs to clear a much higher hurdle, with a t-statistic greater than 3.0. We argue that most claimed research findings in financial economics are likely false.</description><author>Harvey, Campbell R.; Liu, Yan; Zhu, Heqing</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dissecting Anomalies with a Five-Factor Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.
A five-factor model that adds profitability (RMW) and investment (CMA) factors to the three-factor model of Fama and French (1993) suggests a shared story for several average-return anomalies. Specifically, positive exposures to RMW and CMA (stock returns that behave like those of profitable firms that invest conservatively) capture the high average returns associated with low market beta, share repurchases, and low stock return volatility. Conversely, negative RMW and CMA slopes (like those of relatively unprofitable firms that invest aggressively) help explain the low average stock returns associated with high beta, large share issues, and highly volatile returns.</description><author>Fama, Eugene F.; French, Kenneth R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Taxonomy of Anomalies and Their Trading Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Novy-Marx, Robert; Velikov, Mihail
We study the after-trading-cost performance of anomalies and the effectiveness of transaction cost mitigation techniques. Introducing a buy/hold spread, with more stringent requirements for establishing positions than for maintaining them, is the most effective cost mitigation technique. Most anomalies with less than 50% turnover per month generate significant net spreads when designed to mitigate transaction costs; few with higher turnover do. The extent to which new capital reduces strategy profitability is inversely related to turnover, and strategies based on size, value, and profitability have the greatest capacity to support new capital. Transaction costs always reduce strategy profitability, increasing data-snooping concerns.</description><author>Novy-Marx, Robert; Velikov, Mihail</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Policy Uncertainty and Corporate Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gulen, Huseyin; Ion, Mihai
Using a news-based index of policy uncertainty, we document a strong negative relationship between firm-level capital investment and the aggregate level of uncertainty associated with future policy and regulatory outcomes. More importantly, we find evidence that the relation between policy uncertainty and capital investment is not uniform in the cross-section, being significantly stronger for firms with a higher degree of investment irreversibility and for firms that are more dependent on government spending. Our results lend empirical support to the notion that policy uncertainty can depress corporate investment by inducing precautionary delays due to investment irreversibility.</description><author>Gulen, Huseyin; Ion, Mihai</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Looking in the Rearview Mirror: The Effect of Managers' Professional Experience on Corporate Financial Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dittmar, Amy; Duchin, Ran
We track the employment history of over 9,000 managers to study the effects of professional experiences on corporate policies. Our identification strategy exploits exogenous CEO turnovers and employment in other firms and in non-CEO roles. Firms run by CEOs who experienced distress have less debt, save more cash, and invest less than other firms, with stronger effects in poorly governed firms. Experience has a stronger influence when it is more recent or occurs during salient periods in a manager's career. We find similar effects for CFOs. The results suggest that policies vary with managers' experiences and throughout managers' careers.</description><author>Dittmar, Amy; Duchin, Ran</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reputation Concerns of Independent Directors: Evidence from Individual Director Voting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Wei; Wan, Hualin; Zhao, Shan
This study examines the voting behavior of independent directors of public companies in China from 2004-2012. The unique data at the individual-director level overcome endogeneity in both board formation and proposal selection by allowing analysis based on within-board proposal variation. Career-conscious directors, measured by age and the director's reputation value, are more likely to dissent; dissension is eventually rewarded in the marketplace in the form of more outside directorships and a lower risk of regulatory sanctions. Director dissension improves corporate governance and market transparency primarily through the responses of stakeholders (shareholders, creditors, and regulators), to whom dissension disseminates information.</description><author>Jiang, Wei; Wan, Hualin; Zhao, Shan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Fetal Origins Hypothesis in Finance: Prenatal Environment, the Gender Gap, and Investor Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cronqvist, Henrik; Previtero, Alessandro; Siegel, Stephan; White, Roderick E.
We find that differences in individuals' prenatal environments explain heterogeneity in financial decisions later in life. An exogenous increase in exposure to prenatal testosterone is associated with the masculinization of financial behavior, specifically with elevated risk taking and trading in adulthood. We also examine birth weight. Those with higher birth weight are more likely to participate in the stock market, whereas those with lower birth weight tend to prefer portfolios with higher volatility and skewness, consistent with compensatory behavior. Our results contribute to the understanding of how the prenatal environment shapes an individual's behavior in financial markets later in life.</description><author>Cronqvist, Henrik; Previtero, Alessandro; Siegel, Stephan; White, Roderick E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do US Firms Hold More Cash than Foreign Firms Do?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pinkowitz, Lee; Stulz, Rene M.; Williamson, Rohan
From 1998 to 2011, U.S. firms held more cash on average (but not at the median) than similar foreign firms (foreign twins) did. The average difference in cash holdings does not increase after 2008, and it is driven by highly R&amp;D-intensive U.S. firms. Because there are almost no similarly R&amp;D-intensive foreign firms, mean comparisons involving these U.S. firms are not reliable. Without these U.S. firms, neither U.S. multinational firms nor purely domestic U.S. firms hold more cash than their foreign twins do. Country characteristics have negligible explanatory power for differences in cash holdings between U.S. firms and their foreign twins. (JEL G30, G31, G32)</description><author>Pinkowitz, Lee; Stulz, Rene M.; Williamson, Rohan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Enlarging the Contracting Space: Collateral Menus, Access to Credit, and Economic Activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campello, Murillo; Larrain, Mauricio
Recent reforms across Eastern European countries have given more flexibility and information to parties to engage in secured debt transactions. The menu of assets legally accepted as collateral was enlarged to include movable assets (e.g., machinery and equipment). Generalized difference-in-differences tests show that firms operating more movable assets borrowed more as a result. Those firms also invested more, hired more, and became more efficient and profitable following the changes in the contracting environment. The financial deepening we document triggered important reallocation effects: firms affected by the reforms increased their share of fixed assets and employment in the economy. (JEL G32, K22, O16)</description><author>Campello, Murillo; Larrain, Mauricio</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Should Pay for Credit Ratings and How?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kashyap, Anil K.; Kovrijnykh, Natalia
We analyze a model where investors use a credit rating to decide whether to finance a firm. The rating quality depends on unobservable effort exerted by a credit rating agency (CRA). We study optimal compensation schemes for the CRA when a planner, the firm, or investors order the rating. Rating errors are larger when the firm orders it than when investors do (and both produce larger errors than is socially optimal). Investors overuse ratings relative to the firm or planner. Atrade-off in providing time-consistent incentives embedded in the optimal compensation structure makes the CRA slow to acknowledge mistakes. (JEL D82, D83, D86, G24)</description><author>Kashyap, Anil K.; Kovrijnykh, Natalia</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Misinformed Speculators and Mispricing in the Housing Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chinco, Alex; Mayer, Christopher
This paper examines the contribution of out-of-town second-house buyers to mispricing in the housing market. We show that demand from out-of-town second-house buyers during the mid 2000s predicted not only house-price appreciation rates but also implied-to-actual-rent-ratio appreciation rates, a proxy for mispricing. We then apply a novel identification strategy to address the issue of reverse causality. We give supporting evidence that out-of-town second-house buyers behaved like misinformed speculators, earning lower capital gains (misinformed) and consuming smaller dividends (speculators).</description><author>Chinco, Alex; Mayer, Christopher</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Measures of Financial Constraints Measure Financial Constraints?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Farre-Mensa, Joan; Ljungqvist, Alexander
Financial constraints are fundamental to empirical research in finance and economics. We propose two tests to evaluate how well measures of financial constraints actually capture constraints. We find that firms typically classified as constrained do not actually behave as if they were constrained: they have no trouble raising debt when their demand for debt increases exogenously and use the proceeds of equity issues to increase payouts to shareholders. Our evidence suggests that extant findings that have been attributed to constraints may instead reflect differences in the growth and financing policies of firms at different stages of their life cycles. (JEL G12, G31, G32, G33, E44, E52, L26)</description><author>Farre-Mensa, Joan; Ljungqvist, Alexander</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Facilitated Misreporting in Securitized Loans?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, John M.; Maturana, Gonzalo
This paper examines apparent fraud among securitized nonagency loans using three indicators: unreported second liens, owner occupancy misreporting, and appraisal overstatements. We find that around 48% of loans exhibited at least one indicator of misrepresentation. Surprisingly, misreporting is similar in both low and full documentation loans and is associated with a 51% higher likelihood of delinquency. Two-thirds of loans with unreported second liens had the same originator issuing both the first and second lien. Misrepresentations in MBS pools can explain substantial cross-sectional differences in future losses. Losses were predictable and initiating from apparent fraud by MBS underwriters and loan originators. (JEL G21, G23, R30)</description><author>Griffin, John M.; Maturana, Gonzalo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the Market Understand Rating Shopping? Predicting MBS Losses with Initial Yields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Jie; Qian, Jun; Strahan, Philip E.
We study rating shopping on the MBS market. Outside of AAA, losses are higher on single-rated tranches than on multi-rated ones, and yields predict future losses for single-rated tranches, but not for multi-rated ones. Conversely, ratings have less explanatory power for single-rated tranches. These results suggest that single-rated tranches have been "shopped," whereby pessimistic ratings never reach the market. For AAA-rated MBS, by contrast, 93% receive two or three such ratings, and those ratings agree 97% of the time. This ratings convergence suggests that agencies "cater" to investors, who cannot purchase a tranche unless it has multiple AAA ratings.</description><author>He, Jie; Qian, Jun; Strahan, Philip E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Firms Engage in Risk-Shifting? Empirical Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilje, Erik P.
I empirically test whether firms engage in risk-shifting. Contrary to what risk-shifting theory predicts, I find that firms reduce investment risk when they approach financial distress. To identify the effect of distress on risk-taking, I use a natural experiment with exogenous changes to leverage. Risk reduction is most prevalent among firms that have shorter maturity debt, bank debt, and tighter bank loan financial covenants. These findings suggest that debt composition and financial covenants serve as important mechanisms to mitigate debt-equity agency conflicts, such as risk-shifting, that are not explicitly contracted on.</description><author>Gilje, Erik P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital-Market Effects of Securities Regulation: Prior Conditions, Implementation, and Enforcement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christensen, Hans B.; Hail, Luzi; Leuz, Christian
We examine the capital-market effects of changes in securities regulation in the European Union aimed at reducing market abuse and increasing transparency. To estimate causal effects for the population of E.U. firms, we exploit that for plausibly exogenous reasons, such as national legislative procedures, E.U. countries adopted these directives at different times. We find significant increases in market liquidity, but the effects are stronger in countries with stricter implementation and traditionally more stringent securities regulation. The findings suggest that countries with initially weaker regulation do not catch up with stronger countries, and that countries diverge more upon harmonizing regulation.</description><author>Christensen, Hans B.; Hail, Luzi; Leuz, Christian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Investment Cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pan, Yihui; Wang, Tracy Yue; Weisbach, Michael S.
This paper documents the existence of a CEO investment cycle, in which disinvestment decreases over a CEO's tenure, while investment increases, leading to "cyclical" firm growth in assets and employment. The estimated variation in investment rate over the CEO investment cycle is of the same order of magnitude as the differences caused by business cycles or financial constraints. Results from a number of tests generally support the view that the investment cycle is caused by agency problems, leading to increasing investment quantity and decreasing investment quality over time as the CEO gains more control over his board.</description><author>Pan, Yihui; Wang, Tracy Yue; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Credit Crunch Investment Down? New Evidence on the Real Effects of the Bank-Lending Channel</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cingano, Federico; Manaresi, Francesco; Sette, Enrico
We quantify the real effects of the bank-lending channel exploiting the dramatic liquidity drought in interbank markets that followed the 2007 financial crisis as a source of variation in credit supply. Using a large sample of matched firm-bank data from Italy, we find had the interbank market not collapsed, investment expenditure would have been more than 20% higher and would have increased by around 30 cents per additional euro of available credit at the average firm. We also find that credit shocks affect the firm's value added, employment and input purchases, and propagate through firms' trade credit chains. (JEL E22, E44, G01, G21, G32)</description><author>Cingano, Federico; Manaresi, Francesco; Sette, Enrico</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prospect Theory and Stock Returns: An Empirical Test</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barberis, Nicholas; Mukherjee, Abhiroop; Wang, Baolian
We test the hypothesis that, when thinking about allocating money to a stock, investors mentally represent the stock by the distribution of its past returns and then evaluate this distribution in the way described by prospect theory. In a simple model of asset prices in which some investors think in this way, a stock whose past return distribution has a high (low) prospect theory value earns a low (high) subsequent return, on average. We find empirical support for this prediction in the cross-section of stock returns in the U.S. market, and also in a majority of forty-six other national stock markets.</description><author>Barberis, Nicholas; Mukherjee, Abhiroop; Wang, Baolian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Neural Evidence of Regret and Its Implications for Investor Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frydman, Cary; Camerer, Colin
We use neural data collected from an experimental asset market to measure regret preferences while subjects trade stocks. When subjects observe a positive return for a stock they chose not to purchase, a regret signal is observed in an area of the brain that is commonly active during reward processing. Subjects are unwilling to repurchase stocks that have recently increased in price, even though this is suboptimal in our experiment. The strength of stock repurchasing mistakes is correlated with the neural measures of regret. Subjects with high rates of repurchasing mistakes also exhibit large disposition effects.</description><author>Frydman, Cary; Camerer, Colin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loss-Averse Preferences, Performance, and Career Success of Institutional Investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bodnaruk, Andriy; Simonov, Andrei
Using survey-based measures of mutual fund manager loss aversion, we study the effects of institutional investor preferences on their investment decisions, performance, and career outcomes. We find that managers with higher aversion to losses choose portfolios with lower downside risk, increase their risk-taking more in response to poor past performance, and display a stronger disposition effect. Further, we provide evidence that managers who are more loss-averse have lower performance and are more likely to have their contracts terminated.</description><author>Bodnaruk, Andriy; Simonov, Andrei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Peer Pressure: Social Interaction and the Disposition Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heimer, Rawley Z.
Social interaction contributes to some traders' disposition effect. New data from an investment-specific social network linked to individual-level trading records builds evidence of this connection. To credibly estimate causal peer effects, I exploit the staggered entry of retail brokerages into partnerships with the social trading web platform and compare trader activity before and after exposure to these new social conditions. Access to the social network nearly doubles the magnitude of a trader's disposition effect. Traders connected in the network develop correlated levels of the disposition effect, a finding that can be replicated using workhorse data from a large discount brokerage.</description><author>Heimer, Rawley Z.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real Effects of Uncertainty on Merger Activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhagwat, Vineet; Dam, Robert; Harford, Jarrad
Firm values can substantially change between the time deal terms are set and the actual deal closing, risking renegotiation, or termination. We find increases in market volatility decrease subsequent deal activity, but only for public targets subject to an interim period. The effect is strongest when volatility is highest, for deals taking longer to close, and for larger targets. Merging parties attempt to shorten the interim window as risk increases. Firm- and industry-level uncertainty measures reveal similar findings, ruling out an unobserved macro variable. We conclude interim uncertainty contributes to understanding the timing and intensity of public firms' merger activity.</description><author>Bhagwat, Vineet; Dam, Robert; Harford, Jarrad</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Mandatory Shareholder Voting Prevent Bad Acquisitions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becht, Marco; Polo, Andrea; Rossi, Stefano
Shareholder voting on corporate acquisitions is controversial. In most countries, acquisition decisions are delegated to boards, and shareholder approval is discretionary, which makes existing empirical studies inconclusive. We study the U.K. setting in which shareholder approval is imposed exogenously via a threshold test that provides strong identification. U.K. shareholders gain 8 cents per dollar at announcement with mandatory voting, or $ 13.6 billion over 1992-2010 in aggregate; without voting, U.K. shareholders lost $ 3 billion. Multidimensional regression discontinuity analysis supports a causal interpretation. The evidence suggests that mandatory voting imposes a binding constraint on acquirer chief executive officers.</description><author>Becht, Marco; Polo, Andrea; Rossi, Stefano</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Seeking Alpha: Excess Risk Taking and Competition for Managerial Talent</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral; Pagano, Marco; Volpin, Paolo
We present a model in which firms compete for scarce managerial talent ("alpha") and managers are risk averse. When managers cannot move across firms after being hired, employers learn about their talent, efficiently allocate them to projects, and provide insurance to low-quality managers. When, instead, managers can move across firms, firm-level coinsurance is no longer feasible, but managers may self-insure by switching employer to delay the revelation of their true quality. However, this results in inefficient project assignment, with low-quality managers handling projects that are too risky for them. (JEL D62, G32, G38, J33)</description><author>Acharya, Viral; Pagano, Marco; Volpin, Paolo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relationship and Transaction Lending in a Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Patrick; Freixas, Xavier; Gambacorta, Leonardo; Mistrulli, Paolo Emilio
We study how relationship lending and transaction lending vary over the business cycle. We develop a model in which relationship banks gather information on their borrowers, allowing them to provide loans to profitable firms during a crisis. Because of the services they provide, operating costs of relationship banks are higher than those of transaction banks. Relationship banks charge a higher intermediation spread in normal times, but offer continuation lending at more favourable terms than transaction banks to profitable firms in a crisis. Using credit register information for Italian banks before and after the Lehman Brothers' default, we test the theoretical predictions of the model. (JEL E44, G21)</description><author>Bolton, Patrick; Freixas, Xavier; Gambacorta, Leonardo; Mistrulli, Paolo Emilio</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Debt Maturity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Zhiguo; Milbradt, Konstantin
A firm chooses its debt maturity structure and default timing dynamically, both without commitment. Via the fraction of newly issued short-term bonds, equity holders control the maturity structure, which affects their endogenous default decision. A shortening equilibrium with accelerated default emerges when cash flows deteriorate over time so that debt recovery is higher if default occurs earlier. Self-enforcing shortening and lengthening equilibria may coexist, with the latter possibly Pareto dominating the former. The inability to commit to issuance policies can worsen the Leland problem of the inability to commit to a default policy-a self-fulfilling shortening spiral and adverse default policy may arise. (JEL G32, C37)</description><author>He, Zhiguo; Milbradt, Konstantin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Debt Contract Enforcement Costs Affect Financing and Asset Structure?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Mukherjee, Abhiroop; Singh, Manpreet
Using the staggered introduction of fast-track debt recovery courts in India, we estimate the causal effect of a reduction in debt contract enforcement costs on financing and asset maturity. A reduction in enforcement costs is associated with an increase in long-term debt and a decrease in short-term debt and trade credit. The increase in debt maturity is confined to firms that borrow from multiple lenders, have abnormally short debt maturity structures before the reform, and to smaller firms. Firms also reduce the number of banking relationships, and increase the proportion of long-term assets after the reform. (JEL F34, G32, G33, G38, K42)</description><author>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Mukherjee, Abhiroop; Singh, Manpreet</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insolvency Resolution and the Missing High-Yield Bond Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, Bo; Josephson, Jens
In many countries, poorly functioning bankruptcy procedures force viable but insolvent firms to restructure out of court, where banks may have a bargaining advantage over other creditors. We model the choice of restructuring process and derive implications for the corporate mix of bank and bond financing. Empirical patterns match the model: inefficient bankruptcy in a country is associated with less bond issuance by risky, but not by safe, borrowers. This pattern holds for both levels of and changes in bankruptcy recovery. Our results establish a link between bankruptcy reform and corporate bond markets, especially high-yield markets. (JEL G32, G33, G21)</description><author>Becker, Bo; Josephson, Jens</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Negative Equity on Mortgage Default: Evidence From HAMP's Principal Reduction Alternative</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Scharlemann, Therese C.; Shore, Stephen H.
The Home Affordable Modification Program's (HAMP's) Principal Reduction Alternative (PRA) is a government-sponsored program to reduce the principal balances and monthly mortgage payments of troubled borrowers. We examine the effect of principal forgiveness on borrowers' subsequent mortgage default. The program's rules imply a kink in the relationship between principal forgiveness and a borrower's initial equity level. Our identification strategy exploits the quasi-experimental variation in principal forgiveness generated by this kink using a regression kink design (RKD), which compares the relationship between initial equity and default on either side of the kink. We estimate that HAMP PRA reduced the quarterly default hazard from 3.8% to 3.1%. (JEL G21, R30)</description><author>Scharlemann, Therese C.; Shore, Stephen H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Proxy Advisory Firms: Evidence from a Regression-Discontinuity Design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malenko, Nadya; Shen, Yao
Proxy advisory firms have become important players in corporate governance, but the extent of their influence over shareholder votes is debated. We estimate the effect of Institutional Shareholder Services (ISS) recommendations on voting outcomes by exploiting exogenous variation in ISS recommendations generated by a cutoff rule in ISS voting guidelines. Using a regression discontinuity design, we find that from 2010 to 2011, a negative ISS recommendation on a say-on-pay proposal leads to a 25 percentage point reduction in say-on-pay voting support, suggesting a strong influence over shareholder votes. We also use our setting to examine the informational role of ISS recommendations.</description><author>Malenko, Nadya; Shen, Yao</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry Window Dressing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Huaizhi; Cohen, Lauren; Lou, Dong
We explore a new mechanism by which investors take correlated shortcuts and present evidence that managers-using sales management-take advantage of these shortcuts. Specifically, we exploit a regulatory provision wherein a firm's primary industry is determined by the highest sales segment. Exploiting this regulation, we provide evidence that investors classify operationally nearly identical firms as starkly different depending on their placement around this sales cutoff. Moreover, managers appear to exploit this by manipulating sales to be just over the cutoff in favorable industries. Further evidence suggests that managers engage in activities to realize large, tangible benefits from this opportunistic action.</description><author>Chen, Huaizhi; Cohen, Lauren; Lou, Dong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prime Broker-Level Comovement in Hedge Fund Returns: Information or Contagion?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Ji-Woong; Kang, Byoung Uk
We document strong comovement in the returns of hedge funds sharing the same prime broker. This comovement is driven neither by funds in the same family nor in the same style, and it is distinct from market-wide and local comovement. The common information hypothesis attributes this phenomenon to the prime broker providing valuable information to its hedge fund clients. The prime broker-level contagion hypothesis attributes the comovement to the prime broker spreading funding liquidity shocks across its hedge fund clients. We find strong evidence supporting the common information hypothesis, but limited evidence in favor of the prime broker-level contagion hypothesis.</description><author>Chung, Ji-Woong; Kang, Byoung Uk</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership Structure, Limits to Arbitrage, and Stock Returns: Evidence from Equity Lending Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Prado, Melissa Porras; Saffi, Pedro A. C.; Sturgess, Jason
We examine how institutional ownership structure gives rise to limits to arbitrage through its impact on short-sale constraints. Stocks with lower, more concentrated, short-term, and less passive ownership exhibit lower lending supply, higher costs of shorting, and higher arbitrage risk. These constraints limit the ability of arbitrageurs to take short positions and delay the correction of mispricing. Stocks with more concentrated ownership exhibit smaller announcement day reactions, larger post-earnings announcement drift, and an additional negative abnormal return of -0.47% in the week following a positive shorting demand shock.</description><author>Prado, Melissa Porras; Saffi, Pedro A. C.; Sturgess, Jason</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Institutional Investors Demand Public Disclosure?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bird, Andrew; Karolyi, Stephen A.
We examine the effect of institutional ownership on corporate disclosure policy using a regression discontinuity design. Using a novel dataset comprising every 8-K filing between 1996 and 2006, we find that positive shocks to institutional ownership around Russell index reconstitutions increase the quantity, form, and quality of disclosure. Compared with those at the bottom of the Russell 1000 index, firms at the top of the Russell 2000 index increase institutional ownership by 9.8%, and disclose 4.7% longer 8-K filings with 21.3% more embedded graphics. This incremental disclosure significantly increases the information content of 8-K filings for the market and for analysts.</description><author>Bird, Andrew; Karolyi, Stephen A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revealing Shorts An Examination of Large Short Position Disclosures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, Charles M.; Reed, Adam V.; Waller, William
Since 2012, all European Union countries have required disclosure of large short positions. This reduces short interest, bid-ask spreads, and the informativeness of prices. After specific disclosures, short-run abnormal returns are insignificantly negative, but 90-day cumulative abnormal returns are a statistically significant -5.23%. We find disclosures are likely to be followed by other disclosures, especially when the initial discloser is large or centrally located. However, there is no subsequent increase in short interest, and prices do not subsequently reverse. These results indicate that large short sellers are well informed, and that disclosures are not being used to coordinate manipulative attacks.</description><author>Jones, Charles M.; Reed, Adam V.; Waller, William</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Rents vs. Shareholder Value in Delegated Portfolio Management: The Case of Closed-End Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Youchang; Wermers, Russ; Zechner, Josef
We examine the dynamics of assets under management (AUM) and management fees at the portfolio manager level in the closed-end fund industry. We find that managers capitalize on good past performance and favorable investor perceptions about future performance, as reflected in fund premiums, through AUM expansions and fee increases. However, the penalties for poor performance or unfavorable investor perceptions are either insignificant, or substantially mitigated by manager tenure. Long tenure is generally associated with poor performance and high discounts. Our findings suggest substantial managerial power in capturing CEF rents. We also document significant diseconomies of scale at the manager level.</description><author>Wu, Youchang; Wermers, Russ; Zechner, Josef</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political Sentiment and Predictable Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Addoum, Jawad M.; Kumar, Alok
This study shows that shifts in political climate influence stock prices. As the party in power changes, there are systematic changes in the industry-level composition of investor portfolios, which weaken arbitrage forces and generate predictable patterns in industry returns. A trading strategy that attempts to exploit demand-based return predictability generates an annualized risk-adjusted performance of 6% during the 1939 to 2011 period. This evidence of predictability spans 17%-27% of the market and is stronger during periods of political transition. Our demand-based predictability pattern is distinct from cash flow-based predictability identified in the recent literature.</description><author>Addoum, Jawad M.; Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting Mutual Fund Portfolio Disclosure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwarz, Christopher G.; Potter, Mark E.
We document that CRSP and Thomson contain many voluntarily reported mutual fund portfolios that are not in SEC filings while, additionally, CRSP and Thomson are missing many SEC mandated portfolios available in SEC filings. We document that the voluntary disclosures are likely driven by convenience rather than duplicity. Although mandated portfolios contain securities with more return momentum, we find use of SEC or Thomson data lead to similar empirical findings. CRSP, however, contains inaccurate position information prior to 2008. Our findings have important implications, such as highlighting a 35% increase in observed manager trading by combining data sources.</description><author>Schwarz, Christopher G.; Potter, Mark E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which Factors Matter to Investors? Evidence from Mutual Fund Flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barber, Brad M.; Huang, Xing; Odean, Terrance
When assessing a fund manager's skill, sophisticated investors will consider all factors (priced and unpriced) that explain cross-sectional variation in fund performance. We investigate which factors investors attend to by analyzing mutual fund flows as a function of recent returns decomposed into alpha and factor-related returns. Surprisingly, investors attend most to market risk (beta) when evaluating funds and treat returns attributable to size, value, momentum, and industry factors as alpha. Using proxies for investor sophistication (wealth, distribution channels, and periods of high investor sentiment), we find that more sophisticated investors use more sophisticated benchmarks when evaluating fund performance. (JEL G11, G12, G23)</description><author>Barber, Brad M.; Huang, Xing; Odean, Terrance</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Euro Interbank Repo Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mancini, Loriano; Ranaldo, Angelo; Wrampelmeyer, Jan
The search for a market design that ensures stable bank funding is at the top of regulators' policy agenda. This paper empirically shows that the central counterparty (CCP)-based euro interbank repo market features this stability. Using a unique and comprehensive data set, we show that the market is resilient during crisis episodes and may even act as a shock absorber, in the sense that repo lending increases with risk, while spreads, maturities, and haircuts remain stable. Our comparison across different repo markets shows that anonymous CCP-based trading, safe collateral, and the absence of an unwind mechanism are the key characteristics to ensure market resilience. (JEL E43, E58, G01, G12, G21, G28)</description><author>Mancini, Loriano; Ranaldo, Angelo; Wrampelmeyer, Jan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Importance of Trust for Investment: Evidence from Venture Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bottazzi, Laura; Da Rin, Marco; Hellmann, Thomas
We examine the effect of trust in venture capital. Our theory predicts a positive relationship of trust with investment, but a negative relationship with success. Using a hand-collected dataset of European venture capital deals, we find that the Eurobarometer measure of trust among nations positively predicts venture capital firms' investment decisions, but that it has a negative correlation with successful exits. Our theory also predicts that earlier stage investments require higher trust, that syndication is more valuable in low-trust situations, and that higher trust investors use more contingent contracts. The empirical evidence supports these predictions.</description><author>Bottazzi, Laura; Da Rin, Marco; Hellmann, Thomas</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Operational Consequences of Private Equity Buyouts: Evidence from the Restaurant Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Shai; Sheen, Albert
How do private equity firms affect their portfolio companies? We document operational changes in restaurant chain buyouts using comprehensive health inspection records. Store-level operational practices improve after private equity buyout, as restaurants become cleaner, safer, and better maintained. Supporting a causal interpretation, this effect is stronger in chain-owned stores than in franchised locations-"twin" restaurants over which private equity owners have limited control. These changes are particularly apparent when private equity partners have prior industry experience. The results suggest that by bringing in industry expertise, private equity firms improve firm operations.</description><author>Bernstein, Shai; Sheen, Albert</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private Equity and Workers' Career Paths: The Role of Technological Change</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agrawal, Ashwini; Tambe, Prasanna
We analyze a new dataset on workers' career paths to examine whether private equity (PE) investments can have positive spillover effects on workers. We study leveraged buyouts in the context of recent information technology (IT) diffusion, and find evidence supporting the argument that many employees of companies acquired by PE investors gain transferable, IT-complementary human capital. Our estimates indicate that these workers experience increases in both long-run employability and wages relative to what they would have realized in the absence of PE investment. The findings underscore PE's role in mitigating the effects of workforce skill obsolescence resulting from technological change.</description><author>Agrawal, Ashwini; Tambe, Prasanna</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Constraining Are Limits to Arbitrage?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ljungqvist, Alexander; Qian, Wenlan
We document the existence of a strategy designed to circumvent limits to arbitrage. Faced with short-sale constraints and noise trader risk, small arbitrageurs publicly reveal their information to induce the target's shareholders (" the longs") to sell, thereby accelerating price discovery. Using data for 124 short-sale campaigns in the United States between 2006 and 2011, we show that investors respond strongly to the information, with spikes in SEC filing views, volatility, order imbalances, realized spreads, turnover, and selling by the longs. Share prices fall by an aggregate $ 14.8 billion. Our findings imply that even extreme short-sale constraints need not constrain arbitrage.</description><author>Ljungqvist, Alexander; Qian, Wenlan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Pricing in the Frequency Domain: Theory and Empirics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dew-Becker, Ian; Giglio, Stefano
We quantify investors' preferences over the dynamics of shocks by deriving frequency-specific risk prices that capture the price of risk of consumption fluctuations at each frequency. The frequency-specific risk prices are derived analytically for leading models. The decomposition helps measure the importance of economic fluctuations at different frequencies. We precisely quantify the meaning of "long-run" in the context of Epstein-Zin preferences - centuries - and measure the exact relevance of business-cycle fluctuations. Finally, we estimate frequency-specific risk prices and show that cycles longer than the business cycle - long-run risks - are significantly priced in the equity market.</description><author>Dew-Becker, Ian; Giglio, Stefano</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Skewness in Expected Macro Fundamentals and the Predictability of Equity Returns: Evidence and Theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colacito, Riccardo; Ghysels, Eric; Meng, Jinghan; Siwasarit, Wasin
We document that the first and third cross-sectional moments of the distribution of GDP growth rates made by professional forecasters can predict equity excess returns, a finding that is robust to controlling for a large set of well-established predictive factors. We show that introducing time-varying skewness in the distribution of expected growth prospects in an otherwise standard endowment economy can substantially increase the model-implied equity Sharpe ratios, and produce a large amount of fluctuation in equity risk premiums.</description><author>Colacito, Riccardo; Ghysels, Eric; Meng, Jinghan; Siwasarit, Wasin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commodities as Collateral</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tang, Ke; Zhu, Haoxiang
We propose and test a theory of using commodities as collateral for financing. Under capital control and collateral constraint, investors import commodities and pledge them as collateral to earn higher expected returns. Higher collateral demands increase commodity prices and make the inventory- convenience yield relation less negative. Our model illustrates these equilibrium effects and suggests that the violation of covered interest- rate parity is a proxy for collateral demands. Evidence from eight commodities in China and developed markets supports the theoretical predictions. Our findings complement the theory of storage and provide new insights into the financialization of commodity markets.</description><author>Tang, Ke; Zhu, Haoxiang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Currency Premia and Global Imbalances</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Della Corte, Pasquale; Riddiough, Steven J.; Sarno, Lucio
We show that a global imbalance risk factor that captures the spread in countries' external imbalances and their propensity to issue external liabilities in foreign currency explains the cross-sectional variation in currency excess returns. The economic intuition is simple: net debtor countries offer a currency risk premium to compensate investors willing to finance negative external imbalances because their currencies depreciate in bad times. This mechanism is consistent with exchange rate theory based on capital flows in imperfect financial markets. We also find that the global imbalance factor is priced in cross-sections of other major asset markets.</description><author>Della Corte, Pasquale; Riddiough, Steven J.; Sarno, Lucio</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Changes in the Cost of Carry Explain the Dynamics of Corporate "Cash" Holdings?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Azar, Jose A.; Kagy, Jean-Francois; Schmalz, Martin C.
Firms until recently were effectively constrained to hold liquid assets in non-interest-bearing accounts. As a result, the cost of capital of firms' liquid-assets portfolios exceeded the return, especially when the risk-free interest rate was high. The spread between cost and return is the cost of carry. Changes in the cost of carry explain the dynamics of corporate "cash" holdings both in the United States and abroad, and the level of cost of carry explains the level of liquid-asset holdings across countries. We conclude that current US corporate cash holdings are not abnormal in a historical or international comparison.</description><author>Azar, Jose A.; Kagy, Jean-Francois; Schmalz, Martin C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Horizon Effects in Average Returns: The Role of Slow Information Diffusion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boguth, Oliver; Carlson, Murray; Fisher, Adlai; Simutin, Mikhail
We characterize linkages between average returns calculated at different horizons. Theoretically, when stocks incorporate information slowly, average short-horizon returns are downward biased. Buy-and-hold strategies can amplify the effect. In contrast, existing theories analyze price noises that are independent of fundamentals, and buy-and-hold portfolio returns are unaffected. We document horizon effects as large as 10% annualized in daily and monthly style portfolios and international indices. Slow reaction to market information, identified by gradually declining lagged betas, is an important cause. These findings have natural consequences for performance evaluation.</description><author>Boguth, Oliver; Carlson, Murray; Fisher, Adlai; Simutin, Mikhail</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commonality in Liquidity: A Demand-Side Explanation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koch, Andrew; Ruenzi, Stefan; Starks, Laura
We hypothesize that a source of commonality in a stock's liquidity arises from the correlated liquidity demand of the stock's investors. Focusing on correlated trading of mutual funds, we find that stocks with high mutual fund ownership have comovements in liquidity about twice as large as those for stocks with low mutual fund ownership. Further analysis shows that the channels for these comovements derive from both common ownership across funds and funds' correlated liquidity shocks. We obtain inferences supporting causality from an exogenous flow shock for mutual funds in the aftermath of the 2003 mutual fund scandal.</description><author>Koch, Andrew; Ruenzi, Stefan; Starks, Laura</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Shadow Cost of Bank Capital Requirements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kisin, Roni; Manela, Asaf
We estimate the shadow cost of capital requirements using data on a costly loophole that allowed banks to relax these constraints. This loophole-liquidity guarantees to asset-backed commercial paper conduits-was exploited by the largest banks before the crisis of 2008. We show theoretically that a bank's use of the loophole reveals its private compliance cost, which takes into account both the costs of issuing equity and the effectiveness of capital regulation. We find that increasing capital requirements would impose a modest cost-$220 million a year for all participating banks combined per one-percentage-point increase, and $14 million on average. (JEL G21, G28, L51)</description><author>Kisin, Roni; Manela, Asaf</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Don't All Banks Practice Regulatory Arbitrage? Evidence from Usage of Trust-Preferred Securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyson, Nicole M.; Fahlenbrach, Ruediger; Stulz, Rene M.
We investigate why only some banks use regulatory arbitrage. We predict that banks wanting to be riskier than allowed by capital regulations (constrained banks) use regulatory arbitrage, while others do not. We find support for this hypothesis using trust-preferred securities issuance, a form of regulatory arbitrage available to almost all U.S. banks from 1996 to Dodd-Frank. We also find support for predictions that constrained banks are riskier, perform worse during the crisis, and use multiple forms of regulatory arbitrage. We show that neither too-big-to-fail incentives nor misaligned managerial incentives are first-order determinants of this type of regulatory arbitrage. (JEL G01, G21, G28)</description><author>Boyson, Nicole M.; Fahlenbrach, Ruediger; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loan Originations and Defaults in the Mortgage Crisis: The Role of the Middle Class</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adelino, Manuel; Schoar, Antoinette; Severino, Felipe
This paper highlights the importance of middle-class and high-FICO borrowers for the mortgage crisis. Contrary to popular belief, which focuses on subprime and poor borrowers, we show that mortgage originations increased for borrowers across all income levels and FICO scores. The relation between mortgage growth and income growth at the individual level remained positive throughout the pre-2007 period. Finally, middle-income, high-income, and prime borrowers all sharply increased their share of delinquencies in the crisis. These results are consistent with a demand-side view, where homebuyers and lenders bought into increasing house values and borrowers defaulted after prices dropped. (JEL R30, D30, G21)</description><author>Adelino, Manuel; Schoar, Antoinette; Severino, Felipe</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>