<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>RF0</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>How Do Banks React to Catastrophic Events? Evidence from Hurricane Katrina</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schuewer, Ulrich; Lambert, Claudia; Noth, Felix
This paper explores how banks react to an exogenous shock caused by Hurricane Katrina in 2005, and how the structure of the banking system affects economic development following the shock. Independent banks based in the disaster areas increase their risk-based capital ratios after the hurricane, while those that are part of a bank holding company on average do not. The effect on independent banks mainly comes from the subgroup of highly capitalized banks. These independent and highly capitalized banks increase their holdings in government securities and reduce their total loan exposures to non-financial firms, while also increasing new lending to these firms. With regard to local economic development, affected counties with a relatively large share of independent banks and relatively high average bank capital ratios show higher economic growth than other affected counties following the catastrophic event.</description><author>Schuewer, Ulrich; Lambert, Claudia; Noth, Felix</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which Factors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hou, Kewei; Mo, Haitao; Xue, Chen; Zhang, Lu
Many recently proposed, seemingly different factor models are closely related. In spanning tests, the q-factor model largely subsumes the Fama-French five- and six-factor models, and the q(5) model subsumes the Stambaugh-Yuan four-factor model. Their "mispricing" factors are sensitive to the construction procedure, and once replicated via the traditional approach, are close to the q-factors, with correlations of 0.8 and 0.84. Finally, consistent with the investment CAPM, valuation theory predicts a positive relation between the expected investment and the expected return.</description><author>Hou, Kewei; Mo, Haitao; Xue, Chen; Zhang, Lu</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Personal Wealth Interests of Politicians and Government Intervention in the Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tahoun, Ahmed; van Lent, Laurence
We examine whether there is a correlation between personal wealth interests of politicians and their decisions to intervene in the economy. We use the setting of the government's support of financial institutions under the 2008 Emergency Economic Stabilization Act. We find that the personal wealth interests of politicians are positively associated with voting in favor of the EESA.</description><author>Tahoun, Ahmed; van Lent, Laurence</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Horizontal Merger Operating Efficiencies on Rivals, Customers, and Suppliers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernile, Gennaro; Lyandres, Evgeny
We study how operating efficiencies in horizontal mergers affect market reactions of merging firms' rivals, customers, and suppliers. We measure operating efficiency gains using projections disclosed by merging firms' insiders. Higher efficiency gains are associated with lower announcement returns to merging firms' rivals (due to increased equilibrium output of merging firms), higher returns to their customers (due to lower equilibrium price of merging firms' output), and higher returns to their suppliers (due to the merged firm's higher equilibrium demand for inputs). Our results suggest that the pass-through of efficiency gains along merging firms' supply chains is as important as the effects of post-merger changes in market power.</description><author>Bernile, Gennaro; Lyandres, Evgeny</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exploring Mispricing in the Term Structure of CDS Spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jarrow, Robert; Li, Haitao; Ye, Xiaoxia; Hu, May
Based on a reduced-form model of credit risk, we explore mispricing in the credit default swaps (CDS) spreads of North American companies and its economic content. Specifically, we develop a trading strategy using the model to trade out of sample market-neutral portfolios across the term structure of CDS contracts. Our empirical results show that the trading strategy exhibits abnormally large returns, confirming the existence and persistence of a mispricing. The aggregate returns of the trading strategy are positively related to the square of market-wide credit and liquidity risks, indicating that the mispricing is more pronounced when the market is more volatile. When implemented on the Markit data, the strategy shows significant economic value even after controlling for realistic transaction costs.</description><author>Jarrow, Robert; Li, Haitao; Ye, Xiaoxia; Hu, May</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Socially Responsible Firms Survive Competition? An Analysis of Corporate Employee Matching Grant Schemes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gong, Ning; Grundy, Bruce D.
Employee matching grant schemes are coordination mechanisms that reduce free-riding by socially conscious employee-donors. Matching schemes coupled with lower take-home pay than offered by non-matching firms will survive capital and labor market competition if employee type is not observable and socially conscious employees are more productive or value working together. Matching can enhance employee welfare and raise more for charity without reducing profits. We document that matching firms have higher labor productivity and are more likely to be ranked as one of the "100 Best" employers. The result is robust to managerial entrenchment concerns and is not confined to the high-tech sector.</description><author>Gong, Ning; Grundy, Bruce D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Information Acquisition Alleviate Market Anomalies? Categorization Bias in Stock Splits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kong, Dongmin; Lin, Chen; Liu, Shasha
Using a unique proprietary account-level trading dataset in China, we investigate how active information acquisition alleviates price-based return comovement, a typical anomaly in stock splits. We find that: 1) individual trading drives the comovement and the trading correlation between split stocks and the low-price portfolio increases significantly after splits; 2) individuals can learn the firm fundamentals through information acquisition, which effectively alleviates their categorized bias; and 3) the role of information acquisition is more significant in environments characterized by greater uncertainty. Our results are robust to different specifications and alternative measures. Taken together, this paper emphasizes the important role of information acquisition in alleviating behavioral bias and improving decision-making.</description><author>Kong, Dongmin; Lin, Chen; Liu, Shasha</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor and Capital Dynamics under Financing Frictions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Michaels, Ryan; Page, T. Beau; Whited, Toni M.
We assemble a new, quarterly panel dataset that links firms' investment and financing to their employment and wages. In the data, wages and leverage are negatively related, both cross-sectionally and within firms. This pattern contradicts models in which firms insure workers against unemployment risk. We reconcile this fact with a model that integrates factor adjustment frictions and wage bargaining with costly external financing. In the model, the probability of default rises with debt. Because default incurs deadweight costs, the expected surplus over which firms and workers bargain falls, thus depressing wages. We show that raising financing costs reduces employment and wages, in line with recent reduced-form evidence.</description><author>Michaels, Ryan; Page, T. Beau; Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Did You See What I Saw? Interpreting Others' Forecasts When Their Information Is Unknown</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kwasnica, Anthony M.; Velthuis, Raisa; Williams, Jared
We conduct a series of forecasting experiments to examine how people update their beliefs upon observing others' forecasts. Subjects exhibit cursedness, that is, a propensity to underestimate the link between others' forecasts and others' information, which causes subjects to underreact. The behavior of sophisticated subjects is not affected by the framing of information, but unsophisticated subjects switch from underreaction to overreaction when they are only provided qualitative (rather than quantitative) forecast information. Our results have important implications for the way that financial analysts aggregate information and the way that financial institutions present forecasts to their clients.</description><author>Kwasnica, Anthony M.; Velthuis, Raisa; Williams, Jared</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Links and Cross-Predictability of Stock Returns: Evidence from Characteristic-Based "Styles"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mueller, Sebastian
Prior research has shown that information diffuses gradually across stocks that are economically linked at the industry level. I document a similar pattern when stock portfolios are formed based on characteristics that are used in the anomaly literature (e.g., size, value, asset growth). Specifically, characteristics are useful to identify economic links, and earnings surprises contain information about future returns of other firms that share similar characteristics (i.e., similar-style firms). Such style-based earnings surprises can be used to predict style returns in the time series. For the cross-section of stocks, I create a composite style-based earnings surprise measure (SESM), which generates an equal-weighted (value-weighted) long-short strategy return of 167 (101) basis points per month. I do not find that industry spillovers, the traditional post-earnings announcement drift, unconditional abnormal style returns or risk can explain the return predictability. My findings suggest a further channel of gradual information diffusion in security markets.</description><author>Mueller, Sebastian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>To See Is to Know: Simultaneous Display of Market Data for Retail Investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benamar, Hedi
I test whether the display format of market data affects the trading performance and behavior of retail investors. To do so, I exploit a large brokerage dataset covering a period during which the market information provided to the broker's customers changed in format, but not in content. I find that a simultaneous display of cross-stock market data reduces the cognitive cost of monitoring the market and thus helps investors obtain better execution prices. In particular, investors better mitigate non-execution and adverse-selection risks when trading with limit orders. Hence, the display format of market data matters for the individual investor.</description><author>Benamar, Hedi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Political Uncertainty and Cross-Border Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Chunfang; Li, Xiaoyang; Liu, Guilin
Using national elections as sources of exogenous variation in uncertainty, we show that political uncertainty affects the volume and outcome of cross-border acquisitions. When a country is about to hold a national election, this deters foreign firms' inbound acquisitions, especially when the host country poses greater expropriation risk. An upcoming home country election encourages firms to conduct outbound cross-border acquisitions, especially to target countries with free-trade agreements, military allies, or countries with better governance. At transaction level, we show that announcement returns to cross-border deals incorporate political uncertainty considerations. Overall, these results shed light on the effects of political uncertainty through the cross-border acquisition channel.</description><author>Cao, Chunfang; Li, Xiaoyang; Liu, Guilin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Credit Default Swaps Mitigate the Impact of Credit Rating Downgrades?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chava, Sudheer; Ganduri, Rohan; Ornthanalai, Chayawat
We find that a firm's stock price reaction to its credit rating downgrade announcement is muted by 44-52% when credit default swaps (CDSs) trade on its debt. We explore the role of the CDS markets in providing information ex ante and relieving financing frictions ex post for downgraded firms. We find that the impact of CDS trading is more pronounced for firms whose debt financing is more dependent on credit ratings (e.g., those rated around the speculative-grade boundary, those with a higher number of rating-based covenants). Reductions in debt and investment, and the increase in financing costs are less severe for CDS firms than non-CDS firms following an identical credit rating downgrade. Our results suggest that CDSs mute the stock market reaction to a credit rating downgrade by alleviating the financing frictions faced by downgraded firms.</description><author>Chava, Sudheer; Ganduri, Rohan; Ornthanalai, Chayawat</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Structure and the Substitutability versus Complementarity Nature of Leases and Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ambrose, Brent W.; Emmerling, Thomas; Huang, Henry H.; Yildirim, Yildiray
The capital structure irrelevance argument of Modigliani and Miller (1958) implies that the use of debt or leases should have no impact on firm values. This classical argument leaves out several important considerations crucial for the result, in particular, counterparty credit risk. We re-examine the capital structure problem for firms that can utilize debt and leases in the presence of counterparty risk. Our numerical and empirical estimates show a negative term structure of lease rates that steepens as a function of counterparty risk. Moreover, we document numerical evidence for the complementary relationship between debt and leases in the presence of counterparty risk.</description><author>Ambrose, Brent W.; Emmerling, Thomas; Huang, Henry H.; Yildirim, Yildiray</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Transmission of Bank Liquidity Shocks: Evidence from House Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dursun-de Neef, H. Ozlem
This article uses the 2007-09 financial crisis as a negative liquidity shock on banks in the USA and analyzes its transmission to the real economy. The ex ante heterogeneity in the amount of long-term debt that matured during the crisis is used to measure the variation in banks' exposure to the liquidity shock. I find that banks transmitted the liquidity shock to the real economy by reducing their loan supply. The reduction was particularly strong for real estate loans. As a result, house prices declined in the MSAs where these banks have branches. Bank capital plays a significant role in the transmission: under-capitalized banks transmitted the liquidity shock, whereas well-capitalized banks' lending did not show any decline.</description><author>Dursun-de Neef, H. Ozlem</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Growth and Stock Market Returns: A Time-Series Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wen, Quan
I find that aggregate asset growth constructed from bottom-up data negatively predicts future market returns both in and out-of-sample and this result is robust across G7 countries. I further show that aggregate asset growth contains information about future market returns not captured by traditional macroeconomic variables and other measures of investment or growth. The forecasting ability of asset growth is strongly correlated with its propensity to predict more optimistic analyst forecasts and subsequent downward revisions, earnings surprise, and systematic errors in investors' expectations. The time-varying risk premium also appears key in explaining the documented return predictability.</description><author>Wen, Quan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mind the Gap: Disentangling Credit and Liquidity in Risk Spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwarz, Krista
Euro-area sovereign bond and interbank interest rate spreads spiked in the 2007-2009 Global Financial Crisis and the subsequent European Debt Crisis, substantially elevating financing costs. I use a model-free measure of market liquidity to precisely identify the relative contribution of credit versus liquidity to spreads in these episodes. In the Financial Crisis, liquidity is paramount, accounting for 36% of trough-to-peak widening, after controlling for credit. However, default risk becomes relatively more important to sovereign spreads in the Debt Crisis. Aggregate bond liquidity explains a substantial portion of interbank spreads throughout the sample.</description><author>Schwarz, Krista</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Renegotiation Frictions and Financial Distress Resolution: Evidence from CDS Spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campello, Murillo; Ladika, Tomislav; Matta, Rafael
We study how renegotiation frictions impact distressed debt resolution and ex-ante financial contracting. We do so by exploiting an event that exogenously reduced the costs that syndicated lenders incur when renegotiating debt out of court, without affecting in-court restructuring costs (IRS Regulation TD9599). CDS contracts insure creditors against in-court bankruptcy losses and CDS spreads reflect the shadow price of bankruptcy risk. Using a triple-differences approach, we show that CDS spreads fell by record figures on the event's announcement, with declines concentrated among distressed firms that relied most on syndicated loans. Distressed firms' loan renegotiation rates more than doubled, as banks agreed to extend loan maturities in exchange for higher interest payments. Those firms' access to new syndicated loans increased while associated interest markups declined.</description><author>Campello, Murillo; Ladika, Tomislav; Matta, Rafael</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Linear Approximations and Tests of Conditional Pricing Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brandt, Michael W.; Chapman, David A.
If a nonlinear risk premium in a conditional asset pricing model is approximated with a linear function, as is commonly done in empirical research, the fitted model is misspecified. We use a generic reduced-form model economy with moderate risk premium nonlinearity to examine the size of the resulting misspecification-induced pricing errors. Pricing errors from moderate nonlinearity can be large, and a version of a test for nonlinearity based on risk premiums rather than pricing errors has reasonable power properties after properly controlling for the size of the test. We conclude by examining the importance of moderate nonlinearity in the context of the investment-specific technology shock models of Papanikolaou (2011) and Kogan and Papanikolaou (2014).</description><author>Brandt, Michael W.; Chapman, David A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Mechanism for LIBOR</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coulter, Brian; Shapiro, Joel; Zimmerman, Peter
The investigations into the London Interbank Offered Rate (LIBOR) have highlighted that it is subject to manipulation. We examine a new method for constructing LIBOR that produces an unbiased estimator of the true rate. LIBOR itself is based solely on transactions. We allow for fines when a bank's transaction is different than a comparison rate, which depends on the set of transactions and non-manipulated rates elicited by a revealed preference mechanism. These non-manipulated rates will always be used in the fines, but transactions may not. We address how this approach applies to potential replacements for LIBOR and other financial benchmarks, and how it works even in markets in which there are few transactions.</description><author>Coulter, Brian; Shapiro, Joel; Zimmerman, Peter</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Dependence and Diversification in Corporate Credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Peter; Jacobs, Kris; Jin, Xisong; Langlois, Hugues
We characterize dependence in corporate credit and equity returns for 215 firms using a new class of large-scale dynamic copula models. Copula dependence and especially tail dependence are highly variable and persistent, increase significantly in the financial crisis, and have remained high since. The most drastic increases in credit dependence occur in July/August of 2007 and in August of 2011 and the decrease in diversification potential caused by the increases in dependence and tail dependence is large. Credit default swap correlation dynamics are important determinants of credit spreads.</description><author>Christoffersen, Peter; Jacobs, Kris; Jin, Xisong; Langlois, Hugues</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Drives Index Options Exposures?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, Timothy; Liang, Mo; Liu, Yun
This paper documents the history of aggregate positions in US index options and investigates the driving factors behind use of this class of derivatives. We construct several measures of the magnitude of the market and characterize their level, trend, and covariates. Measured in terms of volatility exposure, the market is economically small, but it embeds a significant latent exposure to large price changes. Out-of-the-money puts are the dominant component of open positions. Variation in options use is well described by a stochastic trend driven by equity market activity and a significant negative response to increases in risk. Using a rich collection of uncertainty proxies, we distinguish distinct responses to exogenous macroeconomic risk, risk aversion, differences of opinion, and disaster risk. The results are consistent with the view that the primary function of index options is the transfer of unspanned crash risk.</description><author>Johnson, Timothy; Liang, Mo; Liu, Yun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium with Monoline and Multiline Structures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ibragimov, Rustam; Jaffee, Dwight; Walden, Johan
We study a competitive market for risk-sharing, in which risk-tolerant providers of risk protection, who face frictional costs in holding capital, offer coverage over a range of risk classes to risk-averse agents. We distinguish monoline and multiline industry structures and characterize when each structure is optimal. Markets for which the risks are limited in number, asymmetric or correlated will be served by monoline structures, whereas markets characterized by a large number of essentially independent risks will be served by many multiline firms. Our results are consistent with observed structures within insurance, and also have general implications for the financial services industry.</description><author>Ibragimov, Rustam; Jaffee, Dwight; Walden, Johan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Did Sponsor Banks Rescue Their SIVs? A Signaling Model of Rescues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Segura, Anatoli
At the beginning of the past financial crisis sponsoring banks rescued their structured investment vehicles (SIVs) despite of lack of contractual obligation to do so. I show that this outcome may arise as the equilibrium of a signaling game between banks and their debt investors when a negative shock affects the correlated asset returns of a fraction of banks and their sponsored vehicles. The rescue is interpreted as a good signal and reduces the refinancing costs of the sponsoring bank. If banks' leverage is high or the negative shock is sizable enough, the equilibrium is a pooling one in which all banks rescue. When the aggregate financial sector is close to insolvency, banks' expected net worth would increase if rescues were banned. The model can be extended to discuss the circumstances in which all banks collapse after rescuing their vehicles.</description><author>Segura, Anatoli</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wages and Human Capital in Finance: International Evidence, 1970-2011</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boustanifar, Hamid; Grant, Everett; Reshef, Ariell
We study the allocation and compensation of human capital in the finance industry in a set of developed economies in 1970-2011. Finance relative wages generally increase-but not in all countries, and to varying degrees. Trading-related activities account for 50% of the increases, despite accounting for only 13% of finance employment, on average. Financial deregulation is the most important factor driving up wages in finance; it has a larger effect in environments where informational rents and socially inefficient risk taking are likely to be prevalent. Differential investment in information and communication technology does not have causal explanatory power. High finance wages attract skilled international immigration to finance, raising concerns for "brain drain."</description><author>Boustanifar, Hamid; Grant, Everett; Reshef, Ariell</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk-Based Capital Requirements and Optimal Liquidation in a Stress Scenario</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Braouezec, Yann; Wagalath, Lakshithe
We develop a simple yet realistic framework to analyze the impact of an exogenous shock on a bank's balance-sheet and its optimal response when it is constrained to maintain its risk-based capital ratio above a regulatory threshold. We show that in a stress scenario, capital requirements may force the bank to shrink the size of its assets and we exhibit the bank's optimal strategy as a function of regulatory risk-weights, asset market liquidity, and shock size. When financial markets are perfectly competitive, we show that the bank is always able to restore its capital ratio above the required one. However, for banks constrained to sell their loans at a discount and/or with a positive price impact when selling their marketable assets (large banks) we exhibit situations in which the deleveraging process generates a death spiral. We then show how to calibrate our model using annual reports of banks and study in detail the case of the French bank BNP Paribas. Finally, we suggest how our simple framework can be used to design a systemic capital surcharge.</description><author>Braouezec, Yann; Wagalath, Lakshithe</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trust and Household Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Danling; Lim, Sonya S.
Using a large sample of US individuals, we show that individuals with higher levels of trust have lower likelihoods of default in household debt and higher net worth. The effect is driven by trust values inherited from cultural and family backgrounds more than by trust beliefs about others. We demonstrate a causal impact of trust on financial outcomes by extracting the component of trust correlated with early-life experiences. The effect of trust is more pronounced among females, those with lower education, lower income, lower financial literacy, and higher debt-to-income ratio. Further evidence suggests that enhancing individuals' trust, to the right amount, can improve household financial well-being.</description><author>Jiang, Danling; Lim, Sonya S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gender Gap in Personal Bankruptcy Risks: Empirical Evidence from Singapore</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit; He, Jia; Sing, Tien Foo; Zhang, Jian
Gender gap can arise due to various factors-socio-economic, culture, risk attitudes, and macro-economic circumstances. Using a unique dataset that merges motor vehicle events with bankruptcy outcomes and personal data from Singapore, this study finds significant evidence of a gender gap in personal bankruptcy risk. We show that women's odds of being involved in bankruptcy events are 28% of those of men after controlling for demographic variables, housing type, cultural and spatial fixed effects. Using motor vehicle accidents as an instrument, we confirm that the gender gap in bankruptcy risk is mainly driven by risk-taking behavior. The heterogeneity analyses show that culture also explains part of the difference. Chinese, Indian, and Malay women have differential bankruptcy rates in Singapore.</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; He, Jia; Sing, Tien Foo; Zhang, Jian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Oil Prices and the Stock Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ready, Robert C.
This paper develops a novel method for classifying oil price changes as supply or demand driven using information in asset prices. Motivated by a simple model, demand shocks are identified as returns to an index of oil producing firms which are orthogonal to unexpected changes in the VIX index, with supply shocks capturing the remaining variation in oil prices. Demand shocks are strongly positively correlated with market returns and economic output, whereas supply shocks have a strong negative correlation. The negative correlation of supply shocks and returns is strongest in industries that produce consumer goods, while the positive correlation of demand shocks is stronger for industries which use relatively large amounts of oil as an input.</description><author>Ready, Robert C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Growth Option Exercise and Capital Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Purnanandam, Amiyatosh; Rajan, Uday
We document that firms decrease their leverage when they convert growth options into tangible assets. We argue that the act of growth option exercise decreases information asymmetry about the firm, which in turn reduces the relative cost of issuing information-sensitive securities such as equity. We show that leverage is negatively correlated with unexpected capital expenditure, our proxy for growth option conversion. The negative relationship becomes stronger when the information environment of a firm deteriorates following a reduction in analyst coverage after a brokerage house merger. Overall, our findings are contrary to standard trade-off and pecking order theories, but are consistent with recent work on signaling and growth options.</description><author>Purnanandam, Amiyatosh; Rajan, Uday</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Redemptions and Fund Manager Sales of Emerging Market Bonds: How Are They Related?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shek, Jimmy; Shim, Ilhyock; Shin, Hyun Song
Asset portfolios of open-end mutual funds reflect both the fund flows from ultimate investors as well as discretionary trading by the fund managers. We propose a method for decomposing the change in mutual fund asset holdings into the parts due to investor flows, fund manager discretionary sales, and valuation effects. We find that discretionary sales tend to reinforce the sales due to investor redemptions. We also find that 100 dollars' worth of bond sales is associated with around 4 dollars' worth of valuation losses. Finally, we show that a one percentage point increase in emerging market economy (EME) bond yields is associated with a 9- 10% decline in the dollar value of EME bond fund holdings.</description><author>Shek, Jimmy; Shim, Ilhyock; Shin, Hyun Song</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning and Leverage Cycles in General Equilibrium: Theory and Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hennessy, Christopher A.; Radnaev, Boris
This article develops and empirically tests a tractable general equilibrium model of corporate financing and investment dynamics in a trade-off economy where heterogeneous firms face unobservable disaster risk and engage in rational Bayesian learning. The model sheds light on leverage cycles. During periods absent disasters: equity premia decrease; credit spreads decrease; expected loss-given-default increases; and leverage ratios increase. Time-since-prior-disaster is the key model conditioning variable. In response to a disaster, risk premia increase while firms sharply reduce labor, capital and leverage, with response size increasing in time-since-prior-disasters. Firms with high bankruptcy costs are most responsive to the time-since-disaster variable. Disaster responses are more pronounced than in an otherwise equivalent economy featuring observed disaster risk. Empirical tests of novel corporate finance predictions are conducted. Consistent with the model, we find empirically that leverage and investment are increasing in time-since-prior-recessions, with the effect more pronounced for firms with low recovery ratios.</description><author>Hennessy, Christopher A.; Radnaev, Boris</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Premia and Volatilities in a Nonlinear Term Structure Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feldhutter, Peter; Heyerdahl-Larsen, Christian; Illeditsch, Philipp
We introduce a reduced-form term structure model with closed-form solutions for yields where the short rate and market prices of risk are nonlinear functions of Gaussian state variables. The nonlinear model with three factors matches the timevariation in expected excess returns and yield volatilities of US Treasury bonds from 1961 to 2014. Yields and their variances depend on only three factors, yet the model exhibits features consistent with Unspanned Risk Premia (URP) and Unspanned Stochastic Volatility (USV).</description><author>Feldhutter, Peter; Heyerdahl-Larsen, Christian; Illeditsch, Philipp</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Disclosure and Market Transparency with Costly Information Processing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Di Maggio, Marco; Pagano, Marco
We study a model where some investors ("hedgers") are bad at information processing, while others ("speculators") have superior information-processing ability and trade purely to exploit it. The disclosure of financial information induces a trade externality: if speculators refrain from trading, hedgers do the same, depressing the asset price. Market transparency reinforces this mechanism, by making speculators' trades more visible to hedgers. Hence, issuers will oppose both the disclosure of fundamentals and trading transparency. Issuers may either under-or over-provide information compared to the socially efficient level if speculators have more bargaining power than hedgers, while they never under-provide it otherwise. When hedgers have low financial literacy, forbidding their access to the market may be socially efficient.</description><author>Di Maggio, Marco; Pagano, Marco</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Capital Structure of Nations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Patrick; Huang, Haizhou
When a nation can finance its investments via foreign-currency denominated debt or domestic-currency claims, what is the optimal capital structure of the nation? Building on the functions of fiat money as both medium of exchange, and store of value like corporate equity, our model connects monetary economics, fiscal theory, and international finance under a unified corporate finance perspective. With frictionless capital markets both a Modigliani-Miller theorem for nations and the classical quantity theory of money hold. With capital market frictions, a nation's optimal capital structure trades off inflation dilution costs and expected default costs on foreign-currency debt. Our framing focuses on the process by which new money claims enter the economy and the potential wealth redistribution costs of inflation.</description><author>Bolton, Patrick; Huang, Haizhou</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>ECB Policies Involving Government Bond Purchases: Impact and Channels</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krishnamurthy, Arvind; Nagel, Stefan; Vissing-Jorgensen, Annette
We evaluate the effects of three European Central Bank (ECB) policies (the Securities Markets Programme (SMP), the Outright Monetary Transactions (OMT), and the LongTerm Refinancing Operations (LTROs)) on government bond yields. We use a novel Kalman-filter augmented event-study approach and yields on euro-denominated sovereign bonds, dollar-denominated sovereign bonds, corporate bonds, and corporate credit default swap (CDS) rates to understand the channels through which policies reduced sovereign bond yields. On average across Italy, Spain and Portugal, considering both the SMP and the OMT, yields fall considerably. Decomposing this fall, default risk accounts for 37% of the reduction in yields, reduced redenomination risk for 13%, and reduced market segmentation effects for 50%. Stock price increases in distressed and core countries suggest that these policies also had beneficial macro-spillovers.</description><author>Krishnamurthy, Arvind; Nagel, Stefan; Vissing-Jorgensen, Annette</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Repression in the European Sovereign Debt Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, Bo; Ivashina, Victoria
At the end of 2013, the share of domestic government debt held by the banking sectors of Eurozone countries was more than twice the amount held in 2007. We show that these increased bond holdings generated a crowding out of corporate lending. We find that the corporate loan supply was depressed by domestic sovereign bonds exclusively during the crisis period (2010-11). The crowding-out pattern holds across firms with different relationship banks within a given country. These findings suggest that sovereign bond holdings negatively impact private capital formation and reflect financial repression. We show that direct government ownership, as well as government influence through banks' boards of directors, is among the channels used to influence banks.</description><author>Becker, Bo; Ivashina, Victoria</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing Asset Sales and Business Cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arnold, Marc; Hackbarth, Dirk; Puhan, Tatjana Xenia
Using a dynamic model of financing, investment, and macroeconomic risk, we investigate when firms sell assets to fund investments (financing asset sales) across the business cycle. Equity financed investment transfers wealth from equity to debt because asset volatility declines and earnings increase when firms invest. Financing asset sales reduce asset collateral and, hence, transfer wealth back from debt to equity. Exploring the dynamics of the heretofore overlooked "asset sale versus external equity" financing margin across business cycles helps explain novel stylized facts about asset sales and their business cycle patterns that cannot be rationalized by traditional motives for selling assets.</description><author>Arnold, Marc; Hackbarth, Dirk; Puhan, Tatjana Xenia</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Emotional State and Market Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breaban, Adriana; Noussair, Charles N.
We consider the relationship between trader emotions and asset market behavior. We create experimental asset markets with the structure first studied by Smith, Suchanek, and Williams (1988), which is known to generate price bubbles and crashes. To track traders' emotions in real time, we analyze participants' facial expressions with facereading software before and while the market is operating. We find that a positive emotional state correlates with purchases and overpricing. Fear correlates with selling, low prices, and price decreases. The experiment confirms the intuition that emotions and market dynamics are closely related.</description><author>Breaban, Adriana; Noussair, Charles N.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Futures Trading and the Excess Co-movement of Commodity Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Le Pen, Yannick; Sevi, Benoit
We empirically reinvestigate the issue of the excess co-movement of commodity prices initially raised in Pindyck and Rotemberg (1990). Excess co-movement appears when commodity prices remain correlated even after adjusting for the impact of fundamentals. We use recent developments in large approximate factor models to consider a richer information set and adequately model these fundamentals. We consider a set of eight unrelated commodities along with 184 real and nominal macroeconomic variables, from developed and emerging economies, from which nine factors are extracted over the 1993-2013 period. Our estimates provide evidence of time-varying excess co-movement which is particularly high after 2007. We further show that speculative intensity is a driver of the estimated excess comovement, as speculative trading is both correlated across the commodity futures markets and correlated with the futures prices. Our results can be taken as direct evidence of the significant impact of financialization on commodity-price crossmoments. This paper was written in part while the authors were visiting the MSO Department at the London Business School, whose support and hospitality are greatly appreciated. We wish to thank the Associate Editor (Bernard Dumas) as well as a referee for insightful comments on our work. We are indebted to Lutz Kilian and Jaime Casassus for their many comments that led to significant improvements in the paper, and Derek Bunn, Paolo Pasquariello, and Christian Schluter for making useful remarks on an earlier version. Helpful comments by Laurent Ferrara, Francois Geerolf, Roselyne Joyeux, Fabien Tripier, and Ombretta Signori are also gratefully acknowledged. We thank Serena Ng for making available her Matlab package for large approximate factor models, and Pierre Perron and Yohei Yamamoto for their program to test for structural breaks. We are also grateful to participants at the 3emes Journees de l'Atelier Finance et Risque in Nantes (2010); the Forecasting Financial Markets Annual Meeting in Marseille (2011); the workshop in Development Economics in Aix-en-Provence (2011); the XXIth International Conference on Money, Banking and Finance in Rome (2012); the 30th International French Finance Association (AFFI) Conference in Lyon (2013); the 62nd Annual Meeting of the French Economic Association in Aix-en-Provence (2013); and the Commodity and Energy Markets Conference Annual Meeting in Oxford (2017). Y. L. P. acknowledges financial support by the project MIMO at the Foundation "Europlace Institute of Finance".</description><author>Le Pen, Yannick; Sevi, Benoit</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Credit Risk Premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berndt, Antje; Douglas, Rohan; Duffie, Darrell; Ferguson, Mark
We measure credit risk premia-prices for bearing corporate default risk in excess of expected default losses-using Markit CDS and Moody's Analytics EDF data. We find dramatic variation over time in credit risk premia, with peaks in 2002, during the global financial crisis of 2008-09, and in the second half of 2011. Even after normalizing these premia by expected default losses, median credit risk premia fluctuate over time by more than a factor of 10. Credit risk premia comove with macroeconomic indicators, even after controlling for variation in expected default losses, with higher premia per unit of expected loss during times of market-wide distress. Countercyclical variation of premia-to-expected-loss ratios is more pronounced for investment-grade issuers than for high-yield issuers.</description><author>Berndt, Antje; Douglas, Rohan; Duffie, Darrell; Ferguson, Mark</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Exposures to Sagging Real Estate, Subprime, or Conduits Abroad Lead to Contraction and Flight to Quality in Bank Lending at Home?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ongena, Steven; Tumer-Alkan, Gunseli; von Westernhagen, Natalja
We investigate how differential exposures by German banks to the US real-estate market affect domestic lending in Germany when home prices started to decline in the USA. We find that banks with an exposure to the US real-estate sector and to conduits shift their domestic lending to industry-region combinations with lower insolvency ratios following a decrease in US home prices. These banks also contract their lending to German firms more than banks that do not have such exposure. We mainly document that possible losses abroad shift bank lending at home where the size of the effect depends on the type and the degree of exposure the bank has.</description><author>Ongena, Steven; Tumer-Alkan, Gunseli; von Westernhagen, Natalja</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Media Coverage and Stock Returns on the London Stock Exchange, 1825-70</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Turner, John D.; Ye, Qing; Walker, Clive B.
News media plays an important role in modern financial markets. In this article, we analyze the role played by the news media in an historical financial market. Using The Times's coverage of companies listed on the London stock market between 1825 and 1870, we examine the determinants of media coverage in this era and whether media coverage affected returns. Our main finding is that a media effect mainly manifests itself after the mid-1840s and that the introduction of arm's-length ownership along with markedly increased market participation was the main reason for the emergence of this media effect.</description><author>Turner, John D.; Ye, Qing; Walker, Clive B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Variance-of-Variance Risk Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaeck, Andreas
This article explores the premium for bearing the variance risk of the VIX index, called the variance-of-variance risk premium. I find that during the sample period from 2006 until 2014 trading strategies exploiting the difference between the implied and realized variance of the VIX index yield average excess returns of -24.16% per month, with an alpha of -16.98% after adjusting for Fama-French and Carhart risk factors as well as accounting for variance risk (both highly significant). The article provides further evidence of risk premium characteristics using corridor variance swaps and compares empirical results with the predictions of reduced-form and structural benchmark models.</description><author>Kaeck, Andreas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Measure of Pure Home Bias</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, Ian A.; Sercu, Piet; Vanpee, Rosanne
The literature on international equity holdings distinguishes between home bias (over-weighting of home stocks) and foreign bias (relative underweighting for more "distant" countries). The two biases can be integrated into one distance-based model. We define pure home bias as the excess of home bias relative to this model, and find pure home bias only in emerging markets. Countries with high tax rates and low credit standing have higher pure home bias, and more development comes with lower distance aversion. Methodologically, the choice of portfolio bias measure matters. We find the best measure to be a covariance-based measure relative to the world average.</description><author>Cooper, Ian A.; Sercu, Piet; Vanpee, Rosanne</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Common Factors, Information, and Holdings Dispersion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fontaine, Patrice; Jimenez-Garces, Sonia; Seasholes, Mark S.
We derive closed-form solutions for asset prices and portfolio holdings when agents have asset-specific information and/or information about common components that affect many assets. Our solutions are general, encompass existing information structures, and are used to analyze new structures. A given investor's portfolio can exhibit highly disperse holdings-e.g., portfolio weights may vary significantly from market capitalization weights. Our model also generates large ranges of asset prices due to information asymmetries. We help explain why US investors (e.g.) may underweight German stocks (e.g.) on average, but overweight a particular German stock relative to its market capitalization weight.</description><author>Fontaine, Patrice; Jimenez-Garces, Sonia; Seasholes, Mark S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Bond Trading on a Limit Order Book Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abudy, Menachem; Wohl, Avi
We investigate the trading of corporate bonds (c-bonds) by an open limit order book (LOB) mechanism. To do so, we use the case of the Tel Aviv Stock Exchange (TASE) as a laboratory, in which both stocks and c-bonds are traded by an LOB mechanism. Contrary to the OTC market in the USA, the TASE c-bond market is liquid with narrow spreads and low price dispersion. The short-term traders (STT), who are the analog of the market makers in the LOB, have small trading rents and unconcentrated activity (a low Herfindahl index). In the cross-section of bonds, the low concentration is related to low spreads, low price dispersion, and small STT rents. The non-STT [including retail investors (RIs), whose participation is significant] competes with the STT on quotation and tends to tighter quotes. RIs' activity contributes to narrower spreads.</description><author>Abudy, Menachem; Wohl, Avi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Investment Bank Rankings: Evidence from M&amp;A League Tables</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Derrien, Francois; Dessaint, Olivier
This paper explores how league tables, which are rankings based on market shares, influence the mergers and acquisitions market. A bank's league table rank predicts its future deal flow, above and beyond other determinants. This creates incentives for banks to manage their league table ranks. League table management tools include selling fairness opinions (FOs) and reducing fees. Banks use such tools mostly when their incentives to do so are high: when a transaction affects their league table position or when they lost ranks in recent league tables. League table management seems to affect the quality of FOs.</description><author>Derrien, Francois; Dessaint, Olivier</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity Flows in Interbank Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Castiglionesi, Fabio; Eboli, Mario
This article characterizes the interbank deposit network as a flow network that is able to channel liquidity flows among banks. These flows are beneficial, allowing banks to cope with liquidity risk. First, we analyze the efficiency of three network structures: star-shaped, complete, and incomplete in transferring liquidity among banks. The star-shaped interbank network achieves the complete coverage of liquidity risk with the smallest amount of interbank deposits held by each bank. This result implies that the star-shaped network is most resilient to systemic risk. Second, we analyze the banks' decentralized interbank deposit decisions for a given network structure. We show that all network structures can generate an inefficiently low amount of interbank deposits. However, the star-shaped network induces banks to hold an amount of interbank deposits that is the closest to the efficient level. These results provide a rationale for consistent empirical evidence on sparse and centralized interbank networks.</description><author>Castiglionesi, Fabio; Eboli, Mario</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor Representation in Governance as an Insurance Mechanism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, E. Han; Maug, Ernst; Schneider, Christoph
We hypothesize that labor participation in governance helps improve risk sharing between employees and employers. It provides an ex post mechanism to enforce implicit insurance contracts protecting employees against adverse shocks. Results based on German establishment-level data show that skilled employees of firms with 50% labor representation on boards are protected against layoffs during adverse industry shocks. They pay an insurance premium of 3.3% in the form of lower wages. Unskilled blue-collar workers are unprotected against shocks. Our evidence suggests that workers capture all the gains from improved risk sharing, whereas shareholders are no better or worse off than without codetermination.</description><author>Kim, E. Han; Maug, Ernst; Schneider, Christoph</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Uninformative Feedback and Risk Taking: Evidence from Retail Forex Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben-David, Itzhak; Birru, Justin; Prokopenya, Viktor
We document evidence consistent with retail traders in the Forex market attributing random success to their own skill and, as a consequence, increasing risk taking. Although past performance does not predict future success for these traders, traders increase trade sizes, trade size variability, and number of trades with gains, and less with losses. There is a large discontinuity in all of these trading variables around zero past week returns: e.g., traders increase their trade size dramatically following winning weeks, relative to losing weeks. The effects are stronger for novice traders, consistent with more intense "learning" in early trading periods.</description><author>Ben-David, Itzhak; Birru, Justin; Prokopenya, Viktor</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Complex Mortgages</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amromin, Gene; Huang, Jennifer; Sialm, Clemens; Zhong, Edward
Complex mortgages became a popular borrowing instrument during the bullish housing market of the early 2000s but vanished rapidly during the subsequent downturn. These non-traditional loans, including interest-only and negative-amortization mortgages, enable households to postpone loan repayment in contrast to fully amortizing traditional mortgages. Contrary to common perception, complex mortgages are used by households with high-income levels and prime credit scores, quite unlike the low-income population targeted by subprime mortgages. Nonetheless, we find that complex-mortgage borrowers become delinquent on their mortgages at rates twice as high as borrowers with plain-vanilla fixed-rate contracts even after controlling for household and loan characteristics. Our findings suggest a link between innovations in mortgage markets focused on prime borrowers and the financial crisis.</description><author>Amromin, Gene; Huang, Jennifer; Sialm, Clemens; Zhong, Edward</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Wins When Exchanges Compete? Evidence from Competition after Euro Conversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dewenter, Kathryn L.; Han, Xi; Koski, Jennifer L.
Using euro conversion as the trigger, we examine what drives volume and spread changes when stock exchanges compete. Results show average trading costs on European exchanges decrease almost 9%, and turnover increases over 30%. Trading costs decline or remain unchanged on all exchanges, but volume deteriorates in some markets and improves in others. Frankfurt, Paris, London, and Milan are winners, while Madrid and Brussels lose volume. We examine the role of the spread-volume relation, firm characteristics, exchange trading rules, and country-level factors in determining these outcomes. Results suggest that euro conversion prompted competition by increasing transparency in market prices.</description><author>Dewenter, Kathryn L.; Han, Xi; Koski, Jennifer L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regional Inflation, Banking Integration, and Dollarization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Martin; De Haas, Ralph; Sokolov, Vladimir
We exploit variation in consumer price inflation across seventy-one Russian regions to examine the relationship between the perceived stability of the domestic currency and financial dollarization. Our results show that regions with higher inflation experience an increase in the dollarization of household deposits and a decrease in the dollarization of loans. The impact of inflation on credit dollarization is weaker in regions with less integrated banking markets. This suggests that the currency-portfolio choices of households and firms are constrained by the asset-liability management of banks.</description><author>Brown, Martin; De Haas, Ralph; Sokolov, Vladimir</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Credit Card Debt Puzzle and Noncognitive Ability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Hwan-sik; Laschever, Ron A.
Many households concurrently hold low-yield liquid assets while incurring costly credit card debt. In our sample, more than 80% of households with credit card debt also have low-yield liquid assets. Using data from the Health and Retirement Study (N = 30,517), we examine the role of noncognitive skills as well as the economic, financial, and demographic factors that affect the likelihood of co-holding. We find that the "Big Five" personality traits have a statistically significant and economically important effect: households with a more agreeable, introvert, and less conscientious head of household are more likely to co-hold. We also examine the role of intra-household dynamics.</description><author>Choi, Hwan-sik; Laschever, Ron A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Competition Affect Truth Telling? An Experiment with Rating Agencies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rabanal, Jean Paul; Rud, Olga A.
We use an experimental approach to study the effect of market structure on the incidence of misreporting by credit rating agencies. In the game, agencies receive a signal regarding the type of asset held by the seller and issue a report. The sellers then present the asset, with the report if one is solicited, to the buyer for purchase. We find that competition among rating agencies significantly reduces the likelihood of misreporting.</description><author>Rabanal, Jean Paul; Rud, Olga A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Theory of Costly Sequential Bidding</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Daniel, Kent D.; Hirshleifer, David
We model sequential bidding in a private value English auction when it is costly to submit or revise a bid. We show that, even when bid costs approach zero, bidding occurs in repeated jumps, consistent with certain types of natural auctions such as takeover contests. In contrast with most past models of bids as valuation signals, every bidder has the opportunity to signal and increase the bid by a jump. Jumps communicate bidders' information rapidly, leading to contests that are completed in a few bids. The model additionally predicts; informative delays in the start of bidding; that the probability of a second bid decreases in, and the jump increases in, the first bid; that objects are sold to the highest valuation bidder; and that revenue and efficiency relationships between different auctions hold asymptotically.</description><author>Daniel, Kent D.; Hirshleifer, David</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Combination Return Forecasts and Portfolio Allocation with the Cross-Section of Book-to-Market Ratios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Detzel, Andrew; Strauss, Jack
In this paper, we forecast industry returns out-of-sample using the cross-section of book-to-market (BM) ratios and investigate whether investors can exploit this predictability in portfolio allocation. Cash-flow and return forecasting regressions show that cross-industry BM ratios contain significant predictive information beyond aggregate and industry-specific BM ratios. Forecast combination methods based on industry BM ratios generate significant out-of-sample predictability for many industries. Real-time portfolio-rotation strategies that buy industries with high predicted returns and short industries with low predicted returns based on combination forecasts earn significant alpha with respect to standard asset pricing models net of transaction costs.</description><author>Detzel, Andrew; Strauss, Jack</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fund Flows, Manager Changes, and Performance Persistence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bessler, Wolfgang; Blake, David; Luckoff, Peter; Tonks, Ian
Most empirical studies suggest that mutual funds do not persistently outperform an appropriate benchmark in the long run. We analyze this lack of persistence in terms of two equilibrating mechanisms: fund flows and manager changes. Using data on actively managed US equity mutual funds, we find that if neither mechanism is operating, winner funds (top-decile ranked in previous year) continue to significantly outperform loser funds (bottom-decile ranked in previous year) by 4.08 percentage points per annum. However, the difference between previous winner and loser funds declines to zero within one year if the two mechanisms are acting together. Thus, equity mutual fund out- and underperformance are unlikely to persist in well-functioning financial markets.</description><author>Bessler, Wolfgang; Blake, David; Luckoff, Peter; Tonks, Ian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do FOMC Actions Speak Loudly? Evidence from Corporate Bond Credit Spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Javadi, Siamak; Nejadmalayeri, Ali; Krehbiel, Timothy L.
We find that Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) actions (especially rate cuts) narrowed corporate credit spreads during the pre-crisis period of 2002-07. During the 2008 crisis period, we find that both conventional cuts and quantitative easing decreased spreads. But FOMC inactions caused significant widening of spreads. The effects are especially large for speculative-grade and short-maturity bonds. Overall, the policy uncertainty during the crisis and macroeconomic theories during the pre-crisis period help to explain why FOMC announcements impacted credit spreads. The Fed's actions targeted at promoting growth and/or providing systemic liquidity were especially noted by the corporate bond market.</description><author>Javadi, Siamak; Nejadmalayeri, Ali; Krehbiel, Timothy L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Skewness, Individual Investor Preference, and the Cross-section of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Tse-Chun; Liu, Xin
We find a robust negative relation between skewness/lottery-like features, proxied by maximum return (MAX) over the last month, and future returns for stocks preferred by individual investors. This negative relation is nonexistent for the rest of stocks. We identify stocks preferred by individual investors through bundling ten stock characteristics associated with their stock preferences. The negative relation between MAX and future return is produced by the stocks preferred by individuals that account for less than 5% of the overall market capitalization. Our results are robust to alternative definitions of MAX and lottery-like features such as total, idiosyncratic, and expected skewness.</description><author>Lin, Tse-Chun; Liu, Xin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder Conflicts and Dividends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berzins, Janis; Bohren, Oyvind; Stacescu, Bogdan
We examine how dividend policy is used to mitigate potential conflicts of interest between majority and minority shareholders in private Norwegian firms. The average payout is 50% higher if the majority shareholder's equity stake is 55% (high conflict potential) rather than 95% (low conflict potential). Such minority-friendly payout is also associated with higher subsequent minority shareholder investment. These results suggest that controlling shareholders voluntarily use dividends to reduce agency conflicts and build trust, rather than opportunistically preferring private benefits to dividends. We show that our results are unlikely to arise from liquidity or signaling motives.</description><author>Berzins, Janis; Bohren, Oyvind; Stacescu, Bogdan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leverage, CEO Risk-Taking Incentives, and Bank Failure during the 2007-10 Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyallian, Patricia; Ruiz-Verdu, Pablo
Usual measures of the risk-taking incentives of bank CEOs do not capture the risk-shifting incentives that the exposure of a CEO's wealth to his firm's stock price (delta) creates in highly levered firms. We find evidence consistent with the importance of these incentives for bank CEOs: In a sample of large US financial firms, a higher pre-crisis delta is associated with a significantly higher probability of failure during the 2007-10 financial crisis in highly levered firms, but not in less levered firms.</description><author>Boyallian, Patricia; Ruiz-Verdu, Pablo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Housing Habits and Their Implications for Life-Cycle Consumption and Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kraft, Holger; Munk, Claus; Wagner, Sebastian
We solve a rich life-cycle model of household decisions involving consumption of perishable goods and housing services, habit formation for housing consumption, stochastic labor income, stochastic house prices, home renting and owning, stock investments, and portfolio constraints. In line with empirical observations, the optimal decisions involve (i) stock investments that are low or zero for many young agents and then gradually increasing over life, (ii) an age- and wealth-dependent housing expenditure share, (iii) non-housing consumption being significantly more sensitive to wealth and income shocks than housing consumption, and (iv) non-housing consumption being hump-shaped over life.</description><author>Kraft, Holger; Munk, Claus; Wagner, Sebastian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Some Clients More Equal Than Others? An Analysis of Asset Management Companies' Execution Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben-Rephael, Azi; Israelsen, Ryan D.
Previous research documents differences in trading desk skills across management companies that result in significant variation in execution costs. In this paper, we utilize links between management companies and their institutional clients to explore variation in execution costs within management companies. For a subset of management companies, we find that systematic differences in execution costs exist across clients; these differences are comparable to the variation documented across management companies and persist over time. Clients who receive lower execution costs reward management companies with an increase in dollar trading volume. We find no evidence that the results are driven by broker commissions or differences in trading practices. Given the economic significance of our findings and implications for institutional investors, this aspect of execution should be recognized regardless of the ultimate source of the differences.</description><author>Ben-Rephael, Azi; Israelsen, Ryan D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Indirect Costs of Financial Distress and Bankruptcy Law: Evidence from Trade Credit and Sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sautner, Zacharias; Vladimirov, Vladimir
We argue that stronger debt enforcement in bankruptcy can reduce indirect costs of financial distress: (i) by increasing the likelihood of restructuring outside bankruptcy and (ii) by improving the recovery rate of stakeholders, such as trade creditors, through explicit legal provisions. Consistent with these predictions, we find that when debt enforcement is stronger, financially distressed firms are less exposed to indirect distress costs in the form of reduced access to trade credit and forgone sales. We document these effects in a panel of firms from forty countries with heterogeneous debt enforcement characteristics and in differences-in-differences tests exploiting several recent bankruptcy reforms.</description><author>Sautner, Zacharias; Vladimirov, Vladimir</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tournament Incentives and Firm Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shen, Carl Hsin-han; Zhang, Hao
This study analyzes how promotion-based tournament incentives for non-CEO senior executives affect corporate innovation. We measure tournament incentives using the pay gap between a CEO and the next layer of senior executives. We find that tournament incentives are positively related to innovative efficiency, as measured by the number of patents and patent citations generated per million dollars of R&amp;D expense. Our main finding holds in an instrumental-variable analysis and regressions using alternative innovation measures, including patent generality and originality indices and stock market reactions to patent grants. Consistent with prior theories, the positive effect of tournament incentives is found to be particularly pronounced during the period prior to CEO turnovers.</description><author>Shen, Carl Hsin-han; Zhang, Hao</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance, Comparative Advantage, and Resource Allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jaud, Melise; Kukenova, Madina; Strieborny, Martin
Can financial institutions and markets enhance the discipline imposed by competitive product markets and thus improve resource allocation in the real economy? We address this question in the context of international trade, using disaggregated product-level data from seventy-one countries exporting to the USA. We show that exported products exit the US market sooner if they stand far away from the exporting country's comparative advantage. This pattern is stronger when the exporting country has a well-developed banking system, but it is unaffected by the depth of stock markets. These results are in accordance with theories stressing the disciplining role of debt and monitoring abilities of banks.</description><author>Jaud, Melise; Kukenova, Madina; Strieborny, Martin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Seeing the Unobservable from the Invisible: The Role of CO2 in Measuring Consumption Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Zhuo; Lu, Andrea
In contrast to past studies that assume service flow of durable goods consumption to be a constant fraction of the stock, we study a consumption-based asset pricing model featuring time-varying utilization of durable goods. We propose an innovative measure of the unobserved usage of durable goods from carbon dioxide emissions. We find that the time-varying utilization of durable goods is a valid pricing factor. Our model exhibits a stronger cross-sectional pricing power than several consumption-based capital asset pricing models, including Yogo's (2006) durable goods model. Finally, our model mitigates the joint risk premium and implied risk-free rate puzzle.</description><author>Chen, Zhuo; Lu, Andrea</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning to Take Risks? The Effect of Education on Risk-Taking in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Black, Sandra E.; Devereux, Paul J.; Lundborg, Petter; Majlesi, Kaveh
We investigate whether acquiring more primary education has long-term effects on risk-taking behavior in financial markets. Using exogenous variation in education from a compulsory schooling change combined with wealth data for the Swedish population, we estimate the effect of education on stock market participation and on the share of financial wealth invested in stocks, conditional on participation. For men, an extra year of education increases market participation by two percentage points and the share of financial wealth allocated to stocks by 10%. We find suggestive evidence that greater financial wealth is a potential channel through which education increases participation, consistent with the existence of fixed costs. Lower risk aversion is a potential channel through which education increases the stock share. The reform has less effect on female schooling attainment and there is no evidence that this additional education affects women's asset allocation. There is no evidence of spillovers to children.</description><author>Black, Sandra E.; Devereux, Paul J.; Lundborg, Petter; Majlesi, Kaveh</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Cost of Political Connections</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertrand, Marianne; Kramarz, Francis; Schoar, Antoinette; Thesmar, David
Using plant-level data from France, we document a potential cost of political connections for firms that is not offset by other benefits. Politically connected CEOs alter corporate employment decisions to help (regional) politicians in their re-election efforts by having higher job and plant creation rates, and lower rates of destruction in election years, especially in politically contested areas. There is little evidence that connected firms benefit from preferential access to government resources, such as subsidies or tax exemptions. Connected firms are less profitable in the cross-section and also experience a drop in profitability when a connected CEO comes to power.</description><author>Bertrand, Marianne; Kramarz, Francis; Schoar, Antoinette; Thesmar, David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Zero-Leverage Puzzle: An International Comparison</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane; Kwok, Chuck; Zheng, Xiaolan
Using a large sample of firms from developed and developing countries over the 1990-2010 period, we document evidence of zero-leverage firms around the world. Further, we find strong and robust evidence that in countries with high scores on Schwartz's Conservatism and Mastery indices as well as high levels of trust, firms are more likely to employ a zero-leverage policy, after controlling for various firm- and country-level determinants of leverage. Finally, we find that firms with zero leverage have a lower cost of equity capital in countries where a zero-leverage policy is more compatible with the local culture.</description><author>El Ghoul, Sadok; Guedhami, Omrane; Kwok, Chuck; Zheng, Xiaolan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Behavioral Biases Affect Order Aggressiveness?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bian, Jiangze; Chan, Kalok; Shi, Donghui; Zhou, Hao
We extend previous studies on the effect of behavioral biases on investor hold/sell decisions, and examine whether behavioral biases affect the order submission strategies. We use a unique database provided by the Shanghai Stock Exchange, which contains order submissions and executions as well as trading records of all investors. We find investors are less aggressive in submitting sell orders for stocks that experienced losses, and more aggressive in submitting sell orders for stocks that experienced gains. The sell order aggressiveness is negatively related to the size of losses, but has a quadratic relationship with the size of gains. Results are consistent with the combination of the disposition and the house money effects.</description><author>Bian, Jiangze; Chan, Kalok; Shi, Donghui; Zhou, Hao</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Prior Investment Outcomes on Future Investment Decisions: Is There a Gender Difference?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hibbert, Ann Marie; Lawrence, Edward R.; Prakash, Arun J.
We use our survey of finance professors from universities across the USA to investigate whether men and women react differently to prior gains and losses. We find that after incurring a loss, a large fraction of men continue to invest in stocks, but a majority of women tend to avoid investing in stocks. Even though prior losses increase the expectation of unfavorable market conditions, we find that women are more likely than men to expect unfavorable market conditions irrespective of whether they have made a gain or a loss in their prior stock market investments.</description><author>Hibbert, Ann Marie; Lawrence, Edward R.; Prakash, Arun J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Independent Directors' CEO Experience Matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kang, Shinwoo; Kim, E. Han; Lu, Yao
We find the confluence of CEO-same industry experience makes independent directors particularly helpful in enhancing value-added growth and we identify a channel: guidance toward higher value-added R&amp;D investments and higher quality innovations. Further corroborating these inferences, we find greater improvement in value-added growth when (1) independent directors with industry-CEO experience (IDICEs) have experience in more similar industries; (2) they create more shareholder value as CEO; and (3) they are current CEOs. In addition, IDICEs contribute to value-added growth most when firm environments and characteristics are conducive for active board-management interaction; namely, when product markets are more competitive and dynamic, when outsiders can more easily acquire firm-specific information, and when firms are younger and smaller. Consistent with our inferences on how IDICEs contribute to value-added growth, firms growing faster, less successfully innovating, and/or under strong governance tend to be matched with IDICEs.</description><author>Kang, Shinwoo; Kim, E. Han; Lu, Yao</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Empirical Investigation on Funding Liquidity and Market Liquidity (vol 22, pg 1213, 2018)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Ji-Yeong; Ahn, Dong-Hyun; Baek, In-Seok; Kang, Kyu Ho
nan</description><author>Chung, Ji-Yeong; Ahn, Dong-Hyun; Baek, In-Seok; Kang, Kyu Ho</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Empirical Investigation on Funding Liquidity and Market Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Ji-Yeong; Ahn, Dong-Hyun; Baek, In-Seok; Kang, Kyu Ho
In empirically exploring the link between funding liquidity and market liquidity, the greatest challenge is to designate a suitable market that shows such linkages. In this respect, the 15-year Japanese floating (JF)-rate bond market, characterized by the lack of diversity among highly leveraged trading strategies, is an ideal case for investigation. A clean measure of market liquidity, liquidity discount rate (LDR), is estimated from JF prices and the LDR is found to be intertwined with funding liquidity only during the crisis. The deterioration of funding liquidity precedes that of the LDR, thus providing evidence of the outbreak of liquidity spiral.</description><author>Chung, Ji-Yeong; Ahn, Dong-Hyun; Baek, In-Seok; Kang, Kyu Ho</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option Listing and Information Asymmetry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Jianfeng
Option listing increases informed and uninformed trading by 12.4% and 23.9%, respectively, in the USA between 2001 and 2010, hence reducing relative information risk. We establish the causal effects using control stocks with similar propensities of listing and a quasi-natural experiment using option listing standards. The benefits are more prominent for stocks with active options trading and opaque stocks. The reduction of information risk is larger for good news than bad news, and the stock price response to earnings surprise weakens after listing. The results suggest that options improve the overall market information environment beyond substitutional effects to stock trading.</description><author>Hu, Jianfeng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informational Contagion in the Laboratory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cipriani, Marco; Guarino, Antonio; Guazzarotti, Giovanni; Tagliati, Federico; Fischer, Sven
We study the informational channel of financial contagion in the laboratory. In our experiment, two markets with privately informed subjects open sequentially. Subjects in the second market observe the history of trades and prices in the first market. Although in both markets private information is imperfectly aggregated, subjects in the second market make correct inferences from the information coming from the first market. As theory predicts, when fundamentals are correlated, contagion occurs in the laboratory; in contrast, with independent fundamentals, there is no contagion effect. In both cases, the correlation between asset prices is very close to the theoretical one.</description><author>Cipriani, Marco; Guarino, Antonio; Guazzarotti, Giovanni; Tagliati, Federico; Fischer, Sven</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is There a Distress Risk Anomaly? Pricing of Systematic Default Risk in the Cross-section of Equity Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anginer, Deniz; Yildizhan, Celim
The standard measures of distress risk ignore the fact that firm defaults are correlated and that some defaults are more likely to occur in bad times. We use risk premium computed from corporate credit spreads to measure a firm's exposure to systematic variation in default risk. Unlike previously used measures, the credit risk premium explicitly accounts for the non-diversifiable component of distress risk. In contrast to prior findings in the literature, we find that stocks with higher systematic default risk exposures have higher expected equity returns which are largely explained by the Fama-French risk factors. We confirm the robustness of these results by using an alternative systematic default risk factor for firms that do not have bonds outstanding.</description><author>Anginer, Deniz; Yildizhan, Celim</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dynamics of Tobin's Q</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Puopolo, Giovanni W.
In this article, I propose a general-equilibrium model with proportional adjustment costs and industry-specific capital to study the firm migration phenomenon across market-to-book ratio. In my model, investors' desire to diversify their portfolios and investment frictions generate a mean-reverting dynamics of Tobin's q consistent with the probabilities of migration found in the data, and a non-linear pattern in the conditional volatility of Tobin's q. In addition, since firms' market-to-book ratios are function of the state of the economy and contain information about stock returns, stock prices inherit these properties, yielding asset-pricing implications in line with the empirical evidence, namely the value premium and a non-monotone relationship between the volatility of stock returns and the Tobin's q.</description><author>Puopolo, Giovanni W.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relative Optimism and the Home Bias Puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Solnik, Bruno; Zuo, Luo
We study whether relative optimism leads to home bias in portfolio holdings by looking at two novel databases: a survey that includes expectations of identified professional asset management companies for equity, bonds, and currencies, and the International Monetary Fund portfolio holdings data for equity and bonds. We document that relative optimism for equity is persistent over the period 1997-2012, but relative optimism for bonds and currencies exhibits more time-series variation. Moreover, we show that relative optimism is an economically significant variable that helps explain home bias in portfolio holdings, not only for equity, but also for bonds.</description><author>Solnik, Bruno; Zuo, Luo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Market Competition and the Severity of Distressed Asset Sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Salgado, Pablo; Carrasco, Vinicius; Pinho De Mello, Joao Manoel
This article explores the effect of an industry's market structure on the liquidation value of assets. We show that when firms with financial constraints compete for the gains arising from market concentration, they expend insufficient efforts to deploy assets across industries, leading to significant liquidation discounts when compared with an efficient benchmark. Equilibrium distress costs and private costs of leverage should increase with the rents linked to concentration in the product market.</description><author>Salgado, Pablo; Carrasco, Vinicius; Pinho De Mello, Joao Manoel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effects of Spot Market Short-Sale Constraints on Index Futures Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fabozzi, Frank J.; Karagozoglu, Ahmet K.; Wang, Na
We analyze the effects of spot market short-sale constraints on derivatives trading using a unique Chinese stock market futures trading database. Due to short-sale constraints, investors' pessimistic views on the underlying index can be expressed solely through short futures positions, while investors' optimistic views are dispersed through their spot and futures trading. We hypothesize that trading of pessimistic investors (with net short futures positions) contains more information than that of optimistic investors. We document the negative volatility-volume relation is associated with pessimistic investors' trading, which attenuates with less-restricted spot market short-sale rules. Large pessimistic investors' net demand can predict future returns, but not the case for optimistic investors.</description><author>Fabozzi, Frank J.; Karagozoglu, Ahmet K.; Wang, Na</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Cash Holdings and Ambiguity Aversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breuer, Wolfgang; Rieger, Marc O.; Soypak, K. Can
Previous literature on cash management has revealed that firms hoard cash to protect themselves against external financing constraints that might limit future capital budgeting policies. In a theoretical model based on this finding, we analyze how investors' attitude toward uncertain investment returns affects the valuation of cash and the amount of cash holdings. Subsequently, we show empirically that cash holdings become less valuable with increasing ambiguity aversion in line with our model. We also demonstrate that managers react accordingly and lower cash holdings if their investors tend to be more ambiguity-averse. Several robustness tests confirm our findings.</description><author>Breuer, Wolfgang; Rieger, Marc O.; Soypak, K. Can</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Regulation, CEO Compensation, and Boards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kolm, Julian; Laux, Christian; Loranth, Gyoengyi
We analyze the limits of regulating bank CEO compensation to reduce risk shifting in the presence of an active board that retains the right to approve new investment strategies. Compensation regulation prevents overinvestment in strategies that increase risk, but it is ineffective in preventing underinvestment in strategies that reduce risk. The regulator optimally combines compensation and capital regulations. In contrast, if the board delegates the choice of strategy to the CEO, compensation regulation is sufficient to prevent both types of risk shifting. Compensation regulation increases shareholders' incentives to implement an active board, which reduces the effectiveness of compensation regulation.</description><author>Kolm, Julian; Laux, Christian; Loranth, Gyoengyi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxable and Tax-Deferred Investing with the Limited Use of Losses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fischer, Marcel; Gallmeyer, Michael
We study the impact of the different tax treatment of capital gains and losses on the optimal location of assets in taxable and tax-deferred accounts. The classical result of Black (1980) and Tepper (1981) suggests that investors should follow a strict pecking order asset location rule and hold those assets that are subject to the highest tax rate preferentially in tax-deferred accounts. We show that with the different tax treatment of realized gains and losses, only tax-efficient equity mutual funds are optimally held in taxable accounts, whereas mutual funds with average tax-(in) efficiency are preferentially held in tax-deferred accounts.</description><author>Fischer, Marcel; Gallmeyer, Michael</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Important Are Risk-Taking Incentives in Executive Compensation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dittmann, Ingolf; Yu, Ko-Chia; Zhang, Dan
We consider a model in which shareholders provide a risk-averse CEO with risk-taking incentives in addition to effort incentives. We show that the optimal contract protects the CEO from losses for bad outcomes and is convex for medium outcomes and concave for good outcomes. We calibrate the model to data on 1,707 CEOs and show that it explains observed contracts much better than the standard model without risk-taking incentives. When we apply the model to contracts that consist of base salary, stock, and options, the results suggest that options should be issued in the money. Our model also helps us rationalize the universal use of at-the-money options when the tax code is taken into account. Moreover, we propose a new way of measuring risk-taking incentives in which the expected value added to the firm is traded off against the additional risk a CEO has to bear.</description><author>Dittmann, Ingolf; Yu, Ko-Chia; Zhang, Dan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Venture Capital and the Market for Talent during Booms and Busts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yung, Chris
I develop and test a model in which the characteristics of entrepreneurs and VCs are jointly determined by real investment opportunities. By inducing the entry of inept agents, booms inflate the dispersion in ability on both sides of the market. Consistent with these predictions, venture fund return data show that 1) new entrants in hot markets are associated with high cross-sectional dispersion in abnormal returns, and 2) the worst performing funds in the sample are disproportionately likely to be new entrants in hot markets.</description><author>Yung, Chris</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>State-Dependent Variations in the Expected Illiquidity Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jang, Jeewon; Kang, Jangkoo; Lee, Changjun
Recent evidence on state-dependent variations in market liquidity suggests strong variations in the illiquidity premium across economic states. Adopting a two-state Markov switching model, we find that, while illiquid stocks are affected more by economic conditions than liquid ones are during recessions, the differences in expected returns are relatively small during expansions. Therefore, the expected illiquidity premium displays strong state-dependent variations that are countercyclical. We show that the state of a high illiquidity premium is closely associated with periods of real economic recessions, market declines, and high volatility, which coincides with major events of liquidity dry-up and high liquidity commonality.</description><author>Jang, Jeewon; Kang, Jangkoo; Lee, Changjun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Simple Skewed Distribution with Asset Pricing Applications*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Roon, Frans; Karehnke, Paul
Recent research has identified skewness and downside risk as one of the most important features of risk. We present a new distribution which makes modeling skewed risks no more difficult than normally distributed (symmetric) risks. Our distribution is a combination of the "downside" and "upside" half of two normal distributions, and its parameters can be calculated in closed form to match a given mean, variance, and skewness. Value at risk, expected shortfall, portfolio weights, and risk premia have simple expressions for our distribution and show economically meaningful deviations from the normal case already for very modest levels of skewness. An empirical application suggests that our distribution fits the data well.</description><author>de Roon, Frans; Karehnke, Paul</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Exposures and Sovereign Stress Transmission*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Altavilla, Carlo; Pagano, Marco; Simonelli, Saverio
Using novel monthly data for 226 euro-area banks from 2007 to 2015, we investigate the determinants of banks' sovereign exposures and their effects on lending during and after the crisis. Public, bailed-out and poorly capitalized banks responded to sovereign stress by purchasing domestic public debt more than other banks, consistent with both the "moral suasion" and the "carry trade" hypothesis. Public banks' purchases grew especially in coincidence with the largest ECB liquidity injections, which therefore reinforced the "moral suasion" mechanism. Bank exposures significantly amplified the impact of sovereign stress on bank lending to domestic firms, as well as on lending by foreign subsidiaries of stressed-country banks to firms in non-stressed countries. Altogether, our evidence connects this amplification effect and its cross-border transmission to the moral suasion exerted by domestic governments on banks during the crisis.</description><author>Altavilla, Carlo; Pagano, Marco; Simonelli, Saverio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Banking: Recent Developments and Insights from Research</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Claessens, Stijn
Following recent crises, cross-border capital flows have declined considerably, and many advanced countries' banks are retrenching. At the same time, banks from emerging and developing countries continue to expand abroad, and banking has become more regional. Research highlights that long-term debt flows are less volatile and that foreign banks with larger presence, more domestic funding, and closer relationships provide more finance and share risks better. While ongoing changes in global banking influence its overall benefits, the crises also revealed the need for a consistent framework for supervising and resolving globally active banks, with the European Banking Union an important model.</description><author>Claessens, Stijn</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Are the Best Liquidity Proxies for Global Research?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fong, Kingsley Y. L.; Holden, Craig W.; Trzcinka, Charles A.
Liquidity plays an important role in global research. We identify high-quality liquidity proxies based on low-frequency (daily) data, which provide 1,000 x to 10,000 x computational savings compared to computing high-frequency (intraday) liquidity measures. We find that: (i) Closing Percent Quoted Spread is the best monthly percent-cost proxy when available, (ii) Amihud, Closing Percent Quoted Spread Impact, LOT Mixed Impact, High-Low Impact, and FHT Impact are tied as the best monthly cost-per-dollar-volume proxy, (iii) the daily version of Closing Percent Quoted Spread is the best daily percent-cost proxy, and (iv) the daily version of Amihud is the best daily cost-per-dollar-volume proxy.</description><author>Fong, Kingsley Y. L.; Holden, Craig W.; Trzcinka, Charles A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Trend Is Your Friend: Time-Series Momentum Strategies across Equity and Commodity Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Georgopoulou, Athina; Wang, Jiaguo
This article documents a significant time-series momentum effect that is consistent and robust across all examined conventional asset classes from 1969 to 2015. We find that the duration and magnitude of time-series momentum is different in developed and emerging markets, but this is no longer the case when controlling for the currency component. We further demonstrate that time-series momentum captures a significant proportion of internationalmutual fund performance, but this is predominantly with respect to its long aspect. Finally, the market interventions by central banks in recent years have distorted correlations across assets; this challenges the performance of such portfolios.</description><author>Georgopoulou, Athina; Wang, Jiaguo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Development and Patterns of Industrial Specialization: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Qing; Xue, Chang; Zhu, Chenqi
This article investigates the influence of financial development on patterns of industrial specialization across China's regions. We find that industrial sectors reliant on access to external finance tend to concentrate in regions with well-developed financial markets. Both foreign direct investment (FDI) and alternative financing channels are shown to play significant roles in shaping patterns of industrial specialization in China. In contrast, proxies for formal financial markets, for example, the banking system and capital markets, have few effects on regional industrial agglomeration. This result remains robust to instrumental variable estimation, alternative model specifications, and controlling for other traditional determinants of regional specialization.</description><author>He, Qing; Xue, Chang; Zhu, Chenqi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment Financing and Financial Development: Evidence from Viet Nam</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O'Toole, Conor; Newman, Carol
This article explores whether financial development reduces external financing constraints faced by firms, a key channel through which finance impacts economic growth. Using an extensive firm-level dataset from Viet Nam, we use a structural Q model of investment estimated using a generalized method of moments technique. We focus on three aspects of financial development: financial depth, state-owned enterprise (SOE) use of finance and, the degree of market-driven, commercial bank financing in the economy. Our data allow us to measure financial development at the province level, providing rich within-country variation. We find that financial development reduces external financing constraints for firms thus facilitating higher investment activity. Financing constraints are decreasing in credit to the private sector, increasing in the use of finance by SOEs and decreasing in the degree to which finance is allocated on market-terms by commercial banks.</description><author>O'Toole, Conor; Newman, Carol</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Characterizing the Asymmetric Dependence Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alcock, Jamie; Hatherley, Anthony
We examine the price of asymmetric dependence (AD) in the cross section of US equities. Using a b- invariant AD metric, we demonstrate that the return premiumfor AD is approximately 47% of the premium for b. The premium for lower-tail AD is equivalent to 26% of the market risk premium and has been relatively constant through time. The discount associated with upper-tail AD is 29% of themarket risk premium and has been increasing markedly in recent years. Our findings have substantial implications for the cost of capital, investor expectations, portfolio management, and performance assessment.</description><author>Alcock, Jamie; Hatherley, Anthony</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge Fund Replication: A Model Combination Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O'Doherty, Michael S.; Savin, N. E.; Tiwari, Ashish
Recent years have seen increased demand from institutional investors for passive replication products that track the performance of hedge fund strategies using liquid investable assets such as futures contracts. In practice, linear replication methods suffer from poor tracking performance and high turnover. We propose a model combination approach to index replication that pools information from a diverse set of pre-specified factor models. Compared with existing methods, the pooled clone strategies yield consistently lower tracking errors, generate less severe portfolio drawdowns, and require substantially smaller trading volume. The pooled hedge fund clones also provide economic benefits in a portfolio allocation context.</description><author>O'Doherty, Michael S.; Savin, N. E.; Tiwari, Ashish</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks' Exposure to Rollover Risk and the Maturity of Corporate Loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Paligorova, Teodora; Santos, Joao A. C.
In this article, we show that when banks increase their use of wholesale funding they shorten the maturity of loans to corporations. This effect appears to be linked to banks' exposure to rollover risk resulting from their increasing use of short-term uninsured funding. Banks that use more wholesale funding shorten both the maturity of newly issued loans and the maturity of their loan portfolios. These results are not present among banks that rely predominantly on insured deposits. The link between wholesale funding and loan maturity is robust, and holds when we include firm-year fixed effects, suggesting that the decline in loan maturity is bank driven. In line with this premise, we find that the slope of the loan yield curve becomes steeper for banks that use more wholesale funding and that borrowers turn to the bond market to raise funding with longer maturity in response to banks' loan maturity shortening.</description><author>Paligorova, Teodora; Santos, Joao A. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Housing Wealth on Stock Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Luo, Juan; Xu, Limin; Zurbruegg, Ralf
We document a housing wealth effect on the stock liquidity of local firms. We first demonstrate that the heterogeneity of homeownership rates across geographical areas can explain variations in the impact that changes in house prices have on local stock liquidity. We then show, consistent with expectations that an increase in housing wealth leads to a reduction in household risk aversion, that the liquidity of lottery stocks and stocks dominated by individual investors rises. We also show that it promotes local liquidity commonality and reduces the proportion of firm-specific information revealed in stock returns.</description><author>Luo, Juan; Xu, Limin; Zurbruegg, Ralf</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Simple Skewed Distribution with Asset Pricing Applications (vol 21, pg 2169, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Roon, Frans; Karehnke, Paul
nan</description><author>de Roon, Frans; Karehnke, Paul</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extreme Returns and Herding of Trade Imbalances</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Y. Peter; Kim, S. Thomas
We estimate the stock's likelihood of extreme returns by measuring the extent to which the stock's trades are correlated with market-wide and industry-wide trades during normal times, referred to as herding. We find that stocks whose trades herd most with aggregate-level trades experience most negative (positive) returns during market crashes (booms). While herding generates extreme returns in both sides, investors appear to demand compensation for the possibility of extreme low returns. This is the case even when we control for standard asset pricing variables and other tail risk proxies.</description><author>Chung, Y. Peter; Kim, S. Thomas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Information Value of Stock Lending Fees: Are Lenders Price Takers?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duong, Truong X.; Huszar, Zsuzsa R.; Tan, Ruth S. K.; Zhang, Weina
We find that higher stock lending fees predict significantly lower future returns after controlling for shorting demand for US stocks during the period 2007-10. These results suggest that active institutional investors on the supply side play an important role in the return predictability of fees and they not only respond to demand but also price in additional information around earnings news announcements. Overall, we find evidence that stock lenders are informed and, together with short sellers, contribute to the price discovery process.</description><author>Duong, Truong X.; Huszar, Zsuzsa R.; Tan, Ruth S. K.; Zhang, Weina</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of the Growth in Labor Hours per Worker on Future Stock Returns, Hiring, and Profitability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gu, Li; Huang, Dayong
High growth rate of labor hours per worker signals low future stock returns and high future hiring rate. As labor hours are substituted for hiring, hiring becomes less responsive to future discount rate. The growth rate of the number of labor hours per worker does not appear to be related to future profitability. Our findings are largely consistent with a dynamic labor hours asset pricing model that features large asymmetric costs in adjusting the number of workers and small costs in adjusting the number of hours per worker.</description><author>Gu, Li; Huang, Dayong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Foreign Information Predict the Returns of Multinational Firms Worldwide?*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Finke, Christian; Weigert, Florian
We investigate whether value-relevant foreign information only gradually dilutes into stock prices of multinational firms worldwide. Using an international sample of firms from twenty-two developed countries, we find that a portfolio strategy based on firms' foreign sales information yields future returns of more than 10% p.a. globally. The return spread due to foreign information is substantial across different geographical regions and cannot be explained by traditional risk factors, firm characteristics, and industry momentum. Our results are in line with limited attention of investors to foreign information being the main driver of this effect worldwide.</description><author>Finke, Christian; Weigert, Florian</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Sentiment, Limited Arbitrage, and the Cash Holding Effect*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Xiafei; Luo, Di
We examine the investor sentiment and limits-to-arbitrage explanations for the positive cross-sectional relation between cash holdings and future stock returns. Consistent with the investor sentiment hypothesis, we find that the cash holding effect is significant when sentiment is low, and it is insignificant when sentiment is high. In addition, the cash holding effect is strong among stocks with high transaction costs, high short selling costs, and large idiosyncratic volatility, indicating that arbitrage on the cash holding effect is costly and risky. In line with the limits-to-arbitrage hypothesis, high costs and risk prevent rational investors from exploiting the cash holding effect.</description><author>Li, Xiafei; Luo, Di</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Financial Stability Matter to the Fed in Setting US Monetary Policy?*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oet, Mikhail V.; Lyytinen, Kalle
The Taylor rule presents a traditional approach to guiding and evaluating contemporary monetary policy as a function of inflation and economic slack. While the responsibilities of the Federal Reserve (Fed) include price stability and long-run growth, its mission has grown to include financial stability. Surprisingly, the question of whether financial stability ought to be considered as an element of monetary policy is hotly contested. This study aims to determine whether policymakers' discussions of financial stability and other factors systematically explain deviations of observed policy rates from the rates implied by the Taylor rule. To this end, we conduct content analysis of the Fed's monetary policy discussions to discover actual topics that enter into policy. We offer two main findings: First, discussion themes extracted from released Federal OpenMarket Committee meeting minutes provide explanatory power beyond standard Taylor rule variables. Second, additional explanatory power is provided by a tri-mandate policy rule that accounts for changes in the economic and financial system as moderated by the evolving preferences of the policymakers. We show that a discussion-based thematic model with financial stability dominates Taylor-type rules during normal times. Moreover, the tri-mandate policy model with financial stability dominates Taylor-type rules in zero lower bound conditions. Taken together, these findings reveal that financial stability has mattered to the Fed continuously and remains critical in setting monetary policy in zero lower bound.</description><author>Oet, Mikhail V.; Lyytinen, Kalle</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Special Issue of the International Risk Management Conference in Warsaw Poland</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Franklin; Brenner, Menachem
nan</description><author>Allen, Franklin; Brenner, Menachem</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regime-Dependent Sovereign Risk Pricing During the Euro Crisis*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delatte, Anne-Laure; Fouquau, Julien; Portes, Richard
Previous work has documented a greater sensitivity of long-term government bond yields to fundamentals in euro area peripheral countries during the euro crisis, but we know little about the driver(s) of regime switches. Our estimates based on a panel smooth threshold regression model quantify and explain them: (1) investors have penalized a deterioration of fundamentals more strongly from 2010 to 2012; (2) the higher the bank credit risk, measured with the premium on credit derivatives, the higher the extra premium on fundamentals; (3) after ECB President Draghi's speech in July 2012, it took 1 year to restore the noncrisis regime and suppress the extra premium.</description><author>Delatte, Anne-Laure; Fouquau, Julien; Portes, Richard</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Purchasing of Deferred Income Annuities When Payout Yields are Mean-Reverting*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Huaxiong; Milevsky, Moshe A.; Young, Virginia R.
We determine the optimal lifecycle purchasing strategy for deferred income annuities (DIAs)-which are distinct from single- premium income annuities (SPIAs)-for an individual who wishes to maximize the expected utility of his/her annuity income at a fixed time in the future. In contrast to the vast portfolio- choice literature for SPIAs, we focus on the stochasticity of the DIA's payout yield and address concerns that rates are currently "too low" to justify irreversible annuitization. We assume a mean-reverting model for payout yields and show that a risk- neutral consumer who wishes to maximize his/ her expected retirement income should wait until yields reach a threshold- which lies above historical averages-and then purchase the DIA in one lump sum. In contrast, a risk- averse consumer who is concerned the payout yield will remain below average for an extended period and worries about losing mortality credits while waiting, should employ a barrier purchasing strategy, as in the portfolio choice problem under transaction costs. We illustrate how this insight is applied in the context of annuitization. In fact, the optimal behavior of a risk-averse consumer resembles an asymmetric dollar-cost averaging strategy, with a portion of the DIA-budget spent even while payout rates are below historical averages. As part of our analysis we offer an easy-to-use asymptotic approximation for the optimal purchasing strategy (threshold) and provide some numerical examples to illustrate the concept.</description><author>Huang, Huaxiong; Milevsky, Moshe A.; Young, Virginia R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investing in Disappearing Anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, Christopher S.; Pomorski, Lukasz
We argue that anomalies may experience prolonged decay after discovery and propose a Bayesian framework to study how that impacts portfolio decisions. Using the January effect and short-term index autocorrelations as examples of disappearing anomalies, we find that prolonged decay is empirically important, particularly for small-cap anomalies. Papers that document new anomalies without accounting for such decay may actually underestimate the original strength of the anomaly and imply an overstated level of the anomaly out of sample. We show that allowing for potential decay in the context of portfolio choice leads to out-of-sample outperformance relative to other approaches.</description><author>Jones, Christopher S.; Pomorski, Lukasz</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Great Cross-Border Bank Deleveraging: Supply Constraints and Intra-Group Frictions*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cerutti, Eugenio; Claessens, Stijn
International banks greatly reduced direct cross-border and local affiliates' lending as the global financial crisis strained their balance sheets, lowered borrower demand, and altered government policies. Using bilateral lender-borrower data and controlling for demand, we show that reductions largely varied in line with markets' prior assessments of banks' vulnerabilities, with financial statements' and lender borrower data playing minor roles. Those banking systems subject to less market discipline, however, were less sensitive to markets' perceptions. Moving resources within banking groups became more restricted as drivers of reductions in direct cross-border loans differed from those for local affiliates' lending, especially for more impaired banking systems.</description><author>Cerutti, Eugenio; Claessens, Stijn</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Limitations of Stock Market Efficiency: Price Informativeness and CEO Turnover*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorton, Gary B.; Huang, Lixin; Kang, Qiang
There is a tenuous link between market efficiency and economic efficiency in that stock prices are more informative when the information has less social value. We investigate this link in the context of CEO turnover. Our theoretical model predicts that, when the board's monitoring intensity and the informed trader's information decision are jointly endogenized, stock price informativeness is negatively related to the board's monitoring effort. Our empirical tests provide supporting evidence for this negative effect. Moreover, using the passage of the Sarbanes- Oxley Act (SOX) as a quasi- natural experiment, we find that SOX, while strengthening corporate governance, has a negative effect on stock price informativeness, especially among firms with complex organizational structures.</description><author>Gorton, Gary B.; Huang, Lixin; Kang, Qiang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Equity Funds in the Financial Crisis Propagation*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hau, Harald; Lai, Sandy
The early stage of the 2007/2008 financial crisis was marked by large value losses for bank stocks. This article identifies the equity funds most affected by this valuation shock and examines its consequences for the nonfinancial stocks owned by the respective funds. We document three key empirical findings. First, ownership links to these distressed equity funds lead to large temporary underperformance of the most exposed nonfinancial stocks. Second, distressed equity funds make the better performing stocks in their portfolio the preferred liquidation choice. Third, stocks with higher overall fund ownership generally performed better throughout the crisis.</description><author>Hau, Harald; Lai, Sandy</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Editorial</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Franklin; Edmans, Alex
nan</description><author>Allen, Franklin; Edmans, Alex</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Financial Advice on Trade Performance and Behavioral Biases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoechle, Daniel; Ruenzi, Stefan; Schaub, Nic; Schmid, Markus
We use a dataset from a large retail bank to examine the impact of financial advice on investors' stock trading performance and behavioral biases. Our data allow us to classify each individual trade as either advised or independent and to compare them in a trade-by-trade within-person analysis. Thus, our study is not plagued by the endogeneity problems typically faced by studies on financial advice. We document that advisors hurt trading performance. However, they help to reduce some of the behavioral biases retail investors are subject to, but this does not overcompensate the negative performance effects of the bad stock recommendations.</description><author>Hoechle, Daniel; Ruenzi, Stefan; Schaub, Nic; Schmid, Markus</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expectation Errors in European Value-Growth Strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Walkshaeusl, Christian
This article tests Piotroski and So's (2012) market expectation errors approach to value-growth investing in European equity markets. As in the USA, European value-growth returns are concentrated among firms with existent market expectation errors, but absent among firms without such errors which can be ex ante identified by interacting book-to-market with FSCORE, an accounting-based measure of the firm's fundamental strength. The returns to an expectation errors-based value-growth strategy are highly persistent for up to three years after portfolio formation, pervasive among large firms, and cannot be explained by common risk factors. However, consistent with a mispricing-based interpretation, prior external financing activities significantly influence these market expectation errors. A financing-based misvaluation factor can explain the return behavior of value-growth strategies formed along market expectations errors.</description><author>Walkshaeusl, Christian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jump and Volatility Dynamics for the S&amp;P 500: Evidence for Infinite-Activity Jumps with Non-Affine Volatility Dynamics from Stock and Option Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Hanxue; Kanniainen, Juho
Relatively little is known about the empirical performance of infinite-activity Levy jump models, especially with non-affine volatility dynamics. We use extensive empirical data sets to study how infinite-activity Variance Gamma and Normal Inverse Gaussian (NIG) jumps with affine and non-affine volatility dynamics improve goodness of fit and option pricing performance. With Markov Chain Monte Carlo, different model specifications are estimated using the joint information of the S&amp;P 500 index and the VIX. Our article provides clear evidence that a parsimonious non-affine model with NIG return jumps and a linear variance specification is particularly competitive, even during the recent crisis.</description><author>Yang, Hanxue; Kanniainen, Juho</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical Tests for Stochastic Dominance Optimality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Post, Thierry
If a given risky prospect is compared with multiple choice alternatives, then a joint test for optimality is more appropriate than a series of pairwise Stochastic Dominance tests. We develop and implement a bootstrap empirical likelihood ratio test for this hypothesis. The test statistic and implied probabilities can be computed by searching over discrete distributions that obey a system of linear inequalities using quasi-Monte Carlo simulation and convex optimization methods. An extension of the Kroll-Levy simulation experiment shows favorable small-sample properties for data sets of realistic dimensions. In an application to Fama-French stock portfolios, pairwise tests classify a portfolio of small growth stocks as admissible, whereas our test classifies the portfolio as significantly non-optimal for every risk averter.</description><author>Post, Thierry</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>News Dissemination and Investor Attention</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boulland, Romain; Degeorge, Francois; Ginglinger, Edith
We examine how investor attention changes when a firm adopts a modern news dissemination technology. We find that after continental European firms begin using an English-language electronic wire service to disseminate company news, they exhibit a stronger initial reaction to earnings surprises, a lower post earnings announcement stock price drift, and an increase in abnormal trading volume near earnings announcements, compared with when they disseminated their news in non-electronic format and in a continental European language. Our results hold for a sub-sample of firms for which the decision to use a wire service was likely exogenous. The effect of wire services on investor attention is due to the format of news (electronic and English-language), not to the increased speed of news transmission.</description><author>Boulland, Romain; Degeorge, Francois; Ginglinger, Edith</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do Dealers Buy High and Sell Low? An Analysis of Persistent Crossing in Extremely Segmented Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Atanasov, Vladimir; Merrick, John J.; Schuster, Philipp
We find that small buy trades of US agency mortgage-backed securities (MBS) are priced 3-8% lower than large sell trades. No such "crossing" exists in corporate bonds and agency debentures. We attribute the MBS price patterns to impediments to position aggregation in combination with investor suitability rules that disproportionately affect retail-sized trading and show in a model that classic market frictions cannot produce crossing. Our findings imply that valuations placed on securities affected by aggregation and suitability frictions should adjust for position size. Such securities include not only agency MBS, but also asset-backed securities, commercial mortgage-backed securities, collateralized mortgage obligations, collateralized loan obligations, and private-label residential mortgage-backed securities.</description><author>Atanasov, Vladimir; Merrick, John J.; Schuster, Philipp</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Security Trading on Corporate Restructurings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zachariadis, Konstantinos E.; Olaru, Ioan F.
Hedge funds are heavily involved in corporate restructurings. What makes their involvement distinct from other investors is that hedge funds can trade across the securities of a firm, holding either long or short positions in each security. We analyze the choice of a restructuring proposal by a firm's manager in the presence of a hedge fund as a potential investor in the firm. We show that, under certain market conditions, there is an equilibrium where the firm's manager makes a proposal for which a hedge fund finds it profitable to short-sell the equity of the firm, buy the debt of the firm, and via its debtholdings lead the firm to a value-reducing outcome to gain on its short equity position. The necessary and sufficient market conditions under which the aforementioned equilibrium occurs are that the debt and equity markets are segregated and that other traders in the equity market are net buyers on average.</description><author>Zachariadis, Konstantinos E.; Olaru, Ioan F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Financial Advisors Provide Tangible Benefits for Investors? Evidence from Tax-Motivated Mutual Fund Flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cici, Gjergji; Kempf, Alexander; Sorhage, Christoph
Rationality would suggest that advice-seeking investors receive benefits from costly financial advice. However, evidence documenting these benefits for US investors has so far been lacking. This article is the first to document that US mutual fund investors indeed receive one of the many previously hypothesized benefits associated with financial advice. The documented benefit comes from valuable tax-management advice that helps investors avoid taxable fund distributions and becomes even more valuable when investors face distributions that can cause large and hard-to-predict tax liabilities. Additional evidence suggests that financial advice helps with other aspects of tax management such as tax-loss selling.</description><author>Cici, Gjergji; Kempf, Alexander; Sorhage, Christoph</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fooled by Randomness: Investor Perception of Fund Manager Skill</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heuer, Justus; Merkle, Christoph; Weber, Martin
Return-chasing investors almost exclusively consider top-performing funds for their investment decisions. When drawing conclusions about the managerial skill of these top performers, they tend to neglect fund volatility and the cross-sectional information contained in the number of funds and the distribution of skill. In multiple surveys of sophisticated retail investors, we show that they do not fully understand the role of chance in experimental samples of fund populations. Respondents evaluate each fund in isolation and do not sufficiently account for fund volatility. They confuse risk taking with manager skill and are thus likely to over-allocate capital to lucky past winners.</description><author>Heuer, Justus; Merkle, Christoph; Weber, Martin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Speculative Trade in Market Efficiency: Evidence from a Betting Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Alasdair; Yang, Fuyu
Does speculative trade reduce mispricing and help create efficient markets or does it drive prices further from fundamentals? We analyze betting exchange trading on 9,562 UK horse races in 2013 and 2014 to find out. Crucially, as each race is run, the fundamental value of bets is unambiguously revealed. We find that the volume of trade is predictive of fundamentals, suggesting that speculative trade is on average conducive to market efficiency. However, much of this effect is concentrated in the in-running period during races when, even without trade, asset fundamentals would be revealed seconds later.</description><author>Brown, Alasdair; Yang, Fuyu</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum and Reversal: Does What Goes Up Always Come Down?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Conrad, Jennifer; Yavuz, M. Deniz
The stocks in a momentum portfolio, which contribute to momentum profits, do not experience significant subsequent reversals. Conversely, stocks that do not contribute to momentum profits over the intermediate horizon exhibit subsequent reversals. Merging these separate securities into a single portfolio causes momentum and reversal patterns to appear linked. Stocks with momentum can be separated from those that exhibit reversal by sorting on size and book-to-market equity ratio. Controlling for proxies for behavioral biases, market illiquidity, and macroeconomic factors does not affect our results.</description><author>Conrad, Jennifer; Yavuz, M. Deniz</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Resolving the Spanning Puzzle in Macro-Finance Term Structure Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bauer, Michael D.; Rudebusch, Glenn D.
Most existing macro-finance term structure models (MTSMs) appear incompatible with regression evidence of unspanned macro risk. This "spanning puzzle" appears to invalidate those models in favor of new unspanned MTSMs. However, our empirical analysis supports the previous spanned models. Using simulations to investigate the spanning implications of MTSMs, we show that a canonical spanned model is consistent with the regression evidence; thus, we resolve the spanning puzzle. In addition, direct likelihood-ratio tests find that the knife-edge restrictions of unspanned models are rejected with high statistical significance, though these restrictions have only small effects on cross-sectional fit and estimated term premia.</description><author>Bauer, Michael D.; Rudebusch, Glenn D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Ratings Across Asset Classes: A Long-Term Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornaggia, Jess N.; Cornaggia, Kimberly J.; Hund, John E.
We test whether ratings are comparable across asset classes. We examine default rates by initial rating, accuracy ratios, migration metrics, instantaneous upgrade and downgrade intensities, and rating changes over bonds' lives in multivariate regressions. These approaches reveal substantial and persistent differences across broad asset classes, as well as across subcategories of structured finance products. Our results are best explained by variation in rating agency incentives and variation in underlying risk profiles. We conclude that regulations requiring ratings to perform comparably across asset classes will prove difficult to enforce. We advocate instead a regulatory framework that better distinguishes risks and incentives across asset classes.</description><author>Cornaggia, Jess N.; Cornaggia, Kimberly J.; Hund, John E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Market Power and Firm Performance*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delis, Manthos D.; Kokas, Sotirios; Ongena, Steven
Does market power of banks affect firm performance? To answer this question we examine 25,236 syndicated loan facilities granted between 2000 and 2010 by 296 banks to 9,029 US non-financial firms. Accounting for both observed and unobserved bank and firm heterogeneity, we find that firms that were recently poorly performing obtain loans from banks with more market power. However, in the year after loan origination market power positively affects firm performance, but only if it is not too high. Our estimates thus suggest that bank market power can facilitate access to credit by poorly performing firms, yet at the same time also boosts the performance of the firms that obtain credit.</description><author>Delis, Manthos D.; Kokas, Sotirios; Ongena, Steven</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reference-Dependent Preferences and the Empirical Pricing Kernel Puzzle*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grith, Maria; Hardle, Wolfgang K.; Kratschmer, Volker
Supported by several recent investigations, the empirical pricing kernel (PK) puzzle might be considered as a stylized fact. Based on an economic model with reference dependent preferences for the financial investors, we emphasize a microeconomic view that explains the puzzle via state-dependent aggregate preferences. We also investigate how the shape of the PK estimated from option and stock market index returns changes in relation to the volatility risk premium.</description><author>Grith, Maria; Hardle, Wolfgang K.; Kratschmer, Volker</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Where the Risks Lie: A Survey on Systemic Risk*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benoit, Sylvain; Colliard, Jean-Edouard; Hurlin, Christophe; Perignon, Christophe
We review the extensive literature on systemic risk and connect it to the current regulatory debate. While we take stock of the achievements of this rapidly growing field, we identify a gap between two main approaches. The first one studies different sources of systemic risk in isolation, uses confidential data, and inspires targeted but complex regulatory tools. The second approach uses market data to produce global measures which are not directly connected to any particular theory, but could support a more efficient regulation. Bridging this gap will require encompassing theoretical models and improved data disclosure.</description><author>Benoit, Sylvain; Colliard, Jean-Edouard; Hurlin, Christophe; Perignon, Christophe</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relationship Lending in the Interbank Market and the Price of Liquidity*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brauning, Falk; Fecht, Falko
We empirically investigate the effect that relationship lending has on the availability and pricing of interbank liquidity. Our analysis is based on a daily panel of unsecured overnight loans between 1,079 distinct German bank pairs from March 2006 to November 2007, a period that includes the 2007 liquidity crisis that marked the beginning of the 2007-08 global financial crisis. We find that (i) relationship lenders are more likely to provide liquidity to their closest borrowers, (ii) particularly opaque borrowers obtain liquidity at lower rates when borrowing from their relationship lenders, and (iii) during the crisis, relationship lenders provided cheaper loans to their closest borrowers. Our results hold after controlling for search frictions as well as a large set of (time-varying) bank and bank-pair control variables and fixed effects. While we find some indication that lending relationships help banks reduce search frictions in the over-the-counter interbank market, our results establish that bank-pair relationships have a significant impact on interbank credit availability and pricing due to mitigating uncertainty about counterparty credit quality.</description><author>Brauning, Falk; Fecht, Falko</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance and Blockchains*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yermack, David
Blockchains represent a novel application of cryptography and information technology to age-old problems of financial record-keeping, and they may lead to farreaching changes in corporate governance. Many major players in the financial industry have began to invest in this new technology, and stock exchanges have proposed using blockchains as a new method for trading corporate equities and tracking their ownership. This essay evaluates the potential implications of these changes for managers, institutional investors, small shareholders, auditors, and other parties involved in corporate governance. The lower cost, greater liquidity, more accurate record-keeping, and transparency of ownership offered by blockchains may significantly upend the balance of power among these cohorts.</description><author>Yermack, David</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intertemporal Forecasts of Defaulted Bond Recoveries and Portfolio Losses*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalotay, Egon A.; Altman, Edward I.
Variation in the composition of the defaulted debt pool and credit conditions at the time of default generate time variation in the distribution of recoveries on defaulted debt, and the related distribution of losses on portfolios of credit sensitive debt. We quantify the importance of accounting for such time variation in out-of-sample comparisons of alternative approaches to forecasting recoveries or losses given default (LGD) on defaulted bonds. Using simulations of losses on defaultable bond portfolios, we show that conditional mixture models improve forecasts of expected credit losses through capturing time variation in the recovery/LGD distribution. However, the best forecasts of instrument or firm-level recovery/LGD do not necessarily provide the best forecasts of portfolio-level losses, as the latter depend on the association between errors in the default and recovery/LGD forecasts. Our systematic comparisons of cross-sectional and intertemporal forecasting performance are enabled by a fast maximum-likelihood approach to estimating conditional mixtures of distributions.</description><author>Kalotay, Egon A.; Altman, Edward I.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Performance Incentives and Firm Risk during Economic Expansions and Recessions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Savaser, Tanseli; Sisli-Ciamarra, Elif
We argue that the relationship between managerial pay-for-performance incentives and risk taking is pro-cyclical. We study the relationship between incentives provided by stock-based compensation and firm risk for US non-financial corporations over the two business cycles between 1992 and 2009. We show that a given level of pay-for-performance incentives results in significantly lower firm risk when the economy is in a downturn. The documented pro-cyclical relationship between incentives and risk taking is consistent with state-dependent risk aversion. Our findings contribute to the literature on the depressive effects of performance incentives on firm risk by documenting the importance of the interaction between performance incentives and risk aversion.</description><author>Savaser, Tanseli; Sisli-Ciamarra, Elif</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recovery with Unbounded Diffusion Processes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Walden, Johan
We analyze the problem of recovering the pricing kernel and real probability distribution from observed option prices, when the state variable is an unbounded diffusion process. We derive necessary and sufficient conditions for recovery. In the general case, these conditions depend on the properties of the diffusion process, but not on the pricing kernel. We also show that the same conditions determine whether recovery works in practice, when the continuous problem is approximated on a bounded or discrete domain without further specification of boundary conditions. Altogether, our results suggest that recovery is possible for many interesting diffusion processes on unbounded domains.</description><author>Walden, Johan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Revolving Door for Financial Regulators</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shive, Sophie A.; Forster, Margaret M.
We investigate the motivations and effects of financial firms' hiring of former US financial regulatory employees. The number of top executives with regulatory experience per firm has increased 24% over 2001-15, and hiring is associated with positive average announcement returns and a salary premium. In the quarter after hire, market and balance sheet measures of firm risk decrease significantly and measures of risk management activity increase, especially for hires from prudential regulators, who directly monitor financial firm risk. The absence of this result for unregulated firms and for exogenous shocks to regulatory experience suggests that firms hire ex-employees of their regulators when they perceive a need to reduce risk, consistent with a schooling hypothesis. We find little direct evidence of quid pro quo behavior in regulatory event frequency and fines.</description><author>Shive, Sophie A.; Forster, Margaret M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Disturbing Interaction between Countercyclical Capital Requirements and Systemic Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Horvath, Balint L.; Wagner, Wolf
We present a model in which flat (state-independent) capital requirements are undesirable because of shocks to bank capital. There is a rationale for countercyclical capital requirements that impose lower capital demands when aggregate bank capital is low. However, such capital requirements also have a cost as they increase systemic risk taking: by insulating banks against aggregate shocks (but not bankspecific ones), they create incentives to invest in correlated activities. As a result, the economy's sensitivity to shocks increases and systemic crises can become more likely. Capital requirements that directly incentivize banks to become less correlated dominate countercyclical policies as they reduce both systemic risk-taking and cyclicality.</description><author>Horvath, Balint L.; Wagner, Wolf</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-Ownership: A Device for Management Entrenchment?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, Marc; Szafarz, Ariane
By artificially inflating capital and creating own shares, cross-ownership can be a key device for managerial entrenchment. This article proposes a game-theoretical method to measure the extent of shareholder expropriation through cross-ownership. By properly accounting for cross-ownership linkages, we show how managers can seize indirect voting rights, and so insulate their firms from outside control. Significant examples of cross-ownership are found not only in civil law countries, but also in the US mutual fund industry. We apply our method to Germany's Allianz Group. This article paves the way to better regulatory appraisal of management entrenchment through cross-ownership.</description><author>Levy, Marc; Szafarz, Ariane</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Abusing ETFs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Loos, Benjamin; Meyer, Steffen; Hackethal, Andreas
Using data from a large German brokerage, we find that individuals investing in passive exchange-traded funds (ETFs) do not improve their portfolio performance, even before transaction costs. Further analysis suggests that this is because of poor ETF timing as well as poor ETF selection (relative to the choice of low-cost, well-diversified ETFs). An exploration of investor heterogeneity shows that though investors who trade more have worse ETF timing, no groups of investors benefit by using ETFs, and no groups will lose by investing in low-cost, well-diversified ETFs.</description><author>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Loos, Benjamin; Meyer, Steffen; Hackethal, Andreas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fund Performance and Equity Lending: Why Lend What You Can Sell?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Evans, Richard; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Prado, Melissa Porras
The dramatic increase in the percentage of mutual funds lending equities suggests that lending fees are an increasingly important source of income for investment advisors. We find that funds that lend equities underperform otherwise similar funds in spite of lending income. The effect of lending is concentrated in funds that cannot act on the short-selling signal due investment restrictions set by the fund family to diversify their fund offerings across styles. Our findings suggest that the family organization explains why fund managers lend, rather than sell, stocks with short selling demand.</description><author>Evans, Richard; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Prado, Melissa Porras</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incidence of Bank Levy and Bank Market Power (vol 1353, pg 1023, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Capelle-Blancard, Gunther; Havrylchyk, Olena
nan</description><author>Capelle-Blancard, Gunther; Havrylchyk, Olena</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>No Guts, No Glory: An Experiment on Excessive Risk-Taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eriksen, Kristoffer W.; Kvaloy, Ola
We study risk-taking behavior in tournaments where the optimal strategy is to take no risk. By keeping the optimal strategy constant, while varying the competitiveness in the tournaments, we are able to investigate the relationship between competitiveness and excessive risk-taking. In the most competitive tournament, less than 10% of the subjects played the optimal strategy in the first rounds. The majority playing dominated strategies increased their risk-taking during game of play. When we removed feedback about winner's decisions each round, and when we reduced the number of contestants in the tournaments, subjects significantly reduced their risk-taking.</description><author>Eriksen, Kristoffer W.; Kvaloy, Ola</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Age and Stock Price Crash Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andreou, Panayiotis C.; Louca, Christodoulos; Petrou, Andreas P.
We show that firms with younger CEOs are more likely to experience stock price crashes, including crashes caused by revelation of negative news in the form of breaks in strings of consecutive earnings increases. Such strings are accompanied by large increases in CEO compensation that do not dissipate with crashes. These findings suggest that CEOs have financial incentives to hoard bad news earlier in their career, which increases future crashes. This negative impact of CEO age effect is strongest in the presence of managerial discretion. Overall, the findings highlight the importance of CEO age for firm policies and outcomes.</description><author>Andreou, Panayiotis C.; Louca, Christodoulos; Petrou, Andreas P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>To What Extent Are Savings-Cash Flow Sensitivities Informative to Test for Capital Market Imperfections?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tsoukalas, John D.; Tsoukas, Serafeim; Guariglia, Alessandra
We construct a simple model with lumpy investment, cash accumulation, and costly external finance. Based on this model, we propose a new savings specification aimed at examining savings behavior in the presence of investment lumpiness and financial constraints. We then test a key prediction of our model, namely that under costly external finance, savings-cash flow sensitivities vary significantly by investment regime. We make use of a panel of firms from transition and developed economies to estimate the new savings regression which controls for investment spikes and periods of inactivity. Our findings confirm the validity of the model's prediction.</description><author>Tsoukalas, John D.; Tsoukas, Serafeim; Guariglia, Alessandra</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Add-on Pricing in Retail Financial Markets and the Fallacies of Consumer Education</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kosfeld, Michael; Schuewer, Ulrich
We analyze the consequences of consumer education on prices and welfare in retail financial markets when some consumers are naive about shrouded add-on prices and banks try to exploit this. Allowing for different information and pricing strategies we show that education is unlikely to push banks to full price disclosure, which would be efficient, but instead to a new equilibrium in which banks discriminate between consumer types. Welfare analysis reveals that education, while positive for consumers who learn to make better financial decisions, imposes a negative externality on other consumers when banks respond by setting higher prices. Overall, the welfare effects of consumer education can be negative. Our results identify important pitfalls policy makers should take into account when considering the seemingly harmless intervention of consumer education.</description><author>Kosfeld, Michael; Schuewer, Ulrich</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commodity Markets, Long-Run Predictability, and Intertemporal Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernandez-Perez, Adrian; Fuertes, Ana-Maria; Miffre, Joelle
This article shows that commodity portfolios that capture the backwardation and contango phases exhibit in-sample and out-of-sample predictive power for the first two moments of the distribution of long-horizon aggregate equity market returns, and for the business cycle. It also demonstrates that a pricing model based on the corresponding backwardation and contango risk factors explains relatively well a wide cross-section of equity portfolios. The cross-sectional "hedging" risk prices are economically consistent with the direction of long-horizon predictability. Backwardation and contango thus act as plausible investment opportunity state variables in the context of Merton's (1973) intertemporal capital asset pricing model.</description><author>Fernandez-Perez, Adrian; Fuertes, Ana-Maria; Miffre, Joelle</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hole in the Wall: Informed Short Selling Ahead of Private Placements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkman, Henk; McKenzie, Michael D.; Verwijmeren, Patrick
Companies planning a private placement typically gauge the interest of potential buyers before the offering is publicly announced. Regulators are concerned with this practice, called wall-crossing, as it might invite insider trading, especially when the potential investors are hedge funds. We examine privately placed common stock and convertible offerings and find evidence of widespread pre-announcement short selling. We show that pre-announcement short sellers are able to predict announcement day returns. The effects are especially strong when hedge funds are involved and when the number of buyers is high. We also observe pre-announcement trading in the options market.</description><author>Berkman, Henk; McKenzie, Michael D.; Verwijmeren, Patrick</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incidence of Bank Levy and Bank Market Power</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Capelle-Blancard, Gunther; Havrylchyk, Olena
We study the impact of banks' market power on the incidence of a bank levy that is imposed on balance sheets. Within the framework of an oligopolistic version of the Monti-Klein model, the pass-through of a bank tax levied on loans is stronger when elasticity of credit demand is low. To test this hypothesis, we investigate the incidence of the Hungarian bank tax that was introduced in 2010 on banks' assets. This case is well suited for our analysis because the tax rate is much higher for large banks than for small banks, which allows relying on difference-in-difference methodology. In line with model predictions, our estimations show that the tax is likely to be shifted to customers with the smallest demand elasticity, such as households. This result depends on the common trends assumption that is discussed at length.</description><author>Capelle-Blancard, Gunther; Havrylchyk, Olena</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond Variance Risk Premiums</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Hoyong; Mueller, Philippe; Vedolin, Andrea
This paper studies variance risk premiums in the Treasury market. We first develop a theory to price variance swaps and show that the realized variance can be perfectly replicated by a static position in Treasury futures options and a dynamic position in the underlying. Pricing and hedging is robust even in the underlying jumps. Using a large options panel data set on Treasury futures with different tenors, we report the following findings: First, the term structure of implied variances is downward sloping across maturities and increases in tenors. Moreover, the slope of the term structure is strongly linked to economic activity. Second, returns to the Treasury variance swap are negative and economically large. Shorting a variance swap produces an annualized Sharpe ratio of almost two and the associated returns cannot be explained by standard risk factors. Finally, the returns remain highly statistically significant even when accounting for transaction costs and margin requirements.</description><author>Choi, Hoyong; Mueller, Philippe; Vedolin, Andrea</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macro-Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cochrane, John H.
Macro-finance addresses the link between asset prices and economic fluctuations. Many models reflect the same rough idea: the market's ability to bear risk is greater in good times, and less in bad times. Models achieve this similar result by quite different mechanisms. I contrast their strengths and weaknesses. I highlight directions for future research, including additional facts to be matched, and limitations of the models that should prod future theoretical work. I describe how macro-finance models can fundamentally alter macroeconomics, by putting time-varying risk premiums and risk-bearing capacity at the center of recessions rather than variation in the interest rate and intertemporal substitution.</description><author>Cochrane, John H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Theory of Bank Illiquidity and Default with Hidden Trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Panetti, Ettore
How does the availability of alternative investment opportunities for banks' depositors affect the reaction of the banking system to aggregate liquidity shocks? And what are the implications, if any, for banking regulation? To answer these questions, I study a Diamond-Dybvig environment, where banks hedge against aggregate liquidity risk in the interbank market or default, and depositors borrow and lend in a hidden-bond market. In this framework, banks offer an endogenously incomplete contract, and default in equilibrium only when facing systemic liquidity risk. In this case, the allocation at default is inefficient, and countercyclical liquidity requirements are welfare-improving.</description><author>Panetti, Ettore</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Microfinance Banks and Financial Inclusion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Martin; Guin, Benjamin; Kirschenmann, Karolin
We examine how the geographical proximity to a microfinance bank affects financial inclusion. We study the expansion of the branch network of ProCredit banks in South-East Europe between 2006 and 2010. We report three main findings: First, ProCredit is more likely to open a new branch in areas with a large share of low-income households. Second, in locations where ProCredit opens a new branch the share of banked households increases more than in locations where it does not open a new branch. Third, this increase is particularly strong among low-income households, older households, and households which rely on transfer income.</description><author>Brown, Martin; Guin, Benjamin; Kirschenmann, Karolin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exporters' Exposures to Currencies: Beyond the Loglinear Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boudt, Kris; Liu, Fang; Sercu, Piet
We extend the constant-elasticity regression that is the default choice when equities' exposure to currencies is estimated. In a proper real-option-style model for the exporters' equity exposure to the foreign exchange rate, we argue, the convexity of the relationship implies that the elasticity should depend on the exchange rate level. For instance, it should shrink to zero when the option to export becomes worthless, and that should happen at a critical exchange rate that is still strictly positive. We propose a class of tractable multi-regime regression models featuring, in line with the real-options logic, smooth transitions and within-regime dynamics in the foreign exchange exposure. We then analyze the exchange rate exposure of Chinese exporting firms and find that the model in which the moneyness of the export option has a positive impact on the exchange rate exposure detects a significantly positive and convex exposure for 40% and 65% of the firms depending on whether the market return is included in the regression or not.</description><author>Boudt, Kris; Liu, Fang; Sercu, Piet</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sparse Weighted-Norm Minimum Variance Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yen, Yu-Min
We propose to impose a weighted l(1) and squared l(2) norm penalty on the portfolio weights to improve out-of-sample (OOS) performances of portfolio optimization when the number of assets becomes large. We show that under certain conditions, the realized risk of the optimal minimum variance portfolio (MVP) obtained from the strategy can asymptotically be lower than those of benchmark portfolios with a high probability. Our theoretical results imply that penalty parameters for the weighted-norm penalty can be specified as a simple function of the number of assets and sample size. With the theoretical results, we also develop an automatic calibration procedure for choosing the penalty parameters. We demonstrate superior OOS performances of the weighted-norm MVP with two real data sets. Finally, we propose several alternative norm penalties and show that their OOS performances are comparable to the weighted-norm strategy.</description><author>Yen, Yu-Min</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local Ownership, Crises, and Asset Prices: Evidence from US Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Laeven, Luc
We exploit the domestic portfolios of US mutual funds to provide microeconomic evidence that investors are more likely to liquidate geographically remote investments at times of high aggregate market volatility. This has important implications for asset prices. The valuations of stocks with ex ante less local ownership decline more when aggregate market volatility is high. Furthermore, the returns of stocks with geographically distant owners are more exposed to changes in aggregate market volatility.</description><author>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Laeven, Luc</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is There a "Boom Bias" in Agency Ratings?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dilly, Mark; Mahlmann, Thomas
Theory predicts rating agencies' incentive conflicts to be stronger in boom periods, leading to biased ratings and a reduced level of rating quality. We investigate this prediction empirically based on three different approaches. First, we show that initial ratings disagree with bond spread levels during boom periods in the way that rating agencies hold a systematically more optimistic view. Second, we reveal that boom bond ratings tend to be more heavily downgraded from an ex post perspective; and, third, we demonstrate that boom ratings are inflated compared with "conflicts-free" benchmark ratings. In several robustness tests we show that the observed "boom bias" does not result from changes in credit-worthiness, adjustments in rating standards, competitive pressure, or market supply, but rather from rating agencies' incentive conflicts.</description><author>Dilly, Mark; Mahlmann, Thomas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Making, Buying, and Concurrent Sourcing: Implications for Operating Leverage and Stock Beta</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lambrecht, Bart M.; Pawlina, Grzegorz; Teixeira, Joao C. A.
We present a real options model of a firm's make-or-buy decision under demand uncertainty. "Making" is subject to decreasing returns to scale, fixed costs, and capital investment. "Buying" happens at a fixed price and requires no investment. Three distinct procurement regimes endogenously arise: buying, making, or concurrent sourcing for, respectively, low, intermediate, and high demand. Capital constraints encourage buying or concurrent sourcing. Operating leverage peaks when the firm switches between buying and making, and it is lowest (and negative) at the switch between making and concurrent sourcing. This non-monotonic pattern mirrors and drives the behavior of the firm's beta.</description><author>Lambrecht, Bart M.; Pawlina, Grzegorz; Teixeira, Joao C. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Do Stock Markets Tell Us about Exchange Rates?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cenedese, Gino; Payne, Richard; Sarno, Lucio; Valente, Giorgio
The sign of the correlation between equity returns and exchange rate returns can be positive or negative in theory. Using data for a broad set of forty-two countries, we find that exchange rate movements are in fact unrelated to differentials in country-level equity returns. Consequently, a trading strategy that invests in countries with the highest expected equity returns and shorts those with the lowest generates substantial returns and Sharpe ratios. These returns partially reflect compensation for global equity volatility risk, but significant excess returns remain after controlling for exposure to standard risk factors.</description><author>Cenedese, Gino; Payne, Richard; Sarno, Lucio; Valente, Giorgio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Scale and Performance in Private Equity Investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dyck, A.; Pomorski, L.
We document that defined benefit pension plans with significant holdings in private equity (PE) earn substantially greater returns than plans with small holdings, in both the 1990s and the 2000s. A one standard deviation increase in PE holdings is associated with 4% greater returns per year. Up to one-third of this outperformance comes from lower costs that we link to economizing on costly intermediation by avoiding fund-of-funds and investing directly. The bulk of the outperformance comes from superior gross returns only partially explained by access and experience. We conjecture that larger PE investors have superior due diligence and ability to bridge information asymmetries in PE.</description><author>Dyck, A.; Pomorski, L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing Deflation Risk with US Treasury Yields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christensen, Jens H. E.; Lopez, Jose A.; Rudebusch, Glenn D.
We use an arbitrage-free term structure model with spanned stochastic volatility to determine the value of the deflation protection option embedded in Treasury inflation-protected securities. The model accurately prices the deflation protection option prior to the financial crisis when its value was near zero; at the peak of the crisis in late 2008 when deflationary concerns spiked sharply; and in the post-crisis period. During 2009, the average value of this option at the 5-year maturity was 41 basis points on a par-yield basis. The option value is shown to be closely linked to overall market uncertainty as measured by the VIX, especially during and after the 2008 financial crisis.</description><author>Christensen, Jens H. E.; Lopez, Jose A.; Rudebusch, Glenn D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Performance of Market Timing Measures in a Simulated Environment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chretien, Stephane; Coggins, Frank; d'Amours, Felix
Using simulations controlling for the ability to time the equity, bond, and money markets, we compare daily and monthly performance measures. Our main results highlight the joint importance of the fictitious timer's trading frequency and the data sampling frequency for estimation. Specifically, daily timing measures are superior to those estimated monthly for daily timers, but inferior for occasional or monthly timers. Global measures show more robustness to differences in trading and data sampling frequencies. Finally, conditional measures do not improve upon unconditional ones, and results are similar for performance detection versus ranking.</description><author>Chretien, Stephane; Coggins, Frank; d'Amours, Felix</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Attribution Using the Shapley Value: Methodology and Policy Applications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tarashev, Nikola; Tsatsaronis, Kostas; Borio, Claudio
We present the Shapley Value as a methodology for risk attribution and use it to derive measures of banks' systemic importance. The methodology possesses attractive properties, such as fairness and efficiency. It also leads naturally to a framework for the analysis of different drivers of systemic importance: bank size, bank-specific risk, and the commonality of banks' exposures. We prove that, all else equal, an increase in bank size leads to a more than proportional increase in systemic importance. We also show how alternative applications of the Shapley Value methodology can be used in designing policy tools with system-wide objectives.</description><author>Tarashev, Nikola; Tsatsaronis, Kostas; Borio, Claudio</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>It Hurts (Stock Prices) When Your Team is about to Lose a Soccer Match</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ehrmann, Michael; Jansen, David-Jan
The end result of major sporting events has been shown to affect next day stock returns through shifts in investor mood. By studying intraday data during the soccer matches that led to the elimination of France and Italy from the 2010 FIFA World Cup, we test whether mood-related pricing effects already materialize as events unfold. We use data for a cross-listed firm, which allows for a straightforward identification of underpricing. During the matches, the firm's stock is underpriced by up to 7 basis points in the country that eventually loses. The probability of underpricing increases as elimination becomes more likely.</description><author>Ehrmann, Michael; Jansen, David-Jan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Growth and Idiosyncratic Return Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Song, Zhongzhi
This article studies the empirical relationship between firms' asset growth and idiosyncratic stock return volatility. In the cross-section, firms' idiosyncratic return volatility is V-shaped with respect to their lagged asset growth rates: the volatility is higher for firms with extreme (either high or low) asset growth rates than for firms with moderate growth rates. In the time series, a higher dispersion across firms in asset growth rates predicts a higher average idiosyncratic return volatility. Moreover, the dispersion in asset growth rates has the strongest time series predictive power among alternative explanations of the average idiosyncratic return volatility, such as cash flow volatility and growth options. These findings indicate the importance of nonlinearity in studying the cross-sectional return volatility and provide a new explanation of the idiosyncratic return volatility that is significant in both the cross-section and the time series.</description><author>Song, Zhongzhi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Tail Risk Priced in Credit Default Swap Premia?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Meine, Christian; Supper, Hendrik; Weiss, Gregor N. F.
We show that the propensity of a bank to experience extreme co-movements in its credit default swap (CDS) premia together with the market is priced in the bank's default swap spread during the financial crisis. We measure a bank's CDS tail beta by estimating the upper tail dependence between its default swap spreads and a CDS market index. Our study shows that protection sellers receive a premium for bearing the risk of extreme upward co-movements in default risk. The economic significance of this effect is large yet limited to the recent financial crisis. Banks in the upper quintile of CDS tail beta have spreads that are on average 140 basis points higher than those of banks in the lower CDS tail beta quintile.</description><author>Meine, Christian; Supper, Hendrik; Weiss, Gregor N. F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Processing and Non-Bayesian Learning in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schraeder, Stefanie
Ample empirical and experimental evidence documents that individuals place greater weight on information gained through personal experience-a phenomenon that Tversky and Kahneman call availability bias. I embed this bias in an overlapping generations equilibrium model in which the period that investors first enter the market establishes the starting point of their experience history. The difference in the individuals' experience leads to heterogeneity among agents and perceived noise trading. The model captures several empirical findings. It explains why returns on high-volume trading days tend to revert. Furthermore, it provides explanations for a high trading volume, a connection between trading volume and volatility, excess volatility, and overreaction and reversal patterns. Consistent with empirical evidence, young investors buy high and sell low, trade frequently, and obtain lower returns. For intraday trading, it predicts a high trading volume around the opening hours, especially for cross-listed stocks.</description><author>Schraeder, Stefanie</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Fraction and the Equilibrium Term Structure of Equity Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marfe, Roberto
The recent empirical evidence of a downward-sloping term structure of equity risk is viewed as a challenge to many leading asset pricing models. This article analytically characterizes conditions under which a continuous-time long-run risk model can accommodate the stylized facts about dividend and equity risk, when dividends are a stationary stochastic fraction of aggregate consumption. Such a cointegrating relation not only makes dividends riskier in the short run than at medium horizons but also preserves the role of long-run risk: consequently, the model captures both the traditional puzzles, like the high equity premium, as well as the new evidence about the term structure of equity risk.</description><author>Marfe, Roberto</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transparency, Tax Pressure, and Access to Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellul, Andrew; Jappelli, Tullio; Pagano, Marco; Panunzi, Fausto
More transparent firms enjoy better access to finance, and also enable closer scrutiny by tax authorities and thus face a heavier tax burden, insofar as they are required to report the same data to tax authorities and investors (book-tax conformity). We study this trade-off in a model with distortionary taxes and finance rationing, and test its predictions on an international dataset. As predicted, firms facing low corporate tax rates choose high transparency, particularly if they are not very dependent on external funding. This result is confirmed by the evidence from statutory tax reforms: reductions of corporate tax rates are followed by increases in firm transparency. Moreover, firms choose higher transparency in countries with high audit quality. Investment is positively correlated with transparency, especially for firms more dependent on external finance. Results are stronger in countries with book-tax conformity.</description><author>Ellul, Andrew; Jappelli, Tullio; Pagano, Marco; Panunzi, Fausto</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Sector Reform after the Subprime Crisis: Has Anything Happened?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schaefer, Alexander; Schnabel, Isabel; di Mauro, Beatrice Weder
We analyze the reactions of stock returns and the spreads of credit default swaps (CDS) of banks from Europe and the USA to four major regulatory reforms in the aftermath of the subprime crisis, employing an event study analysis. Contrary to public perception, we find that financial markets indeed reacted to the structural reforms enacted at the national level. The reforms succeeded in reducing bail-out expectations relative to the post-bail-out period, especially for systemic banks. The strongest effects were found for the Dodd-Frank Act and in particular for the Volcker rule. Bank profitability was affected in all countries, showing up in lower equity returns.</description><author>Schaefer, Alexander; Schnabel, Isabel; di Mauro, Beatrice Weder</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bondholder Concentration and Credit Risk: Evidence from a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Manconi, Alberto; Massa, Massimo; Zhang, Lei
We exploit the impact of hurricane Katrina on insurance companies to study the relationship between bondholder concentration and credit risk. Redemption-driven sales by property and casualty (re)insurance companies exposed to hurricane Katrina are associated with a large drop in bondholder concentration faced by corporate bond issuers. Exploiting this shock to capture exogenous variation in bondholder concentration, we find that greater bondholder concentration is associated with higher bond yield spreads, as well as with firm characteristics associated with credit risk.</description><author>Manconi, Alberto; Massa, Massimo; Zhang, Lei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Stock-Financed Acquisitions Destroy Value? New Methods and Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golubov, Andrey; Petmezas, Dimitris; Travlos, Nickolaos G.
We contribute to the debate on whether stock-financed acquisitions destroy value for shareholders. A stock-financed acquisition is a joint takeover/equity-issue event. Using seasoned equity offering announcement returns, we estimate through linear prediction and propensity-score matching the share price drop that stock acquirers experience due to the financing choice. Net of this effect, stock-financed acquisitions are not value destructive, and the method of payment generally has no further explanatory power in the cross-section of acquirer returns. Our evidence is largely inconsistent with the agency costs of overvalued equity hypothesis.</description><author>Golubov, Andrey; Petmezas, Dimitris; Travlos, Nickolaos G.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Presentation and Portfolio Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bateman, Hazel; Eckert, Christine; Geweke, John; Louviere, Jordan; Satchell, Stephen; Thorp, Susan
Efficient investment of personal savings depends on clear risk disclosures. We study the propensity of individuals to violate some implications of expected utility under alternative "mass-market" descriptions of investment risk, using a discrete choice experiment. We found violations in around 25% of choices, and substantial variation in rates of violation, depending on the mode of risk disclosure and participants' characteristics. When risk is described as the frequency of returns below or above a threshold we observe more violations than for range and probability-based descriptions. Innumerate individuals are more likely to violate expected utility than those with high numeracy. Apart from the very elderly, older individuals are less likely to violate the restrictions. The results highlight the challenges of disclosure regulation.</description><author>Bateman, Hazel; Eckert, Christine; Geweke, John; Louviere, Jordan; Satchell, Stephen; Thorp, Susan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predisclosure Accumulations by Activist Investors and Price Impact of Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mihov, Atanas
This study presents novel, robust evidence on the effect of price impact of trading, or Kyle's lambda, on activist hedge funds' predisclosure ownership accumulations.(1) We find that hedge fund investors are less likely to target illiquid firms; upon targeting an illiquid firm, activists choose private transactions to limit the price impact of their trades; upon doing open market transactions, the activist investors buy more shares of those firms with liquid stock. Our study suggests that market impact can be a factor with significant implications for shareholder activism, and more generally, corporate governance.</description><author>Mihov, Atanas</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Credit Default Swap Trading on Loan Syndication</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Streitz, Daniel
We analyze the impact of credit default swap (CDS) trading on bank syndication activity. Theoretically, the effect of CDS trading is ambiguous: on the one hand, CDS can improve risk-sharing and hence be a more flexible risk management tool than loan syndication; on the other hand, CDS trading can reduce bank monitoring incentives. We document that banks are less likely to syndicate loans and retain a larger loan fraction once CDS are actively traded on the borrower's debt. We then discern the risk management and the moral hazard channel. We find no evidence that the reduced likelihood to syndicate loans is a result of increased moral hazard problems.</description><author>Streitz, Daniel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Investment over the Business Cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dangl, Thomas; Wu, Youchang
The average capital growth rate across firms declines sharply during a recession, and recovers only slowly. We provide a micro-founded explanation for this and several new stylized facts of investment asymmetry. Our investment model features various degrees of reversibility, cyclical macroeconomic shocks, and uncertainty about the state of the economy. Model simulations replicate strikingly different empirical patterns of capital growth rates at the aggregate and firm levels, featuring no slope asymmetry and a positive level asymmetry at the firm level, negative slope and level asymmetries at the aggregate level, and a positive relation between the industry-level slope asymmetry and asset illiquidity.</description><author>Dangl, Thomas; Wu, Youchang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting the Risk-Neutral Approach to Optimal Policyholder Behavior: A Study of Withdrawal Guarantees in Variable Annuities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moenig, Thorsten; Bauer, Daniel
Policyholder exercise behavior presents an important risk factor for pricing Variable Annuities. However, approaches presented in the literature-building on value-maximizing strategies akin to pricing American options-do not square with observed price and exercise patterns for popular withdrawal guarantees. We show that including taxes into the valuation closes this gap between theory and practice. In particular, we develop a subjective risk-neutral valuation methodology that takes into consideration differences in the tax structure between investment opportunities. We demonstrate that accounting for tax advantages significantly affects the value of the guarantees and produces results that are in line with empirical patterns.</description><author>Moenig, Thorsten; Bauer, Daniel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Active Flows and Passive Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, Ariel; Lieberman, Offer
The positive relationship between money flows into investment products and their return performance is an important market indicator for market practitioners and academics. This article studies the impact that active versus passive investment styles have on this relationship. We further evaluate the effects of a passive approach in two crucial stages: portfolio selection and asset allocation. We find that a passive investment style in either stage weakens the relationship between flows and returns compared with an active style. However, the investment style in the asset allocation stage has a greater effect than in the portfolio selection stage, on the relationship between flows and returns.</description><author>Levy, Ariel; Lieberman, Offer</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intertemporal Substitution and Equity Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Wei
This article presents a model that incorporates habit formation and long-run risks into the Epstein-Zin preferences, and reveals intertemporal substitution as a distinctive channel, separate from risk aversion, in generating key asset market phenomena. With habit formation, both the risk aversion and intertemporal substitution channels enhance the market price of short-run consumption risk. With long-run risks, intertemporal substitution reduces the market prices of long-run consumption risks, working against risk aversion. The contrasting effects of the intertemporal substitution channel drive key differences in the model implications of habit formation and long-run risks.</description><author>Yang, Wei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulatory Oversight and Return Misreporting by Hedge Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dimmock, Stephen G.; Gerken, William C.
We use Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) rule changes to show that regulatory oversight reduces return misreporting by hedge funds. Specifically, we use a 2004 rule change that expanded SEC oversight of hedge funds and the 2006 revocation of this rule. Differences-in-differences tests show that, following the rule change, misreporting by newly regulated funds decreased. After revocation, funds that exited the regulatory system increased misreporting relative to funds that remained registered. Placebo tests show no change in misreporting by foreign funds exempt from the rule change. We show that regulatory oversight increased the level of flows and decreased the sensitivity of flows to underperformance.</description><author>Dimmock, Stephen G.; Gerken, William C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Share Repurchase Announcement Puzzle: Theory and Evidence*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Jacobsen, Stacey E.
Why is the mere announcement of an open-market share repurchase program, which involves no commitment to purchase shares, regarded as good news by the market? We develop a theoretical model to resolve this puzzle. The model predicts that firms with large underpricing can attract attention from speculators by announcing repurchases, and the subsequent trades from these speculators lead to value corrections. Firms with small underpricing, however, cannot attract attention by announcing repurchases, and these firms have to use costly share repurchases as a value-correcting signal. We then provide empirical evidence corroborating the predictions of the theoretical model.</description><author>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Jacobsen, Stacey E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Alphabetic Bias, Investor Recognition, and Trading Behavior*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobs, Heiko; Hillert, Alexander
Extensive research has revealed that alphabetical name ordering tends to provide an advantage to those positioned in the beginning of an alphabetical listing. This article is the first to explore the implications of this alphabetic bias in financial markets. We find that US stocks that appear near the top of an alphabetical listing have about 5-15% higher trading activity and liquidity than stocks that appear toward the bottom. The magnitude of these results is negatively related to firm visibility and investor sophistication. International evidence and fund flows further indicate that ordering effects can affect trading activity and liquidity.</description><author>Jacobs, Heiko; Hillert, Alexander</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bubbling with Excitement: An Experiment*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrade, Eduardo B.; Odean, Terrance; Lin, Shengle
Anecdotal and indirect empirical evidence suggest that excitement and market bubbles are intertwined, such that excitement not only arises during bubbles but may also help fuel them. We directly test the impact of excitement on bubbles in a bubble-prone experimental asset-pricing market (Capinalp, Porter, and Smith, 2001). Prior to trading, participants are assigned to emotion inductions through video clips The results of fifty-five markets show larger asset pricing bubbles in magnitude and amplitude in the excitement treatment relative to a treatment of same valence and lower intensity (calm) and a treatment of similar intensity and opposite valence (fear).</description><author>Andrade, Eduardo B.; Odean, Terrance; Lin, Shengle</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Hidden Peril: The Role of the Condo Loan Market in the Recent Financial Crisis*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit; Deng, Yongheng; Luo, Chenxi; Qian, Wenlan
This article studies the condominium loan market, which experienced a 15-fold increase in origination and constituted 15% of the overall residential loan originations from 2001 to 2007. Condominium loan defaults grow at a faster rate than single-family (including subprime) loan defaults. Further analysis suggests that the greater default level and growth rate in later loan cohorts are consistent with the investor channel explanation: investor borrowers default more, especially when house prices start to decline. We also show that condo defaults have triggered more defaults of the same cohort subprime mortgages at the same location.</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; Deng, Yongheng; Luo, Chenxi; Qian, Wenlan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International Sourcing and Capital Structure*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eun, Cheol S.; Wang, Lingling
Motivated by the rising importance of international sourcing by US firms in recent decades, we study the influence of international sourcing on capital structure. We find that international sourcing has a significant negative influence on financial leverage. The negative influence is stronger in industries that have high R&amp;D intensities and are financially constrained. However, the negative relation is mitigated when suppliers are from countries with strong legal environments and when the supplier markets are more competitive. Overall, our findings suggest that relationship-specific investments, supplier market characteristics, and financial market conditions are key determinants of the sourcing-leverage relation.</description><author>Eun, Cheol S.; Wang, Lingling</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Post-Retirement Benefit Plans and Leverage*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartram, Soehnke M.
Defined benefit pension and health care plans are important for firm leverage around the world. While consolidating off-balance sheet post-retirement plans increases effective leverage by 32%, firms reduce their level of regular debt by only 22 cents for every dollar of projected benefit obligation, yielding overall 23% higher total leverage of plan sponsors compared with similar firms without post-retirement plans. The most important driver of substitution rates between regular debt and post-retirement obligations is rule of law, followed by labor market freedom and taxes. In contrast, pension guarantee funds and priority of unfunded pension obligations are less important for substitution rates.</description><author>Bartram, Soehnke M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>ABCs of Trading: Behavioral Biases affect Stock Turnover and Value*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Itzkowitz, Jennifer; Itzkowitz, Jesse; Rothbort, Scott
Psychological research suggests that individuals are satisficers. That is, when confronted with a large number of options, individuals often choose the first acceptable option, rather than the best possible option (Simon, 1957). Given the vast quantity of information available and the widespread convention of listing stocks in alphabetical order, we conjecture that investors are more likely to buy and sell stocks with early alphabet names. Consistent with this view, we find that early alphabet stocks are traded more frequently than later alphabet stocks and that alphabeticity also affects firm value. We also document how these effects have changed over time.</description><author>Itzkowitz, Jennifer; Itzkowitz, Jesse; Rothbort, Scott</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Bank Boards Prevent Misconduct?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nguyen, Duc Duy; Hagendorff, Jens; Eshraghi, Arman
We study regulatory enforcement actions issued against US banks to show that both board monitoring and advising are effective in preventing misconduct by banks. While better monitoring by boards prevents all categories of misconduct, better advising prevents misconduct of a technical nature. Board monitoring increases the likelihood that misconduct is detected, increases the penalties imposed on the CEO, and alleviates shareholder wealth losses following the detection of misconduct by regulators. Our article offers novel insights on how to structure bank boards to prevent bank misconduct.</description><author>Nguyen, Duc Duy; Hagendorff, Jens; Eshraghi, Arman</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reputation and Loan Contract Terms: The Role of Principal Customers*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cen, Ling; Dasgupta, Sudipto; Elkamhi, Redouane; Pungaliya, Raunaq S.
Principal customers have strong incentives to screen and/or monitor suppliers to ensure supply-chain stability; consequently, the implicit certification from the existence of long-term relationships with principal customers has reputational consequences that potentially spill over to other markets. We argue that one such consequence is smaller loan spreads and looser loan covenants on bank loans, as firms that are able to hold on to principal customers longer are perceived as safer firms by banks. We address causality and endogeneity issues via a variety of tests and find consistent results. Our study suggests that non-financial stakeholders can have important effects on the decisions of financial stakeholders.</description><author>Cen, Ling; Dasgupta, Sudipto; Elkamhi, Redouane; Pungaliya, Raunaq S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rollover Risk and Credit Spreads: Evidence from International Corporate Bonds*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Valenzuela, Patricio
Using a new dataset on corporate bonds placed in international markets by emerging and developed borrowers, this article demonstrates that a high proportion of short-term debt exacerbates the effect of debt market illiquidity on corporate bond spreads. This effect is present during both periods of financial stability and of financial distress, and it is smaller in the banking sector than in other sectors. The article's major finding is robust when controlling for potential endogeneity. Moreover, the results are consistent with the predictions of structural credit risk models that argue that a higher proportion of short-term debt increases a firm's exposure to debt market illiquidity through a "rollover risk" channel.</description><author>Valenzuela, Patricio</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investors' Interacting Demand and Supply Curves for Common Stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dierker, Martin; Kim, Jung-Wook; Lee, Jason; Morck, Randall
Complete limit order data from Korea show individual stocks' demand and supply elasticities correlating negatively in short windows. That is, whenever a stock's demand is unusually elastic, its supply is unusually inelastic, and vice versa. However, in long windows, individual stocks' demand and supply elasticities correlate positively. Notably, both fall about 40% with the 1997 Asian Financial Crisis, and remain depressed long after the market and macroeconomic variables recover. A parsimonious model explains both findings with investor information heterogeneity and risk-aversion parameters, fixed in the short-run, being permanently shifted by the crisis.</description><author>Dierker, Martin; Kim, Jung-Wook; Lee, Jason; Morck, Randall</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Savings and Consumption When Children Move Out</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rottke, Simon; Klos, Alexander
We show, using data from the Italian Survey on Household Income and Wealth and the German Socio-economic Panel, that household consumption drops after a child moves out of a household, while at the same time adult-equivalent consumption increases significantly. After all children are gone, parents upgrade their personal lifestyle to a level approximately that of childless peers, and save only a small proportion of the freed-up resources. Since parents had fewer resources to save while they were young, retirement preparedness among them is a more serious concern than among childless individuals.</description><author>Rottke, Simon; Klos, Alexander</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intraday Share Price Volatility and Leveraged ETF Rebalancing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shum, Pauline; Hejazi, Walid; Haryanto, Edgar; Rodier, Arthur
Regulators and market participants are concerned about leveraged exchange-traded funds (ETFs)' role in driving up end-of-day volatility through hedging activities near the market's close. Leveraged ETF providers counter that the funds are too small to make a meaningful impact on volatility. For the period surrounding the financial crisis, 2006-11, we show that end-of-day volatility was positively and statistically significantly correlated with the ratio of potential rebalancing trades to total trading volume. The impacts were not all economically significant, but largest during the most volatile days. Given the predictable pattern of leveraged ETF hedging demands, implications for predatory trading are explored.</description><author>Shum, Pauline; Hejazi, Walid; Haryanto, Edgar; Rodier, Arthur</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>"Whatever it takes": An Empirical Assessment of the Value of Policy Actions in Banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fiordelisi, Franco; Ricci, Ornella
What types of policy intervention had a greater impact during the financial crisis? By using a detailed dataset of worldwide policy, we answer this question focusing on Global Systemically Important banks (G-SIBs), looking both to stock returns and Credit Default Swap (CDS) spreads reactions. As robustness checks, we also analyze a control sample of 31 large Non-Financial Companies (NFCs). Overall, we show that different policy interventions from governments and central banks have produced diverse market reactions: investors generally appreciate monetary policy interventions for G-SIBs (but not for NFCs) and do not welcome bank failures and bailouts (for both G-SIBs and NCFs).</description><author>Fiordelisi, Franco; Ricci, Ornella</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Better than Expected: The Hidden Dynamic of Variable Annuity Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, Massimo; Yadav, Vijay
We study how variable annuity affiliation affects fund performance. We find that VA-affiliated funds outperform pure open-end funds by about 70 basis points four-factor alpha per year in case of actively managed US equity funds. We argue that affiliation with a variable annuity wrapper increases the ability of investors to compare performance of funds offered within the same wrapper. This increases the competitive pressure among fund families. We explain the superior performance of VA-affiliated funds in terms of self-selection: only the better funds are chosen by fund families to be part of insurance wrappers.</description><author>Massa, Massimo; Yadav, Vijay</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Home Bias, an Academic Puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karolyi, G. Andrew
Only 16% (23%) of all empirical studies published in the top four (fourteen) Finance journals examine non-US markets, a fraction that is well below measures reflecting their economic importance. This "home bias" measure fluctuates across years with a weakly declining trend. There is also a "foreign bias" in which some non-US countries are more frequently the subject of published papers than others. I am able to explain only a small fraction of either the home-bias or the foreign-bias puzzles. Surprisingly, there are on average 2.01 higher annual cumulative citations per non-US paper published relative to cohort-matched US-focused papers.</description><author>Karolyi, G. Andrew</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Non-Exclusive Financial Advice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Piccolo, Salvatore; Puopolo, Giovanni W.; Vasconcelos, Luis
We propose a simple model of non-exclusive financial advice in which two households rely on a self-interested (common) expert to make their investment choices. There is only one source of risk, and the expert is privately informed about the risky asset's volatility. When monetary transfers are unenforceable, we show that investors may delegate their investment decisions to the expert. When doing so, however, they impose restrictions on her choices which crucially depend on whether the expert perceives investors' asset allocations as complements or as substitutes. Finally, we analyze the implications of non-exclusivity in financial advice on investment behavior and welfare, and highlight a set of novel testable implications.</description><author>Piccolo, Salvatore; Puopolo, Giovanni W.; Vasconcelos, Luis</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Leverage Ratio and Capital Requirements with Limited Regulatory Power</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Ho-Mou; Zhao, Yue
This article discusses the optimal leverage ratio and capital requirements when asymmetric information exists between the bank and the regulator. We show that the optimal requirements take different forms in the short and long run. In either case, imposing the risk-weighted capital requirement without considering the incentives of the bank to misreport its risk profile is never optimal by itself. In the long run, the optimal requirements take the form of a leverage ratio requirement on top of the risk-weighted capital requirement. The add-on leverage ratio requirement, which serves as a compensation for the limited supervisory power of the regulators, should be set such that the risk-taking behavior of the bank is unchanged from the situation in which the regulator uses the risk-weighted capital requirement alone, and the misreporting incentive of the bank is eliminated by the add-on leverage ratio requirement.</description><author>Wu, Ho-Mou; Zhao, Yue</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rushing into the American Dream? House Prices Growth and the Timing of Homeownership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit; Hu, Luojia; Huang, Xing
We use the New York Fed Consumer Credit Panel data set to empirically examine how past house price growth influences the timing of homeownership. We find that the median individual in metropolitan areas with the highest quartile house price growth becomes a homeowner 5 years earlier than that in areas with the lowest quartile house price growth. The result is consistent with a life cycle housing-demand model in which high past price growth increases expectations of future price growth thus accelerating home purchases at young ages. We show that extrapolative expectations formed by homebuyers are a necessary channel to explain the result.</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; Hu, Luojia; Huang, Xing</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>