<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>RF1</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Banking and Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boot, Arnoud W. A.; Ratnovski, Lev
We study the interaction between relationship banking and short-term arm's length activities of banks, called trading. We show that a bank can use the franchise value of its relationships to expand the scale of trading, but may allocate too much capital to trading ex post, compromising its ability to build relationships ex ante. This effect is reinforced when trading is used for risk shifting. Overall, combining relationship banking and trading offers benefits under small-scale trading, but distortions may dominate when trading is unbridled. This suggests that trading by banks, while benign historically, might be distortive with deeper financial markets.</description><author>Boot, Arnoud W. A.; Ratnovski, Lev</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Outsourcing and Financing Decisions in Industry Equilibrium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kanatas, George; Qi, Jianping
In a competitive product market, firms that buy their input have lower profit volatility than they would have if they were to make it. This effect on profit volatility is an important consideration in the firms' capital structure choices and their make or buy decisions when it interacts with the risk-taking incentive of equityholders of levered firms. Even with a cost advantage enjoyed by a supplier and passed on to its customers, in an industry equilibrium of a priori identical firms, only those that use little or no debt outsource their input to the supplier; all significantly debt-financed firms produce their own input and take advantage of the greater profit volatility resulting from internal production.</description><author>Kanatas, George; Qi, Jianping</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>R&amp;D Spillover and Predictable Returns*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Yi; Qian, Yiming; Yao, Tong
We show that firms' R&amp;D activities can predict the stock returns of their industry peers. When an industry experiences substantial R&amp;D growth driven by the activities of a small group of firms, industry peers experience positive abnormal returns and abnormal operating performance despite having no aggressive R&amp;D growth. Exogenous industry shocks to demand or productivity do not explain these results. Further, abnormal returns are concentrated in peer firms that receive low investor attention.</description><author>Jiang, Yi; Qian, Yiming; Yao, Tong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Say Pays! Shareholder Voice and Firm Performance*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cunat, Vicente; Gine, Mireia; Guadalupe, Maria
This article estimates the effects of Say-on-Pay (SoP), a policy that increases shareholder "voice" by providing shareholders with a regular vote on executive pay. We apply a regression discontinuity design to the votes on shareholder-sponsored SoP proposals. Adopting SoP leads to large increases in market value (5%) and to improvements in long-term profitability. In contrast, it has limited effects on pay levels and structure. Taken together our results suggest that SoP can be seen as a repeated regular vote of confidence on the CEO and that it serves as a disciplining device.</description><author>Cunat, Vicente; Gine, Mireia; Guadalupe, Maria</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign Investor Heterogeneity and Stock Liquidity around the World*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ng, Lilian; Wu, Fei; Yu, Jing; Zhang, Bohui
This article examines whether foreign investor heterogeneity plays a role in stock liquidity in a sample of 27,828 firms from thirty-nine countries worldwide. Foreign direct ownership is negatively associated with stock liquidity, while foreign portfolio ownership is positively associated with stock liquidity. Consistent with theoretical predictions, foreign ownership explains stock liquidity through both trading activity and information channels. The value-enhancing benefits of foreign direct investors' monitoring efforts outweigh their liquidity costs and high adverse selection premium. However, the positive impact of foreign portfolio ownership on firm performance becomes negative and is not robustly significant after controlling for liquidity.</description><author>Ng, Lilian; Wu, Fei; Yu, Jing; Zhang, Bohui</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer Bankruptcy, Bank Mergers, and Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Jason; Damar, H. Evren; Martinez-Miera, David
This article analyzes the relationship between consumer bankruptcy patterns and the destruction of soft information caused by mergers. Using a major Canadian bank merger as a source of exogenous variation in local banking conditions, we show that local markets affected by the merger exhibit an increase in consumer bankruptcy rates post-merger. The evidence is consistent with the most plausible mechanism being the disruption of consumer-bank relationships. Markets affected by the merger show a decrease in the merging institutions' branch presence and market share, including those stemming from higher switching rates. We rule out alternative mechanisms such as changes in quantity of credit, loan rates, or observable borrower characteristics.</description><author>Allen, Jason; Damar, H. Evren; Martinez-Miera, David</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Firm Bankruptcy and Contagion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Helwege, Jean; Zhang, Gaiyan
The Lehman bankruptcy highlights the potential for interconnectedness to cause negative externalities through counterparty contagion, but the externalities may also arise from information contagion. We examine troubled financial firms and find that both channels are significant factors in creating spillover effects. Counterparty contagion is greater in cases of riskier firms and larger and more complex exposures. However, the counterparty exposures are small, especially among banks that face diversification regulations, and do not typically cause a cascade of failures. Information contagion is stronger for rivals in the same markets and has a larger impact in cases of distress than in bankruptcies.</description><author>Helwege, Jean; Zhang, Gaiyan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The "CAPS" Prediction System and Stock Market Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avery, Christopher N.; Chevalier, Judith A.; Zeckhauser, Richard J.
We study approximately 5.0 million stock picks submitted by individual users to the "CAPS" website run by the Motley Fool company ( ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.caps.fool.com"&gt;www.caps.fool.com). These picks prove to be surprisingly informative about future stock prices. Shorting stocks with a disproportionate number of negative picks and buying stocks with a disproportionate number of positive picks yields a return of over 12% per annum over the sample period. Negative picks mostly drive these results; they strongly predict future stock price declines. Returns to positive picks are statistically indistinguishable from the market. A Fama-French decomposition suggests that stock-picking rather than style factors largely produced these results.</description><author>Avery, Christopher N.; Chevalier, Judith A.; Zeckhauser, Richard J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fund Tournaments and Asset Bubbles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sato, Yuki
This article studies how fund managers' relative-performance concerns affect their investment strategies in bubble periods. The managers compete for flows that are sensitive to their performance ranking. Severe ranking tournaments with highly convex flow-performance relationship lead managers to ride bubbles to outperform each other, making bubbles long-lived. However, moderate tournaments may lead them to attack bubbles quickly. The results are consistent with the observed cross-sectional variation in funds' investment strategies in bubble periods. Bubble-riding behavior is pronounced if the funds' tournament is too close to call, as interim followers try to catch up while interim leaders try to stay ahead.</description><author>Sato, Yuki</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Experimental Examination of Portfolio Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ackert, Lucy F.; Church, Bryan K.; Qi, Li
Investors do not hold optimal portfolios. We use an experimental method to isolate factors that compel individuals to hold optimal portfolios. Our design includes two risky assets with perfectly negatively correlated payoffs so that all risk can be eliminated. We find that participants' holdings approach optimal portfolios only under very specific conditions: the variance cost of holding an imbalanced portfolio is substantial and feedback on period-by-period outcomes is suppressed (eliminating the impact of cognitive biases resulting from misperceptions of randomness).</description><author>Ackert, Lucy F.; Church, Bryan K.; Qi, Li</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Can Margin Requirements Increase Volatility and Benefit Margin Constrained Investors?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Yajun
We propose a tractable equilibrium model to examine how margin requirements affect asset prices, market volatility, and market participants' welfare. We show that margin requirements can have opposite effects on market volatility when they constrain different investors and thus can help explain why empirical results have been mixed. Contrary to one of the main regulatory goals, we find that even though margin requirements restrict borrowing and shorting, they can significantly increase market volatility. In addition, margin requirements can make margin constrained investors better off and can lead to a greater return reversal. Our analysis also provides new empirically testable implications.</description><author>Wang, Yajun</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment in Relationship-Specific Assets: Does Finance Matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Strieborny, Martin; Kukenova, Madina
Banks (but not stock markets) promote economic growth by facilitating relationship-specific investment between buyers and suppliers of intermediate goods. Combined insights from literature on signaling role of banks and on relationship-specific investment motivate this economic channel: A supplier is reluctant to undertake relationship-specific investment as she cannot observe financial stability and planning horizon of buyer. Banks can mitigate this information asymmetry. Empirical results from twenty-eight industries in ninety countries confirm that industries dependent on relationship-specific investment from their suppliers grow disproportionately faster in countries with a well-developed banking sector. The channel works via increased entry of new firms and higher capital accumulation.</description><author>Strieborny, Martin; Kukenova, Madina</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Changing Risk Perception and the Time-Varying Price of Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fuess, Roland; Gehrig, Thomas; Rindler, Philipp B.
This article investigates the impact of changes in risk perception on bond markets triggered by the 2007-08 financial crisis. Using a methodology novel to empirical finance, we quantify the increase in credit spreads caused by changes in risk pricing and changes in risk factors. The lasting increase in credit spreads is almost exclusively due to time-varying prices of risk. We interpret this as a change in risk perception which provides a possible solution to the credit spread puzzle. Default premia spiked during the crisis and did not return to their pre-crisis levels. Liquidity premia increased during and after the crisis.</description><author>Fuess, Roland; Gehrig, Thomas; Rindler, Philipp B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Pressures on UK Real Rates: An Empirical Investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zinna, Gabriele
We assess the impact of institutional investors' demand for gilts on UK real rates by structurally estimating the model of Vayanos and Vila (2009). We therefore include those investors believed to display inelastic demand for gilts and preferences for longer-term maturities. The estimated model fits the term structure of real rates well, and strongly supports our choice of institutional investors. These investors' demand contributed to the decline in medium- to longer-term real rates by compressing bond risk premia. However, the price impact varied across investors and over time, and was only partly attenuated by increased supply.</description><author>Zinna, Gabriele</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Note on Event Studies in Finance and Management Research</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>de Jong, Abe; Naumovska, Ivana
Event studies are a common research method in finance and management research. This note argues that the validity of inferences based on announcement effects hinges critically on controls for confounding events and appropriate statistical tests. We present a unique case where data is available for a replication of two key event studies. Specifically, we examine and show the importance of systematic confounding information on findings of the effect of corporate name changes on stock market reactions. We demonstrate that systematic confounding events are critical challenges when testing theories about investors' reactions in finance and management research.</description><author>de Jong, Abe; Naumovska, Ivana</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real Costs of Financial Efficiency When Some Information Is Soft</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex; Heinle, Mirko S.; Huang, Chong
This article shows that improving financial efficiency may reduce real efficiency. While the former depends on the total amount of information available, the latter depends on the relative amounts of hard and soft information. Disclosing more hard information (e.g., earnings) increases total information, raising financial efficiency and reducing the cost of capital. However, it induces the manager to prioritize hard information over soft by cutting intangible investment to boost earnings, lowering real efficiency. The optimal level of financial efficiency is non-monotonic in investment opportunities. Even if low financial efficiency is desirable to induce investment, the manager may be unable to commit to it. Optimal government policy may involve upper, not lower, bounds on financial efficiency.</description><author>Edmans, Alex; Heinle, Mirko S.; Huang, Chong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Liquidity Regulation on Bank Intermediation*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bonner, Clemens; Eijffinger, Sylvester C. W.
We analyze the impact of a requirement similar to the Basel III Liquidity Coverage Ratio on the bank intermediation applying Regression Discontinuity Designs. Using a unique dataset on Dutch banks, we show that a liquidity requirement causes long-term borrowing and lending rates as well as demand for long-term interbank loans to increase. Lower levels of aggregate liquidity increase the estimated effects. Short-term borrowing and lending rates only rise during periods of lower market-wide liquidity. Further, banks do not seem able to pass on the increased funding costs in the interbank market to their private sector clients. Rather, a liquidity requirement seems to decrease banks' interest margins.</description><author>Bonner, Clemens; Eijffinger, Sylvester C. W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Capital and the Viability of Stakeholder-Oriented Firms: Evidence from Savings Banks*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ostergaard, Charlotte; Schindele, Ibolya; Vale, Bent
We show that social capital improves the viability of stakeholder-oriented firms operating in competitive markets. Studying exits from the population of Norwegian savings banks after deregulations, we find that banks located in communities with high social capital have a higher probability of survival, but no similar effect exists for commercial banks. Norwegian savings banks are collectively governed by their stakeholders and we provide evidence that social capital improves the efficiency of stakeholder governance. In high social capital areas, banks raise more deposits locally, distribute more of their surplus for altruistic purposes, and operate more locally focused branch networks.</description><author>Ostergaard, Charlotte; Schindele, Ibolya; Vale, Bent</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Good Monitoring, Bad Monitoring*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grinstein, Yaniv; Rossi, Stefano
Are courts effective monitors of corporate decisions? In a controversial landmark case, the Delaware Supreme Court held directors personally liable for breaching their fiduciary duties, signaling a sharp increase in Delaware's scrutiny over corporate decisions. In our event study, low-growth Delaware firms outperformed matched non-Delaware firms by 1% in the three day event window. In contrast, high-growth Delaware firms under-performed by 1%. Contrary to previous literature, we conclude that court decisions can have large, significant and heterogeneous effects on firm value, and that rules insulating directors from court scrutiny benefit the fastest growing sectors of the economy.</description><author>Grinstein, Yaniv; Rossi, Stefano</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Speculative Trading and Stock Returns*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pan, Li; Tang, Ya; Xu, Jianguo
Using data from Chinese stock markets, we examine the effect of speculative trading on stock returns. We develop a volume-related variable, abnormal turnover ratio (ATR), by isolating speculative trading from liquidity and other components in trading volume. After a group of tests verifying that ATR indeed represents speculative trading, we show that ATR negatively predicts future stock returns. The average monthly return spread between the top and bottom ATR deciles is -1.87%, suggesting a highly significant negative ATR premium. The return predictability of ATR survives after controlling for common risk factors and event-driven information shocks. These findings indicate that speculative trading affects asset prices.</description><author>Pan, Li; Tang, Ya; Xu, Jianguo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Short-Sale Costs Affect Put Options Trading? Evidence from Separating Hedging and Speculative Shorting Demands*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Tse-Chun; Lu, Xiaolong
We find that put options trading volume and bid-ask spreads both increase with equity lending fees. However, we also find that put options trading volume decreases with lending fees for banned stocks during the 2008 Short-Sale Ban period, when only options market makers could short. By separating the speculative demand of short sellers from the hedging demand of options market makers in the lending market, our results provide a thorough analysis of the interaction between the options market and the equity lending market. We also shed light on the substitutability/complementarity between put options volume and short interest shown in the literature.</description><author>Lin, Tse-Chun; Lu, Xiaolong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lend Global, Fund Local? Price and Funding Cost Margins in Multinational Banking*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Galema, Rients; Koetter, Michael; Liesegang, Caroline
In a proposed model of a multinational bank, interest margins determine local lending by foreign affiliates and the internal funding by parent banks. We exploit detailed parent-affiliate-level data of all German banks to empirically test our theoretical predictions in pre-crisis times. Local lending by affiliates depends negatively on price margins, the difference between lending and deposit rates in foreign markets. The effect of funding cost margins, the gap between local deposit rates faced by affiliates abroad and the funding costs of their parents, on internal capital market funding is positive but statistically weak. Interest margins are central to explain the interaction between internal capital markets and foreign affiliates lending.</description><author>Galema, Rients; Koetter, Michael; Liesegang, Caroline</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International Firm Investment under Exchange Rate Uncertainty*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jeanneret, Alexandre
This article develops a real options theory to examine the effects of exchange rate uncertainty on foreign direct investment. Firms face a choice between participating in foreign markets through exports or investing abroad to relocate production. The model predicts that the most productive firms invest abroad when exchange rate volatility is low and export otherwise, whereas the least productive firms invest abroad when volatility is high. Aggregation over heterogeneous firms produces a negative and nonlinear relation between exchange rate uncertainty and total international investment. An analysis of eighty-four developed and emerging economies over the 1996-2012 period provides empirical support for the model's predictions.</description><author>Jeanneret, Alexandre</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutions, Bailout Policies, and Bank Loan Contracting: Evidence from Korean Chaebols</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Minetti, Raoul; Yun, Sung-Guan
In emerging economies, institutional and regulatory constraints can distort loan contracting and, hence, the incentives of lenders and borrowers. Studying the South Korean syndicated loan market, we find that during the 90s the safety net protecting business groups (chaebols)-especially the government's bailout policy-affected the structure and pricing of loans to chaebol firms. However, after the chaebol reform of the late 90s dismantled the chaebol safety net, the differences in loan contracts between chaebol and non-chaebol firms narrowed or disappeared. The results suggest that the reform restored lenders' incentives to monitor chaebol firms and properly assess their risk.</description><author>Minetti, Raoul; Yun, Sung-Guan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Out-of-Sample Evaluation of Dynamic Portfolio Strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lan, Chunhua
This article evaluates out-of-sample portfolio performance for a real-time investor who can exploit time variation in the conditional mean and volatility of stock returns in optimizing a multiperiod portfolio choice problem. With the presence of parameter uncertainty, our out-of-sample analysis shows that ignoring time variation in the first two return moments leads to significant utility costs of at least 1.97% of annualized certainty equivalent return. Accounting for the time-varying risk premium plays a more important role than considering time-varying volatility in improving portfolio performance. Interestingly, behaving myopically or ignoring the hedge against changes in future investment opportunities can lead to small out-of-sample utility losses or even utility gains.</description><author>Lan, Chunhua</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Aging and Takeover Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loderer, Claudio; Waelchli, Urs
Although growth opportunities fade and profitability declines as firms mature, older firms are no more likely to be acquired than young firms are. This article documents and explains that phenomenon. We argue that, because mature organizations are rationally less flexible, they are more costly to integrate and therefore comparatively unattractive acquisition candidates. The evidence supports this explanation of the negative age dependence of takeover hazard. The evidence also shows that negative exogenous shocks to merger benefits further reduce the takeover hazard of mature firms. We test many alternative explanations and find no evidence that they can explain the hazard decline.</description><author>Loderer, Claudio; Waelchli, Urs</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Implied Risk Exposures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benoit, Sylvain; Hurlin, Christophe; Perignon, Christophe
We show how to reverse-engineer banks' risk disclosures, such as value-at-risk, to obtain an implied measure of their exposures to equity, interest rate, foreign exchange, and commodity risks. Factor implied risk exposures are obtained by breaking down a change in risk disclosure into a market volatility component and a bank-specific risk exposure component. In a study of large US and international banks, we show that (i) changes in risk exposures are negatively correlated with market volatility and (ii) changes in risk exposures are positively correlated across banks, which is consistent with banks exhibiting commonality in trading.</description><author>Benoit, Sylvain; Hurlin, Christophe; Perignon, Christophe</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive Compensation and Risk Taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Patrick; Mehran, Hamid; Shapiro, Joel
This article studies the connection between risk taking and executive compensation in financial institutions. A model of shareholders, debtholders, depositors, and an executive demonstrates that (i) excess risk taking can be addressed by basing compensation on both stock price and the credit default swaps (CDS) spread, (ii) shareholders may not be able to commit to design such contracts, and (iii) they may not want to due to distortions from deposit insurance or unobservable tail risk. The advantage of using the CDS spread rather than deferred compensation or debt is due to the fact that it is a market price and reduces agency costs.</description><author>Bolton, Patrick; Mehran, Hamid; Shapiro, Joel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Relationships and the Limits to Arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kondo, Jiro E.; Papanikolaou, Dimitris
We propose a model of limited arbitrage based on financial relationships. Financially constrained arbitrageurs may choose to seek additional financing from banks that have the technology to profit from the strategies themselves. A holdup problem arises because banks cannot commit to providing capital. To minimize competition, arbitrageurs will choose to stay constrained and underinvest in the arbitrage unless banks have sufficient reputational capital. This problem arises when mispricing is largest. More competition among financiers, higher arbitrageur wealth, and allowing for explicit contracts can worsen the holdup problem. When arbitrage is risky, financial relationships are more valuable, mitigating the problem.</description><author>Kondo, Jiro E.; Papanikolaou, Dimitris</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stakeholder Governance, Competition, and Firm Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Franklin; Carletti, Elena; Marquez, Robert
We analyze the strengths and weaknesses of stakeholder and shareholder firms in a model of imperfect competition. Stakeholder firms are more concerned with avoiding bankruptcy to protect their employees and suppliers. In equilibrium, they are more valuable than shareholder firms when marginal cost uncertainty exceeds demand uncertainty. With globalization shareholder firms and stakeholder firms often compete. We identify the circumstances where stakeholder firms are more valuable than shareholder firms and compare these mixed equilibria with the pure equilibria with stakeholder and shareholder firms only. Finally, we analyze firm financial constraints and derive implications for the capital structure of stakeholder firms.</description><author>Allen, Franklin; Carletti, Elena; Marquez, Robert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Markets with Ethical Banks and Motivated Borrowers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barigozzi, Francesca; Tedeschi, Piero
We investigate the corporate social responsibility of banks. Lenders offer loans to standard and motivated borrowers who undertake either standard or ethical projects. Standard banks have no restriction on the types of projects for which they can provide a loan. Ethical banks, instead, commit to financing only ethical projects, which have social profitability but lower expected revenues. Motivated borrowers are keen to invest in ethical projects and to deal with ethical banks. When they are active, ethical banks increase social welfare because the matching of ethical lenders with motivated borrowers reduces the frictions caused by the agency issue.</description><author>Barigozzi, Francesca; Tedeschi, Piero</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Risk and Competition: Evidence from Regional Banking Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kick, Thomas; Prieto, Esteban
We investigate the bank competition-stability nexus based on a unique regulatory dataset. First, we use outright bank defaults, and control for a wide array of different time-varying bank characteristics which are likely to influence the nexus. Second, we simultaneously include measures of competition and market power corresponding to the bank, county, and federal state level. Third, we investigate the role of bank competition in the transmission of monetary policy to bank risk. From a policy perspective, our findings indicate that competition-reducing regulation does not necessarily enhance either the stability of individual banks or their resilience to monetary policy shocks.</description><author>Kick, Thomas; Prieto, Esteban</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Weather on German Retail Investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schmittmann, Jochen M.; Pirschel, Jenny; Meyer, Steffen; Hackethal, Andreas
We explore the impact of weather on trading by individual investors. Over a time span of 94 months, we analyze daily trading records of individual investors. Controlling for various investor- and market-specific factors, we find a two-fold effect of weather. We first observe that investor sentiment, as measured by purchases relative to sales, is significantly higher on days with good weather. In addition, we find that retail investors generally trade more on bad weather days. This result is consistent with the notion that retail investors incur an opportunity cost for spending time trading on days with good weather.</description><author>Schmittmann, Jochen M.; Pirschel, Jenny; Meyer, Steffen; Hackethal, Andreas</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed Headquarters and Socialistic Internal Capital Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoang, Daniel; Ruckes, Martin
This article develops a theory of resource allocation in internal capital markets that is consistent with the empirical finding that multidivision firms bias their investment levels in favor of divisions with weaker investment prospects. Headquarters has private information about the capital productivities of its divisions; therefore, capital allocations in the present serve as a signal to divisional managers about future allocations. To facilitate effort provision, headquarters biases capital allocation so as to not disclose productivity differences across divisions or to credibly signal their absence. The capital allocation bias is time-varying and the relationship between the bias and the difference in average division productivities is inversely U-shaped.</description><author>Hoang, Daniel; Ruckes, Martin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning about Rare Disasters: Implications For Consumption and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gillman, Max; Kejak, Michal; Pakos, Michal
Rietz (1988) and Barro (2006) subject consumption and dividends to rare disasters in the growth rate. We extend their framework and subject consumption and dividends to rare disasters in the growth persistence. We model growth persistence by means of two hidden types of economic slowdowns: recessions and lost decades. We estimate the model based on the postwar US data using maximum likelihood and find that it can simultaneously match a wide array of dynamic pricing phenomena in the equity and bond markets. The key intuition for our results stems from the inability to discriminate between the short and the long recessions ex ante.</description><author>Gillman, Max; Kejak, Michal; Pakos, Michal</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Improving Investment Decisions with Simulated Experience</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bradbury, Meike A. S.; Hens, Thorsten; Zeisberger, Stefan
We apply a new and innovative approach to communicating risks associated with financial products that should support investors in making better investment decisions. In our experiments, participants are able to gain "simulated experience" by random sampling of a previously described return distribution. We find that simulated experience considerably improves participants' understanding of the underlying risk-return profile and prompts them to reconsider their investment decisions and to choose riskier financial products without regretting their higher risk-taking behavior afterwards. This method of experienced-based learning has high potential for being integrated into real-world applications and services.</description><author>Bradbury, Meike A. S.; Hens, Thorsten; Zeisberger, Stefan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Funding Versus Real Economy Shock: The Impact of the 2007-09 Crisis on Small Firms' Credit Availability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berg, Gunhild; Kirschenmann, Karolin
We analyze how banks adjust their lending to small firms after distinct shocks from the cross-border transmission of the 2007-09 crisis by using unique loan application and contract data from AccessBank Azerbaijan. These data allow us to disentangle the effects of a funding shock from the effects of a real shock. Contrary to conventional assumptions, we find that the funding shock works through reduced prospecting-as opposed to tightened lending standards-and leads to fewer loan applications among new applicants in particular, which improves the borrower pool. The real economy shock instead works through loan approval and affects small and medium enterprise rather than micro borrowers.</description><author>Berg, Gunhild; Kirschenmann, Karolin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jump-Diffusion Long-Run Risks Models, Variance Risk Premium, and Volatility Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jin, Jianjian
This article calibrates a class of jump-diffusion long-run risks models and quantifies how well they can account for both equity and variance risk premiums while generating realistic volatility dynamics. I find that jumps in the level and the volatility of long-run consumption growth rates perform equally well in explaining the variance risk premium. Moreover, compared to jump-in-growth models, jump-in-volatility models generate more realistic volatility dynamics and stronger predictability of returns by the variance risk premium. Finally, both jump-in-volatility and jump-in-growth models suggest that a nontrivial portion of the equity risk premium is due to compensation for jump risks.</description><author>Jin, Jianjian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling the Dynamics of Correlations among Implied Volatilities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engle, Robert; Figlewski, Stephen
Implied volatility (IV) reflects both expected empirical volatility and also risk premia. Stochastic variation in either creates unhedged risk in a delta hedged options position. We develop EGARCH/DCC models for the dynamics of volatilities and correlations among daily IVs from options on twenty-eight large cap stocks. The data strongly support a general correlation structure and also a one-factor model with the VIX index as the common factor. Using IVs from stocks that are either highly correlated with the target stock's IV or in the same industry together with the VIX can significantly improve hedging of individual IV changes.</description><author>Engle, Robert; Figlewski, Stephen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing Measures of Order Flow Toxicity and Early Warning Signals for Market Turbulence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andersen, Torben G.; Bondarenko, Oleg
Following the "flash crash" on May 6, 2010, warning signals for impending market stress have been in high demand, yet only the VPIN metric of Easley, Lopez de Prado, and O'Hara (ELO) has claimed success. In addition, ELO find the metric useful in predicting short-term volatility. VPIN involves decomposing volume into active buys and sells. We utilize quotes and trade data to construct an accurate trade classification measure for E-mini S&amp;P 500 futures. Against this benchmark, the ELO Bulk Volume Classification (BVC) scheme is inferior to a standard tick rule. Moreover, VPIN predicts volatility solely because increasing volatility induces systematic classification errors in the BVC procedure. We conclude that VPIN is unsuitable for capturing order flow toxicity or signaling ensuing market turbulence.</description><author>Andersen, Torben G.; Bondarenko, Oleg</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systemic Risk in Europe*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engle, Robert; Jondeau, Eric; Rockinger, Michael
Systemic risk may be defined as the propensity of a financial institution to be undercapitalized when the financial system as a whole is undercapitalized. In this article, we investigate the case of non-US institutions, with several factors explaining the dynamics of financial firms returns and with asynchronicity of time zones. We apply this methodology to the 196 largest European financial firms and estimate their systemic risk over the 2000-12 period. We find that, for certain countries, the cost for the taxpayer to rescue the riskiest domestic banks is so high that some banks might be considered too big to be saved.</description><author>Engle, Robert; Jondeau, Eric; Rockinger, Michael</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary Policy, Risk-Taking, and Pricing: Evidence from a Quasi-Natural Experiment*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ioannidou, Vasso; Ongena, Steven; Peydro, Jose-Luis
We study the risk-taking channel of monetary policy in Bolivia, a dollarized country where monetary changes are transmitted exogenously from the USA. We find that a lower policy rate spurs the granting of riskier loans, to borrowers with worse credit histories, lower ex-ante internal ratings, and weaker ex-post performance (acutely so when the rate subsequently increases). Effects are stronger for small firms borrowing from multiple banks. To uniquely identify risk-taking, we assess collateral coverage, expected returns, and risk premia of the newly granted riskier loans, finding that their returns and premia are actually lower, especially at banks suffering from agency problems.</description><author>Ioannidou, Vasso; Ongena, Steven; Peydro, Jose-Luis</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>China's Pseudo-monetary Policy*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deng, Yongheng; Morck, Randall; Wu, Jing; Yeung, Bernard
China's monetary stimulation after the global financial crisis rapidly boosted its GDP. We argue that its efficacy derives from state control over its banking and corporate sectors. Beijing ordered state-owned banks to lend and they lent. Beijing ordered centrally-controlled state-owned enterprises (SOEs) to invest and they invested. Our data show much of this investment was highly leveraged purchases of real estate and land prices rises occurred where these SOEs were active buyers. This episode mimics the credit channel for monetary policy, but actually entails internal transfers between arms of the government pressuring on real estate prices upwards.</description><author>Deng, Yongheng; Morck, Randall; Wu, Jing; Yeung, Bernard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Optimization Using Forward-Looking Information*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kempf, Alexander; Korn, Olaf; Sassning, Sven
We develop a new family of estimators of the covariance matrix that relies solely on forward-looking information. It uses only current prices of plain-vanilla options. In an out-of-sample study, we show that a minimum variance strategy based on these fully-implied estimators outperforms several benchmark strategies, including various strategies based on historical estimates, index investing, and 1/N investing. The outperformance originates in crisis periods when information flow and information asymmetry are high. Although the historical benchmark strategies improve when more recent data are used, they never outperform fully-implied strategies. Thus, our results suggest that investors are better off relying on forward-looking information.</description><author>Kempf, Alexander; Korn, Olaf; Sassning, Sven</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium Predictability, Term Structure of Equity Premia, and Other Return Characteristics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hore, Satadru
This article presents a structural model of aggregate return characteristics based on a one-channel Bansal and Yaron (2004) economy under recursive preferences. The results rest on an endogenously determined price-dividend ratio that is not exponentially affine, which implies time-variation and predictability of equity premia. The predictability coefficient itself is stochastic. This provides theoretical foundations for recent works in predictability like Dangl and Halling (2011). In longer horizons, the predictability relationship is highly volatile making it difficult to make inferences about long-horizon predictability.</description><author>Hore, Satadru</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recession Prediction Using Yield Curve and Stock Market Liquidity Deviation Measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erdogan, Oral; Bennett, Paul; Ozyildirim, Cenktan
This article extends the benchmark Estrella and Hardouvelis term spread approach to recession forecasting by including the stock market macro liquidity deviation factor. We use a probit framework to predict recessions, as defined by the NBER between 1959Q1 and 2011Q4. We find that combining the yield curve parameter with the stock market liquidity deviation significantly improves our ability to predict the onset of a US recession, based both on in-sample and out-of-sample tests. In addition, changes in stock market depth further increase the accuracy of the model. We suggest that economic forecasters and those charged with conducting economic stabilization policy more generally would benefit from monitoring not only the yield curve but also stock market depth and liquidity, and their deviation from one another.</description><author>Erdogan, Oral; Bennett, Paul; Ozyildirim, Cenktan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumption Volatility and the Cross-Section of Stock Returns*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tedongap, Romeo
I derive and test multi-horizon implications of a consumption-based equilibrium model featuring fluctuating expected growth and volatility. My setup allows consumption dynamics to be estimated jointly with covariance risk prices in a single-stage generalized method of moment, and then inferences from asset pricing tests reflect uncertainty coming from factor estimation. I show that changes in consumption volatility are the key driver for explaining major asset pricing anomalies across risk horizons, while other factors play no or a secondary role. Value stocks and past long-term losers pay higher average returns mainly because they covary more negatively with these changes than what other stocks do.</description><author>Tedongap, Romeo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Engagement and Stock Market Participation*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Changwony, Frederick K.; Campbell, Kevin; Tabner, Isaac T.
We investigate the separate and joint influences of social engagement measures on stock market participation and find that socially engaged individuals are more likely to participate. Consistent with Granovetter's theory of social networks we find that a weak tie (measured by social group involvement) has a positive effect on stock market participation whereas a strong tie (measured by frequency of talking to neighbors) has no effect. More trusting individuals are more likely to participate in the stock market, as are those who identify with a political party. In contrast, the degree to which religion is important appears to have little impact.</description><author>Changwony, Frederick K.; Campbell, Kevin; Tabner, Isaac T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insuring Nonverifiable Losses*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doherty, Neil A.; Laux, Christian; Muermann, Alexander
Insurance contracts are often complex and difficult to verify outside the insurance relation. We show that standard one-period insurance policies with an upper limit and a deductible are the optimal incentive-compatible contracts in a competitive market with repeated interaction. Optimal group insurance policies involve a joint upper limit and individual deductibles; insurance brokers can play a role implementing such contracts for their clients. Our model provides new insights and predictions about the determinants of insurance.</description><author>Doherty, Neil A.; Laux, Christian; Muermann, Alexander</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Cross-Trading in the US Stock Market*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pasquariello, Paolo; Vega, Clara
We model and test for the role of heterogeneously informed, strategic multi-asset speculation for cross-price impact-the impact of trades in one asset on the prices of other (even unrelated) assets-in the U.S. stock market. Our investigation of the trading activity in New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) and National Association of Securities Dealers Automated Quotation System (NASDAQ) stocks between 1993 and 2004 reveals that, consistent with our model, (1) daily order imbalance in one industry or random stock has a significant, persistent, and robust impact on daily returns of other (even unrelated) industries or random stocks; (2) cross-price impact is often negative; and (3) both direct (i.e., an asset's own) and absolute (i.e., unsigned) cross-price impact are smaller when speculators are more numerous, greater when market-wide dispersion of beliefs is higher, and greater among stocks dealt by the same specialist.</description><author>Pasquariello, Paolo; Vega, Clara</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Depositors' Perception of "Too-Big-to-Fail"*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oliveira, Raquel De F.; Schiozer, Rafael F.; Barros, Lucas A. B. De C.
We exploit the exogenous shock to the Brazilian banking system caused by the international turmoil of 2008 and find evidence that the run to systemically important banks is better explained by the perception of a too-big-to-fail policy than by bank fundamentals. We infer that the extra inflow of deposits received by systemically important banks during crises gives them an important competitive advantage. Our analysis also indicates that a bank's share of funding from institutional investors affects the nonfinancial firms' and institutional investors' decision to run.</description><author>Oliveira, Raquel De F.; Schiozer, Rafael F.; Barros, Lucas A. B. De C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Variance Reduction for Asian Options under a General Model Framework</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dingec, Kemal Dincer; Sak, Halis; Hormann, Wolfgang
We present a new variance reduction method for Asian options under a general model framework. The three special cases we consider are L,vy processes, Heston stochastic volatility, and regime switching models. The proposed method combines a very effective control variate with conditional Monte Carlo. While the control variate can be used for any model allowing the numerical computation of the multivariate characteristic function of the log-return vector, conditional Monte Carlo is based on the unified representation of the three models. Computational results confirm that the new method performs better than available control variate methods.</description><author>Dingec, Kemal Dincer; Sak, Halis; Hormann, Wolfgang</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stealth Trading and Trade Reporting by Corporate Insiders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Betzer, Andr; Gider, Jasmin; Metzger, Daniel; Theissen, Erik
Regulations in the pre-Sarbanes-Oxley era allowed corporate insiders considerable flexibility in timing their trades and engaging in stealth trading, for example, by executing several trades and reporting them jointly after the last trade. We document that even these lax reporting requirements were frequently violated and stealth trading was common. Event study abnormal returns are larger after reports of stealth trades than after reports of otherwise similar non-stealth trades. Our results imply that delayed reporting impedes the adjustment of prices to the information revealed by insider trades. They lend strong support to the more stringent reporting requirements established by the Sarbanes-Oxley Act.</description><author>Betzer, Andr; Gider, Jasmin; Metzger, Daniel; Theissen, Erik</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxation, Transfer Income and Stock Market Participation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fischer, Marcel; Jensen, Bjarne Astrup
This article studies the impact of a redistributive tax system on consumption, portfolio decisions, and asset prices in a dynamic general equilibrium model. Poorer agents, which receive more in transfers than they pay in taxes, optimally reduce their exposure to equity, because the transfer income they receive is subject to stock market risk. This article thus provides a novel explanation for the low stock market participation rates of poorer investors.</description><author>Fischer, Marcel; Jensen, Bjarne Astrup</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Casting Doubt on the Predictability of Stock Returns in Real Time: Bayesian Model Averaging using Realistic Priors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Turner, James A.
Previous studies have identified several variables that would have predicted future stock returns, though other studies suggest these results may be due to data snooping. To guard against data snooping, researchers have suggested use of Bayesian model averaging (BMA) to account for the uncertainty about prediction models. In common with other researchers, I find evidence of predictability during time periods when a hypothetical investor uses BMA with no restrictions on what variables may be included in the model. However, when the hypothetical investor is limited to using only variables whose predictive ability would have been known at the time of the forecast, predictability disappears. Moreover, predictability also disappears when data are updated through 2010, even without constraints on variable use. The results cast doubt on whether stock returns were ever predictable in real time and also suggest that returns may no longer be predictable even if real-time constraints are removed.</description><author>Turner, James A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Household Portfolio Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bucciol, Alessandro; Miniaci, Raffaele
We exploit the US Survey of Consumer Finances from 1998 to 2010 to study households' portfolio risk. We compare alternative measures of ex-ante risk, based on a financial portfolio including deposits, bonds, and stocks, or a broader portfolio also including real estate, business wealth, and related debt. The measures provide different rankings of portfolio risk, but they all show a skewed distribution with many households bearing limited risk. Large wealth holdings lead to more aggressive risk positions. Moreover, risk falls at the beginning of the sample period and rises at the end, together with the business cycle.</description><author>Bucciol, Alessandro; Miniaci, Raffaele</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Network Systemic Risk Contributions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hautsch, Nikolaus; Schaumburg, Julia; Schienle, Melanie
We propose the realized systemic risk beta as a measure of financial companies' contribution to systemic risk, given network interdependence between firms' tail risk exposures. Conditional on statistically pre-identified network spillover effects and market and balance sheet information, we define the realized systemic risk beta as the total time-varying marginal effect of a firm's Value-at-risk (VaR) on the system's VaR. Statistical inference reveals a multitude of relevant risk spillover channels and determines companies' systemic importance in the US financial system. Our approach can be used to monitor companies' systemic importance, enabling transparent macroprudential supervision.</description><author>Hautsch, Nikolaus; Schaumburg, Julia; Schienle, Melanie</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Small Banks and Local Economic Development</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hakenes, Hendrik; Hasan, Iftekhar; Molyneux, Philip; Xie, Ru
This article discusses the effects of small banks on economic growth. We first theoretically show that small banks operating at a regional level can spur local economic growth. As compared with big interregional banks, small regional banks are more effective in promoting local economic growth, especially in regions with lower initial endowments and severe credit rationing. We then test the model predictions using a sample of German banks and corresponding regional statistics. We find that small regional banks are more important funding providers in regions with low access to finance. The empirical results support the theoretical hypotheses.</description><author>Hakenes, Hendrik; Hasan, Iftekhar; Molyneux, Philip; Xie, Ru</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multiple Bank Lending, Creditor Rights, and Information Sharing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bennardo, Alberto; Pagano, Marco; Piccolo, Salvatore
Multiple bank lending induces borrowers to take too much debt when creditor rights are poorly protected; moreover, banks wish to engage in opportunistic lending at their competitors' expenses if borrowers' collateral is sufficiently risky. These incentives lead to credit rationing and positive-profit interest rates, possibly exceeding the monopoly level. If banks share information about past debts and seniority via credit reporting systems, the incentive to overborrow is mitigated: interest and default rates decrease; credit access improves if the value of collateral is not very volatile, but worsens otherwise. Recent empirical studies report evidence consistent with these predictions. The article also shows that private and social incentives to share information are not necessarily aligned.</description><author>Bennardo, Alberto; Pagano, Marco; Piccolo, Salvatore</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ending "Too Big To Fail": Government Promises Versus Investor Perceptions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gormley, Todd A.; Johnson, Simon; Rhee, Changyong
Can a government credibly promise not to bailout firms whose failure would have major negative systemic consequences? Our analysis of Korea's 1997-98 crisis suggests an answer: No. Despite a general "no bailout" policy during the crisis, the largest Korean corporate groups-facing severe financial and governance problems-could still borrow heavily from households by issuing bonds at prices implying very low expected default risk. The evidence suggests "too big to fail" beliefs were not eliminated by government promises because investors believed that this policy was not time consistent. Subsequent bailouts confirmed the market view that creditors would be protected.</description><author>Gormley, Todd A.; Johnson, Simon; Rhee, Changyong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tug-of-War: Time-Varying Predictability of Stock Returns and Dividend Growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhu, Xiaoneng
We propose a regime-switching present-value model with latent variables to jointly investigate the predictability of stock returns and dividend growth. We find that both return predictability and dividend growth predictability are time-varying. Interestingly, the predictability of stock returns and dividend growth is a tug-of-war contest: when dividend growth is highly predictable in the high-volatility regime, stock returns are largely unpredictable; in contrast, when dividend growth is less predictable in the low-volatility regime, stock returns are significantly predictable. We also investigate macroeconomic determinants of regime switches and find that two regimes are intimately related to macroeconomic risk and economic activity.</description><author>Zhu, Xiaoneng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Herding Behavior and Rating Convergence among Credit Rating Agencies: Evidence from the Subprime Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lugo, Stefano; Croce, Annalisa; Faff, Robert
This article examines how credit rating agencies (CRAs) react to rating decisions on mortgage-backed securities by rival agencies in the aftermath of the subprime crisis. While Fitch is on average the first mover, Moody's and S&amp;P perform more timely downgrades given a downgrade or a more severe evaluation by a CRA other than Fitch, and they also influence Fitch more than they are influenced by it. Rating convergence is more likely when Fitch rather than the rival has to adjust its evaluation downwards. Our results support theoretical predictions on the role of reputation in explaining herding behavior among CRAs.</description><author>Lugo, Stefano; Croce, Annalisa; Faff, Robert</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-Term Trading and Stock Return Anomalies: Momentum, Reversal, and Share Issuance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, Martijn; Pareek, Ankur
This article examines how the extent of short-term trading relates to the efficiency of stock prices. We employ a new duration measure based on quarterly institutional investors' portfolio holdings, next to existing proxies such as trading volume, the percentage of transient institutions, and fund turnover. Momentum returns and subsequent returns reversal are generally much stronger for stocks held primarily by short-term investors, especially if these investors recently had superior recent performance which could make them overconfident. Our results point toward the behavioral theory in Daniel, Hirshleifer and Subrahmanyam (1998) and seem inconsistent with short-term institutions improving efficiency.</description><author>Cremers, Martijn; Pareek, Ankur</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Improved Portfolio Choice Using Second-Order Stochastic Dominance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hodder, James E.; Jackwerth, Jens Carsten; Kolokolova, Olga
Constructing portfolios based on second-order stochastic dominance (SSD) is theoretically attractive since all risk-averse investors would prefer a dominating portfolio. However, choosing among SSD efficient portfolios is a challenge without an obvious ranking metric. We explore particular choices based on Kuosmanen (2004) plus Kopa and Post (2011), comparing their performance to other SSD-related strategies and to standard portfolio choice approaches. These SSD-related choices outperform portfolios chosen based on their Sharpe ratio, information ratio, or using equal weights. Portfolios based on minimum variance that also match the benchmark's mean return perform on a par with the SSD-related choices.</description><author>Hodder, James E.; Jackwerth, Jens Carsten; Kolokolova, Olga</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Dark Trading and Visible Fragmentation on Market Quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Degryse, Hans; De Jong, Frank; Van Kervel, Vincent
Two important characteristics of current equity markets are the large number of competing trading venues with publicly displayed order books and the substantial fraction of dark trading, which takes place outside such visible order books. This article evaluates the impact on liquidity of dark trading and fragmentation in visible order books. Dark trading has a detrimental effect on liquidity. Visible fragmentation improves liquidity aggregated over all visible trading venues but lowers liquidity at the traditional market, meaning that the benefits of fragmentation are not enjoyed by investors who choose to send orders only to the traditional market.</description><author>Degryse, Hans; De Jong, Frank; Van Kervel, Vincent</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Emerging Equity Market Comovements: Trends and Macroeconomic Fundamentals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eiling, Esther; Gerard, Bruno
Emerging equity markets have become increasingly interrelated over the past two decades. For a sample of thirty-two emerging markets from four different regions, we find significant positive time trends in cross-country correlations within regions, correlations across regions, and in comovements with the rest of the world. Furthermore, we examine the economic mechanisms that drive these trends. We find that official market liberalization, a continuous measure of equity market openness, equity market development, and to some extent, trade openness all play a role. However, we show important heterogeneity across regions, both in the speed at which comovements increase over time and in the underlying macroeconomic channels.</description><author>Eiling, Esther; Gerard, Bruno</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Acquiring Acquirers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phalippou, Ludovic; Xu, Fangming; Zhao, Huainan
Target acquisitiveness stands out as one of the primary drivers of all the key aspects of the market for corporate takeovers: acquisition announcement returns, probability of deal success, propensity to acquire and be acquired. Acquisitive targets, though a small proportion of the sample, are responsible for half of the overall negative acquisition announcement returns. Our large body of empirical evidence consistently supports the view that the motivation behind acquisitions of acquisitive targets is defensive: acquirers "eat in order not to be eaten".</description><author>Phalippou, Ludovic; Xu, Fangming; Zhao, Huainan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Earned Versus House Money on Price Bubble Formation in Experimental Asset Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corgnet, Brice; Hernan-Gonzalez, Roberto; Kujal, Praveen; Porter, David
Does house money exacerbate price bubbles? We compare house money asset market experiments with an earned money treatment where initial portfolios are constructed from a real effort task. Bubbles occur; however, trading volumes and earnings dispersion are significantly higher with house money. We investigate the role of cognitive ability in accounting for the differences in earnings distribution across treatments by using the cognitive reflection test (CRT). Low CRT subjects earned less than high CRT subjects. Low CRT subjects were net purchasers (sellers) of shares when the price was above (below) fundamental value. The opposite was true for high CRT subjects.</description><author>Corgnet, Brice; Hernan-Gonzalez, Roberto; Kujal, Praveen; Porter, David</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Profits-Leverage Puzzle Revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frank, Murray Z.; Goyal, Vidhan K.
The inverse relation between leverage and profitability is widely regarded as a serious defect of the trade-off theory. We show that the defect is not with the theory but with the use of a leverage ratio in which profitability affects both the numerator and the denominator. Profitability directly increases the value of equity. Firms do take the predicted offsetting actions. They issue debt and repurchase equity when profitability rises, and retire debt and issue equity when profitability falls. Consistent with variable transactions costs, the adjustment is not generally sufficient to fully undo the profitability shocks. Accordingly, on average the leverage ratio falls as profitability rises.</description><author>Frank, Murray Z.; Goyal, Vidhan K.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance Pay, CEO Dismissal, and the Dual Role of Takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burkart, Mike; Raff, Konrad
We propose that an active takeover market provides incentives by offering acquisition opportunities to successful managers. This allows firms to reduce performance-based compensation and can rationalize loss-making acquisitions. When choosing its acquisition policy and the quality of its board, each firm ignores the adverse effect on other firms' acquisition opportunities and takeover threat. As a result, the takeover market is not sufficiently liquid and too few takeovers occur. Furthermore, liquidity in the takeover and managerial labor markets are inversely related. When poaching managers becomes more profitable, firms invest more in board quality which in turn reduces the incidence of takeovers.</description><author>Burkart, Mike; Raff, Konrad</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Much Can Financial Literacy Help?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guiso, Luigi; Viviano, Eliana
We use a dataset of individual investors containing test-based measures of financial literacy and administrative records on their assets holding and trades before and during the financial crisis of September 2008. We design three tests of the benefits of financial literacy during the Global Financial Crisis, by comparing the decisions actually taken by individuals with a dominated alternative, i.e., one giving lower utility according to simple normative models of financial decision-making. We find that high-literacy investors are better at timing the market. High-literacy investors are also more likely to trade according to the prescriptions of normative models and to detect intermediaries' potential conflicts of interest. However, though statistically significant, these effects are economically small.</description><author>Guiso, Luigi; Viviano, Eliana</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Conditional Effects of Market Power on Bank Risk-Cross-Country Evidence*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Forssbaeck, Jens; Shehzad, Choudhry Tanveer
We investigate the relationship between market power and risk for a large panel of banks worldwide. Loan and deposit market power are measured separately at bank-year level, and the risk effect of market power is conditioned on several factors predicted by theory. Both loan and deposit market power have a stable, monotonically negative effect on risk, irrespective of risk measure. The effect is larger for asset risk, and is independent of charter value and capital ratios. The effect on default risk tends to decrease in the quality of banking regulation, whereas the conditioning effects of deposit insurance protection are mixed.</description><author>Forssbaeck, Jens; Shehzad, Choudhry Tanveer</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Size Structure and Small Business Lending: Are Crisis Times Different from Normal Times?*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; Cerqueiro, Geraldo; Penas, Maria Fabiana
Conventional wisdom holds that small banks have comparative advantages vis-A -vis large banks in serving small firms, while recent literature suggests this may not be the case. Using a panel of recent US start-ups, we investigate how small bank presence affects these firms in normal times (2004-06) and in the recent financial crisis (2007-09). We find that greater small bank presence yields significantly more lending to and slightly lower failure rates of these firms during normal times. However, these benefits disappear during the financial crisis, possibly because small banks are less diversified and benefit less from government guarantees than large banks.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; Cerqueiro, Geraldo; Penas, Maria Fabiana</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Market Literacy, Trust, and Participation*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balloch, Adnan; Nicolae, Anamaria; Philip, Dennis
This article studies the importance of stock market literacy and trust for stock ownership decisions. We find that these two distinct channels simultaneously explain not only the probability of participation, but, conditional on participation, also explain the share of investment in stocks. Once we account for stock market literacy, sociability is no longer significant for participation; what matters is literacy rather than sociability. Further, we observe that economic shocks and future expectations are key behavioral characteristics that explain a household's decision to invest in stocks. However, upon participation, a larger set of behavioral characteristics explains the level of stock investment.</description><author>Balloch, Adnan; Nicolae, Anamaria; Philip, Dennis</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade Credit, Relationship-specific Investment, and Product Market Power*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dass, Nishant; Kale, Jayant R.; Nanda, Vikram
We rely on a model with incomplete contracts and bargaining power to argue that trade credit (TC) can serve as a commitment device for making relationship-specific investments (RSIs). Unlike existing theories, we explain within a single theoretical framework why TC is affected by firms' bargaining power and by the specialized nature of transacted goods. Using a large panel of publicly listed firms and innovation-based proxies for RSI, we find strong support for the model's predictions: TC increases in upstream firm's RSI and downstream firm's market power. Endogeneity concerns are addressed by using the passage of innovation-increasing state laws to instrument for RSI and import penetration to instrument for bargaining power.</description><author>Dass, Nishant; Kale, Jayant R.; Nanda, Vikram</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private Equity Fund Returns and Performance Persistence*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marquez, Robert; Nanda, Vikram; Yavuz, M. Deniz
Successful private equity managers have funds that are often oversubscribed and provide persistent abnormal returns. Why do not successful managers increase fund size or fees? We argue that managers want to attract high-quality entrepreneurs, while entrepreneurs want to match with high-ability managers. However, observing fund performance does not allow entrepreneurs to distinguish a manager's ability from the quality of firms in the fund's portfolio. As a consequence, a fund manager may devote unobserved effort to select firms, and keep fund size small to limit the cost of effort, hoping to manipulate entrepreneurs' beliefs about his ability.</description><author>Marquez, Robert; Nanda, Vikram; Yavuz, M. Deniz</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Convective Risk Flows in Commodity Futures Markets*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheng, Ing-Haw; Kirilenko, Andrei; Xiong, Wei
We study the joint responses of commodity future prices and positions of various trader groups to changes of the CBOE Volatility Index (VIX) before and after the recent financial crisis. Financial traders reduced their net long positions during the crisis in response to market distress, whereas hedgers facilitated this by reducing their net short positions as prices fell. This "convective risk flow" induced by the greater distress of financial institutions led to a change in the allocation of risk with hedgers holding more risk than they did previously. The presence of such a risk flow confirms the market impact of financial traders conditional on trades they initiate.</description><author>Cheng, Ing-Haw; Kirilenko, Andrei; Xiong, Wei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Market Integration and the Global Financial Crisis*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lehkonen, Heikki
We study the dynamics of stock market integration and its consequences during the recent financial crisis for twenty-three developed and sixty emerging markets. We find that integration increased slightly for emerging markets but decreased for developed countries during the crisis. Moreover, we argue that the high degree of integration propagated the crisis across the global financial markets at the beginning of the crisis, but it had little effect during the crisis. We also find that integration is mostly affected by financial openness, the institutional environment, and global financial uncertainty but that these determinants vary slightly between emerging and developed markets.</description><author>Lehkonen, Heikki</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exporting Sovereign Stress: Evidence from Syndicated Bank Lending during the Euro Area Sovereign Debt Crisis*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Popov, Alexander; Van Horen, Neeltje
We show that after the start of the euro area sovereign debt crisis, lending by non-GIIPS European banks with sizeable holdings of GIIPS sovereign bonds declined relative to nonexposed banks. This effect is not driven by changes in borrower demand or by other shocks to banks' balance sheets. We also find that affected banks withdrew from all foreign markets with the exception of the USA, suggesting an increase in home bias. The slowdown in lending continued after ECB's LTRO in December 2011, but it was lower for banks that increased their risky exposures in the early stages of the crisis.</description><author>Popov, Alexander; Van Horen, Neeltje</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Government-Sponsored Venture Capital: International Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brander, James A.; Du, Qianqian; Hellmann, Thomas
This article examines enterprises funded by government-sponsored venture capitalists (GVCs). We find that enterprises funded by both GVCs and private venture capitalists (PVCs) obtain more investment than enterprises funded purely by PVCs, and much more than those funded purely by GVCs. Also, markets with more GVC funding have more VC funding per enterprise and more VC-funded enterprises, suggesting that GVC finance largely augments rather than displaces PVC finance. There is also a positive association between mixed GVC/PVC funding and successful exits, as measured by initial public offerings (IPOs) and acquisitions, attributable largely to the additional investment.</description><author>Brander, James A.; Du, Qianqian; Hellmann, Thomas</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance Terms in CEO Compensation Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Angelis, David; Grinstein, Yaniv
In December 2006, the Securities and Exchange Commission issued new rules that require enhanced disclosure on how firms tie CEO compensation to performance. We use this new available data to study the terms of performance-based awards in CEO compensation contracts in S&amp;P 500 firms. We observe large variations in the choice of performance measures. Our evidence is consistent with predictions from optimal contracting theories: firms rely on performance measures that are more informative of CEO actions.</description><author>De Angelis, David; Grinstein, Yaniv</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Downside Market Risk of Carry Trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dobrynskaya, Victoria
I propose a new factor-the global downside market factor-to explain high returns to carry trades. I show that carry trades have high downside market risk, i.e. they crash systematically in the worst states of the world when the global stock market plunges or when a disaster occurs. The downside market factor explains the returns to currency portfolios sorted by the forward discount better than other factors previously proposed in the literature. GMM estimates of the downside beta premium are similar in the currency and stock markets, statistically significant and close to their theoretical value. High returns to carry trades are fair compensation for their high downside market risk.</description><author>Dobrynskaya, Victoria</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Structure under Heterogeneous Beliefs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jung, Hae Won; Subramanian, Ajay
We develop a structural model to quantitatively analyze the effects of asymmetric beliefs and agency conflicts on capital structure. Capital structure reflects the dynamic tradeoff between the positive incentive effects of managerial optimism and the negative effects of risk-sharing costs. Consistent with empirical evidence, long-term debt declines with optimism, whereas short-term borrowing increases. Permanent and transitory risk components have contrasting effects. Long-term debt increases with the intrinsic risk, but varies nonmonotonically with the transient risk. Short-term borrowing declines with the intrinsic risk, but increases with the transient risk. Overall, our findings show that asymmetric beliefs significantly influence firms' financial policies.</description><author>Jung, Hae Won; Subramanian, Ajay</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real Effect of Foreign Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bruno, Valentina; Hauswald, Robert
Although foreign banks can act as catalysts for financial and economic development, their role remains controversial because they might displace local lending, thereby tightening firms' overall access to credit. We study the economic channels through which domestic lending by foreign banks affects real economic activity in a large cross-section of developing and advanced countries. We find that foreign lending alleviates financial constraints and increases real growth net of the competitive reaction of local lenders. In addition to providing stable access to credit, foreign banks also mitigate the consequence of informational and legal obstacles to lending, especially in developing credit markets.</description><author>Bruno, Valentina; Hauswald, Robert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Performance of Separate Accounts and Collective Investment Trusts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elton, Edwin J.; Gruber, Martin J.; Blake, Christopher R.
Despite the size and importance of separately managed accounts (SMAs) and collective investment trusts, their characteristics and performance have not been studied in detail. We show that separate account performance is similar to that of index funds and superior to that of actively managed mutual funds. Management supplies a benchmark for each separate account. When the management-selected benchmark is used to measure performance, performance is significantly overstated. Despite this, investors react to differences in performance from the management-preferred benchmark in choosing among SMAs. Finally we find variables that explain both the cross section of alphas and the cross section of cash flows.</description><author>Elton, Edwin J.; Gruber, Martin J.; Blake, Christopher R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dealing with Venture Capitalists: Shopping Around or Exclusive Negotiation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Casamatta, Catherine; Haritchabalet, Carole
We study the fund-raising strategy of an entrepreneur when investors have private information about his project's profitability. The entrepreneur cares about monetary profits and about the probability to obtain financing. If he contacts both venture capitalists (VCs) simultaneously, he obtains high monetary profits. If he commits to a period of exclusive negotiation with one VC, he increases the probability to obtain financing but deal terms deteriorate. The optimal negotiation strategy results from this tradeoff. We also solve for the equilibrium financial contracts and obtain implications for VCs' portfolios and entrepreneurs' deals.</description><author>Casamatta, Catherine; Haritchabalet, Carole</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Default Correlations in the Merton Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erlenmaier, Ulrich; Gersbach, Hans
We examine the relationship between default probabilities and default correlations of two firms in the Merton model. We show that default correlations increase under a homogeneous increase of default probabilities. The same is true if the increase of the default probability is more pronounced for the firm with the lower likelihood of default. Default correlations may only decline if the increase of the default probability is significantly larger for the firm with higher default risk. These findings may have important implications for the assessment of credit portfolio risk, loan pricing, and capital requirements when adverse macroeconomic shocks occur.</description><author>Erlenmaier, Ulrich; Gersbach, Hans</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Regulations and Income Inequality: Empirical Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delis, Manthos D.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Kazakis, Pantelis
This article provides cross-country evidence that variations in bank regulatory policies result in differences in income distribution. In particular, the overall liberalization of banking systems decreases income inequality significantly. However, this effect becomes insignificant for countries with low levels of economic and institutional development and for market-based economies. Among liberalization policies, credit and interest rate controls have the most significant negative effect on inequality. Privatizations and liberalization of international capital flows also decrease income inequality; the latter also increases the income share of the relatively poor. In contrast, liberalization of securities markets increases income inequality substantially.</description><author>Delis, Manthos D.; Hasan, Iftekhar; Kazakis, Pantelis</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International Diversification Benefits with Foreign Exchange Investment Styles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kroencke, Tim A.; Schindler, Felix; Schrimpf, Andreas
Style-based management of the foreign exchange (FX) component of international investments with carry trade, FX momentum, and FX value strategies provides economically large and significant diversification benefits. These speculative benefits go beyond the hedging benefits of FX risk documented in the earlier literature. Our results hold after transaction costs and are confirmed in an extensive out-of-sample experiment mimicking investor decisions in real time. Adding a composite FX style portfolio to diversified allocations of global bonds and stocks leads to a 64% increase in the out-of-sample Sharpe ratio from 0.64 to 1.05, without adverse impact on other portfolio characteristics such as skewness.</description><author>Kroencke, Tim A.; Schindler, Felix; Schrimpf, Andreas</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do Financial Intermediaries Create Value in Security Issues?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adriani, Fabrizio; Deidda, Luca G.; Sonderegger, Silvia
We study incentive provision in a model of securities issuance with an informed issuer and uninformed investors. We show that the presence of an informed intermediary may increase surplus even if we allow for collusion between the intermediary and the issuer. Collusion is neutralized by introducing a misalignment between the interests of the issuer and those of the intermediary. To achieve this, the intermediary commits to hold some of the securities. The intermediary then underprices the remaining securities and extracts any investor surplus through a "participation fee." We provide an explanation for the diffusion of book building and quid pro quo practices in Initial Public Offerings (IPOs).</description><author>Adriani, Fabrizio; Deidda, Luca G.; Sonderegger, Silvia</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Non-Markov Gaussian Term Structure Models: The Case of Inflation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feunou, Bruno; Fontaine, Jean-Sebastien
Standard Gaussian term structure models impose the Markov property: the conditional mean is a function of the risk factors. We relax this assumption and consider models where yields are linear in the conditional mean (but not in the risk factors). To illustrate, yields should span expected inflation but not inflation. Second, expected and surprise yield changes can have opposite contemporaneous effects on expected inflation. Third, the survey forecasts and inflation rate can both be in the state. These three features are inconsistent with the Markov assumption. These effects matter empirically in the USA and in Canada.</description><author>Feunou, Bruno; Fontaine, Jean-Sebastien</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the Secondary Loan Market Reduce Borrowing Costs?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kamstra, Mark J.; Roberts, Gordon S.; Shao, Pei
We show that lenders make price concessions for the right to resell loans and reveal a strong countervailing association between the ex ante probability of loan resale and the initial loan spreads. We disentangle the side effects (reduced monitoring) from the benefits (enhanced liquidity) brought by the secondary loan resales. The average net impact of simultaneously reducing the probability of the presence of resale constraint and raising the probability of resale across the full sample is to lower spreads by 14 basis points. On balance, the secondary loan market provides clear benefits to the issuers of debt.</description><author>Kamstra, Mark J.; Roberts, Gordon S.; Shao, Pei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Peso Problems and Term Structure Anomalies of Repo Rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhu, Xiaoneng
The evidence from the repo market is more supportive to the expectations hypothesis, but term structure anomalies still remain. Using the Bekaert-Hodrick-Marshall ( 2001) method, we investigate whether term structure anomalies can be explained by peso problems by estimating a regime-switching model for the overnight repo rate. We find that term structure anomalies can largely be accounted for by peso problems, probably along with a small time-varying risk premium for the full sample. However, peso problem explanations cannot resolve term structure anomalies for the postcrisis sample. In addition, we find that three regimes are related to calendar effects in the repo market.</description><author>Zhu, Xiaoneng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility Inadaptability: Investors Care About Risk, but Cannot Cope with Volatility*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ehm, Christian; Kaufmann, Christine; Weber, Martin
This article investigates two research questions: do investors see a relationship between risk attitude and the amount invested into risky assets? Further, do investors adjust their investments if provided with assets that have different volatilities? In an experimental study, investors allocate an amount between a risky and a risk-free asset. Investors' risk attitude predicts risk taking. Investors are, however, unable to adapt to risky assets with different volatilities; they choose almost the same allocation to the risky asset independently of its volatility, thus amassing significantly different portfolios.</description><author>Ehm, Christian; Kaufmann, Christine; Weber, Martin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm Expansion and Stock Price Momentum*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nyberg, Peter; Poeyry, Salla
We document a significant and robust connection between firm-level asset changes and return momentum. Momentum profits are large and significant for firms that have experienced large asset expansions or contractions, whereas they otherwise are small and often insignificant. The interaction pattern is not subsumed by previously documented drivers of momentum and shows up in market states where prior literature has documented an absence of momentum profits. Furthermore, we find a positive time series relationship between aggregate asset growth (AG) and return momentum, and the effect of aggregate AG is stronger than that of variables related to business cycles and investor sentiment. While most existing models of firm investment and momentum cannot explain our results, recent real options models appear to hold the most promise.</description><author>Nyberg, Peter; Poeyry, Salla</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Sentiment for Real Assets: The Case of Dry Bulk Shipping Market*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Papapostolou, Nikos C.; Nomikos, Nikos K.; Pouliasis, Panos K.; Kyriakou, Ioannis
We investigate the role of sentiment and its implications for real assets. Using shipping sentiment proxies that capture market expectations, valuation, and liquidity, we construct sentiment indices for the dry bulk shipping market. Evidence suggests that sentiment affects the monthly returns of real assets. The empirical findings also show that market sentiment serves as a contrarian indicator for future cycle phases in all sectors. Furthermore, a sentiment-based trading simulation exercise on the sale and purchase of vessels shows that investors can benefit from higher returns compared to the buy-and-hold benchmark, while partially offsetting the highly volatile nature of the shipping industry.</description><author>Papapostolou, Nikos C.; Nomikos, Nikos K.; Pouliasis, Panos K.; Kyriakou, Ioannis</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identifying the Interaction between Foreign Investor Flows and Emerging Stock Market Returns*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Uelkue, Numan; Weber, Enzo
We introduce the structural conditional correlation (SCC) methodology to the foreign flows literature to identify the contemporaneous return-flow interaction and provide new evidence using the first daily data from a sizeable European emerging market and comparing to Asian markets. SCC results indicate significant bilateral intraday interaction between net foreign flows and market returns, and the presence of their latent common drivers. Allowing for these effects alters previously uniform results of positive feedback trading for some Asian markets, as well as the price impact estimates. Foreigners display a sluggish response to global information, which cannot be attributed to their information disadvantage.</description><author>Uelkue, Numan; Weber, Enzo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Sharing and Information Acquisition in Credit Markets*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karapetyan, Artashes; Stacescu, Bogdan
We examine the effect of information sharing via credit bureaus or credit registers on banks' incentives to collect information about their borrowers. Information asymmetries have been identified as an important source of bank profits, and sharing knowledge about borrowers can reduce those rents. Despite that, we show that banks' incentives to collect information actually increase in the presence of information sharing. The reason is that when hard, standardized information is shared, banks' incentives to invest in soft, nonverifiable information increase. The result can be more accurate lending decisions and improved welfare.</description><author>Karapetyan, Artashes; Stacescu, Bogdan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liberalization and Risk-Taking: Evidence from Government-Controlled Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Illueca, Manuel; Norden, Lars; Udell, Gregory F.
We study the effects of the interplay between deregulation and governance on risk-taking in the financial industry. We consider the removal of regulatory geographic constraints for savings banks in Spain, the cajas, which led to a nationwide expansion of these banks during the past two decades. Based on a unique dataset that combines information on the geographic distribution of bank lending, matched lender-borrower financial statements, and borrower defaults, we find that the governance of the savings banks significantly affects the way in which they expand their lending activities. Savings banks that are subject to political influence by regional governments exhibit higher ex ante risk-taking and higher ex post loan defaults. Our study highlights the broader implications of the impact of global deregulation and consolidation and their interaction with governance issues.</description><author>Illueca, Manuel; Norden, Lars; Udell, Gregory F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Hedge Funds Supply or Demand Liquidity?*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jylha, Petri; Rinne, Kalle; Suominen, Matti
Regressing hedge funds' returns on returns to a long-short contrarian trading strategy, a measure of the returns from providing liquidity, we find that hedge funds typically supply liquidity in the stock market. In the cross-section, strict redemption restrictions and large fund size increase funds' propensity to supply liquidity. In time series, poor market liquidity and good funding conditions increase funds' propensity to supply liquidity. Although the hedge funds typically supply liquidity, during crises they demand liquidity. We also find that increases in the amount of speculative capital improve market liquidity and reduce the amount of short-term return reversals and volatility.</description><author>Jylha, Petri; Rinne, Kalle; Suominen, Matti</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Firms Buy Their Stock at Bargain Prices? Evidence from Actual Stock Repurchase Disclosures*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben-Rephael, Azi; Oded, Jacob; Wohl, Avi
Using new monthly data, we investigate open-market repurchase executions of US firms. We find that firms repurchase at prices that are significantly lower than average market prices. This price discount is negatively related to size and positively related to market-to-book ratio. Firms' repurchase activity is followed by a positive and significant abnormal return. Importantly, the market response occurs when firms disclose their actual repurchase data in earnings announcements, and this positive response is followed by a 1-month drift. Consistent with these results, we find that insider trading is positively related to actual repurchases.</description><author>Ben-Rephael, Azi; Oded, Jacob; Wohl, Avi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing Major Investments: Information about Capital Structure Decisions*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elsas, Ralf; Flannery, Mark J.; Garfinkel, Jon A.
We evaluate US firms' leverage determinants by studying how firms paid for 2,073 very large investments between 1989 and 2006. This approach complements existing empirical work on capital structure, which typically estimates regression models of leverage for a broad set of firms. Because large investments are mostly externally financed, security issuances should provide information about managers' attitudes toward leverage. We find that issued securities move firms toward target debt ratios. Firms also tend to issue more equity following a share price run-up, consistent with both the tradeoff hypothesis and managerial efforts to time market sentiment. We find little support for the standard pecking order hypothesis.</description><author>Elsas, Ralf; Flannery, Mark J.; Garfinkel, Jon A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash Holdings and Mutual Fund Performance*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Simutin, Mikhail
Cash holdings of equity mutual funds impose a drag on fund performance but also allow managers to make quick investments in attractive stocks and satisfy outflows without costly fire sales. This article shows that actively managed equity funds with high abnormal cash-that is, with cash holdings in excess of the level predicted by fund attributes-outperform their low abnormal cash peers by over 2% per year. Managers carrying high abnormal cash compensate for the low return on cash by making superior stock selection decisions, whereas less capable managers find abnormal cash costly and remain more fully invested in equities. Managers of high abnormal cash funds also proficiently satisfy fund outflows and control fund transaction costs, whereas low abnormal cash funds lack flexibility to cover outflows and can suffer from costly fire sales. The empirical evidence suggests that managers carrying abnormal cash benefit from the flexibility it provides despite the costs of holding cash.</description><author>Simutin, Mikhail</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Venture Capital Meets Contract Theory: Risky Claims or Formal Control?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cestone, Giacinta
This article develops a theory of the joint allocation of control and cash-flow rights in venture capital (VC) deals. When the need for VC advice and support calls for a high-powered outside claim, the entrepreneur should optimally retain control in order to avoid undue interference. Hence, I predict that more high-powered claims should be associated with fewer control rights. This challenges the idea that control should always be attached to equity-like claims and is in line with contractual terms used in venture capital, corporate venturing, and partnerships between biotech start-ups and large corporations. The article also rationalizes evidence that venture capital contracts include contingencies triggering both a reduction in VC control and the automatic conversion of VC's preferred stock into common.</description><author>Cestone, Giacinta</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Venture Capital and Industry Structure: Evidence from Local US Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Popov, Alexander
I use a panel of US manufacturing industries to test how venture capital (VC) affects the size distribution of business firms. The estimates suggest that an increase in the supply of VC affects positively mean firm size by increasing the relative share of medium-sized and larger firms. These results are robust to specifications that address the endogeneity in the supply of VC. The empirical evidence is consistent with the idea that VC promotes the "elitization" of firm entry.</description><author>Popov, Alexander</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Seasoned Equity Offerings, Corporate Governance, and Investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kim, E. Han; Purnanandam, Amiyatosh
We find weak governance is a primary reason investors react negatively to the announcement of seasoned equity offerings (SEOs). Using a difference-in-differences approach, we find investors worry about nonproductive use of SEO proceeds when external pressure for good governance lifts due to an external shock. Investors react negatively only when treated firms raise funds to increase capital investments. Market reaction is more negative when issuers have prior records of value-reducing acquisitions and weaker managerial wealth sensitivity to shareholder value. The magnitudes of these governance effects are surprisingly large, explaining most of the previously documented negative market reactions to primary SEOs.</description><author>Kim, E. Han; Purnanandam, Amiyatosh</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk and Reward Preferences under Time Pressure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nursimulu, Anjali D.; Bossaerts, Peter
Financial decision making under time pressure, though ubiquitous, is poorly understood; classical and behavioral finance are silent about the time required for a decision to be made. In an experiment, calibrating allowable decision times to 1, 3, and 5 s, we find that classical moment-based preferences reflect time-invariant sensitivity to expected reward, purchase impulsiveness under extreme time pressure, and decreased aversion to variance and increased aversion to skewness with decision time. These timevarying sensitivities translate into increased probability distortions and decreased risk aversion for gains under prospect theory (PT). Strikingly, moment-based theory provides a better fit than PT.</description><author>Nursimulu, Anjali D.; Bossaerts, Peter</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Anomalies Exist Ex Ante?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tang, Yue; Wu, Jin; Zhang, Lu
The anomalies literature in capital markets research in finance and accounting is based (almost) exclusively on average realized returns. In contrast, we construct accountingbased expected returns for dollar-neutral long-short trading strategies formed on a wide array of anomaly variables, including book to market, size, composite issuance, net stock issues, abnormal investment, asset growth, investment to assets, accruals, earnings surprises, failure probability, return on assets, and short-term prior returns. Our findings are striking. Except for the value and the size premiums, the cost of equity estimates differ drastically from the average realized returns.</description><author>Tang, Yue; Wu, Jin; Zhang, Lu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Small Businesses Worthy of Financial Aid? Evidence from a French Targeted Credit Program</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bach, Laurent
We ask whether public financial aid reduces small businesses' credit constraints. To answer the question, we analyze a policy of bank loans made from subsidized funds. Extensions of this large program are plausibly exogenous and help identify its effects. Using firm-level data, we find that the program substantially increases debt financing without substitution between subsidized and unsubsidized finance. Returns on subsidized debt are significantly above its market cost, with no subsequent surge in default risk. We interpret this as evidence that targeted firms are credit-constrained and underline the implied welfare differences between upfront financial aid and public guarantees.</description><author>Bach, Laurent</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the Market for CEO Talent Explain Controversial CEO Pay Practices?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Grinstein, Yaniv
Benchmarking, pay for luck, and the large compensation packages given to CEOs in recent years are three major controversial compensation practices. We examine the extent to which variation in the market for CEO talent explains these practices. We find that CEO compensation is benchmarked against other firms only in industries where CEO talent is not firm-specific, and that pay for luck is more prevalent there also. These findings are consistent with theories based on the market for CEO talent. However, CEO compensation levels do not depend on whether CEO talent is firm-specific, which seems inconsistent with the talent competition argument.</description><author>Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Grinstein, Yaniv</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Study of Bankruptcy Costs and the Allocation of Control</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Franks, Julian; Loranth, Gyongyi
This article studies how the allocation of control rights in bankruptcy influences outcomes. Using Hungarian data, we find that the large majority of bankrupt firms in our sample are maintained as going concerns despite the fact that these firms generate large operating losses and low recovery rates for pre-bankruptcy creditors. We trace the bias to the allocation of control rights between secured and unsecured creditors and the compensation scheme of the agent managing the bankruptcy process. Our findings shed light on a very important bankruptcy design question: how particular provisions of the bankruptcy code affect the costs of bankruptcy and the size of the pie available to pre-bankruptcy creditors.</description><author>Franks, Julian; Loranth, Gyongyi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Price Manipulation: Prevalence and Determinants*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Comerton-Forde, Carole; Putnins, Talis J.
We empirically analyze the prevalence and economic underpinnings of closing price manipulation and its detection. We estimate that similar to 1% of closing prices are manipulated, of which only a small fraction is detected and prosecuted. We find that stocks with high levels of information asymmetry and mid to low levels of liquidity are most likely to be manipulated. A significant proportion of manipulation occurs on month/quarter-end days. Manipulation on these days is more likely in stocks with high levels of institutional ownership. Government regulatory budget has a strong effect on both manipulation and detection.</description><author>Comerton-Forde, Carole; Putnins, Talis J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Your Former Employees Matter: Private Equity Firms and Their Financial Advisors*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Siming, Linus
This article shows that former investment bankers become important clients for their previous employers and also provide access to profitable business opportunities to their new private equity employers through their previous employment networks. I observe 1,326 individuals directly involved in 1,285 transactions, of whom a large majority have changed their occupation from financial advisor to private equity professional. The social networks arising from these labor market movements affect private equity firms' choices of financial advisors, as well as the sourcing, pricing, and performance of deals.</description><author>Siming, Linus</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance Rules and Insider Trading Profits*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cziraki, Peter; De Goeij, Peter; Renneboog, Luc
We investigate patterns of abnormal stock performance around insider trades on the Dutch market. Listed firms in the Netherlands have a long tradition of limiting shareholders' rights. Using a change in corporate governance regulations as a natural experiment, we show that governance rules have a causal effect on insider trading profits. Our results imply that insider transactions are more profitable at firms where shareholder rights are not restricted by antishareholder mechanisms. These findings are inconsistent with internal monitoring of insider trading. Rather, we explain this empirical pattern by imperfect substitution between insider trading profits and other private benefits of control.</description><author>Cziraki, Peter; De Goeij, Peter; Renneboog, Luc</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act on Shareholders and Managers of Foreign Firms*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duarte, Jefferson; Kong, Katie; Siegel, Stephan; Young, Lance
Existing evidence suggests that the Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) may be beneficial to US investors, but that foreign firms are perhaps less likely to list in the USA after SOX. This raises the question of whether foreign firms avoid listing in the USA after SOX because the Act imposes unnecessary costs upon firms. The objective of this article is to reconcile the US and international evidence by distinguishing between the effect of SOX on controlling shareholders and managers of foreign firms and the effect on minority investors of these firms. Our results suggest that insiders of foreign firms believe that the regulation makes the extraction of value from minority investors more difficult and costly for them. Outside investors in foreign firms, on the other hand, seem on average to believe that SOX is beneficial to them. The combination of these results reconciles the existing US and international evidence regarding SOX.</description><author>Duarte, Jefferson; Kong, Katie; Siegel, Stephan; Young, Lance</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility Bounds, Size, and Real Activity Prediction*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nieto, Belen; Rubio, Gonzalo
This article shows how to extract future real activity information from optimally combined size-sorted portfolios. In particular, we analyze the capacity of the size-based model-free Hansen-Jagannathan volatility bound to predict future economic growth. We find that the volatility bound is a powerful in-sample and out-of-sample predictor of future industrial production growth. The asymmetric sensitivities of small and large companies through the business cycle explain our findings. Alternative volatility bounds estimated with sorting procedures based on book-to-market, momentum, or dividend yield do not show these asymmetric sensitivities or forecasting capacity of output growth.</description><author>Nieto, Belen; Rubio, Gonzalo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Another Look at the Stock Return Response to Monetary Policy Actions*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maio, Paulo
I analyze the effect of monetary policy actions on the cross-section of equity returns. Based on earlier theoretical work for the monetary transmission mechanism one can argue that changes in monetary policy should produce differentiated effects on firms and stocks with different characteristics. By using different portfolio sorts the results show that the impact of monthly changes in the Federal funds rate is greater for the returns of more financially constrained stocks (e.g., small and value stocks) than on the returns of stocks with a more favorable financial position (e.g., large and growth stocks). By using a VAR methodology, the results indicate that the negative effect of Fed funds rate shocks on stock returns comes from a corresponding negative effect on future expected cash flows (cash-flow news), which is stronger than the impact on future equity risk premia (discount rate news). Thus, cash-flow news is the main return component affected by changes in the Fed funds rate. These results are reasonably robust to different VAR specifications. Moreover, the dispersion in return responses to monetary shocks across stocks is explained by a similar dispersion in the effects into cash-flow news, which outweighs the dispersion in discount rate news betas. These results represent new evidence on the effect of monetary policy on stock prices and on the monetary transmission mechanism.</description><author>Maio, Paulo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Activist Arbitrage, Lifeboats, and Closed-End Funds*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lenkey, Stephen L.
We present a dynamic rational expectations model of closed-end fund discounts that incorporates feedback effects from activist arbitrage and lifeboats. Both activist arbitrage and lifeboats distort closed-end fund prices and lead to narrower discounts. Furthermore, both activist arbitrage and lifeboats effectuate an ex post wealth transfer from managers to investors but an ex ante wealth transfer from low-ability managers to high-ability managers. On average, investor wealth is unaffected by either activist arbitrage or lifeboats because their potential benefits are factored into higher fund prices. Although lifeboats can reduce takeover attempts, they do not increase expected managerial wealth.</description><author>Lenkey, Stephen L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Premium, Variance Premium, and the Maturity Structure of Uncertainty*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feunou, Bruno; Fontaine, Jean-Sebastien; Taamouti, Abderrahim; Tedongap, Romeo
Structural or no-arbitrage asset-pricing models emphasize risk factors that cannot be observed directly. We show that the term structure of risk implicit in option prices can reveal these risk factors. Empirically, the variance term structure reveals two predictors of the bond premium, the equity premium, and the variance premium, jointly. Similarly, the term structures of skewness and kurtosis measures also reveal risk factors, but these are subsumed in the predictive content of the variance. The predicted premium is countercyclical and robust to the inclusion of known returns predictors.</description><author>Feunou, Bruno; Fontaine, Jean-Sebastien; Taamouti, Abderrahim; Tedongap, Romeo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance of Buyout Funds Revisited?*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phalippou, Ludovic
This article shows that publicly available data on buyout fund returns are sufficient to replicate the recent findings derived from superior but proprietary datasets. The average buyout fund outperforms the S&amp;P 500. However, this study shows that buyout funds mainly invest in small and value companies; and the average buyout fund return is similar to that of small-cap indices and that of the oldest small-cap passive mutual fund ("DFA micro-cap"). If the benchmark is changed to small and value indices, and is levered up, the average buyout fund underperforms by 3.1% p.a.</description><author>Phalippou, Ludovic</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Portfolio Choice with Annuities and Life Insurance for Retired Couples*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hubener, Andreas; Maurer, Raimond; Rogalla, Ralph
Using a portfolio choice model, we derive the optimal demand for stocks, bonds, annuities, and term life insurance for a retired couple with uncertainty in both lifetimes. We show that the optimal portfolio is heavily weighted with joint annuities and that life insurance is purchased mainly to protect a surviving spouse from loss of annuitized income rather than for bequest. Consistent with these predictions, empirical analyses on Health and Retirement Study data indicate that life insurance holdings are related to the degree of asymmetry in the couple's annuitized income distribution.</description><author>Hubener, Andreas; Maurer, Raimond; Rogalla, Ralph</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Speed of Information Revelation and Eventual Price Quality in Markets with Insiders: Comparing Two Theories*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bossaerts, Peter; Frydman, Cary; Ledyard, John
Two theoretical literatures, one using Bayesian Nash equilibrium (BNE), and the other using noisy rational expectations equilibrium (NREE), both provide a foundation for understanding how private information is impounded into asset prices, yet some of their predictions are conflicting. Here, we compare for the first time, the two theories using data from carefully controlled laboratory asset markets. In the dynamics, we find strong evidence for BNE theory, although final prices support predictions of the NREE theory. Finally, we document that price volatility increases when information is being impounded in prices.</description><author>Bossaerts, Peter; Frydman, Cary; Ledyard, John</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Public Guarantees on Bank Risk-Taking: Evidence from a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gropp, Reint; Gruendl, Christian; Guettler, Andre
In 2001, government guarantees for savings banks in Germany were removed following a lawsuit. We use this natural experiment to examine the effect of government guarantees on bank risk-taking. The results suggest that banks whose government guarantee was removed reduced credit risk by cutting off the riskiest borrowers from credit. Using a difference-in-differences approach we show that none of these effects are present in a control group of German banks to whom the guarantee was not applicable. Furthermore, savings banks adjusted their liabilities away from risk-sensitive debt instruments after the removal of the guarantee, while we do not observe this for the control group. We also document that yield spreads of savings banks' bonds increased significantly right after the announcement of the decision to remove guarantees, while the yield spread of a sample of bonds issued by the control group remained unchanged. The evidence implies that public guarantees may be associated with substantial moral hazard effects.</description><author>Gropp, Reint; Gruendl, Christian; Guettler, Andre</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Firms Benefit from Concentrating their Borrowing? Evidence from the Great Recession</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gobbi, Giorgio; Sette, Enrico
We investigate whether the extent to which firms concentrate their borrowing from banks mitigates the credit contraction that followed the default of Lehman. Using micro data from a large sample of Italian firms, we show that firms borrowing from fewer banks and those with more concentrated borrowing suffer on average a smaller contraction in bank credit and have a lower probability of being credit-rationed. The results hold controlling for several firm-level characteristics and for the possible endogeneity of the measures of concentration of borrowing.</description><author>Gobbi, Giorgio; Sette, Enrico</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regulating Conflicts of Interest: The Effect of Sanctions and Enforcement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dubois, Michel; Fresard, Laurent; Dumontier, Pascal
This article studies how legal sanctions and enforcement affect brokers' conflicts of interest emanating from investment banking activities. We exploit the recent adoption of the Market Abuse Directive (MAD) across European countries and use the variation in legal sanctions and enforcement that exists in Europe to identify brokers' reaction. Overall, the enactment of MAD significantly reduced optimistic investment advice. This reduction is larger in countries equipped with more severe legal sanctions and in countries that strongly enforce the rules. Our analysis underscores the importance of legal sanctions and enforcement power to understand the real consequences of regulatory changes.</description><author>Dubois, Michel; Fresard, Laurent; Dumontier, Pascal</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investing in a Global World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Busse, Jeffrey A.; Goyal, Amit; Wahal, Sunil
We examine active retail mutual funds and institutional products with a mandate to invest in global equity markets. We find little reliable evidence of alphas in the aggregate or on average. The right tail of the distribution contains some large alphas. Decomposing stock selection from country selection, we find some evidence of superior stock picking abilities in the extreme right tail. However, simulations suggest that they are produced just as likely by luck as by skill. Persistence tests show little evidence of continuation in superior performance.</description><author>Busse, Jeffrey A.; Goyal, Amit; Wahal, Sunil</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Implied Price Risk and Momentum Strategy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chuang, Hongwei; Ho, Hwai-Chung
Examining the properties of stock returns has long been a central topic in finance. Most quantitative analyses conducted by academic researchers and practitioners focus only on the return distribution. However, the return distribution itself hardly helps to determine whether the price of a winner stock picked by using the momentum strategy reaches the level where the risk incurred from the falling of prices is imminent. Therefore, we construct an implied price risk index to quantify the downside risk of a stock and use it to manage the tail risk of the momentum strategy. The empirical results demonstrate that our modified strategy can not only achieve significant improvement on the overall performance but also substantially reduce the drastic losses suffered from the 2008 global recession. We also establish the connection between the implied price risk index and the cross-sectional return differences based on the well-known three factors, the market beta, the firm size, and the book-to-market ratio.</description><author>Chuang, Hongwei; Ho, Hwai-Chung</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Don't Fight the Fed!</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maio, Paulo
Monetary policy, as captured by changes in the Fed funds rate (FFR), is a useful signal for investors. I analyze the economic significance of trading strategies based on the "out-of-sample" forecasting power of FFR for excess equity returns. A simple market-timing strategy produces an annual Sharpe ratio of 0.55 and a certainty equivalent return (CER) gain of 3.37% per year, whereas a buy-hold strategy has a Sharpe ratio of 0.41. Rotation trading strategies for portfolios sorted on size, book-to-market, and momentum have a Sharpe ratio and CER gain as high as 0.73 and 9.60% per year, respectively. Dynamic strategies for other asset classes also produce economically significant gains. Generally, the strategies based on FFR outperform those associated with alternative predictors.</description><author>Maio, Paulo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Asset Repurchases and Issues in an Experimental Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haruvy, Ernan; Noussair, Charles N.; Powell, Owen
We create an experimental asset market in which the value of the shares is independent of the quantity outstanding, and find that (i) repurchases increase, whereas share issues decrease, the price of the asset. These effects are consistent with downward-sloping demand for the asset. (ii) This behavior is consistent with three trader types-fundamental, speculator, and momentum-interacting in the market. (iii) Share issues drive prices down toward, but not beyond, fundamental values. This downward resistance at the fundamental value is predicted by the impact of an intervention on the proportion of units and cash held by each trader type.</description><author>Haruvy, Ernan; Noussair, Charles N.; Powell, Owen</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash Flow Hedging and Liquidity Choices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Disatnik, David; Duchin, Ran; Schmidt, Breno
This article studies the interaction between corporate hedging and liquidity policies. We present a theoretical model that shows how corporate hedging facilitates greater reliance on cost-effective, externally provided liquidity in lieu of internal resources. We test the model's predictions by employing a new empirical approach that separates cash flow hedging from other hedging instruments. Using detailed, hand-collected data, we find that cash flow hedging reduces the firm's precautionary demand for cash and allows it to rely more on bank lines of credit. Furthermore, we find a significant positive effect of cash flow hedging on firm value, where prior evidence is mixed.</description><author>Disatnik, David; Duchin, Ran; Schmidt, Breno</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity Issuances, Equity Mutual Fund Flows, and Noise Trader Sentiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiu, H. H.; Kini, O.
We examine whether equity issuances initial public offerings (IPOs) and seasoned equity offerings (SEOs) are in part driven by investor sentiment by using equity mutual fund flows to proxy for the rational and/or irrational components of aggregate demand for equity. We find that more firms issue equity when flows are higher and repurchase equity when flows are lower. More firms file with the Securities Exchange Commission when predicted flows in the expected issuance month are greater. Price revisions are positively related to contemporaneous flows and unexpected flows. Initial returns are positively related to contemporaneous flows only for IPO issuances. These results are driven by retail, and not institutional, flows. Our evidence suggests that investor sentiment partially drives equity issuances.</description><author>Chiu, H. H.; Kini, O.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Multiperiod Bank Run Model for Liquidity Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liang, Gechun; Luetkebohmert, Eva; Xiao, Yajun
We present a new dynamic bank run model for liquidity risk where a financial institution finances its risky assets by a mixture of short- and long-term debt. The financial institution is exposed to insolvency risk at any time until maturity and to illiquidity risk at a finite number of rollover dates. We compute both insolvency and illiquidity default probabilities in this multiperiod setting using a structural credit risk model approach. Firesale rates can be determined endogenously as expected debt value over current asset value. Numerical results illustrate the impact of various input parameters on the default probabilities.</description><author>Liang, Gechun; Luetkebohmert, Eva; Xiao, Yajun</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance and the Timing of Earnings Announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Michaely, Roni; Rubin, Amir; Vedrashko, Alexander
Using comprehensive time stamp data on earnings announcements collected from newswires, we show that earnings news announced within trading hours results in approximately 50% smaller immediate reaction compared to similar earnings announced outside trading hours. Negative news tends to be announced during trading hours, which, together with the reduced response, may allow for managerial opportunistic behavior. We also provide evidence that announcement timing is affected by internal corporate governance. Recent regulations that tightened firms' governance are associated with a significant shift to announcing outside trading hours, especially for firms with better corporate governance. Our surveys of corporate managers corroborate these results.</description><author>Michaely, Roni; Rubin, Amir; Vedrashko, Alexander</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Life-Cycle Portfolios for Heterogeneous Workers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bagliano, Fabio C.; Fugazza, Carolina; Nicodano, Giovanna
Household portfolios include risky bonds, beyond stocks, and respond to permanent labor income shocks. This article brings these features into a life-cycle setting, and shows that optimal stock investment is constant or increasing in age before retirement for realistic parameter combinations. The driver of such inversion in the life-cycle profile is the resolution of uncertainty regarding social security pension, which increases the investor's risk appetite. This occurs if a small positive contemporaneous correlation between permanent labor income shocks and stock returns is matched by a realistically high degree of risk aversion. Absent this combination, the typical downward-sloping profile obtains. Overlooking differences in optimal investment profiles across heterogeneous workers results in large welfare losses, in the order of 15-30% of lifetime consumption.</description><author>Bagliano, Fabio C.; Fugazza, Carolina; Nicodano, Giovanna</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predatory Short Selling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brunnermeier, Markus K.; Oehmke, Martin
Financial institutions may be vulnerable to predatory short selling. When the stock of a financial institution is shorted aggressively, leverage constraints imposed by short-term creditors can force the institution to liquidate long-term investments at fire sale prices. For financial institutions that are sufficiently close to their leverage constraints, predatory short-selling equilibria coexist with no-liquidation equilibria (the vulnerability region) or may even be the unique equilibrium outcome (the doomed region). Increased coordination among short sellers expands the doomed region, where liquidation is the unique equilibrium. Our model provides a potential justification for temporary restrictions on short selling of vulnerable institutions and can be used to assess recent empirical evidence on short-sale bans.</description><author>Brunnermeier, Markus K.; Oehmke, Martin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decomposing Euro-Area Sovereign Spreads: Credit and Liquidity Risks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Monfort, Alain; Renne, Jean-Paul
This article presents an intensity-based model of euro-area sovereign spreads. To identify liquidity-pricing effects, we exploit the information contained in the spreads between bonds issued by a German agency (KfW) and their sovereign counterparts. KfW's liabilities being guaranteed by the German government, these spreads are essentially liquidity-driven. Liquidity effects are found to account for a sizeable share of spreads' fluctuations. After having filtered risk premiums out of the spreads, we estimate the physical default probabilities of eleven countries. Physical probabilities of default are lower than risk-neutral ones, consistently with the existence of a nondiversifiable euro-area sovereign credit risk.</description><author>Monfort, Alain; Renne, Jean-Paul</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Once Burned, Twice Shy? Financial Literacy and Wealth Losses during the Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bucher-Koenen, Tabea; Ziegelmeyer, Michael
The recent financial crisis caused a shock to private wealth. Households with low financial literacy are less likely to own risky assets directly. Therefore, fewer of them report financial losses. More importantly, financially illiterate households are more prone to sell assets that have lost in value. Thereby losses become permanent, and these households do not participate in markets' resurgence. This flight from risky assets is persistent-the financial crisis may prove to be a traumatic experience that shapes investment behavior and gives rise to serious distributional consequences, as households with lower financial literacy face lower returns in the long run.</description><author>Bucher-Koenen, Tabea; Ziegelmeyer, Michael</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collective Action Clauses for the Eurozone</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bradley, Michael; Gulati, Mitu
One of the primary policy initiatives instituted in response to the Eurozone sovereign debt crisis is a requirement that all Eurozone sovereign bonds issued after January 1 2013 include provisions referred to as Collective Action Clauses or CACs. These CACs allow for a super-majority of creditors to impose restructuring terms on minority holdouts. This article assesses the likely effect of this proposal on the borrowing costs of sovereign debtors. Contrary to much of the literature, we find that the presence of CACs leads to a lower cost of capital, especially for below-investment grade bonds.</description><author>Bradley, Michael; Gulati, Mitu</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hidden Costs of Hidden Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almenberg, Johan; Karapetyan, Artashes
We argue that salience-the extent to which a cost is visible and difficult to ignore-may have economically significant effects on homeowners' borrowing behavior, through a bias toward less salient but more expensive loans. We first use a simple model to show that the presence of some biased consumers in the market will affect equilibrium prices. Next, we show that market data support the predictions of the model. We conduct several robustness checks to address unobserved heterogeneity. The observed effect is large. We finally report a survey evidence consistent with this bias.</description><author>Almenberg, Johan; Karapetyan, Artashes</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bargaining with Venture Capitalists: When Should Entrepreneurs Show their Financial Muscle?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Renucci, Antoine
In this article, I model bargaining between an entrepreneur and a venture capitalist over the profits from an investment project. I show that, conditional on venture capital being available, more personal wealth, even if it is not invested in the project, helps the entrepreneur capture a larger fraction of the profits. I also show that access to bank financing can preclude access to venture capital. This occurs when bank financing works as a lever that raises the fraction of the profits the entrepreneur demands up to a level that is not incentive compatible with initiative from the venture capitalist.</description><author>Renucci, Antoine</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systematic Trading Behavior and the Cross-Section of Stock Returns on the OMXH</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leung, Henry; Rose, Annica; Westerholm, P. Joakim
Signed small trade turnover (SSTT) measures temporary uninformed buy or sell pressure that is initiated by small trades in the same direction. Using Nasdaq OMX Helsinki tick-by-tick trade data with known investor category, we confirm that SSTT is a robust proxy for uninformed trading. In the short term (1-3 months), stocks with a high proportion of signed small trades outperform, but in the medium (4-6 months) and long term (7-36 months), SSTT by individual investors has a negative correlation to stock returns, while SSTT by institutional investors and foreign nominees is not related to stock returns. Systematic trading behavior appears to better explain the excess return generated by the low SSTT portfolio relative to the high SSTT portfolio when compared to traditional risk factors in the CAPM and Fama-French models. In the aggregate, small trades are noise in the spirit of Kyle (1985) and Black (1986), but small trade behavior impacts the performance of individuals and not the performance of institutions. Large trades by both individuals and institutions perform better in the intermediate and long term, which lends some credibility to the practice of classifying larger trades as informed, but our results show that these trades are not always by institutions.</description><author>Leung, Henry; Rose, Annica; Westerholm, P. Joakim</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cautiousness, Skewness Preference, and the Demand for Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, James; Stapleton, Richard
In this article we establish cautiousness as a new downside risk aversion measure, using a portfolio problem with a risk-free bond, a stock, and an option. We show that, an investor has higher cautiousness (i) if and only if she is always more likely to buy the option; and (ii) if and only if she always demands more options per share. As an option's payoff is a convex function, increasing positions in the option increases the convexity of a portfolio, which leads to an increase in skewness. Thus the results in this article establish the link between cautiousness and skewness preference.</description><author>Huang, James; Stapleton, Richard</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling Market Downside Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feunou, Bruno; Jahan-Parvar, Mohammad R.; Tedongap, Romeo
We propose a new methodology for modeling and estimating time-varying downside risk and upside uncertainty in equity returns and for assessment of risk-return trade-off in financial markets. Using the salient features of the binormal distribution, we explicitly relate downside risk and upside uncertainty to conditional heteroskedasticity and asymmetry through binormal GARCH (BiN-GARCH) model. Based on S&amp;P 500 and international index returns, we find strong empirical support for existence of significant relative downside risk, and robust positive relationship between relative downside risk and conditional mode.</description><author>Feunou, Bruno; Jahan-Parvar, Mohammad R.; Tedongap, Romeo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Interactions Between Interest-Rate and Credit Risk: Theory and Evidence on the Credit Default Swap Term Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Ren-Raw; Cheng, Xiaolin; Wu, Liuren
This paper examines the interaction between default risk and interest-rate risk in determining the term structure of credit default swap spreads at different industry sectors and credit-rating classes. The paper starts with a parsimonious three-factor interest-rate dynamic term structure and projects the credit spread at each industry sector and rating class to these interest-rate factors while also allowing the projection residual dynamics to depend on the level of the interest-rate factors. Estimation shows that credit risk exhibits intricate dynamic interactions with the interest-rate factors.</description><author>Chen, Ren-Raw; Cheng, Xiaolin; Wu, Liuren</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How the 52-Week High and Low Affect Option-Implied Volatilities and Stock Return Moments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Driessen, Joost; Lin, Tse-Chun; Van Hemert, Otto
We provide a new perspective on option and stock price behavior around 52-week highs and lows. We analyze whether option-implied volatilities (IVs) change when stock prices approach or break through their 52-week high or low. We also study the effects of highs and lows on a stock's beta and return volatility. We find that IVs and stock betas decrease when approaching a high or low, and that volatilities increase after breakthroughs. The effects are economically large and significant. The approach results can be explained by the anchoring theory. The breakthrough results are consistent with anchoring and the investor attention hypothesis.</description><author>Driessen, Joost; Lin, Tse-Chun; Van Hemert, Otto</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Theory of Net Debt and Transferable Human Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lambrecht, Bart M.; Pawlina, Grzegorz
Traditional theories of capital structure do not explain the puzzling phenomena of zero-leverage firms and negative net debt ratios. We develop a theory where firms adopt a net debt target that acts as a balancing variable between equityholders and managers. Negative (positive) net debt occurs in human (physical) capital intensive industries. Negative net debt arises because tradeable claims cannot be issued against transferable human capital. Heterogeneity in capital structure occurs when firms have debt that is not fully collateralized. Physical capital intensive firms take on high leverage but may underlever to avoid bankruptcy costs. This creates excess rents for managers (even if the supply of human capital is competitive) because wealth constraints prevent managers from coinvesting.</description><author>Lambrecht, Bart M.; Pawlina, Grzegorz</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Payout Policy Choices and Shareholder Investment Horizons</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gaspar, Jose-Miguel; Massa, Massimo; Matos, Pedro; Patgiri, Rajdeep; Rehman, Zahid
This paper examines how shareholder investment horizons influence payout policy choices. The authors infer institutional shareholders' investment horizons using the churn rate of their overall stock portfolios prior to the payout decision. The authors find that the frequency and amount of repurchases increases with ownership by short-term investors to the detriment of dividends. They also find that the market reacts less positively to repurchase announcements made by firms held by short-term institutions. These findings are consistent with a model in which undervalued firms signal their value through repurchases, but firms held by short-term investors make repurchases more often because those investors care mostly about the short-term price reaction. Hence, the market rationally discounts the signal provided by such repurchases. Our findings suggest that shorter shareholder investment horizons might be one contributing factor to the increasing popularity of buybacks.</description><author>Gaspar, Jose-Miguel; Massa, Massimo; Matos, Pedro; Patgiri, Rajdeep; Rehman, Zahid</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Financing Constraints on Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Huidan; Paravisini, Daniel
We provide evidence on the causal link between financing constraints and the risk of corporate cash flows and returns. For identification, we compare public US firms in the same industry, location, and size quintile, but whose access to bank credit was differentially affected by WorldCom's demise in 2002. A credit shortage induces a permanent increase in the volatility and skewness of operating cash flows and an increase in the correlation between firm stock and market returns. We document how firms' cash, payout, and investment policies respond endogenously to mitigate the impact of constraints on risk.</description><author>Lin, Huidan; Paravisini, Daniel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comovement of Newly Added Stocks with National Market Indices: Evidence from Around the World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Claessens, Stijn; Yafeh, Yishay
We document increased stock price comovement for companies added to major indices around the world. Using data on forty developed and emerging markets for 10 years, we find that in most markets, when added to a major index, firms experience an increase in their beta (especially if their pre-inclusion beta is low) and in the extent to which market returns explain firm stock returns (R-2). Stock turnover and analyst coverage also typically increase upon inclusion. Various empirical tests suggest that the category/habitat views of Barberis, Shleifer and Wurgler explain most of these results, although information-related factors also account for some findings.</description><author>Claessens, Stijn; Yafeh, Yishay</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mortgage Market Design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, John Y.
This article explores the causes and consequences of cross-country variation in mortgage market structure. It draws on insights from several fields: urban economics, asset pricing, behavioral finance, financial intermediation, and macroeconomics. It discusses lessons from the credit boom, the challenges of mortgage modification in the aftermath of the boom, consumer financial protection, and alternative mortgage forms and funding models. The article argues that the USA has much to learn from mortgage finance in other countries, and specifically from the Danish implementation of the European covered bonds system.</description><author>Campbell, John Y.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bottom-Up Corporate Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Landier, Augustin; Sauvagnat, Julien; Sraer, David; Thesmar, David
This article empirically relates the internal organization of a firm with decision making quality and corporate performance. We call "independent from the CEO" a top executive who joined the firm before the current CEO was appointed. In a very robust way, firms with a smaller fraction of independent executives exhibit (1) a lower level of profitability and (2) lower shareholder returns following large acquisitions. These results are unaffected when we control for traditional governance measures such as board independence or other well-studied shareholder friendly provisions. One interpretation is that "independently minded" top ranking executives act as a counter-power imposing strong discipline on their CEO, even though they are formally under his authority.</description><author>Landier, Augustin; Sauvagnat, Julien; Sraer, David; Thesmar, David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Precautionary Hoarding of Liquidity and Interbank Markets: Evidence from the Subprime Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Merrouche, Ouarda
We study the liquidity demand of large settlement banks in the UK and its effect on the money markets before and during the subprime crisis of 2007-08. We find that the liquidity demand of large settlement banks experienced a 30% increase in the period immediately following August 9 2007, the day when money markets froze, igniting the crisis. Following this shift, liquidity demand had a precautionary nature in that it rose on days of high payment activity and for banks with greater credit risk. This caused overnight interbank rates to rise, an effect virtually absent in the precrisis period.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Merrouche, Ouarda</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Fundamentals of Commodity Futures Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorton, Gary B.; Hayashi, Fumio; Rouwenhorst, K. Geert
Commodity futures risk premiums vary across commodities and over time depending on the level of physical inventories. The convenience yield is a decreasing, nonlinear function of inventories. Price measures, such as the futures basis, prior futures returns, prior spot returns, and spot price volatilities reflect the state of inventories and are informative about commodity futures risk premiums. We verify these theoretical predictions using a comprehensive data set on 31 commodity futures and physical inventories between 1971 and 2010. We find no evidence that the positions of participants in futures markets predict risk premiums on commodity futures.</description><author>Gorton, Gary B.; Hayashi, Fumio; Rouwenhorst, K. Geert</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The World Business Cycle and Expected Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, Ilan; Priestley, Richard
We study the predictability of stock returns using a pure macroeconomic measure of the world business cycle, namely the world's capital to output ratio. This variable tracks variation in expected stock returns in a group of the major industrial economies in the presence of world financial market-based predictor variables. The world's capital to output ratio exhibits strong out-of-sample predictive power in almost all countries studied. This is in contrast to financial market-based variables that almost never have out-of-sample forecasting power. Using the stock return predictability that we uncover, we find that international versions of conditional asset pricing models perform well. The world capital to output ratio also predicts bond returns, interest rate changes, and credit spreads. The results highlight the importance of world business conditions for financial markets.</description><author>Cooper, Ilan; Priestley, Richard</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Three Solutions to the Pricing Kernel Puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hens, Thorsten; Reichlin, Christian
The pricing kernel is an important link between economics and finance. In standard models of financial economics, it is proportional to the aggregate marginal utility in the economy. We first show that none of the three standard assumptions (completeness, risk aversion, and correct beliefs) is needed for the pricing kernel to be generally decreasing. If at least one of the three assumptions is violated, the pricing kernel can have increasing parts. We explain the economic principles that lead to an increasing part in the pricing kernel and compare the resulting pricing kernels with the empirical pricing kernel estimated in Jackwerth (2000, Rev. Financ. Stud., 13, 433-451).</description><author>Hens, Thorsten; Reichlin, Christian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Do Managers Seek Private Equity Backing in Public-to-Private Transactions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fidrmuc, Jana P.; Palandri, Alessandro; Roosenboom, Peter; van Dijk, Dick
Managers have the choice to take the firm private themselves in a management buyout or to seek private equity backing. We argue that managers seek private equity backing in case they are more constrained to finance the deal themselves. We confirm the hypothesis using a sample of UK public-to-private transactions over the period 1997-2003. A post going private performance analysis reveals that both management buyouts and private equity backed deals outperform their industry peers. However, private equity backed deals outperform their peers already before the deal takes place whereas management buyouts improve performance afterwards. This suggests a passive role for private equity firms in going private transactions.</description><author>Fidrmuc, Jana P.; Palandri, Alessandro; Roosenboom, Peter; van Dijk, Dick</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gender and Banking: Are Women Better Loan Officers?*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beck, Thorsten; Behr, Patrick; Guettler, Andre
Using a unique data set for a commercial bank in Albania, we analyze gender differences in loan officers' performance. Loans screened and monitored by female loan officers have a lower likelihood to turn problematic than loans handled by male loan officers. This effect cannot be explained by borrower or loan officer selection or differences in screening, work load, and experience. However, while the performance gap always exists for female borrowers, female loan officers only gain a performance advantage with male borrowers with experience and do not have an advantage with borrowers that are legal entities. We therefore interpret this as suggestive evidence for female loan officers' better capacity to build trust relationships with borrowers.</description><author>Beck, Thorsten; Behr, Patrick; Guettler, Andre</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who takes Risks When and Why: Determinants of Changes in Investor Risk Taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weber, Martin; Weber, Elke U.; Nosic, Alen
Between September 08 and June 09, a period with significant market events, we surveyed UK online-brokerage customers at 3-month intervals for their willingness to take risk, 3-month expectations of returns and risks for the market and their own portfolio, and self-reported risk attitude. This unique dataset allowed us to analyze how these variables changed over time, and whether changes in risk taking were related to changes in expectations and/or risk attitudes. Risk taking changed substantially during the period, as did return and risk expectations. Numeric assessments of return and risk expectations were only weakly correlated with corresponding subjective judgments. Consistent with the risk-as-feelings hypothesis, changes in risk taking were associated with changes in subjective expectations of market portfolio risk and returns, but less with changes in numeric expectations.</description><author>Weber, Martin; Weber, Elke U.; Nosic, Alen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Pumping, Trading Activity and Fund Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharyya, Sugato; Nanda, Vikram
We develop a model of trading by an informed fund manager compensated on the basis of her fund's Net Asset Value (NAV). We show that she has an incentive to pump her portfolio by buying securities she already holds. Pumping leads to excessive trading and hurts long-term fund performance. It also biases upward measured NAVs and contributes to closed-end fund discounts. Despite such costs, it may still be optimal to base her compensation on NAV.</description><author>Bhattacharyya, Sugato; Nanda, Vikram</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Sentiment and Return Comovements: Evidence from Stock Splits and Headquarters Changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Alok; Page, Jeremy K.; Spalt, Oliver G.
We examine whether the trading activities of retail and institutional investors cause comovements in stock returns. Around stock splits, retail trading correlations (RTCs) decrease with stocks in the presplit price range and increase with stocks in the post-split price range. These shifts in RTCs induce changes in return comovements. In the cross section, return comovements among low-priced stocks are amplified when retail trades are more correlated and when aggregate uncertainty amplifies behavioral biases. We find similar patterns among local stocks and when firms change their corporate headquarters. In contrast to retail trading, institutional trading attenuates return comovements.</description><author>Kumar, Alok; Page, Jeremy K.; Spalt, Oliver G.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Choice and Mental Health</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bogan, Vicki L.; Fertig, Angela R.
Close to 30% of the US population experiences at least one mental or substance abuse disorder each year. Given the prevalence of mental health issues, this paper analyzes the role of mental health and cognitive functioning in household portfolio choice decisions. Generally, we find that households affected by mental health issues decrease investments in risky instruments. Various mental health issues can reduce the probability of holding risky assets by up to 19%. Moreover, single women diagnosed with psychological disorders increase investments in safe assets. We also find that cognitive functioning issues are associated with an increase in financial assets devoted to retirement accounts.</description><author>Bogan, Vicki L.; Fertig, Angela R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Issuer Conservatism on IPO Pricing and Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferris, Stephen P.; Hao; Liao
Based on a textual analysis of initial public offering (IPO) prospectuses, we obtain a number of important findings regarding the relation between the conservatism in prospectuses, IPO pricing, and subsequent operating and stock return performance. First, prospectus conservatism is positively related to underpricing, with the relation more pronounced for technology than nontechnology firms. Second, for nontechnology IPOs, prospectus conservatism is able to predict the firm's post-IPO operating performance. Specifically, we find that conservatism is inversely related to the firm's operating performance for the 3 years following the IPO. However, this predictability is limited to nontechnology IPOs. Finally, we find some evidence that for nontechnology IPOs conservatism is inversely related to the firm's post-IPO abnormal stock return. We conclude that the conservatism contained in an IPO's prospectus contains useful information about pricing and subsequent operating and stock return performance. Moreover, prospectus conservatism for nontechnology IPOs deserves more attention from investors.</description><author>Ferris, Stephen P.; Hao; Liao</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge Funds and Equity Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiao, Yawen
This article analyzes hedge funds' expansion during 2000-09 and its implications for stock returns. Hedge funds more than doubled their equity ownership prior to the 2007-09 financial crisis. In this expansion period, their trading predicts increasing one-quarter-ahead stock returns and return reversals in the 2nd year. These reversals stem from the expansion of mature funds, while young funds' trading predicts one-quarter-ahead returns without future reversals. The above price pressures disappear when hedge funds shift to contractions in the financial crisis. These findings are consistent with mature funds' expansions exerting pressures on equities and young funds possessing stock picking skills.</description><author>Jiao, Yawen</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Selection and Welfare in a Multi-asset Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fedyk, Yurii; Heyerdahl-Larsen, Christian; Walden, Johan
We analyze the performance of irrational investors, who mistake expected returns of assets in a multi-asset economy. Mistakes by probabilistically unsophisticated investors that a priori seem small lead to severe underperformance compared with rational investors, under general conditions. Our results contrast with previous studies of single-asset economies, which find modest underperformance by irrational investors. In a calibration, an irrational investor who mistakes expected returns by 20% loses almost 95% of his consumption and wealth in about 25 years. The welfare cost of this underperformance is significant, about 40% of the total wealth in the economy.</description><author>Fedyk, Yurii; Heyerdahl-Larsen, Christian; Walden, Johan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sources of Momentum Profits: Evidence on the Irrelevance of Characteristics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bandarchuk, Pavel; Hilscher, Jens
Several recent studies document that sorting stocks first on certain stock-level characteristics and then on past returns results in elevated momentum profits. We show that such strategies enhance momentum profits simply by trading in stocks with more extreme past returns. Adjusted for this effect, elevated momentum profits resulting from characteristics (size, R-2, turnover, age, analyst coverage, analyst forecast dispersion, market-to-book, price, illiquidity, credit rating) disappear almost entirely. Interaction patterns have been used to support behavioral and limits-to-arbitrage explanations of momentum; our findings imply that explanations of momentum should instead focus on the link between momentum profits and extreme past returns.</description><author>Bandarchuk, Pavel; Hilscher, Jens</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity Issues and Return Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Larrain, Borja; Varas, Felipe
We show that the repurchaser-issuer return spread is stronger among stocks with high return volatility. Rational and behavioral theories predict that this finding is the product of risk volatility and sentiment volatility, respectively. However, our results are inconsistent with these theories as they currently stand. Loadings on standard risk factors do not follow the dynamics that would explain the return predictability related to issuance decisions. If we sort on a stock's beta with respect to the aggregate sentiment index of Baker and Wurgler (2006, J. Finance, 61, 1645-1680), which proxies for sentiment volatility, the results are weaker-economically and statistically-than when sorting on return volatility.</description><author>Larrain, Borja; Varas, Felipe</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evolutionary Beliefs and Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jouini, Elyes; Napp, Clotilde; Viossat, Yannick
Why do investors keep different opinions even though they learn from their own failures and successes? Why do investors keep different opinions even though they observe each other and learn from their relative failures and successes? We analyze beliefs dynamics when beliefs result from a very general learning process that favors beliefs leading to higher absolute or relative utility levels. We show that such a process converges to the Nash equilibrium in a game of strategic belief choices. The asymptotic beliefs are subjective and heterogeneous across the agents. Optimism (respectively overconfidence) as well as pessimism (respectively doubt) emerge from the learning process. Furthermore, we obtain a positive correlation between pessimism (respectively doubt) and risk tolerance. Under reasonable assumptions, beliefs exhibit a pessimistic bias and, as a consequence, the risk premium is higher than in a standard setting.</description><author>Jouini, Elyes; Napp, Clotilde; Viossat, Yannick</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional Investors as Minority Shareholders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hamdani, Assaf; Yafeh, Yishay
We examine the link between minority shareholders' rights and corporate governance by studying institutional investors' voting patterns in a concentrated ownership environment. Institutions rarely vote against insider-sponsored proposals even when the law empowers the minority. Institutions vote against compensation-related proposals more often than against related party transactions even when minority shareholders cannot influence outcomes. Potentially conflicted institutions are more likely to vote for insiders' proposals than stand-alone investors, regardless of their effect on outcomes. A plausible conclusion is that empowering minority shareholders affects the selection of proposals but not actual voting; another is that empowering minority shareholders is ineffective without addressing conflicts of interest.</description><author>Hamdani, Assaf; Yafeh, Yishay</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition, Bonuses, and Risk-taking in the Banking Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bannier, Christina E.; Feess, Eberhard; Packham, Natalie
Remuneration systems in the banking industry, in particular bonus payments, have frequently been blamed for contributing to the buildup of risks leading to the recent financial crisis. In our model, banks compete for managerial talent that is private information. Competition for talent sets incentives to offer bonuses inducing risk-taking that is excessive not only from society's perspective but also from the viewpoint of the banks themselves. In fact, bonus payments and excessive risk-taking are increasing with competition. Thus, our model offers a rationale why bonuses are paid even when reducing the expected profits of banks.</description><author>Bannier, Christina E.; Feess, Eberhard; Packham, Natalie</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Noise Trading and Illusory Correlations in US Equity Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bender, Jennifer C.; Osler, Carol L.; Simon, David
This paper provides evidence that "illusory correlations"-a well-documented source of cognitive bias-lead some agents to be imperfectly rational noise traders. We focus on the head-and-shoulders chart pattern, considered by technical analysts to provide one of the most reliable trading signals. Our findings indicate that the pattern is associated with a substantial rise in trading volume even though it does not profitably predict directional movements. We further substantiate the connection between head-and-shoulders trading and imperfectly rational noise trading by showing that the pattern is associated with lower bid-ask spreads.</description><author>Bender, Jennifer C.; Osler, Carol L.; Simon, David</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance Evaluation and Financial Market Runs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wagner, Wolf
This paper develops a model in which performance evaluation causes runs by fund managers and results in asset fire sales. Performance evaluation nonetheless is efficient as it disciplines managers. Optimal performance evaluation combines absolute and relative components in order to make runs less likely. When runs induce large price discounts, this requires a high degree of absolute performance evaluation and a low degree of relative performance evaluation. The overall costs of using performance evaluation are shown to be decreasing in asset liquidity, implying that more developed financial markets should have more delegation. However, such markets are not less prone to runs.</description><author>Wagner, Wolf</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Investors Suffer from Money Illusion? A Direct Test of the Modigliani-Cohn Hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acker, Daniella; Duck, Nigel W.
We propose a direct test of the explanation by Modigliani and Cohn (MC) for the positive correlation between inflation and equity values-that it results from investors' money illusion. This explanation, unlike its main rivals, suggests that because in inflationary periods dividends will, on average, be higher than expected, dividend announcements will trigger positive abnormal returns. These will be higher the higher the inflation, and the more levered the firm. The behavior of abnormal returns of US stocks on dividend-announcement days from 1955 to 2007 supports these predictions. We investigate alternative explanations of our results. None dominates MC's.</description><author>Acker, Daniella; Duck, Nigel W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Say on Pay Votes and CEO Compensation: Evidence from the UK</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferri, Fabrizio; Maber, David A.
We examine the effect of say on pay regulation in the UK. Consistent with the view that shareholders regard say on pay as a value-creating mechanism, the regulation's announcement triggered a positive stock price reaction at firms with weak penalties for poor performance. UK firms responded to negative say on pay voting outcomes by removing controversial CEO pay practices criticized as rewards for failure (e.g., generous severance contracts) and increasing the sensitivity of pay to poor realizations of performance.</description><author>Ferri, Fabrizio; Maber, David A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Determinants of Mutual Fund Performance: A Cross-Country Study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Keswani, Aneel; Miguel, Antonio F.; Ramos, Sofia B.
We use a new data set to study the determinants of the performance of open-end actively managed equity mutual funds in 27 countries. We find that mutual funds underperform the market overall. The results show important differences in the determinants of fund performance in the USA and elsewhere in the world. The US evidence of diminishing returns to scale is not a universal truth as the performance of funds located outside the USA and funds that invest overseas is not negatively affected by scale. Our findings suggest that the adverse scale effects in the USA are related to liquidity constraints faced by funds that, by virtue of their style, have to invest in small and domestic stocks. Country characteristics also explain fund performance. Funds located in countries with liquid stock markets and strong legal institutions display better performance.</description><author>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Keswani, Aneel; Miguel, Antonio F.; Ramos, Sofia B.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Payment Defaults and Interfirm Liquidity Provision</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boissay, Frederic; Gropp, Reint
Using a unique data set on French firms, we show that credit constrained firms that face liquidity shocks are more likely to default on their payments to suppliers. Credit constrained firms pass on a sizeable fraction of such shocks to their suppliers. This is consistent with the idea that firms provide liquidity insurance to each other and that this mechanism is able to alleviate credit constraints. We show that the chain of defaults stops when it reaches unconstrained firms. Liquidity appears to be allocated from firms with access to outside finance to credit constrained firms along supply chains.</description><author>Boissay, Frederic; Gropp, Reint</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Market Linkages, Manager Quality, and Mutual Fund Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Lixin; Kale, Jayant R.
Mutual funds typically invest a disproportionately large portion of their portfolio in one industry (main industry). We present a simple theoretical model to demonstrate that better mutual fund managers make larger investments in the important supplier/customer industries related to the main industry. Consistent with our theory, empirical tests on a large sample of mutual funds show that investment in related industries is positively associated with fund performance and plays a more significant role in explaining fund performance than investment in the main industry. Furthermore, the positive relation between main investment and fund performance obtains only when related investment is high.</description><author>Huang, Lixin; Kale, Jayant R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Irrationality or Efficiency of Macroeconomic Survey Forecasts? Implications from the Anchoring Bias Test</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hess, Dieter; Orbe, Sebastian
Recent findings indicate that macroeconomic survey forecasts are anchoring biased and therefore are inefficient. However, despite highly significant test coefficients, a bias adjustment does not improve forecasts' quality. We find that the cognitive bias is a statistical artifact because the anchoring test is biased itself. In particular, it produces misleading results if macroeconomic analysts use more comprehensive information than assumed by the test. Our results have important implications for a wide range of empirical research relying on survey data to capture market participants' expectations, for example, studies analyzing the impact of macroeconomic conditions on asset prices, equity risk premiums, or market liquidity.</description><author>Hess, Dieter; Orbe, Sebastian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Risk Sensitivity of Capital Requirements: Evidence from an International Sample of Large Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vallascas, Francesco; Hagendorff, Jens
Using an international sample of large banks between 2000 and 2010, we evaluate the risk sensitivity of minimum capital requirements. Our results show that risk-weighted assets (the regulatory measure of portfolio risk, which determines minimum capital requirements) are ill-calibrated to a market measure of bank portfolio risk. We show that this low-risk sensitivity of capital requirements permits banks to build up capital buffers by underreporting their portfolio risk and undermines banks' ability to withstand adverse shocks. While the risk sensitivity of capital requirements is higher for banks that have adopted Basel II, it remains low across banks and countries.</description><author>Vallascas, Francesco; Hagendorff, Jens</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Governance and Equity Prices: Does Transparency Matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gu, Lifeng; Hackbarth, Dirk
This article examines how accounting transparency and corporate governance interact. Firms with better governance are associated with higher abnormal returns, but even more so if they also have higher transparency. The effect is largely monotonic-it is small and insignificant for opaque firms and large and significant for transparent firms-and survives numerous robustness tests. We find supportive evidence for firm value and operating performance. Hence, governance and transparency are complements. This complementarity effect is consistent with the view that more transparent firms are more likely takeover targets, because acquirers can bid more effectively and identify synergies more precisely.</description><author>Gu, Lifeng; Hackbarth, Dirk</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk in Islamic Banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Abedifar, Pejman; Molyneux, Philip; Tarazi, Amine
This article investigates risk and stability features of Islamic banking using a sample of 553 banks from 24 countries between 1999 and 2009. Small Islamic banks that are leveraged or based in countries with predominantly Muslim populations have lower credit risk than conventional banks. In terms of insolvency risk, small Islamic banks also appear more stable. Moreover, we find little evidence that Islamic banks charge rents to their customers for offering Sharia-compliant financial products. Our results also show that loan quality of Islamic banks is less responsive to domestic interest rates compared to conventional banks.</description><author>Abedifar, Pejman; Molyneux, Philip; Tarazi, Amine</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Does Stock Ownership Breadth Measure?*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, James J.; Jin, Li; Yan, Hongjun
Using holdings data on a representative sample of all Shanghai Stock Exchange investors, we show that increases in ownership breadth (the fraction of market participants who own a stock) predict low returns: highest change quintile stocks underperform lowest quintile stocks by 23% per year. Small retail investors drive this result. Retail ownership breadth increases appear to be correlated with overpricing. Among institutional investors, however, the opposite holds: stocks in the top decile of wealth-weighted institutional breadth change outperform the bottom decile by 8% per year, consistent with prior work that interprets breadth as a measure of short-sales constraints.</description><author>Choi, James J.; Jin, Li; Yan, Hongjun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization and Compensation in Financial Institutions*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Inderst, Roman; Pfeil, Sebastian
We analyze the interaction between financial institutions' internal compensation policy, the quality of loans, and their securitization decision. We show when mandatory deferred bonus pay makes incentives more commensurate with the longer term risk of their transactions and hence improves the quality of loans. We also show when it has the opposite effect. We further analyze when mandatory deferred compensation can complement a policy that requires financial institutions to retain a minimum exposure to their originated loans, and we discuss the impact of a tax on short-term bonus pay. Generally, our framework allows us to study the interaction of financial institutions' internal agency problems with the external agency problem that arises from securitization.</description><author>Inderst, Roman; Pfeil, Sebastian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt and Capacity Commitments*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leach, J. Chris; Moyen, Nathalie; Yang, Jing
In capital-intensive industries, firms face complicated multi-staged financing, investment, and production decisions under the watchful eye of existing and potential industry rivals. In various representations of this environment, we show that a first-mover advantage in debt weakly dominates a first-mover advantage in capacity. Without a first-mover advantage in debt, the incumbent may suffer a dead-weight loss. When both the entrant and incumbent deploy debt prior to capacity, a first-mover in capacity benefits from softer competition. With a long-purse debt cost, leading in debt still remains advantageous.</description><author>Leach, J. Chris; Moyen, Nathalie; Yang, Jing</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Banks Benefit from Internationalization? Revisiting the Market Power-Risk Nexus*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buch, Claudia M.; Koch, Catherine T.; Koetter, Michael
We analyze the impact of bank internationalization on domestic market power (Lerner index) and risk for German banks. Risk is measured by the official declaration of regulatory authorities that a bank is distressed. We distinguish the volume of foreign assets, the number of foreign countries, and different modes of foreign entry. Our analysis has three main results. First, higher market power is associated with lower risk. Second, holding assets in many countries reduce market power at home, but banks with a higher share of foreign assets exhibit higher market power. Third, bank internationalization is only weakly related to bank risk.</description><author>Buch, Claudia M.; Koch, Catherine T.; Koetter, Michael</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Investments and Learning*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moyen, Nathalie; Platikanov, Stefan
Using age as a proxy for learning within a firm, we show that the investments of firms with younger projects react more to profit realizations. With time, firms learn about their long-term quality, and their investment decisions become less influenced by the random shocks they receive. We also show that the learning process depends on the volatility of the economic environment. In more volatile industries, firms observe more noise and less signal from profit realizations. Their investments are therefore less influenced by profits. These new empirical results are consistent with a Tobin's q framework augmented with Bayesian learning.</description><author>Moyen, Nathalie; Platikanov, Stefan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The "Fed Model" and the Predictability of Stock Returns*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maio, Paulo
The focus of this article is on the predictive role of the stock-bond yield gap-the difference between the stock market earnings (dividend) yield and the 10-year Treasury bond yield-also known as the "Fed model". The results show that the yield gap forecasts positive excess market returns, both at short and long forecasting horizons, and for both value- and equal-weighted stock indexes, and it also outperforms competing predictors commonly used in the literature. These findings go in line with the predictions from a present-value decomposition. The absence of predictive power for dividend growth, dividend payout ratios, earnings growth, and future one-period interest rates, actually strengthens the return predictability associated with the yield gap at very long horizons. By performing an out-of-sample analysis, the results show that the yield gap has reasonable out-of-sample predictability for the equity premium when the comparison is made against a simple historical average, especially when one imposes a restriction of positive equity premia. Furthermore, the yield gap proxies generally show greater out-of-sample forecasting power than the alternative state variables. An investment strategy based on the forecasting ability of the yield gap produces significant gains in Sharpe ratios.</description><author>Maio, Paulo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging Surprises, Jumps, and Model Misspecification: A Risk Management Perspective on Hedging S&amp;P 500 Options*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaeck, Andreas
This article provides comprehensive tests of alternative jump-diffusion models for the purpose of hedging S&amp;P 500 options. We explicitly take into account the risk arising from price and variance jumps and assess the hedging performance by focusing on the ability of competing specifications to forecast hedging errors. To this end, we devise density prediction tests and find evidence that jumps are important features of S&amp;P 500 index dynamics. All jump-diffusion models tested in this article show signs of misspecification, but the inclusion of jumps can improve the hedging performance and risk assessment, especially in two-instrument hedges.</description><author>Kaeck, Andreas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Public Equity Markets Matter in Emerging Economies? Evidence from India</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Gormley, Todd A.
Do public equity markets serve an unique role that is not easily served by other forms of financing in emerging economies? We analyze this question using the collapse of India's equity market in 1997, which provides an exogenous shock to firms' ability to issue equity. We find that both public and private firms exhibit higher bankruptcy rates and lower growth after 1997. The decline in growth is greater among firms with more external finance needs and fewer tangible assets. Overall, the evidence suggests that public equity markets are an important, not easily replaced, source of finance in emerging economies.</description><author>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Gormley, Todd A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading and Under-Diversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Anders
This article documents a link between trading and diversification by using detailed trading records from a Swedish discount broker matched with individual tax records. Diversification is measured by the investors' stake size, defined as the fraction of their risky financial wealth invested in individual stocks through the broker under study. High-stake investors have concentrated portfolios, trade more, and achieve lower trading performance. They share several features with those who trade excessively, namely lower income, wealth, age, and education, suggesting that they lack investment expertise. The results directly imply that trading losses in the cross-section are mainly borne by those who can least afford them.</description><author>Anderson, Anders</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Monthly Seasonals Real? A Three Century Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Cherry Y.; Jacobsen, Ben
Over 300 years of UK stock returns reveal that well-known monthly seasonals are sample specific. For instance, the January effect only emerges around 1830. Most months have had their 50 years of fame, showing the importance of long time series to safeguard against sample selection bias, noise, and data snooping. The overall conclusion is that monthly seasonals might simply be in the eye of the beholder.</description><author>Zhang, Cherry Y.; Jacobsen, Ben</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Working Capital Management and Shareholders' Wealth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kieschnick, Robert; Laplante, Mark; Moussawi, Rabih
We provide the first empirical study of the relationship between corporate working capital management and shareholders' wealth. Examining US corporations from 1990 through 2006, we find evidence that: the incremental dollar invested in net operating working capital is worth less than the incremental dollar held in cash for the average firm; the valuation of the incremental dollar invested in net operating working capital is significantly influenced by a firm's future sales expectations, its debt load, its financial constraints, and its bankruptcy risk; and the value of the incremental dollar extended in credit to one's customers has a greater effect on shareholders' wealth than the incremental dollar invested in inventories for the average firm.</description><author>Kieschnick, Robert; Laplante, Mark; Moussawi, Rabih</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Politically Connected Boards of Directors and The Allocation of Procurement Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldman, Eitan; Rocholl, Joerg; So, Jongil
This article analyzes whether political connections of the board of directors of publicly traded companies in the USA affect the allocation of government procurement contracts. It focuses on the change in control of both House and Senate following the 1994 election and finds that companies with boards connected to the winning (losing) party experience a significant and large increase (decrease) in procurement contracts after the election. The results remain significant after controlling for industry classifications as well as for several other company characteristics. The findings highlight one of the main avenues through which corporate political connections add value to US companies.</description><author>Goldman, Eitan; Rocholl, Joerg; So, Jongil</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real Option Value of Cash</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kisser, Michael
This article focuses on the idea that cash has a real option value and it presents an explicit valuation framework of cash holdings in the context of a capacity expansion option. The model characterizes the optimal dynamic cash retention policy, the value of internal funds, and it provides a model implied regression specification based on simulated data. Results imply that high cash flow volatility decreases the value of cash and that optimal cash retention can actually delay investment relative to the case of full outside financing. Both novel implications are confirmed by subsequent empirical tests.</description><author>Kisser, Michael</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do Firms Pay Dividends?: Evidence from an Early and Unregulated Capital Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Turner, John D.; Ye, Qing; Zhan, Wenwen
Why do firms pay dividends? To answer this question, we use a hand-collected data set of companies traded on the London stock market between 1825 and 1870. As tax rates were effectively zero, the capital market was unregulated, and there were no institutional stockholders, we can rule out these potential determinants ex ante. We find that, even though they were legal, share repurchases were not used by firms to return cash to shareholders. Instead, our evidence provides support for the information-communication explanation for dividends, while providing little support for agency, illiquidity, catering, or behavioral explanations.</description><author>Turner, John D.; Ye, Qing; Zhan, Wenwen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Venture Capital and Corporate Governance in the Newly Public Firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hochberg, Yael V.
I examine the effects of venture capital backing on the corporate governance of the entrepreneurial firm at the time of transition from private to public ownership. Using a selection model framework that instruments for venture backing with variations in the supply of venture capital, I conduct three sets of tests comparing corporate governance in venture- and non-venture-backed initial public offering (IPO) firms. Venture-backed firms have lower levels of earnings management, more positive reactions to the adoption of shareholder rights agreements, and more independent board structures than similar non-venture-backed firms, consistent with better governance. These effects are not common to all pre-IPO large shareholders.</description><author>Hochberg, Yael V.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Access to Liquidity and Corporate Investment in Europe during the Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campello, Murillo; Giambona, Erasmo; Graham, John R.; Harvey, Campbell R.
We use a unique data set to show how firms in Europe used credit lines during the financial crisis. We find that firms with restricted access to credit (small, private, non-investment-grade, and unprofitable) draw more funds from their credit lines during the crisis than their large, public, investment-grade, profitable counterparts. Interest spreads increased (especially in "market-based economies"), but commitment fees remained unchanged. Our findings suggest that credit lines did not dry up during the crisis and provided the liquidity that firms used to cope with this exceptional contraction. In particular, credit lines provided the liquidity companies needed to invest during the crisis.</description><author>Campello, Murillo; Giambona, Erasmo; Graham, John R.; Harvey, Campbell R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Nonfinancial Stakeholders Affect the Pricing of Risky Debt? Evidence from Unionized Workers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Huafeng; Kacperczyk, Marcin; Ortiz-Molina, Hernan
The authors study the impact of a powerful nonfinancial stakeholder-unionized workers-on the pricing of corporate debt. Firms in more unionized industries have lower bond yields. This relation is stronger in firms with weaker financial conditions and cannot be explained by the correlation of unionization with industry characteristics, governance mechanisms, or financial leverage. Firms in unionized industries implement less risky investment policies and are less likely targets of acquisitions. Unionization reduces yields by more when firms' takeover barriers are lower. Hence, unions are viewed favorably in the bond market because, through their influence on corporate affairs, they protect bondholders' wealth.</description><author>Chen, Huafeng; Kacperczyk, Marcin; Ortiz-Molina, Hernan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option-Implied Measures of Equity Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Bo-Young; Christoffersen, Peter; Jacobs, Kris; Vainberg, Gregory
Equity risk measured by beta is of great interest to both academics and practitioners. Existing estimates of beta use historical returns. Many studies have found option-implied volatility to be a strong predictor of future realized volatility. We find that option-implied volatility and skewness are also good predictors of future realized beta. Motivated by this finding, we establish a set of assumptions needed to construct a beta estimate from option-implied return moments using equity and index options. This beta can be computed using only option data on a single day. It is therefore potentially able to reflect sudden changes in the structure of the underlying company.</description><author>Chang, Bo-Young; Christoffersen, Peter; Jacobs, Kris; Vainberg, Gregory</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tying in Universal Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loranth, Gyoengyi; Morrison, Alan D.
This paper examines the tying of lending to investment banking business by universal banks. Tying may alleviate credit rationing by assuring the lender of an adequate share of the social surplus that its lending generates; however, tying raises the profitability of loans to troubled entrepreneurs, softening entrepreneurial budget constraints and reducing effort levels. When investment banking is uncompetitive, the former effect dominates, and there is too little tying; when investment banking is competitive, there is too much tying. We relate our results to the authority structure of the universal bank, which we argue is the appropriate focus for regulation.</description><author>Loranth, Gyoengyi; Morrison, Alan D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Theory of Strategic Mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernile, Gennaro; Lyandres, Evgeny; Zhdanov, Alexei
We examine firms' strategic incentives to engage in horizontal mergers. In a real options framework, we show that strategic considerations may explain abnormally high takeover activity during periods of positive and negative demand shocks. Importantly, this pattern emerges solely as a result of firms' strategic interaction in output markets. We show that the U-shaped relation between the state of demand and the propensity of firms to merge, documented in past studies, is driven by horizontal mergers in industries that are: (1) relatively more concentrated, (2) characterized by relatively strong competitive interaction among firms, and (3) characterized by relatively low merger-related operating synergies and restructuring costs. The empirical evidence, based on parametric and semi-parametric regression analyses, is consistent with these predictions.</description><author>Bernile, Gennaro; Lyandres, Evgeny; Zhdanov, Alexei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>