<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>RF2</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>The Dynamics of Going Public</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bustamante, M. Cecilia
This paper develops a real options model in which firms may use the timing of their initial public offerings (IPOs) to signal the quality of their investment prospects to outside investors. When adverse selection is more relevant (cold markets), firms with better investment prospects accelerate their IPO relative to their perfect information benchmark to reveal their type to outside investors. When adverse selection is less relevant (hot markets), all firms issue simultaneously, issuers are younger on average, and IPO timing is uninformative. An extension with multiple signals and the empirical evidence show that better ranked firms are younger, issue a lower fraction of shares, and underprice more during cold markets, and that issuers are younger on average during hot markets.</description><author>Bustamante, M. Cecilia</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Asymmetry, Information Precision, and the Cost of Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lambert, Richard A.; Leuz, Christian; Verrecchia, Robert E.
This paper examines the relation between information differences across investors (i.e., information asymmetry) and the cost of capital and establishes that with perfect competition information asymmetry makes no difference. Instead, a firm's cost of capital is governed solely by the average precision of investors' information. With imperfect competition, however, information asymmetry affects the cost of capital even after controlling for investors' average precision. In other words, the capital market's degree of competition plays a critical role for the relation between information asymmetry and the cost of capital. This point is important to empirical research in finance and accounting.</description><author>Lambert, Richard A.; Leuz, Christian; Verrecchia, Robert E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Drives Market Share in the Mutual Fund Industry?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khorana, Ajay; Servaes, Henri
This article examines competition and investor behavior in the mutual fund industry for the universe of US mutual funds during 1976-2009. Over this period, industry assets increased by a factor of 200, the number of active fund families quadrupled, and the average market share of a family declined by four-fifths. We find that price competition and product differentiation are both effective strategies in obtaining market share. Families that pass along economies of scale to investors and those that charge lower fees than the competition gain market share, but only if these fees are above average to begin with. Loads and 12b-1 fees, however, have a positive effect on market share, consistent with the use of these types of fees for marketing and distribution. Families that perform better, offer a wider range of products, and start more funds relative to the competition (a measure of innovation) also have a higher market share. Innovation is rewarded more if the new fund is more differentiated from existing offerings. Overall, our evidence suggests that mutual fund families compete effectively along both price and non-price dimensions.</description><author>Khorana, Ajay; Servaes, Henri</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining Corporate Capital Structure: Product Markets, Leases, and Asset Similarity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rauh, Joshua D.; Sufi, Amir
Better measurement of the output produced and capital employed by firms substantially improves the ability to explain capital structure variation in the cross section. For every firm, we construct the set of other films producing the same output using the set of product market competitors listed in the firm's public Securities and Exchange Commission filings. In addition, we improve measurement of capital structure by explicitly accounting for leased capital. These two steps increase the explanatory power of the average capital structure of other firms producing similar output on a firm's capital structure by 50% compared to using only the average unadjusted debt ratio of other firms in the same three-digit Standard Industrial Classification (SIC) code. We provide evidence that the large explanatory power of the capital structure of other firms producing similar output is related to the assets used in the production process. Our findings suggest that what a firm produces and the assets used in production are the most important determinants of capital structure in the cross section.</description><author>Rauh, Joshua D.; Sufi, Amir</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Dynamics of Venture Capital Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bienz, Carsten; Hirsch, Julia
Using a detailed German data set on venture capital contracts, the authors document that contracts between venture capitalists (VC) and their portfolio firms specify more complete conditions for future financing for firms that do have no suitable outside financing option and therefore lower ex post bargaining power. The authors' result is consistent with theories of holdup, where complete contracts protect the entrepreneur from expropriation by the financier. Moreover, there is evidence of learning by VCs. Other possible explanations for observed contracts, such as multitasking or coordination costs, instead have little explanation power.</description><author>Bienz, Carsten; Hirsch, Julia</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Venture Capital Syndication in Value Creation for Entrepreneurial Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tian, Xuan
This paper provides evidence that venture capital (VC) syndication creates value for entrepreneurial firms in two dimensions. First, VC syndication creates product market value for their portfolio firms. Specifically, VC syndicates invest significant amounts in younger firms, in earlier financing rounds, and in early stage firms. Further, VC syndicates nurture innovation of their portfolio firms and help them achieve better post-initial public offering operating performance. Second, VC syndication creates financial market value for their portfolio firms. Specifically, VC syndicate-backed firms are more likely to have a successful exit, enjoy a lower initial public offering (IPO) underpricing, and receive a higher IPO market valuation. The findings are robust to a variety of alternative syndication measures, subsamples, econometric models, and controlling for endogeneity in VC syndication.</description><author>Tian, Xuan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Markets Equilibrium with Heterogeneous Agents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cvitanic, Jaksa; Jouini, Elyes; Malamud, Semyon; Napp, Clotilde
This paper presents an equilibrium model in a pure exchange economy when investors have three possible sources of heterogeneity. Investors may differ in their beliefs, in their level of risk aversion, and in their time preference rate. The authors study the impact of investors' heterogeneity on equilibrium properties and, in particular, on the consumption shares, the market price of risk, the risk-free rate, the bond prices at different maturities, the stock price and volatility as well as on the stock's cumulative returns, and optimal portfolio strategies. The authors relate the heterogeneous economy with the family of associated homogeneous economies with only one class of investors. Cross-sectional as well as long-run properties are analyzed.</description><author>Cvitanic, Jaksa; Jouini, Elyes; Malamud, Semyon; Napp, Clotilde</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility in Equilibrium: Asymmetries and Dynamic Dependencies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollerslev, Tim; Sizova, Natalia; Tauchen, George
Stock market volatility clusters in time, appears fractionally integrated, carries a risk premium, and exhibits asymmetric leverage effects. At the same time, the volatility risk premium, defined by the difference between the risk-neutral and objective expectations of the volatility, features short memory. This paper develops the first internally consistent equilibrium-based explanation for all these empirical facts. Using newly available high-frequency intraday data for the S&amp;P 500 and the VIX volatility index, the authors show that the qualitative implications from the new theoretical continuous-time model match remarkably well with the distinct shapes and patterns in the sample autocorrelations and dynamic cross-correlations actually observed in the data.</description><author>Bollerslev, Tim; Sizova, Natalia; Tauchen, George</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Disciplines Bank Managers?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schaeck, Klaus; Cihak, Martin; Maechler, Andrea; Stolz, Stephanie
We exploit a unique data set of executive turnovers in community banks to test the micro-mechanisms of discipline by examining the monitoring and influencing role of different stakeholders. We find executives are more likely to be dismissed in risky institutions. Examining the roles of shareholders, debtholders, and regulators as monitors, we obtain evidence for shareholder discipline. However, there is no evidence that risk affects dismissals more if debtholders have a larger stake in the bank or when regulators are aware of distress. Examining the roles of shareholders, debtholders, and regulators as monitors, we obtain evidence for shareholder discipline. However, there is no evidence that risk affects dismissals more if debtholders have a larger stake in the bank or when regulators are aware of distress. When we analyze risk, losses, and profitability following turnovers, we obtain no evidence that replacing executives improves performance.</description><author>Schaeck, Klaus; Cihak, Martin; Maechler, Andrea; Stolz, Stephanie</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash Savings and Stock Price Informativeness*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fresard, Laurent
This paper shows that managers use the information they learn from the stock market when they decide on corporate cash savings. In particular, corporate savings are much more sensitive to stock price when the price contains more information that is new to managers. Moreover, the significant effect of stock price informativeness on the savings-to-price sensitivity is not due to market mispricings and remains even after controlling for various sources of public and managerial private information. Overall, the results highlight a new channel through which the stock market affects corporate decisions, which suggests that the stock market is not a sideshow.</description><author>Fresard, Laurent</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Trading Volume Impact of Local Bias: Evidence from a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jacobs, Heiko; Weber, Martin
Exploiting regional holidays in Germany as a source of exogenous cross-sectional variation in investor attention, we provide evidence that the well-known local bias at the individual level materially affects stock turnover at the firm level. Stocks of firms located in holiday regions are temporarily strikingly less traded than otherwise very similar stocks in non-holiday regions. This negative turnover shock survives comprehensive tests for differences in information release. It appears particularly pronounced in stocks less visible to nonlocal investors and for smaller stocks disproportionately driven by retail investors. Our findings contribute to research on local bias, trading activity, and investor distraction.</description><author>Jacobs, Heiko; Weber, Martin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Default Risk of Advanced Economies: An Empirical Analysis of Credit Default Swaps during the Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dieckmann, Stephan; Plank, Thomas
Prices observed in the European sovereign credit default swap (CDS) market have severely increased since the beginning of the financial crisis. We document that the state of a country's financial system and, since the beginning of the crisis, also the state of the world financial system have strong explanatory power for the behavior of CDS spreads, and the magnitude of this impact depends on the importance of a country's financial system pre-crisis. Furthermore, Economic and Monetary Union member countries exhibit higher sensitivities to the health of the financial system. Our results suggest the presence of a private-to-public risk transfer through which market participants incorporate their expectations about financial industry bailouts.</description><author>Dieckmann, Stephan; Plank, Thomas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium Implications of Delegated Asset Management under Benchmarking*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leippold, Markus; Rohner, Philippe
Despite the enormous growth of the asset management industry during the past decades, little is known about the asset pricing implications of investment intermediaries. Standard models of investment theory neither address the distinction between individual and institutional investors nor the potential implications of direct investing and delegated investing. In a model with endogenous delegation, the authors find that delegation leads to a more informative price system and lower equity premia. In the presence of relative return objectives, stocks exhibiting high correlations with the benchmark have significantly lower returns than stocks with low correlations. The authors' empirical results support the model's predictions.</description><author>Leippold, Markus; Rohner, Philippe</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inducing Agents to Report Hidden Trades: A Theory of an Intermediary</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leitner, Yaron
When contracts are unobserved (and nonexclusive), agents can promise the same asset to multiple counterparties and subsequently default. I show that a central mechanism can extract all relevant information about contracts that agents enter by inducing them to report one another. The mechanism sets position limits and reveals the names of agents who hit the limits according to (voluntary) reports from their counterparties. This holds even if sending reports is costly and even if agents can collude. In some cases, an agent's position limit must be nonbinding in equilibrium. The mechanism has some features of a clearinghouse.</description><author>Leitner, Yaron</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Basel Accord and the Value of Bank Differentiation*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feess, Eberhard; Hege, Ulrich
The authors investigate optimal capital requirements in a model in which banks decide on their investment in credit scoring systems. The main result is that regulators should encourage sophisticated banks to keep their asset portfolios safe, while assets with high systematic risk should be concentrated in smaller banks. The proposed regulatory differentiation follows the Basel Accord's distinction between internal ratings-based approach and standard approach. Sophisticated banks should increase their equity capital relative to other banks, leading to further size differentiation. The moral hazard problem of banks misrepresenting their loan portfolio risk is analyzed, with the result that it induces stricter capital requirements.</description><author>Feess, Eberhard; Hege, Ulrich</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private Equity Fund Size, Investment Size, and Value Creation*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Humphery-Jenner, Mark
This paper examines why large private equity (PE) funds earn lower returns. The article argues that large PE funds are suited to making large investments and small PE funds are suited to nurturing start-ups. Thus, the suboptimal investment in small companies is one driver of the size effect in PE. A theoretical model and empirical results from a sample of 1,222 funds in the USA support this prediction. The largest 25% of PE funds earn internal rates of return of 5.17% when they invest in the largest 25% of companies but only -2.98% when they invest in the smallest 25%. This suggests that investment size is a driver of the size effect in PE.</description><author>Humphery-Jenner, Mark</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the Real Rate Conundrum: An Application of No-Arbitrage Models to the UK Real Yield Curve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Joyce, Michael A. S.; Kaminska, Iryna; Lildholdt, Peter
During 2004 and 2005, long-horizon interest rates fell sharply in major international government bond markets (Greenspan's "conundrum"). This common fall mainly reflected lower long real rates. To investigate possible causes, the authors apply a no-arbitrage affine modeling framework to understanding the UK real term structure. The authors find that time-varying term premia are important in explaining movements in long real forward rates. And, although there is evidence that long-horizon expected short real rates declined over the conundrum period, the authors' results suggest that lower term premia played the dominant role. This could be consistent with the so-called "search for yield" and excess liquidity explanations for the conundrum.</description><author>Joyce, Michael A. S.; Kaminska, Iryna; Lildholdt, Peter</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Euro-Zone Equity Returns: Country versus Industry Effects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eiling, Esther; Gerard, Bruno; De Roon, Frans A.
This paper uses style analysis to investigate whether Euro-zone equity returns are driven by country or industry effects over the 1990-2008 period. We find that before the introduction of the Euro, country effects dominate, while industry effects prevail after 1999. This reversal is driven mainly by the countries that were least integrated in the Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) and world markets in the early 1990s and for which the EMU convergence process led to rapid strengthening of linkages with the core Euro-zone. For markets with stronger economic linkages, industry effects dominate both before and after the introduction of the Euro.</description><author>Eiling, Esther; Gerard, Bruno; De Roon, Frans A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the Partial Adjustment Model a Useful Tool for Capital Structure Research?*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hovakimian, Armen; Li, Guangzhong
Recent research has focused on the estimates of the speed of adjustment to target leverage as the indicators of the importance of dynamic trade-off behavior. We show that the observed corporate financing behavior and the resulting dynamics of corporate debt ratios are such that the speed of adjustment is not an economically meaningful measure of the importance of target debt ratios. We conclude that partial adjustment regressions that rely on the existence of a well-defined target debt ratio are ill-suited for quantifying the importance of dynamic trade-off behavior vis-a-vis alternative theories.</description><author>Hovakimian, Armen; Li, Guangzhong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Gambling Preference and the New Year Effect of Assets with Lottery Features*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doran, James S.; Jiang, Danling; Peterson, David R.
This paper shows that a New Year's gambling preference of individual investors impacts prices and returns of assets with lottery features. January call options, especially the out-of-the-money calls, have higher retail demand and are the most expensive and actively traded. Lottery-type stocks outperform their counterparts in January but tend to underperform in other months. Retail sentiment is more bullish in lottery-type stocks in January than in other months. Furthermore, lottery-type Chinese stocks outperform in the Chinese New Year's Month but not in January. This New Year effect provides new insights into the broad phenomena related to the January effect.</description><author>Doran, James S.; Jiang, Danling; Peterson, David R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structure and Determinants of Financial Covenants in Leveraged Buyouts*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Achleitner, Ann-Kristin; Braun, Reiner; Hinterramskogler, Bastian; Tappeiner, Florian
The authors use proprietary loan contracts and financial information negotiated between banks and private equity sponsors to explore the financial covenant structure and the determinants of covenant restrictiveness in a large set of leveraged buyouts. With respect to the covenant structure, we analyze the utilized types of financial covenants in sponsored loans and in comparable nonsponsored loans, such as highly levered term loans or loans used toward M&amp;A. The authors find that sponsored loans show less variation in the included types and combinations of covenants and include more financial covenants than the comparable nonsponsored loans. With respect to covenant restrictiveness, the authors measure precisely the distance between threshold and financial forecast. They show that two competing mechanisms, reduced information asymmetry costs and increased financial risk, affect the restrictiveness in sponsored loans.</description><author>Achleitner, Ann-Kristin; Braun, Reiner; Hinterramskogler, Bastian; Tappeiner, Florian</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Examination of Mutual Fund Timing Ability Using Monthly Holdings Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elton, Edwin J.; Gruber, Martin J.; Blake, Christopher R.
In this paper, the authors use monthly holdings to study timing ability. These data differ from holdings data used in previous studies in that the authors' data have a higher frequency and include a full range of securities, not just traded equities. Using a one-index model, the authors find, as do two recent studies, that management appears to have positive and statistically significant timing ability. When a multiindex model is used, the authors show that timing decisions do not result in an increase in performance, whether timing is measured using conditional or unconditional sensitivities. The authors show that sector rotation decisions with respect to high-tech stocks are a major contribution to negative timing.</description><author>Elton, Edwin J.; Gruber, Martin J.; Blake, Christopher R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Operating Leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Novy-Marx, Robert
I derive and test implications of the operating leverage hypothesis for the cross-section of expected returns. Using a novel measure of operating leverage, I document that operating leverage predicts returns in the cross-section, and that strategies formed by sorting on operating leverage earn significant excess returns. Operating leverage also explains why the value premium is weak and non-monotonic across industries, but strong and monotonic within industries. Intra-industry differences in book-to-market are driven by differences in operating leverage, giving rise to expected return differences. Industry differences in book-to-market are driven by differences in the capital intensity of production unrelated to returns.</description><author>Novy-Marx, Robert</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Approximate Equilibrium Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Restoy, Fernando; Weil, Philippe
Arguing that total consumer wealth is unobservable, we invert the (approximate) consumption function to reconstruct, in a world with Kreps-Porteus generalized isoelastic preferences, (i) the wealth that supports the agents' observed consumption as an optimal outcome and (ii) the rate of return on the consumers' wealth portfolio. This allows us to (approximately) price assets solely as a function of their payoffs and of consumption-in both homoskedastic or heteroskedastic environments. We compare implied equilibrium returns on the wealth portfolio to observed stock market returns and gauge whether the stock market is a good proxy for unobserved aggregate wealth.</description><author>Restoy, Fernando; Weil, Philippe</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finance and Efficiency: Do Bank Branching Regulations Matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Imbs, Jean; Sturgess, Jason
We document that the deregulation of bank branching restrictions in the United States triggered a reallocation across sectors, with end effects on state-level volatility. The change cannot be explained simply by shifts in sector-level returns and volatility. A reallocation effect is at play, which we study in the context of mean-variance portfolio theory applied to sectoral returns. We find the reallocation is particularly strong in sectors characterized by young, small and external finance dependent firms, and for states that have a larger share of such sectors. The findings suggest that improving bank access to branching affects the sectoral specialization of output, in a manner that depends on the variance-covariance properties of sectoral returns, rather than on their average only.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Imbs, Jean; Sturgess, Jason</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fear of the Unknown: Familiarity and Economic Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, H. Henry; Han, Bing; Hirshleifer, David; Zhang, Harold H.
Evidence indicates that people fear change and the unknown. We model this behavior as familiarity bias in which individuals focus on adverse scenarios in evaluating defections from the status quo. The model explains portfolio underdiversification, home and local biases. More importantly, equilibrium stock prices reflect an unfamiliarity premium. In an international setting, our model predicts that while the standard CAPM fails to hold with respect to the world market portfolio, a modified CAPM holds wherein the market portfolio is replaced with a portfolio of the stock holdings of investors not subject to familiarity bias.</description><author>Cao, H. Henry; Han, Bing; Hirshleifer, David; Zhang, Harold H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The External Financing of Emerging Markets-Evidence from Two Waves of Financial Globalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faria, Andre; Mauro, Paolo; Zaklan, Aleksandar
What determines the yields at which international investors are willing to lend to emerging market countries, and the amounts of such lending? We analyze the motivation underlying investors' choices in allocating their holdings across countries, through regressions for both prices (bond yields) and quantities (bond market capitalization or stocks of external liabilities) estimated during two waves of financial globalization (1870-1913 and today). The results suggest that, throughout the past one and a half centuries, a combination of human capital (including informal human capital) and institutional quality has been a key determinant of emerging market countries' ability to attract international investors.</description><author>Faria, Andre; Mauro, Paolo; Zaklan, Aleksandar</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Value and Growth Tilts in Long-Horizon Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jurek, Jakub W.; Viceira, Luis M.
We develop an analytical solution to the dynamic portfolio choice problem of an investor with power utility defined over wealth at a finite horizon, who faces a time-varying investment opportunity set, parameterized using a flexible vector autoregression. We apply this framework to study the horizon effects in the allocations of equity-only investors, who hold a mix of value and growth indices, and a more general investor, who also has access to Treasury bills and bonds. We find that the mean allocation of equity-only investors is heavily tilted towards value stocks at short-horizons, but the magnitude of this tilt declines dramatically with the investment horizon, implying that growth is less risky than value at long horizons. Investors with access to bills and bonds exhibit similar behavior, when value and growth tilts are computed relative to the total equity allocation of the portfolio. However, after accounting for the propensity of these investors to increase their total equity allocation as the horizon increases, the mean value tilt of the optimal allocation is shown to be positive and stable across time.</description><author>Jurek, Jakub W.; Viceira, Luis M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inside Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex; Liu, Qi
Existing theories advocate the exclusive use of equity-like instruments in executive compensation. However, recent empirical studies document the prevalence of debt-like instruments such as pensions. This paper justifies the use of debt as efficient compensation. Inside debt is a superior solution to the agency costs of debt than the solvency-contingent bonuses and salaries proposed by prior literature, since its payoff depends not only on the incidence of bankruptcy but also firm value in bankruptcy. Contrary to intuition, granting the manager equal proportions of debt and equity is typically inefficient. In most cases, an equity bias is desired to induce effort. However, if effort is productive in increasing liquidation value, or if bankruptcy is likely, a debt bias can improve effort as well as alleviate the agency costs of debt. The model generates a number of empirical predictions consistent with recent evidence.</description><author>Edmans, Alex; Liu, Qi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is College a Focal Point of Investor Life?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, Massimo; Simonov, Andrei
We study the link between college interaction and portfolio choice. We consider both the general imprinting of values shared by all the students attending the same school-values-based interaction-and the ensuing interaction with the classmates-bonding-based interaction. We show that even after controlling for the standard motivations of portfolio theory, college-based interaction affects the choice of styles-growth/value investing as well as stock picking. Both dimensions of interaction-values-based and bonding-based interactions-contribute to shape the investor choice. Overall, college interaction significantly affects portfolio choice. Investors invest in the same stocks in which their former classmates do. Each individual college leaves a specific and distinct trace on his students.</description><author>Massa, Massimo; Simonov, Andrei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Attitudes Toward Small and Large Bets in the Presence of Background Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chapman, David A.; Polkovnichenko, Valery
If an individual with expected utility and a reasonable level of wealth rejects a small actuarially favorable gamble, it implies a very high degree of risk aversion. It also predicts (counterfactually) the rejection of more sizable and very attractive bets. If additional background uncertainty affects wealth, this result also applies to non-expected utilities. The authors describe a set of reasonable conditions under which an individual may reject the small bet but accept the large bet, even in the presence of background uncertainty. The two critical assumptions that the authors use are rank-dependent utility and a discrete distribution for background risk. Plausible calibrations can reconcile large/small bet risk attitudes and the empirical evidence on limited stock market participation in the presence of labor income risk.</description><author>Chapman, David A.; Polkovnichenko, Valery</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Portfolio Choice over the Life Cycle with Flexible Work, Endogenous Retirement, and Lifetime Payouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chai, Jingjing; Horneff, Wolfram; Maurer, Raimond; Mitchell, Olivia S.
This paper derives optimal lifecycle asset allocations for consumers who select work hours and retirement ages given uncertain labor income and investment returns. These shocks shape retirement and asset allocation patterns in complex ways: negative labor market shocks and high stock returns influence the young to work less and buy more annuities, and later, to retire early. This flexibility enhances welfare; our model also fits several important empirical stylized facts including the two peaks in retirement rates, the hump-shaped pattern of work hours, the sizeable discontinuity in consumption at retirement, and low annuity take-ups of older households.</description><author>Chai, Jingjing; Horneff, Wolfram; Maurer, Raimond; Mitchell, Olivia S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insuring Consumption Using Income-Linked Assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fuster, Andreas; Willen, Paul S.
We evaluate financial assets with payoffs linked to individual labor income, as conceived by Shiller (2003) and others. Using a realistically calibrated life-cycle model, we find that such assets can generate nontrivial welfare benefits, depending on the precise structure of the instrument. However, the assets we consider can only eliminate a relatively small fraction of the welfare costs of labor income risk over the life cycle. We highlight the fact that although the purpose of such assets is to smooth consumption across states of nature, one must also consider the assets' effects on households' ability to smooth consumption over time.</description><author>Fuster, Andreas; Willen, Paul S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Annuity Risk Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koijen, Ralph S. J.; Nijman, Theo E.; Werker, Bas J. M.
This paper studies the life-cycle consumption and portfolio choice problem taking account of annuity risk at retirement. The study allows for government-provided annuity income. Optimally, households allocate retirement wealth to nominal, inflation-linked and variable annuities, and condition this choice on the state of the economy. The case in which there are limitations in the types of annuities that are available is also considered and the costs of annuity market incompleteness are quantified. Subsequently, the paper determines how investors optimally anticipate annuitization before retirement. The conclusion is that ignoring annuity risk before and at retirement can be economically costly.</description><author>Koijen, Ralph S. J.; Nijman, Theo E.; Werker, Bas J. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trust and the Choice Between Housing and Financial Assets: Evidence from Spanish Households</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>El-Attar, Mayssun; Poschke, Markus
Trusting behavior has been shown to affect households' portfolio choice between risky and risk-free financial assets. We extend the analysis to include the dominant component of households' portfolios, real estate. Using data from the European Social Survey, we estimate individual-level trust by applying a hierarchical item response model. Combining these estimates with data on Spanish households' financial decisions from the Survey of Household Finances, we show that households with less trust invest more in housing and less in financial assets, in particular risky ones. Trust thus may drive not only (limited) stock market participation but also financial development more generally.</description><author>El-Attar, Mayssun; Poschke, Markus</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trust, Sociability, and Stock Market Participation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Georgarakos, Dimitris; Pasini, Giacomo
This article investigates the importance of both trust and sociability for stock market participation and for differences in stockholding across Europe. We estimate significant effects for the two, and find that sociability can partly balance the discouragement effect on stockholding induced by low regional prevailing trust. We test for exogeneity of trust and sociability indicators using variation in history of political institutions and in frequency of contacts with grandchildren, respectively. Moreover, the effect of trust is stronger in countries with limited participation and low average trust, offering an explanation for the remarkably low stockholding rates of the wealthy living therein.</description><author>Georgarakos, Dimitris; Pasini, Giacomo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Special issue on household finance Preface</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haliassos, Michael; Jappelli, Tullio; Pagano, Marco; Zechner, Josef
nan</description><author>Haliassos, Michael; Jappelli, Tullio; Pagano, Marco; Zechner, Josef</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric Momentum Effects Under Uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kelsey, David; Kozhan, Roman; Pang, Wei
This paper studies asymmetric profitability of the momentum trading strategy. When investors face Knightian uncertainty, they react differently to past winners and losers, which creates asymmetric patterns in price continuations. This asymmetry increases with the level of market and idiosyncratic uncertainty relating to the fundamental value of stocks. We provide a model explaining this phenomenon and empirical evidence supporting the hypothesis. Our results also imply that momentum is more likely to continue for downward trends in a highly uncertain market.</description><author>Kelsey, David; Kozhan, Roman; Pang, Wei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed Finance and Technological Conservatism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Minetti, Raoul
This paper studies an economy in which firms can operate either a mature or a new technology and lenders acquire information on the productive assets of the borrowing firms that are eligible as collateral. We demonstrate that when contracts are imperfectly enforceable informed lenders offer inexpensive funding for the mature technology but may choose not to finance the new one, seeking to preserve the value of their information on the mature assets. Using firm-level data from Italy, we find that banks that establish long-term relationships with firms promote technological progress on average. However, we find that relationship banks inhibit innovations that entail a large depreciation of existing technology-specific information such as radical innovations.</description><author>Minetti, Raoul</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unbiased Disagreement in Financial Markets, Waves of Pessimism and the Risk-Return Trade-off</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jouini, Elyes; Napp, Clotilde
Can investors with irrational beliefs be neglected as long as they are rational on average? Do their trades cancel out with no consequences on prices, as implicitly assumed by traditional models? We consider a model with irrational investors, who are rational on average. We obtain waves of pessimism and optimism that lead to countercyclical market prices of risk and procyclical risk-free rates. The variance of the state price density is greatly increased. The long run risk-return relation is modified; in particular, the long run market price of risk might be higher than both the instantaneous and the rational ones.</description><author>Jouini, Elyes; Napp, Clotilde</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Returns to Private Equity - Idiosyncratic Risk Does Matter!</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mueller, Elisabeth
Owners of private companies often invest a substantial share of their net worth in one company, which exposes them to idiosyncratic risk. We investigate whether owners of US companies require compensation for lack of diversification in the form of higher returns on equity. Exposure to idiosyncratic risk is measured as the share of the owner's net worth invested in the company. Equity returns are measured as the earnings rate and as capital gains. For both returns measures we find a positive and significant influence of exposure to idiosyncratic risk. This paper improves our understanding of returns on private equity.</description><author>Mueller, Elisabeth</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Supervisory Effectiveness and Bank Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Delis, Manthos D.; Staikouras, Panagiotis K.
This paper investigates the role of banking supervision in controlling bank risk. Banking supervision is measured in terms of enforcement outputs (i.e., on-site audits and sanctions). Our results show an inverted U-shaped relationship between on-site audits and bank risk, while the relationship between sanctions and risk appears to be linear and negative. We also consider the combined effect of effective supervision and banking regulation (in the form of capital and market discipline requirements) on bank risk. We find that effective supervision and market discipline requirements are important and complementary mechanisms in reducing bank fragility. This is in contrast to capital requirements, which prove to be rather futile in controlling bank risk, even when supplemented with a higher volume of on-site audits and sanctions.</description><author>Delis, Manthos D.; Staikouras, Panagiotis K.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is There a Relationship Benefit in Credit Ratings?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maehlmann, Thomas
This paper shows that firms with longer rating agency relationships have better credit ratings, conditional on observables. The paper also finds that (1) controlling for observables, firms with longer relationships, while having higher average ratings, do not have lower default rates, (2) relationship benefits are larger among firms with a greater incentive to game their information supplied to agencies or to pressure agencies into giving higher ratings, and (3) investors demand a (price) discount on bonds sold by relationship firms and the correlation between bond yield spreads and ratings is decreasing with relationship length. In sum, the evidence is inconsistent with first-order credit quality explanations but rather supports a "learning-to-gaming" and an "adverse incentives" story.</description><author>Maehlmann, Thomas</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Ambiguity Premium vs. the Risk Premium under Limited Market Participation*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ui, Takashi
This paper considers a stock market with ambiguity-averse informed investors under the CARA-normal setting, and studies the relationship between limited market participation and the equity premium which is decomposed into the risk premium and the ambiguity premium. In a rational expectations equilibrium, limited market participation arises if the largest deviation of investors' ambiguity increases sufficiently or if the variance of the stock return decreases sufficiently. In each case, a change in the risk premium and a change in the ambiguity premium may have opposite signs. This paper identifies conditions under which a change with the plus sign dominates and thus the equity premium increases when fewer investors participate in the stock market.</description><author>Ui, Takashi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder-Manager Disagreement and Corporate Investment*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thakor, Anjan V.; Whited, Toni M.
We develop a simple theoretical argument that generates testable predictions about how disagreement affects corporate investment and find strong empirical support for these predictions. Investment is negatively related to a proxy for disagreement, after controlling for Tobin's q, and after dealing with the fact that Tobin's q and our disagreement proxy contain measurement error. This proxy is unrelated to traditional indicators of asymmetric information. We also find that variation in disagreement is an important component of the portion of the variation in Tobin's q that matters for investment, and that disagreement affects investment and Tobin's q more if the firm has greater financial flexibility.</description><author>Thakor, Anjan V.; Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO Information Aggregation and Underwriter Quality*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Wei; Yung, Chris
A key distinction between some models of IPO pricing (e.g., auctions and bookbuilding) and others (e.g., fixed-priced models) is whether price discovery occurs in the primary or secondary market. Higher investment bank reputation is associated with 1) more active filing price revisions and 2) reduced secondary market volatility, indicating greater resolution of uncertainty before trading begins. Revisions of nonreputable banks cluster on exactly zero dollars. Finally, the "partial adjustment" phenomenon - often attributed to information aggregation - is primarily due to the behavior of reputable underwriters. We conclude that theoretical models of primary market information aggregation are better suited for reputable underwriters.</description><author>Wang, Wei; Yung, Chris</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Survivorship Bias and Mutual Fund Performance: Relevance, Significance, and Methodical Differences*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rohleder, Martin; Scholz, Hendrik; Wilkens, Marco
This is the first paper systematically calculating, testing and explaining different definitions of the survivorship bias in fund performance. We document that the survival-performance-relation is stronger for small funds and we find significant under-performance of non-survivors but no significant out-performance of new funds. Survivorship bias is still a problem as well in other fields of research, e.g., in countries where survivorship bias-free data is not available and because certain methods require truncated data. This paper provides guidance on how to deal with and reduce survivorship bias in empirical studies.</description><author>Rohleder, Martin; Scholz, Hendrik; Wilkens, Marco</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of Analysts' Recommendations and the Organization of Financial Research*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Salva, Carolina; Sonney, Frederic
Brokerage houses usually organize their research activities by country or economic sector. We evaluate which research structure provides most value to investors. To do so, we study the relative information content of recommendations issued by country-specialized analysts and sector-specialized analysts. Our findings show that the former issue more valuable recommendations. The strength of country-specific commonalities and institutional factors explain at least part of the better performance of country-specialized financial analysts. Although analysts' geographic location has been shown in the literature to be a significant determinant of earnings forecast accuracy, its relevance is more subtle when it comes to stock recommendations.</description><author>Salva, Carolina; Sonney, Frederic</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is a Team Different from the Sum of its Parts? Evidence from Mutual Fund Managers*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baer, Michaela; Kempf, Alexander; Ruenzi, Stefan
This paper provides the first empirical test of the diversification of opinions theory and the group shift theory using real business data. Our data set covers management teams and single managers of US equity mutual funds. Our results reject the group shift theory and support the diversification of opinions theory: teams follow less extreme investment styles, their portfolios are less industry concentrated, and they are eventually less likely to achieve extreme performance outcomes. These results hold after taking into account the impact of fund and family characteristics as well as manager characteristics.</description><author>Baer, Michaela; Kempf, Alexander; Ruenzi, Stefan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Security Design in Initial Public Offerings*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chakraborty, Archishman; Gervais, Simon; Yilmaz, Bilge
We investigate an IPO security design problem when information asymmetries across investors lead to a winner's curse. Firms that are riskier in down markets can lower the cost of going public by using unit IPOs, in which equity and warrants are combined into a non-divisible package. Furthermore, firms that have a sizeable growth potential even in bad states of the world can fully eliminate the winner's curse problem by making the warrants callable. Our theory is consistent with the prominent use of unit IPOs and produces empirical implications that differentiate it from existing theories.</description><author>Chakraborty, Archishman; Gervais, Simon; Yilmaz, Bilge</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Franchising Microfinance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bubna, Amit; Chowdhry, Bhagwan
Financial intermediaries worldwide are seeking mechanisms for participating in micro lending. Using informed "local capitalists" as bank's on-lenders fails due to borrowers' incentive to default with multiple credit sources. A coalition of local capitalists may not resolve the problem in the presence of a monopoly moneylender with superior skills in lending and enforcement. A credible competitive threat to the moneylender can only arise if the local capitalist coalition also provides information sharing benefits that lower their cost of lending vis-a-vis the moneylender. Franchising allows local capitalists to form such a coalition. We analyze conditions under which welfare-enhancing franchising would obtain.</description><author>Bubna, Amit; Chowdhry, Bhagwan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Safe Haven Currencies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ranaldo, Angelo; Soederlind, Paul
We study high-frequency exchange rates over the period 1993-2008. Based on the recent literature on volatility and liquidity risk premia, we use a factor model to capture linear and non-linear linkages between currencies, stock and bond markets as well as proxies for market volatility and liquidity. We document that the Swiss franc and Japanese yen appreciate against the US dollar when US stock prices decrease and US bond prices and FX volatility increase. These safe haven properties materialise over different time granularities (from a few hours to several days) and non-linearly with the volatility factor and during crises. The latter effects were particularly discernible for the yen during the recent financial crisis.</description><author>Ranaldo, Angelo; Soederlind, Paul</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Long-Run Risks Model of Asset Pricing with Fat Tails</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Zhiguang; Bidarkota, Prasad V.
We explore the effects of fat tails on the equilibrium implications of the long-run risks model of asset pricing by introducing innovations with dampened power law to consumption and dividends growth processes. We estimate the model structural parameters by maximum likelihood. We find that the stochastic volatility model with fat tails can generate implied risk premium, expected risk free rate and their volatilities comparable to the magnitudes observed in data. The model with fat tails leads to a significant increase in implied risk premia over the benchmark Gaussian model, but similar values for other equilibrium quantities of interest.</description><author>Wang, Zhiguang; Bidarkota, Prasad V.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securities Auctions under Moral Hazard: An Experimental Study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kogan, Shimon; Morgan, John
In many settings, including venture capital financing, mergers and acquisitions, and lease competition, the structure of the contracts over which firms compete differs. Furthermore, the structure of the contract affects the future incentives of the firm to engage in value-creating activities by potentially diluting effort or investment incentives. We study, both theoretically and in the lab, the performance of debt and equity auctions in the presence of both private information and hidden effort. We show that the revenues to sellers in debt and equity auctions differ systematically depending on the returns to entrepreneurial effort. Using a controlled laboratory experiments we test the model's predictions and find strong support for the theory.</description><author>Kogan, Shimon; Morgan, John</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Myopic Investment Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eriksen, Kristoffer W.; Kvaloy, Ola
Myopic loss aversion (MLA) has been proposed as an explanation for the equity premium puzzle, and experiments indicate that investors exhibit behavior consistent with MLA. But a caveat is that a large bulk of financial assets is managed by investment managers whose objectives may differ substantially from those of private investors. Most importantly they manage their clients' money, not their own. In this paper we test experimentally how individuals take risk with other people's ("clients") money. We find that subjects behave consistently with MLA over their clients' money and take less risk with their clients' money than with their own.</description><author>Eriksen, Kristoffer W.; Kvaloy, Ola</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Financing Activities and Contrarian Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Demirtas, K. Ozgur; Hovakimian, Armen
This paper investigates the risk versus mispricing explanation of superior returns to contrarian strategies using the interactions between value-to-market indicators and corporate financing transactions that increase or decrease a firm's outstanding equity. Portfolio-level analyses and firm-level cross-sectional regressions indicate that the well-documented contrarian profits soar when value stocks which repurchase shares (value repurchasers) and growth stocks which issue shares (growth issuers) are considered. Various risk measures indicate that value repurchasers are not riskier than growth issuers. Furthermore, time-series of realized growth rates, analysts' long-term growth estimates, and sensitivity of portfolio returns to investor sentiment support the misvaluation explanation.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Demirtas, K. Ozgur; Hovakimian, Armen</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Determinants of Bank Capital Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gropp, Reint; Heider, Florian
The paper shows that mispriced deposit insurance and capital regulation were of second-order importance in determining the capital structure of large U.S. and European banks during 1991 to 2004. Instead, standard cross-sectional determinants of non-financial firms' leverage carry over to banks, except for banks whose capital ratio is close to the regulatory minimum. Consistent with a reduced role of deposit insurance, we document a shift in banks' liability structure away from deposits towards non-deposit liabilities. We find that unobserved time-invariant bank fixed-effects are ultimately the most important determinant of banks' capital structures and that banks' leverage converges to bank specific, time-invariant targets.</description><author>Gropp, Reint; Heider, Florian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Out-of-Court Restructuring versus Formal Bankruptcy in a Non-Interventionist Bankruptcy Setting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jostarndt, Philipp; Sautner, Zacharias
We investigate debt restructurings in Germany for a sample of 116 financially distressed companies. About half of the firms succeed in restructuring their debt in a workout while the others file for bankruptcy. Our evidence suggests that firms which have higher leverage, owe more debt to banks, and exhibit higher going concern values are more likely to conduct a workout. Bankruptcy is more likely for firms with deficient lender coordination and a high fraction of collateralized debt. An analysis of stock returns suggests that the market uses similar information to predict workouts. 84% of the bankrupt firms were ultimately liquidated.</description><author>Jostarndt, Philipp; Sautner, Zacharias</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Helping Hand or Grabbing Hand? Central vs. Local Government Shareholders in Chinese Listed Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheung, Yan-Leung; Rau, P. Raghavendra; Stouraitis, Aris
We analyze related party transactions between Chinese publicly listed firms and their state-owned shareholders to examine whether companies benefit or lose from the presence of government shareholders and politically connected directors. Minority shareholders seem to be expropriated in firms controlled by local governments, firms with a large proportion of local government directors on their board, firms without central government directors, and firms in provinces where local government bureaucrats are less likely to be prosecuted for corruption. In contrast, firms controlled by the central government (or having central government affiliated directors), benefit in related party transactions with their government parents.</description><author>Cheung, Yan-Leung; Rau, P. Raghavendra; Stouraitis, Aris</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Convergence Model of the Term Structure of Interest Rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ajevskis, Viktors; Vitola, Kristine
This paper develops a convergence model of the term structure of interest rates in context of entering the European Monetary Union (EMU). Compared to other models developed so far in this field, our model specification ensures convergence of the domestic short-term interest rates to the euro area ones. We achieve this convergence by stating that the spread between domestic and euro short-term interest rate follows the Brownian bridge process. We also develop an econometric counterpart of the theoretical model. To tackle the problem of nonstationarity and nonlinearity of the model, we apply the extended Kalman filter for coefficient estimation.</description><author>Ajevskis, Viktors; Vitola, Kristine</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Duration Between Trades of Underlying Securities Affects Option Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cartea, Alvaro; Meyer-Brandis, Thilo
We propose a model for stock price dynamics that explicitly incorporates random waiting times between trades, also known as duration, and show how option prices can be calculated using this model. We use ultra-high-frequency data for blue-chip companies to motivate a particular choice of waiting-time distribution and then calibrate risk-neutral parameters from options data. We also show that the convexity commonly observed in implied volatilities may be explained by the presence of duration between trades. Furthermore, we find that, ceteris paribus, implied volatility decreases in the presence of longer durations, a result consistent with the findings of Engle (2000) and Dufour and Engle (2000) which demonstrates the relationship between levels of activity and volatility for stock prices. Finally, by directly employing information given by time-stamps of trades, our approach provides a direct link between the literature on stochastic time changes and business time (see Clark (1973)) and, at the same time, highlights the link between number and time of arrival of transactions with implied volatility and stochastic volatility models.</description><author>Cartea, Alvaro; Meyer-Brandis, Thilo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Firms Believe in Interest Rate Parity?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McBrady, Matthew R.; Mortal, Sandra; Schill, Michael J.
Using a broad sample of international corporate bond offerings, we provide evidence that corporate borrowers make opportunistic currency choices, in that they denominate the currency of their bonds in a manner that is inconsistent with a belief in either covered or uncovered interest rate parity. Using firm-level tests, we identify a number of characteristics of firms that engage in opportunistic behavior. We observe that large issuers located in developed markets with investment-grade ratings and low cash flow characterize those firms that are responsive to covered borrowing rate differences across currencies. Corporate responsiveness to uncovered borrowing rate differences appears more general. We observe that although the gains firms achieve through opportunistic currency denomination are economically significant, the yield differential tends to systematically decline after issuance. This finding suggests that opportunistic issuance by corporations may be a primary mechanism for driving covered interest yields toward parity.</description><author>McBrady, Matthew R.; Mortal, Sandra; Schill, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Limits of the Limits of Arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brav, Alon; Heaton, J. B.; Li, Si
We test the limits of arbitrage argument for the survival of irrationality-induced financial anomalies by sorting securities on their individual residual variability as a proxy for idiosyncratic risk - a commonly asserted limit to arbitrage - and comparing the strength of anomalous returns in low versus high residual variability portfolios. We find no support for the limits of arbitrage argument to explain undervaluation anomalies (small value stocks, value stocks generally, recent winners, and positive earnings surprises) but strong support for the limits of arbitrage argument to explain overvaluation anomalies (small growth stocks, growth stocks generally, recent losers, and negative earnings surprises). Other tests also fail to support the limits of arbitrage argument for the survival of overvaluation anomalies and suggest that at least some of the factor premiums for size, book-to-market, and momentum are unrelated to irrationality protected by limits to arbitrage.</description><author>Brav, Alon; Heaton, J. B.; Li, Si</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When It Cannot Get Better or Worse: The Asymmetric Impact of Good and Bad News on Bond Returns in Expansions and Recessions*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beber, Alessandro; Brandt, Michael W.
We examine empirically the response of bond returns and their volatility to good and bad macroeconomic news during expansions and recessions. We find that macroeconomic announcements are most important when they contain bad news for bond returns in expansions and, to a lesser extent, good news in contractions. In expansions, the bond market responds most strongly to bad news in non-farm payrolls, while in recessions good news about inflation is relatively more important. We also document that macroeconomic news impacts the volatility of bond returns at all maturities by increasing jump intensities and altering the jump size distribution.</description><author>Beber, Alessandro; Brandt, Michael W.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash Breeds Success: The Role of Financing Constraints in Patent Races*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schroth, Enrique; Szalay, Dezsoe
This paper studies the impact of financing constraints in patent races. We develop a model of optimal contracting where firms finance their R&amp;D expenditures with an investor who cannot verify their effort. In equilibrium, firms are more likely to win the more cash and assets they hold prior to the race, and the less cash and assets their rivals hold prior to the race. Evidence from US pharmaceutical patents awarded between 1975 and 1999 supports our theoretical predictions.</description><author>Schroth, Enrique; Szalay, Dezsoe</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankers on the Boards of German Firms: What They Do, What They Are Worth, and Why They Are (Still) There*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dittmann, Ingolf; Maug, Ernst; Schneider, Christoph
We analyze the role of bankers on the boards of German non-financial companies for the period from 1994 to 2005. We find that banks that are represented on a firm's board promote their own business as lenders and as M&amp;A advisors. They also seem to act as financial experts who help firms to obtain funding, especially in difficult times. We find little evidence that bankers monitor management and suggest that bankers on the board cause a decline in the valuations of non-financial firms. Banks' equity ownership declined sharply during our sample period and the German financial system lost some of its formerly distinctive features.</description><author>Dittmann, Ingolf; Maug, Ernst; Schneider, Christoph</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance Externalities*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Volpin, Paolo F.
When firms compete in the managerial labor market, the choice of corporate governance by a firm affects, and is affected by, the choice of governance by other firms. Firms with weaker governance offer managers more generous incentive compensation, which induces firms with good governance to also overpay their management. Due to this externality, overall level of governance in the economy can be inefficiently low. Poor governance can in fact be employed by incumbent firms to deter entry by new firms. Such corporate governance externalities have important implications for regulatory standards, ownership structure of firms, and the market for corporate control.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Volpin, Paolo F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust Portfolio Optimisation with Multiple Experts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lutgens, Frank; Schotman, Peter C.
We consider mean-variance portfolio choice of a robust investor. The investor receives advice from J experts, each with a different prior for expected returns and risk, and follows a min-max portfolio strategy. The robust investor endogenously combines the experts' estimates. When experts agree on the main return generating factors, the investor relies on the advice of the expert with the strongest prior. Dispersed advice leads to averaging of the alternative estimates. The robust investor is likely to outperform alternative strategies. The theoretical analysis is supported by numerical simulations for the 25 Fama-French portfolios and for 81 European country and value portfolios.</description><author>Lutgens, Frank; Schotman, Peter C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Anticipation of Fed Policy Changes and the Term Structure of Interest Rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heidari, Massoud; Wu, Liuren
The Federal Reserve adjusts the federal funds target rate discretely, causing discontinuity in short-term interest rates. Unlike Poisson jumps, these adjustments are well anticipated by the market. We propose a term structure model that incorporates an anticipated jump component with known arrival times but random jump size. We find that doing so improves the model performance in capturing the term structure behavior. The mean jump sizes extracted from the term structure match the realized target rate changes well. Specification analysis indicates that the jump sizes show strong serial dependence and dependence on the interest-rate factors.</description><author>Heidari, Massoud; Wu, Liuren</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decomposing European CDS Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berndt, Antje; Obreja, Iulian
Nearly half of the variation in European CDS returns is captured by a novel factor that mimics economic catastrophe risk. During the financial crisis of 2007-8, this factor became more important relative to other sources of risk, leading to a shift in the correlation structure of CDS returns. Using equivalent CDS and equity portfolios, we show that while crucial for explaining temporal and cross-sectional variation in CDS returns, the factor plays a lesser role for equity. This is likely due to the limited sensitivity of the equity value at default to whether the event is of systemic or idiosyncratic nature.</description><author>Berndt, Antje; Obreja, Iulian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of Sovereign Risk: Macroeconomic Fundamentals and the Pricing of Sovereign Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hilscher, Jens; Nosbusch, Yves
This paper investigates the effects of macroeconomic fundamentals on emerging market sovereign credit spreads. We find that the volatility of terms of trade in particular has a statistically and economically significant effect on spreads. This is robust to instrumenting terms of trade with a country-specific commodity price index. Our measures of country fundamentals have substantial explanatory power, even controlling for global factors and credit ratings. We also estimate default probabilities in a hazard model and find that model implied spreads capture a significant part of the variation in observed spreads out-of-sample. The fit is better for lower credit quality borrowers.</description><author>Hilscher, Jens; Nosbusch, Yves</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rating opaque borrowers: why are unsolicited ratings lower?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bannier, Christina E.; Behr, Patrick; Guettler, Andre
This paper examines why unsolicited ratings tend to be lower than solicited ratings. Both self-selection among issuers and strategic conservatism of rating agencies may be reasonable explanations. Analyses of default incidences of non-U.S. borrowers between January 1996 and December 2006 show that rating conservatism may play a role for industrial firms, but self-selection cannot be fully rejected. Neither can it for insurance companies, though data restrictions impede further conclusions. For unsolicited bank ratings, however, we find strong evidence that rating conservatism is an important cause. The downward bias also appears to increase along with banks' opaqueness.</description><author>Bannier, Christina E.; Behr, Patrick; Guettler, Andre</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inflation Targeting and Exchange Rate Regimes: Evidence from the Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brenner, Menachem; Sokoler, Meir
Inflation targeting is gaining popularity as a framework for conducting monetary policy. At the same time many countries employ some sort of foreign exchange intervention policy assuming that these two policies can coexist. This paper attempts to show that both policies are not sustainable. Israel is a classic test case. We test our hypothesis using information from the financial markets. The results support the hypothesis that both policies cannot be sustained in the long run. The conclusion is that a credible monetary policy aimed at inflation targets should be conducted in a free floating exchange rate regime.</description><author>Brenner, Menachem; Sokoler, Meir</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Experimental Test of the Impact of Overconfidence and Gender on Trading Activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deaves, Richard; Lueders, Erik; Luo, Guo Ying
We perform an asset market experiment in order to investigate whether overconfidence induces trading. We investigate three manifestations of overconfidence: calibration-based overconfidence, the better-than-average effect and illusion of control. Novelly, the measure employed for calibration-based overconfidence is task-specific in that it is designed to influence behavior. We find that calibration-based overconfidence does engender additional trade, though the better-than-average also appears to play a role. This is true both at the level of the individual and also at the level of the market. There is little evidence that gender influences trading activity.</description><author>Deaves, Richard; Lueders, Erik; Luo, Guo Ying</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anything is Possible: On the Existence and Uniqueness of Equilibria in the Shleifer-Vishny Model of Limits of Arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arnold, Lutz G.
This paper characterizes equilibria in the Shleifer-Vishny model of limits of arbitrage. To prove existence, one has to consider types of equilibria ignored by Shleifer and Vishny, even if one adopts their parameter restrictions. For example, the only equilibrium may be one in which maximization of expected wealth requires an "all-or-nothing" investment strategy, with intermediate investment levels being strictly unprofitable. If one goes beyond Shleifer and Vishny's parameter restrictions, multiple equilibria may arise, and equilibrium selection may be governed by sunspots. Moreover, there may exist an equilibrium in which the asset price returns to fundamentals despite worsening noise trader sentiment.</description><author>Arnold, Lutz G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Risk and Return of Arbitrage in Dual-Listed Companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Jong, Abe; Rosenthal, Leonard; Van Dijk, Mathijs A.
This paper evaluates investment strategies that exploit the deviations from theoretical price parity in a sample of 12 dual-listed companies (DLCs) in the period 1980-2002. We show that simple trading rules produce abnormal returns of up to almost 10% per annum adjusted for systematic risk, transaction costs, and margin requirements. However, arbitrageurs face uncertainty about the horizon at which prices will converge and deviations from parity are very volatile. As a result, DLC arbitrage is characterized by substantial idiosyncratic return volatility and a high incidence of large negative returns, which are likely to impede arbitrage.</description><author>De Jong, Abe; Rosenthal, Leonard; Van Dijk, Mathijs A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Target-firm information asymmetry and acquirer returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Officer, Micah S.; Poulsen, Annette B.; Stegemoller, Mike
We show that acquirer returns are significantly higher in stock-swap acquisitions of difficult-to-value targets, as measured by R&amp;D intensity and idiosyncratic return volatility. This finding contributes to an explanation of the determinants of, and value gains from, using stock as a method of payment. The effects of target-valuation uncertainty on both the method of payment and the market reaction to acquisitions are more likely to be apparent in samples of private acquisitions, as these effects can be masked in samples of acquisitions of publicly held targets. Nevertheless, our results hold for publicly traded targets in multivariate analysis.</description><author>Officer, Micah S.; Poulsen, Annette B.; Stegemoller, Mike</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic News and International Stock Market Co-movement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albuquerque, Rui; Vega, Clara
We analyze the effects that real-time domestic and foreign news about fundamentals have on the co-movement between stock returns of a small, open economy, Portugal, and a large economy, the United States. Consistent with our theoretical model, we find that US macroeconomic news and Portuguese earnings news do not affect stock market co-movement, whereas Portuguese macroeconomic news lowers stock market co-movement. We find that US news affects Portuguese stock market returns, though less so when US stock market returns are included in the regression. We provide evidence, contrary to common wisdom, that this last result does not derive from contagion.</description><author>Albuquerque, Rui; Vega, Clara</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Special issue on banking Preface</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Franklin; Boot, Arnoud; Pagano, Marco; Udell, Gregory
nan</description><author>Allen, Franklin; Boot, Arnoud; Pagano, Marco; Udell, Gregory</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Integration and Firm Performance: Evidence from Foreign Bank Entry in Emerging Markets*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Ongena, Steven
While the positive growth effects of financial integration are extensively documented, little is known of its impact on small and young firms. This paper aims to fill this void relying on a panel of 60,000 firm-year observations on listed and unlisted companies in Eastern European economies to assess the differential impact of foreign bank lending on firm growth and financing. Foreign lending stimulates growth in firm sales, assets, and use of financial debt even though the effect is dampened for small firms. More strikingly, young firms benefit most from foreign bank presence, while businesses connected to domestic banks or to the government suffer. Overall, our findings suggest that foreign banks can help to mitigate connected-lending problems and to improve capital allocation.</description><author>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Ongena, Steven</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Welfare Analysis of Regulation in Relationship Banking Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlin, Bruce Ian; Rob, Rafael
The increasing dependence of individuals on debt financing raises several welfare considerations that we analyze in this paper. We develop a dynamic, competitive model of relationship banking to determine how regulation influences borrowing and lending behavior, and analyze how it affects welfare in the market. We characterize the lending regimes that arise based on public policy, and evaluate the optimal choice by the government to induce particular lending practices to arise. Finally, we consider the effect that a credit reporting agency has on the market. In the paper, we highlight the new empirical implications that the model generates.</description><author>Carlin, Bruce Ian; Rob, Rafael</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-Selling Lending and Underwriting: Scope Economies and Incentives*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Laux, Christian; Walz, Uwe
We highlight the implications of combining underwriting services and lending for the choice of underwriters and for competition in the underwriting business. We show that cross-selling can increase underwriters' incentives, and we explain three phenomena: first, that cross-selling is important for universal banks to enter the investment banking business; second, that cross-selling is particularly attractive for highly leveraged borrowers; third, that less-than-market rates are no prerequisite for cross-selling to benefit a bank's clients. In our model, cross-selling reduces rents in the underwriting business.</description><author>Laux, Christian; Walz, Uwe</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Market Power and SME Financing Constraints*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carbo-Valverde, Santiago; Rodriguez-Fernandez, Francisco; Udell, Gregory F.
Some studies find that market power is associated with credit availability (information hypothesis); others find that less competitive banking markets lead to more credit rationing (market power hypothesis). Empirical research has relied solely on concentration as a measure of market power. The industrial organization literature, however, argues that a structural competition indicator such as the Lerner index is a superior measure. We test the information hypothesis and the market power hypothesis using these two alternative measures of market power and find that they generally give conflicting results. However, we also offer evidence suggesting that both views can be reconciled.</description><author>Carbo-Valverde, Santiago; Rodriguez-Fernandez, Francisco; Udell, Gregory F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks, Distances and Firms' Financing Constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alessandrini, Pietro; Presbitero, Andrea F.; Zazzaro, Alberto
Bank deregulation and progress in information technology altered the geographical diffusion of banking structures and instruments, and reduced operational distance between banks and local economies. Although, the consolidation of the banking industry promoted the geographical concentration of banking decision-making centres and increased functional distance between local banking systems and local borrowers. This paper focuses on the impact that these spatial diffusion-concentration phenomena had on the financing constraints of Italian firms over the period 1996-2003. Our findings show that greater functional distance stiffened financing constraints, especially for small firms, while smaller operational distance did not always enhance credit availability.</description><author>Alessandrini, Pietro; Presbitero, Andrea F.; Zazzaro, Alberto</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Organizational Structure and Lending Technology on Banking Competition*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Degryse, Hans; Laeven, Luc; Ongena, Steven
We investigate how bank organization shapes banking competition. We show that a bank's geographical lending reach and loan pricing strategy is determined by its own and its rivals' organizational structure. We estimate the impact of organization on the geographical reach and loan pricing of a large bank. We find that the reach of the bank is smaller when rival banks are large and hierarchically organized, have superior communication technology, have a narrower span of organization, and are closer to a decision unit with lending authority. Rival banks' size and the number of layers to a decision unit soften spatial pricing.</description><author>Degryse, Hans; Laeven, Luc; Ongena, Steven</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When No Law is Better Than a Good Law</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Daouk, Hazeni
This paper argues, both theoretically and empirically, that sometimes no securities law may be better than a good securities law that is not enforced. The first part of the paper formalizes the sufficient conditions under which this happens for any law. The second part of the paper shows that a specific securities law - the law prohibiting insider trading - may satisfy these conditions. The third part of the paper takes this prediction to the data. We find that the cost of equity actually rises when some countries enact an insider trading law, but do not enforce it.</description><author>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Daouk, Hazeni</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Proximity Always Matters: Local Bias When the Set of Local Companies Changes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bodnaruk, Andry
I analyze the portfolios of individual investors who have changed their place of residence. As distance from a company they invest in changes, investors adjust their portfolio composition. The farther investors move away from the closest establishment of a company in their portfolio, the more of its shares they sell compared to investors who do not move. Among the companies that investors held before the move, after moving, investors abnormally increase their ownership in companies closer to their new location; these companies provide them with higher risk-adjusted returns than companies in which they kept holdings unchanged or abnormally reduced holdings.</description><author>Bodnaruk, Andry</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Card Debt Puzzles and Debt Revolvers for Self Control</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bertaut, Carol C.; Haliassos, Michael; Reiter, Michael
Most US credit card holders revolve high-interest debt, often with substantial liquid and retirement assets. We model separation of accounting from shopping allowed by credit cards, in a rational, dynamic game. When the shopper is more impatient than the accountant, selling assets to repay debt is not necessarily optimal, as the shopper can restore debt. Modest relative impatience generates asset-debt co-existence and target utilization rates, matching incidence and median assets of debt revolvers with substantial assets. Empirical evidence is consistent with a role for spending control considerations, after allowing for standard determinants of credit card debt.</description><author>Bertaut, Carol C.; Haliassos, Michael; Reiter, Michael</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bounded Rationality and Asset Pricing with Intermediate Consumption</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berrada, Tony
We consider a pure exchange economy with incomplete information. Some agents display learning bias and over- or under-react to the arrival of new information. We show under which conditions biased agents survive over a finite horizon. We also study the distribution of irrational agents consumption shares. Irrational agents have a signicant consumption share in the economy when (i) shocks are less persistent (ii) risk aversion is high (iii) volatility of aggregate consumption is high. We also show that agents impact on prices is increasing in their consumption share and conclude that biased agents can signicantly influence equilibrium quantities.</description><author>Berrada, Tony</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Convertibles in Sequential Financing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Susheng
Sequential financing is a popular strategy in corporate finance. However, depending on the type of financial instrument used to carry out the strategy, sequential financing can have many potential problems. This paper shows that certain types of convertibles can be deployed to resolve the problems completely. This may explain why convertibles are widely adopted to implement sequential financing in reality, especially among companies with many real options. We find that the call feature and some popular call restrictions are necessary for an efficient convertible. Indeed, almost all real-world convertibles have a call feature and call restrictions.</description><author>Wang, Susheng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option Compensation and Industry Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stoughton, Neal M.; Wong, Kit Pong
Compensation policy has become one of the most important ingredients of corporate governance. In this paper we take a new look at the issue, by contrasting the use of options with that of stock. We do this by integrating the repricing or resetting aspect of options with that of industrial structure. We show that industry competition may play an important role in dictating which form of compensation is optimal. When aggressive competition for key professional staff is an issue, the flexibility of options may actually become a disadvantage and therefore pure stock compensation may survive as an equilibrium. Thus compensation trends may be partly explained by trends in the nature of the competitive environment.</description><author>Stoughton, Neal M.; Wong, Kit Pong</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Incentives and Corporate Fraud: The Sources of Incentives Matter*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, Shane A.; Ryan, Harley E.; Tian, Yisong S.
Operating performance and stock return results imply that managers who commit fraud anticipate large stock price declines if they were to report truthfully, which would cause greater losses for managerial stockholdings than for options because of differences in convexity. Fraud firms have significantly greater incentives from unrestricted stockholdings than control firms do, and unrestricted stockholdings are their largest incentive source. Our results emphasize the importance of the shape and vesting status of incentive payoffs in providing incentives to commit fraud. Fraud firms also have characteristics that suggest a lower likelihood of fraud detection, which implies lower expected costs of fraud.</description><author>Johnson, Shane A.; Ryan, Harley E.; Tian, Yisong S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder Rights, Boards, and CEO Compensation*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fahlenbrach, Ruediger
I analyze the role of executive compensation in corporate governance. As proxies for corporate governance, I use board size, board independence, CEO-chair duality, institutional ownership concentration, CEO tenure, and an index of shareholder rights. The results from a broad cross-section of large U.S. public firms are inconsistent with recent claims that entrenched managers design their own compensation contracts. The interactions of the corporate governance mechanisms with total pay-for-performance and excess compensation can be explained by governance substitution. If a firm has generally weaker governance, the compensation contract helps better align the interests of shareholders and the CEO.</description><author>Fahlenbrach, Ruediger</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Shareholders Vote Strategically ? Voting Behavior, Proposal Screening, and Majority Rules*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maug, Ernst; Rydqvist, Kristian
We analyze how shareholders screen management proposals at annual general meetings. First, we use a simple model of strategic voting to develop a theoretical benchmark of effective information aggregation through voting. Then, we derive testable implications and provide structural estimates of the model parameters. The main conclusions are that shareholders vote strategically and that proposal screening increases value. Shareholders largely neutralize the lock-in effect of supermajority rules, thereby preventing the incorrect rejection of proposals.</description><author>Maug, Ernst; Rydqvist, Kristian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Resolving Macroeconomic Uncertainty in Stock and Bond Markets*</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beber, Alessandro; Brandt, Michael W.
We establish an empirical link between the ex-ante uncertainty about macroeconomic fundamentals and the ex-post resolution of this uncertainty in financial markets. We measure macroeconomic uncertainty using prices of economic derivatives and relate this measure to changes in implied volatilities of stock and bond options when the economic data is released. Higher macroeconomic uncertainty is associated with greater reduction in implied volatilities following the news release. It is also associated with increased volume and decreased open interest in option markets after the release, consistent with market participants using financial options to hedge or speculate on macroeconomic news.</description><author>Beber, Alessandro; Brandt, Michael W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What caused the bank capital build-up of the 1990s?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Flannery, Mark J.; Rangan, Kasturi P.
Large U.S. banks dramatically increased their capitalization during the 1990s, to the highest levels in more than 50 years. We document this buildup of capital and evaluate several potential motivations. Our results support the hypothesis that regulatory innovations in the early 1990s weakened conjectural government guarantees and enhanced bank counterparties' incentives to monitor and price default risk. We find no evidence that a bank holding company's (BHC's) market capitalization increases with its asset volatility prior to 1994. Thereafter, the data display a strong cross-sectional relation between capitalization and asset risk.</description><author>Flannery, Mark J.; Rangan, Kasturi P.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board structures around the world: An experimental investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gillette, Ann B.; Noe, Thomas H.; Rebello, Michael J.
We model and experimentally examine the board structure-performance relationship. We examine single-tiered boards, two-tiered boards, insider-controlled boards, and outsider-controlled boards. We find that even insider-controlled boards frequently adopt institutionally preferred rather than self-interested policies. Two-tiered boards adopt institutionally preferred policies more frequently but tend to destroy value by being too conservative, frequently rejecting good projects. Outsider-controlled single-tiered boards, both when they have multiple insiders and only a single insider, adopt institutionally preferred policies most frequently. In those board designs where the efficient Nash equilibrium produces strictly higher payoffs to all agents than the coalition-proof equilibria, agents tend to select the efficient Nash equilibria.</description><author>Gillette, Ann B.; Noe, Thomas H.; Rebello, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive pay and shareholder litigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peng, Lin; Roeell, Ailsa
The paper examines the impact of executive compensation on private securities litigation. We find that incentive pay in the form of options increases the probability of securities class action litigation, holding constant a wide range of firm characteristics. We further document that there is abnormal upward earnings manipulation during litigation class periods and that insiders exercise more options and sell more shares during class periods, but that this activity is largely driven by pre-existing option holdings of the managers. Our results suggest that option-based compensation may have the unintended side effect of giving executives an incentive to focus excessively on the short term share price.</description><author>Peng, Lin; Roeell, Ailsa</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional investors and private equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nielsen, Kasper Meisner
Entrepreneurial finance literature has highlighted that institutional investors are the main contributors to private equity funds. This paper complements these findings by documenting that institutional investors also invest directly in private equity. A major concern for such investments is the higher agency costs associated with private equity. We show that institutions invest in private firms with governance mechanisms that tend to reduce the expected agency costs and risk of minority expropriation. Good governance mechanisms further allow institutional investors to enjoy the benefits of syndication and thereby reduce idiosyncratic risk. In addition, we show that institutional investments tend to be followed by further improvements in corporate governance and tend to occur in high-growth firms within research and development intensive industries.</description><author>Nielsen, Kasper Meisner</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Czech mate: Expropriation and investor protection in a converging world</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desai, Mihir A.; Moel, Alberto
This paper examines the expropriation of a foreign investor by a local partner and the subsequent resolution of the case through international arbitration in favor of the investor. Despite the investor's 99% interest in the joint venture, the local partner managed to divert the entire value of the underlying entity for his personal benefit. This clinical examination of an expropriation and its aftermath illustrates the interaction of property and contract rights in a global setting, how corporate control is shaped by geography, and how multinational firms may be advantaged by availing themselves of stronger investor protections than local firms.</description><author>Desai, Mihir A.; Moel, Alberto</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-run pain, long-run gain: Financial liberalization and stock market cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaminsky, Graciela Laura; Schmukler, Sergio L.
The views on financial liberalization are quite conflictive. Many argue that it triggers financial bubbles and crises. Others claim that financial liberalization allows markets to function properly and capital to move to its most profitable destination. The empirical evidence on these effects is not robust. This paper constructs a new comprehensive chronology of financial liberalization and shows that a key reason for the inconclusive evidence is that the effects of liberalization are time-varying. Financial liberalization is followed by large booms and busts only in the short run. In the long run institutions improve and financial markets tend to stabilize.</description><author>Kaminsky, Graciela Laura; Schmukler, Sergio L.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-listing and firm growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khurana, Inder K.; Martin, Xiumin; Periera, Raynolde
Extant research posits that cross-listing improves firms' access to lower cost external financing. But so far, there is scarce evidence that improved access to external funds through cross-listing contributes to higher firm growth. Documenting the relation between firm growth and cross-listing is critical because the presumption in prior research is that funds raised via cross-listing will be channeled towards potentially profitable projects. Using a sample of firms from thirty-seven countries that are cross-listed in the USA, we find a positive association between cross-listing and subsequent externally financed firm growth rates. However, we do not find that increases in externally financed firm growth after cross-listing vary systematically as a function of the home-country attributes of the cross-listed firms. Overall, our results provide new and direct evidence on the impact of cross-listing on the firm growth rates.</description><author>Khurana, Inder K.; Martin, Xiumin; Periera, Raynolde</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An examination of heterogeneous beliefs with a short-sale constraint in a dynamic economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gallmeyer, Michael; Hollifield, Burton
We study the effects of a market-wide short-sale constraint in a dynamic economy with heterogeneous beliefs. Imposing the constraint reduces the stock price if the optimistic investors' intertemporal elasticity of substitution (IES) is less than one and increases the stock price if the optimist's IES is greater than one. In calibrated examples, the optimist's market price of risk falls and the interest rate rises when the constraint binds. Imposing the constraint leads to a higher stock volatility if the optimist's IES is less than one and a lower stock volatility if the IES is greater than one.</description><author>Gallmeyer, Michael; Hollifield, Burton</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding common factors in domestic and international bond spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martell, Rodolfo
I study the determinants of changes in credit spreads for US. dollar denominated domestic and foreign sovereign bonds using fundamentals specified by structural models to separate spreads into their credit and non-credit components. I find that the non-default portions of spreads have a component that is common for each type of debt. Further, using a vector autoregressive model, I find that domestic spreads are related to the lagged component of sovereign spreads. I also find that some proxies for liquidity are related to the common components, suggesting a liquidity-based explanation for the common component not identified by previous research.</description><author>Martell, Rodolfo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity portfolio diversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goetzmann, William N.; Kumar, Alok
This study shows that US. individual investors hold under-diversified portfolios, where the level of under-diversification is greater among younger, low-income, less-educated, and less-sophisticated investors. The level of under-diversification is also correlated with investment choices that are consistent with over-confidence, trend-following behavior, and local bias. Furthermore, investors who over-weight stocks with higher volatility and higher skewness are less diversified. In contrast, there is little evidence that portfolio size or transaction costs constrains diversification. Under-diversification is costly to most investors, but a small subset of investors under-diversify because of superior information.</description><author>Goetzmann, William N.; Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are economists more likely to hold stocks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christiansen, Charlotte; Joensen, Juanna Schroeter; Rangvid, Jesper
Using a large panel data set containing detailed information on educational attainments as well as financial and socioeconomic variables for individual investors, we show that economists are more likely to hold stocks than otherwise identical investors. First, we consider the change in stockholdings associated with (i) completing an economics education and (ii) an economist moving into the household. Second, we model stock market participation using a probit model with unobserved individual heterogeneity. Third, instrumental variables estimation allows us to identify the causal effect of an economics education on stock market participation. Throughout, we focus explicitly on the effect of a change in educational status on the likelihood of holding stocks.</description><author>Christiansen, Charlotte; Joensen, Juanna Schroeter; Rangvid, Jesper</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed traders as liquidity providers: Anonymity, liquidity and price formation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rindi, Barbara
The tendency to introduce anonymity into financial markets apparently runs counter to the theory supporting transparency. This paper studies the impact of pre-trade transparency on liquidity in a market where risk-averse traders accommodate the liquidity demand of noise traders. When some risk-averse investors become informed, an adverse selection problem ensues for the others, making them reluctant to supply liquidity. Hence the disclosure of traders' identities improves liquidity by mitigating adverse selection. However, informed investors are effective liquidity suppliers, as their adverse selection and inventory costs are minimized. With endogenous information acquisition, transparency reduces the number of informed investors, thus decreasing liquidity. The type of information that traders hold and the effectiveness of insider trading regulation are crucial to distinguish between equilibria.</description><author>Rindi, Barbara</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Suppressed negative information and future underperformance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Scherbina, Anna
I present evidence of inefficient information processing in equity markets by documenting that negative information withheld by securities analysts is incorporated in stock prices with a significant delay. I estimate the extent of the withheld negative information based on the proportion of analysts who stop revising their annual earnings forecasts. This measure predicts negative earnings surprises and negative price reaction around earnings announcements. It could also be used to generate profitable trading strategies. I show that institutions tend to sell their stock holdings as my measure of unreported negative news increases, thus ameliorating the mispricing.</description><author>Scherbina, Anna</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Priming the risk attitudes of professionals in financial decision making</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilad, Dalia; Kliger, Doron
We explore the influence of priming on financial decisions by reinforcing subjects' risk-seeking behavior under uncertainty and comparing it to behavior in control groups. We focused on professionals: commercial banks' investment advisors and accountants in CPA firms. Results indicate that priming affects subjects' risk attitudes and investment decisions. Professionals' decisions were affected more than undergraduates', suggesting they employ a more intuitive and less analytic approach in making their decisions. Our work is related to field-data research documenting correlations between returns (investors' decisions) and situational factors, (i.e., weather) by suggesting controlled tests of professionals' behavior vis-a-vis the complexity inherent in field data.</description><author>Gilad, Dalia; Kliger, Doron</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the Costs of International Equity Investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sercu, Piet; Vanpee, Rosanne
Generalizing Cooper-Kaplanis (1994), we estimate implied costs that reconcile international portfolios with InCAPM predictions. Costs depend on home- and host-country characteristics and on interactions; we estimate risk tolerance rather than pre-specifying it and we control for currency risk, inflation hedging, fixed-interest investments, round-tripping and omitted countries. Estimates for developed markets are lower than reported before, but those for new markets are quite high: 2001-2004 inward shadow costs range from 0.01 %p.a. (US) to 37 (Indonesia). We find that equity home bias is related to a mixture of risks and frictions, such as information asymmetries,</description><author>Sercu, Piet; Vanpee, Rosanne</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Dynamic Analysis of Growth via Acquisition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Margsiri, Worawat; Mello, Antonio S.; Ruckes, Martin E.
Firms can grow through internal investment or through acquisition. While internal growth takes time, an acquisition provides cash flows immediately The opportunity to grow internally affects the price of an acquisition as it is a fall-back option for the acquirer should negotiations break down. Assuming investors do not have full information about the time a firm requires to grow internally, acquirers earn positive returns before the announcement of an acquisition, and there are negative stock price reactions to acquisition announcements. This research provides predictions about how pre-announcement price run-up and negative announcement returns relate to integration costs and synergies from acquisition.</description><author>Margsiri, Worawat; Mello, Antonio S.; Ruckes, Martin E.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Optimality of Uniform Pricing in IPOs: An Optimal Auction Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bennouri, Moez; Falconieri, Sonia
This paper uses an optimal auction approach to investigate the conditions under which uniform pricing in IPOs is optimal. We show that the optimality of a uniform price in IPOs depends crucially on whether the (optimal) allocation rule is restricted. These restrictions may stein from the retail investors' budget constraint and/or from the institutional investors' preferences. We show that the main determinant of the optimality of a uniform pricing rule is the existence and the shape of the retail investors' budget constraint. In contrast. institutional investors' preferences are shown to mainly affect the optimal allocation rule.</description><author>Bennouri, Moez; Falconieri, Sonia</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which Investors Leave Money on the Table? Evidence from Rights Issues</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rantapuska, Elias; Knupfer, Samuli
This study documents patterns of investor behavior around Finnish rights issues. We find that shareholders of issuing companies lost at least is an element of 9.9 million in aggregate from 1995 to 2002 by exercising rights too early, selling rights in the open market below their intrinsic value, or leaving rights unexercised. At the investor level, the losses are modest. For example, the median household investor suffered a loss of is an element of 135 from not exercising or selling the rights. Investors with small portfolios, inactive trading history, those who know neither of the official languages in Finland, or who are living abroad leave money on the table the most.</description><author>Rantapuska, Elias; Knupfer, Samuli</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>One share-one vote: The empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, Renee; Ferreira, Daniel
We survey the empirical literature on disproportional ownership, i.e. the use of mechanisms that separate voting rights from cash flow rights in corporations. Our focus is mostly on explicit mechanisms that allow some shareholders to acquire control with less than proportional economic interest in the firm (dual-class equity structures, stock pyramids, cross-ownership, etc.), but we also briefly discuss other mechanisms, such as takeover defenses and fiduciary voting. We provide a broad overview of different areas in this literature and highlight problems of interpretation that may arise because of empirical difficulties. We outline potentially promising areas for future research.</description><author>Adams, Renee; Ferreira, Daniel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Special issue on corporate governance - Preface</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Franklin; Mayer, Colin; Pagano, Marco; Zechner, Josef
nan</description><author>Allen, Franklin; Mayer, Colin; Pagano, Marco; Zechner, Josef</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>One share-one vote: the theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burkart, Mike; Lee, Samuel
The theoretical literature on security-voting structure can be organized around three questions: What impact do nonvoting shares have on takeover outcomes? How does disproportional voting power affect the incentives of blockholders? What are the repercussions of mandating one share - one vote for firms' financing and ownership choices? Overall, the costs and benefits of separating cash flow and votes reflect the fundamental governance trade off between disempowering blockholders and empowering managers. It is therefore an open question whether mandating one share-one vote would improve the quality of corporate governance, notably in systems that so far relied on active owners.</description><author>Burkart, Mike; Lee, Samuel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Should Insider Trading be Prohibited When Share Repurchases are Allowed?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buffa, Andrea M.; Nicodano, Giovanna
This paper considers share repurchases as the way long-term shareholders preserve their ability to use corporate information for Speculative purposes when insider trading regulation is enforced. This use of corporate information increases the adverse selection losses of short-term shareholders. Thus, buy-back programs reduce their incentive to invest in stocks that back the most productive technology, leading to a socially inefficient equilibrium. It follows that insider trading should not be banned when share repurchases are allowed. More generally, the paper argues that the regulation of insider trading and repurchases can not be considered in isolation, and analyzes their interplay.</description><author>Buffa, Andrea M.; Nicodano, Giovanna</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>