<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>RFS4</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Learning from Prices and the Dispersion in Beliefs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Snehal
The article develops a dynamic model that nests the rational expectations (RE) and differences of opinion (DO) approaches to study how investors use prices to update their valuations. When investors condition on prices (RE), investor disagreement is related positively to expected returns, return volatility, and market beta, but negatively to return autocorrelation. When investors do not use prices (DO), these relations are reversed. Tests of these predictions on the cross-section of stocks using analyst forecast dispersion and volume as proxies for disagreement provide empirical evidence that is consistent with investors using prices on average. (JEL G12, G14)</description><author>Banerjee, Snehal</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Good or the Bad? Which Mutual Fund Managers Join Hedge Funds?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deuskar, Prachi; Pollet, Joshua M.; Wang, Z. Jay; Zheng, Lu
Does the mutual fund industry lose its best managers to hedge funds? We find that mutual funds are able to retain managers with good performance in the face of competition from a growing hedge fund industry. On the other hand, poor performers are more likely to leave the mutual fund industry. A small fraction of these poor performers find jobs with smaller and younger hedge fund companies, especially when the hedge fund industry is growing rapidly. Analogously, a small fraction of the better-performing mutual fund managers are retained by allowing them to manage a hedge fund side-by-side. (JEL G23, G29)</description><author>Deuskar, Prachi; Pollet, Joshua M.; Wang, Z. Jay; Zheng, Lu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Constraints, R&amp;D Investment, and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Dongmei
Through the interaction between financial constraints and R&amp;D, I study two asset-pricing puzzles: mixed evidence on the financial constraints-return relation and the positive R&amp;D-return relation. Unlike capital investment, R&amp;D is more inflexible. A financially constrained R&amp;D-intensive firm is more likely to suspend/discontinue R&amp;D projects. Therefore, R&amp;D-intensive firms' risk increases with their financial constraints. Conversely, constrained firms' risk increases with their R&amp;D intensity. I find a robust empirical relation between financial constraints and stock returns, primarily among R&amp;D-intensive firms. Moreover, R&amp;D predicts returns only among financially constrained firms. This evidence suggests that financial constraints potentially drive the positive R&amp;D-return relation. (JEL G12, G32, O32)</description><author>Li, Dongmei</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividend Policies in an Unregulated Market: The London Stock Exchange, 1895-1905</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Braggion, Fabio; Moore, Lyndon
Miller and Modigliani (1961) show that in perfect and complete financial markets a firm's value is unaffected by its dividend policy. Much of the more recent research has demonstrated that dividend policy becomes important in the presence of taxation, asymmetric information, incomplete contracts, institutional constraints, and transaction costs. By examining the effects of dividend policies on 475 British firms existing between 1895 and 1905, and consequently operating in an environment of very low taxation with an absence of institutional constraints, we find strong support for asymmetric information theories of dividend policy, and little support for agency models. (JEL N23, G14, G35)</description><author>Braggion, Fabio; Moore, Lyndon</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information in (and not in) the Term Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duffee, Gregory R.
Standard approaches to building and estimating dynamic term structure models rely on the assumption that yields can serve as the factors. However, the assumption is neither theoretically necessary nor empirically supported. This article documents that almost half of the variation in bond risk premia cannot be detected using the cross-section of yields. Fluctuations in this hidden component have strong forecast power for both future short-term interest rates and excess bond returns. They are also negatively correlated with aggregate economic activity, but macroeconomic variables explain only a small fraction of variation in the hidden factor. (JEL G12)</description><author>Duffee, Gregory R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Property Rights in Financial Contracting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ayotte, Kenneth; Bolton, Patrick
This article adopts a definition of property rights from legal scholarship: A property right (in contrast to a contractual right) is enforceable, not only against the parties to a contract, but also against third parties outside the contract. In a financial contracting setting, we ask: When should the law enforce a lender's contractual protections as property rights, given that these rights may be hidden and costly for other lenders to discover? Our model explains why the law limits the creation and enforceability of property rights, and develops principles of optimal enforceability. These principles are often reflected in the law.</description><author>Ayotte, Kenneth; Bolton, Patrick</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Hedge Funds Manage Their Reported Returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Vikas; Daniel, Naveen D.; Naik, Narayan Y.
For funds with high incentives and more opportunities to inflate returns, we find that (i) returns during December are significantly higher than returns during the rest of the year, even after controlling for risk in both the time series and the cross-section; and (ii) this December spike is greater than for funds with lower incentives and fewer opportunities to inflate returns. These results suggest that hedge funds manage their returns upward in an opportunistic fashion in order to earn higher fees. Finally, we find strong evidence that funds inflate December returns by underreporting returns earlier in the year but only weak evidence that funds borrow from January returns in the following year.</description><author>Agarwal, Vikas; Daniel, Naveen D.; Naik, Narayan Y.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Bear's Lair: Index Credit Default Swaps and the Subprime Mortgage Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stanton, Richard; Wallace, Nancy
During the recent financial crisis, ABX.HE index credit default swaps (CDS) on baskets of mortgage-backed securities were a benchmark widely used by financial institutions to mark their subprime mortgage portfolios to market. However, we find that prices for the AAA ABX.HE index CDS during the crisis were inconsistent with any reasonable assumption for mortgage default rates, and that these price changes are only weakly correlated with observed changes in the credit performance of the underlying loans in the index, casting serious doubt on the suitability of these CDS as valuation benchmarks. We also find that the AAA ABX.HE index CDS price changes are related to short-sale activity for publicly traded investment banks with significant mortgage market exposure. This suggests that capital constraints, limiting the supply of mortgage-bond insurance, may be playing a role here similar to that identified by Froot (2001) in the market for catastrophe insurance.</description><author>Stanton, Richard; Wallace, Nancy</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global versus Local Asset Pricing: A New Test of Market Integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hau, Harald
Should capital cost calculations be based on a global or local market benchmark? The December 2000 redefinition of the Morgan Stanley Capital International (MSCI) global equity index was a natural experiment addressing this question. It is argued that this event triggered a portfolio shift (by index funds) large enough to affect the residual asset supplies constituting the global and local market benchmarks of all actively managed capital. Changes in the market benchmarks imply distinct and predictable changes to global and local stock betas. Exploring whether global or local beta changes best explain the cross-section of event returns reveals that stocks in developed markets are priced globally and not locally.</description><author>Hau, Harald</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Important Is the Financial Media in Global Markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, John M.; Hirschey, Nicholas H.; Kelly, Patrick J.
This article studies differences in the information content of 870,000 news announcements in 56 markets around the world. In most developed markets, a firm's stock price moves much more on days with public news about the firm. In contrast, in many emerging markets volatility is similar on news and non-news days. We examine several hypotheses for our findings. Cross-country differences in stock price reactions are best explained by insider trading, followed by differences in the quality of the news dissemination mechanism. Our findings are useful for quantifying the extent of insider trading and how the financial media affects international markets.</description><author>Griffin, John M.; Hirschey, Nicholas H.; Kelly, Patrick J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Common Risk Factors in Currency Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lustig, Hanno; Roussanov, Nikolai; Verdelhan, Adrien
We identify a "slope" factor in exchange rates. High interest rate currencies load more on this slope factor than low interest rate currencies. This factor accounts for most of the cross-sectional variation in average excess returns between high and low interest rate currencies. A standard, no-arbitrage model of interest rates with two factors-a country-specific factor and a global factor-can replicate these findings, provided there is sufficient heterogeneity in exposure to global or common innovations. We show that our slope factor identifies these common shocks, and we provide empirical evidence that it is related to changes in global equity market volatility. By investing in high interest rate currencies and borrowing in low interest rate currencies, U.S. investors load up on global risk.</description><author>Lustig, Hanno; Roussanov, Nikolai; Verdelhan, Adrien</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conglomerates and Industry Distress</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Xie, Kangzhen
Focusing on economic distress episodes in an industry, we estimate the effect of conglomeration on resource allocation. Distressed segments have higher sales growth, higher cash flow, and higher expenditure on research and development than single-segment firms. This is especially true for segments with high past performance, for unrated firms, and in competitive industries. Single-segment firms increase cash holding, and the diversification discount reduces during industry distress. Firms with high past performance acquire their industry counterparts, and firms with low past performance exit the distressed industry. Industries more prone to distress have greater conglomeration. Overall, conglomeration enables segments to avoid financial constraints during industry distress.</description><author>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Xie, Kangzhen</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Family Business Groups around the World: Financing Advantages, Control Motivations, and Organizational Choices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Masulis, Ronald W.; Pham, Peter Kien; Zein, Jason
Using a dataset of 28,635 firms in 45 countries, this study investigates the motivations for family-controlled business groups. We provide new evidence consistent with the argument that particular group structures emerge not only to perpetuate control, but also to alleviate financing constraints at the country and firm levels. At the country level, family groups, especially those structured as pyramids, are more prevalent in markets with limited availability of capital. At the firm level, investment intensity is greater for firms held in pyramidal rather than in horizontal structures, reflecting the financing advantages of the former. Within a pyramid, internal equity funding, investment intensity, and firm value all increase down the ownership chain. However, group firm performance declines when dual-class shares and cross shareholdings are employed as additional control-enhancing mechanisms.</description><author>Masulis, Ronald W.; Pham, Peter Kien; Zein, Jason</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Reactions to CEOs' Inside Debt Incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wei, Chenyang; Yermack, David
Pensions and deferred compensation represent substantial components of CEO incentives. We study stockholder and bondholder reactions to companies' initial reports of CEOs' inside debt positions following a 2007 SEC disclosure reform. We find that bond prices rise, equity prices fall, and the volatility of both securities drops for firms whose CEOs have sizeable defined benefit pensions or deferred compensation. Similar changes occur for credit default swap spreads and exchange-traded options. The results indicate a reduction in firm risk, a transfer of value from equity toward debt, and an overall destruction of enterprise value when CEOs' inside debt holdings are large.</description><author>Wei, Chenyang; Yermack, David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Model of Portfolio Delegation and Strategic Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kyle, Albert S.; Ou-Yang, Hui; Wei, Bin
This article endogenizes information acquisition and portfolio delegation in a one-period strategic trading model. We find that, when the informed portfolio manager is relatively risk tolerant (averse), price informativeness increases (decreases) with the amount of noise trading. When noise trading is endogenized, the linear equilibrium in the traditional literature breaks down under a wide range of parameter values. In contrast, a linear equilibrium always exists in our model. In a conventional portfolio delegation model under a competitive partial equilibrium, the manager's effort of acquiring information is independent of a linear incentive contract. In our strategic trading model, however, a higher-powered linear contract induces the manager to exert more effort for information acquisition.</description><author>Kyle, Albert S.; Ou-Yang, Hui; Wei, Bin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Does Equity Sector Orderflow Tell Us About the Economy?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beber, Alessandro; Brandt, Michael W.; Kavajecz, Kenneth A.
Investors rebalance their portfolios as their views about expected returns and risk change. We use empirical measures of portfolio rebalancing to back out investors' views, specifically, their views about the state of the economy. We show that aggregate portfolio rebalancing across equity sectors is consistent with sector rotation, an investment strategy that exploits perceived differences in the relative performance of sectors at different stages of the business cycle. The empirical footprint of sector rotation has predictive power for the evolution of the economy and future bond market returns, even after controlling for relative sector returns. Contrary to many theories of price formation, trading activity, therefore, contains information that is not entirely revealed by resulting relative price changes.</description><author>Beber, Alessandro; Brandt, Michael W.; Kavajecz, Kenneth A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Large Shareholder Diversification and Corporate Risk-Taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faccio, Mara; Marchica, Maria-Teresa; Mura, Roberto
Using new data for the universe of firms covered in Amadeus, we reconstruct the portfolios of shareholders who hold equity stakes in private- and publicly traded European firms. We find great heterogeneity in the degree of portfolio diversification across large shareholders. Exploiting this heterogeneity, we document that firms controlled by diversified large shareholders undertake riskier investments than firms controlled by nondiversified large shareholders. The impact of large shareholder diversification on corporate risk-taking is both economically and statistically significant. Our results have important implications at the policy level because they identify one channel through which policy changes can improve economic welfare.</description><author>Faccio, Mara; Marchica, Maria-Teresa; Mura, Roberto</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Self-fulfilling Credit Market Freezes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bebchuk, Lucian A.; Goldstein, Itay
This article develops a model of a self-fulfilling credit market freeze and uses it to study alternative governmental responses to such a crisis. We study an economy in which operating firms are interdependent, where their success depends on the ability of other operating firms to obtain financing. In such an economy, an inefficient credit market freeze may arise in which banks abstain from lending to operating firms with good projects because of their self-fulfilling expectations that other banks will not be making such loans. Our model enables us to study the effectiveness of using alternative measures as a means of getting an economy out of an inefficient credit market freeze. In particular, we study the effectiveness of interest rate cuts, an infusion of capital into banks, direct lending by the government to operating firms, and the provision of government capital or guarantees to encourage privately managed lending. Our analysis provides a framework for analyzing and evaluating the standard and nonstandard instruments used by authorities during the 2008-2009 financial crisis. Our analysis also provides testable implications for how firms, banks, and economies can be expected to be affected by shocks to the banking system.</description><author>Bebchuk, Lucian A.; Goldstein, Itay</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Costs of Being Private: Evidence from the Loan Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saunders, Anthony; Steffen, Sascha
Using a new dataset of UK-syndicated loans, we document a significant loan cost disadvantage incurred by privately held firms. For identification, we use the distance of a firm's headquarters to London's capital markets as a plausibly exogenous variation in corporate structure (i.e., public/private) choice. We analyze the channels of the loan cost disadvantage of being private by documenting the importance of: the higher costs of information production, the lower bargaining power, the differences in ownership structure, and the differences in secondary market trading. Interestingly, we find no evidence that lenders price expected future performance into the loan spread differential.</description><author>Saunders, Anthony; Steffen, Sascha</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Does Venture Capital Financing Improve Efficiency in Private Firms? A Look Beneath the Surface</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Krishnan, Karthik; Nandy, Debarshi K.
We use the Longitudinal Research Database (LRD) of the U.S. Census Bureau, which covers the entire universe of private and public U.S. manufacturing firms, to study several related questions regarding the efficiency gains generated by venture capital (VC) investment in private firms. First, do VCs indeed improve the efficiency (total factor productivity, TFP) of private firms, and if so, are certain kinds of VCs (high reputation vs. low reputation) better at generating such efficiency gains than others? Second, do VCs invest in more efficient firms to begin with (screening), or do they improve efficiency after investment (monitoring)? Third, do efficiency improvements due to VC backing arise from increases in sales or reductions in costs? Fourth, do VC backing and the associated efficiency gains affect the probability of a successful exit (IPO or acquisition)? Our analysis shows that the overall efficiency of VC-backed firms is higher than that of non-VC-backed firms at every point in time. This efficiency advantage of VC-backed firms arises from both screening and monitoring: The efficiency of VC-backed firms prior to receiving financing is higher than that of non-VC-backed firms, and further, the growth in efficiency subsequent to VC financing is greater for such firms. The above increases in efficiency of VC-backed firms are spread over the first two rounds of VC financing after which the TFP of such firms remains constant until exit. Additionally, we show that while the TFP of firms prior to receiving financing is lower for high-reputation VC-backed firms, the increase in TFP subsequent to financing is significantly greater for these firms, consistent with high-reputation VCs having greater monitoring ability. We disentangle the screening and monitoring effects of VC backing using three different methodologies: switching regression with endogenous switching, regression discontinuity analysis, and propensity score matching. We show that while overall efficiency gains generated by VC backing arise primarily from improvements in sales, the efficiency gains of high-reputation VC-backed firms arise also from lower increases in production costs. Finally, we show that VC backing and the associated efficiency gains positively affect the probability of a successful exit.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Krishnan, Karthik; Nandy, Debarshi K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real Options Signaling Games with Applications to Corporate Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grenadier, Steven R.; Malenko, Andrey
We study games in which the decision to exercise an option is a signal of private information to outsiders, whose beliefs affect the utility of the decision-maker. Signaling incentives distort the timing of exercise, and the direction of distortion depends on whether the decision-maker's utility increases or decreases in outsiders' belief about the payoff from exercise. In the former case, signaling incentives erode the value of the option to wait and speed up option exercise, while in the latter case option exercise is delayed. We demonstrate the model's implications through four corporate finance settings: investment under managerial myopia, venture capital grandstanding, investment under cash flow diversion, and product market competition.</description><author>Grenadier, Steven R.; Malenko, Andrey</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Segments Equity Markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekaert, Geert; Harvey, Campbell R.; Lundblad, Christian T.; Siegel, Stephan
We propose a new, valuation-based measure of world equity market segmentation. While we observe decreased levels of segmentation in many countries, the level of segmentation remains significant in emerging markets. We characterize the factors that account for variation in market segmentation both through time as well as across countries. Both a country's regulation with respect to foreign capital flows and certain nonregulatory factors are important. In particular, we identify a country's political risk profile and its stock market development as two additional local segmentation factors as well as the U.S. corporate credit spread as a global segmentation factor.</description><author>Bekaert, Geert; Harvey, Campbell R.; Lundblad, Christian T.; Siegel, Stephan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond Ladders and Optimal Portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Judd, Kenneth L.; Kubler, Felix; Schmedders, Karl
We analyze complex bond portfolios within the framework of a dynamic general equilibrium asset-pricing model. Equilibrium bond portfolios are nonsensical and imply a trading volume that vastly exceeds observed trading volume on financial markets. Instead, portfolios that combine bond ladders with a market portfolio of equity assets are nearly optimal investment strategies. The welfare loss of these simple investment strategies, when compared to the equilibrium portfolio, converges to zero as the length of the bond ladder increases. This article, therefore, provides a rationale for naming bond ladders as a popular bond investment strategy.</description><author>Judd, Kenneth L.; Kubler, Felix; Schmedders, Karl</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Government Ownership Affect the Cost of Debt? Evidence from Privatization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Borisova, Ginka; Megginson, William L.
We explore whether government ownership affects the cost of debt using a sample of fully and partially privatized companies. On average across firms, a one-percentage-point decrease in government ownership is associated with an increase in the credit spread, used as a proxy for the cost of debt, by three-quarters of a basis point. However, fully privatized companies exhibit lower credit spreads than partially privatized firms, indicating the cost of a lengthy privatization process. Empirical evidence suggests that these findings result from decreasing government guarantees, firm performance improvements, ownership uncertainty, and bondholder-shareholder conflicts.</description><author>Borisova, Ginka; Megginson, William L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mergers, Spinoffs, and Employee Incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fulghieri, Paolo; Sevilir, Merih
This article studies mergers between competing firms and shows that while such mergers reduce the level of product market competition, they may have an adverse effect on employee incentives to innovate. In industries where value creation depends on innovation and development of new products, mergers are likely to be inefficient even though they increase the market power of the post-merger firm. In such industries, a stand-alone structure where independent firms compete both in the product market and in the market for employee human capital leads to a greater profitability. Furthermore, our analysis shows that multidivisional firms can improve employee incentives and increase firm value by reducing firm size through a spinoff transaction, although doing so eliminates the economies of scale advantage of being a larger firm and the benefits of operating an internal capital market within the firm. Finally, our article suggests that established firms can benefit from creating their own competition in the product and labor markets by accommodating new firm entry, and the desire to do so is greater at the intermediate stages of industry/product development. (JEL G34)</description><author>Fulghieri, Paolo; Sevilir, Merih</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anticipation, Acquisitions, and Bidder Returns: Industry Shocks and the Transfer of Information across Rivals</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cai, Jie; Song, Moon H.; Walkling, Ralph A.
We document market anticipation of merger bids and show that less anticipated bids earn significantly higher announcement returns. Subsequent bidders in the industry experience significant and positive abnormal returns around the time of initial industry bid announcements. These results suggest that announcement period returns underestimate the wealth effects of bidding. After accounting for anticipation, bidding activity is, on average, a significant wealth-creating event. Moreover, bidders pursuing public targets increase shareholder wealth and bidders in stock swaps do not lose. These results contradict conventional wisdom. Our results shed light on the correct magnitude of acquisition returns and on the transfer of information throughout an industry around the time of an economic shock. (JEL G34, G14)</description><author>Cai, Jie; Song, Moon H.; Walkling, Ralph A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A New Perspective on Gaussian Dynamic Term Structure Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Joslin, Scott; Singleton, Kenneth J.; Zhu, Haoxiang
In any canonical Gaussian dynamic term structure model (GDTSM), the conditional forecasts of the pricing factors are invariant to the imposition of no-arbitrage restrictions. This invariance is maintained even in the presence of a variety of restrictions on the factor structure of bond yields. To establish these results, we develop a novel canonical GDTSM in which the pricing factors are observable portfolios of yields. For our normalization, standard maximum likelihood algorithms converge to the global optimum almost instantaneously. We present empirical estimates and out-of-sample forecasts for several GDTSMs using data on U.S. Treasury bond yields.</description><author>Joslin, Scott; Singleton, Kenneth J.; Zhu, Haoxiang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Price Impact of Institutional Herding</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dasgupta, Amil; Prat, Andrea; Verardo, Michela
We develop a simple model of the price impact of institutional herding. The empirical literature indicates that institutional herding positively predicts short-term returns but negatively predicts long-term returns. We offer a theoretical resolution to this dichotomy. In our model, career-concerned money managers trade with security dealers endowed with market power and exhibit an endogenous tendency to imitate past trades. This tendency is exploited by dealers and thus affects prices. In equilibrium, institutional herding positively predicts short-term returns but negatively predicts long-term returns. Our article also generates several new, testable predictions that link institutional herding with the time-series properties of returns and volume.</description><author>Dasgupta, Amil; Prat, Andrea; Verardo, Michela</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Efficiency and Short Selling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saffi, Pedro A. C.; Sigurdsson, Kari
This article presents a study of how stock price efficiency and return distributions are affected by short-sale constraints. The study is based on a global dataset, from 2005 to 2008, that includes more than 12,600 stocks from 26 countries. We present two main findings. First, lending supply has a significant impact on efficiency. Stocks with higher short-sale constraints, measured as low lending supply, have lower price efficiency. Second, relaxing short-sales constraints is not associated with an increase in either price instability or the occurrence of extreme negative returns.</description><author>Saffi, Pedro A. C.; Sigurdsson, Kari</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Obfuscation, Learning, and the Evolution of Investor Sophistication</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlin, Bruce Ian; Manso, Gustavo
Investor sophistication has lagged behind the growing complexity of retail financial markets. To explore this, we develop a dynamic model to study the interaction between obfuscation and investor sophistication in mutual fund markets. Taking into account different learning mechanisms within the investor population, we characterize the optimal timing of obfuscation for financial institutions who offer retail products. We show that educational initiatives that are directed to facilitate learning by investors may induce providers to increase wasteful obfuscation, further disorienting investors and decreasing overall welfare. Obfuscation decreases with competition among firms, since the information rents from obfuscation dissipate as each institution attracts a smaller market share.</description><author>Carlin, Bruce Ian; Manso, Gustavo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Liquidity and Flow-driven Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Deuskar, Prachi; Johnson, Timothy C.
Using a unique dataset of trades and limit orders for S&amp;P 500 futures, we decompose the aggregate risk into a component driven by the impact of net market orders and a component unrelated to net orders. The first component-flow-driven risk-is large, accounting for approximately 50% of market variance, and it is not transient. This risk represents the joint effect of net trade demand and the price impact of that demand-i.e., illiquidity. We find that flows are largely unpredictable, and lagged flows have no price impact. Flow-driven risk is time varying because price impact is highly variable. Illiquidity rises with market volatility, but not with flow uncertainty. Net selling increases illiquidity, which amplifies downside flow-driven risk. The findings are consistent with flow-driven shocks resulting from fluctuations in aggregate risk-bearing capacity. Under this interpretation, investors with constant risk tolerance should trade against such shocks (i.e., "supply liquidity") to achieve substantial utility gains. Quantitatively accounting for the scale of flow-driven risk poses a major challenge for asset pricing theory.</description><author>Deuskar, Prachi; Johnson, Timothy C.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Impatient Trading, Liquidity Provision, and Stock Selection by Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Da, Zhi; Gao, Pengjie; Jagannathan, Ravi
We show that a mutual fund's stock selection skill can be decomposed into additional components that include liquidity-absorbing impatient trading and liquidity provision. We find that past performance predicts future performance better among funds trading in stocks affected more by information events: Past winners earn a risk-adjusted after-fee excess return of 35 basis points per month in the future. Most of that superior performance comes from impatient trading. We also find that impatient trading is more important for growth-oriented funds, and liquidity provision is more important for younger income funds.</description><author>Da, Zhi; Gao, Pengjie; Jagannathan, Ravi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revisiting Asset Pricing Puzzles in an Exchange Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parlour, Christine A.; Stanton, Richard; Walden, Johan
We show that several well-known asset pricing puzzles are largely mitigated if we endow the representative agent with an arbitrarily small minimum consumption level. This allows us to solve the model for parameter values where the standard "Lucas tree" model is not defined. For these parameters, disasters become more important, and the market risk premium therefore higher, even though consumption is less risky. Our model yields reasonable risk premia, Sharpe ratios, and discount rates; excess price volatility; and a high market price-dividend ratio. We derive closed-form solutions for all variables of interest.</description><author>Parlour, Christine A.; Stanton, Richard; Walden, Johan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Investment Banks Matter for M&amp;A Returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bao, Jack; Edmans, Alex
We document a significant investment bank fixed effect in the announcement returns of M&amp;A deals. The interquartile range of bank fixed effects is 1.26%, compared with a full-sample average return of 0.72%. The results remain significant after controlling for the component of returns attributable to the acquirer. Our findings suggest that investment banks matter for M&amp;A outcomes, and contrast earlier studies that show no positive link between various measures of advisor quality and M&amp;A returns. Differences in average returns across banks are also persistent over time and predictable from prior performance. Clients do not chase past returns, which may explain why persistence exists in M&amp;A performance while it is absent in mutual funds. (JEL G24, G34)</description><author>Bao, Jack; Edmans, Alex</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interbank Contagion at Work: Evidence from a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iyer, Rajkamal; Peydro, Jose-Luis
This article tests financial contagion due to interbank linkages. For identification, we exploit an idiosyncratic, sudden shock caused by a large-bank failure in conjunction with detailed data on interbank exposures. First, we find robust evidence that higher interbank exposure to the failed bank leads to large deposit withdrawals. Second, the magnitude of contagion is higher for banks with weaker fundamentals. Third, interbank linkages among surviving banks further propagate the shock. Finally, we find results suggesting that there are real economic effects. These results suggest that interbank linkages act as an important channel of contagion and hold important policy implications. (JEL G01, G21, G28, E58)</description><author>Iyer, Rajkamal; Peydro, Jose-Luis</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lending Relationships and Loan Contract Terms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bharath, Sreedhar T.; Dahiya, Sandeep; Saunders, Anthony; Srinivasan, Anand
We find that repeated borrowing from the same lender translates into a 10-17 bps lowering of loan spreads and that relationships are especially valuable when borrower transparency is low. These results hold using multiple approaches (propensity score matching, instrumental variables, and treatment effects model) that control for the endogeneity of relationships. We also provide a demarcation line between relationship and transactional lending. Spreads charged for relationship loans and nonrelationship loans are statistically identical if the borrower is in the largest 30% by asset size; has public rated debt; or is part of the S&amp;P 500 index. Past relationships reduce collateral requirements and are also associated with obtaining larger loans. Our results imply that, even for firms that have multiple sources of outside financing, borrowing from a prior lender obtains better loan terms. (JEL D82, G30, G20, G21, G24, L14, N20)</description><author>Bharath, Sreedhar T.; Dahiya, Sandeep; Saunders, Anthony; Srinivasan, Anand</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Too Many to Fail? Evidence of Regulatory Forbearance When the Banking Sector Is Weak</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Craig O.; Dinc, I. Serdar
This article studies bank failures in twenty-one emerging market countries in the 1990s. By using a competing risk hazard model for bank survival, we show that a government is less likely to take over or close a failing bank if the banking system is weak. This Too-Many-to-Fail effect is robust to controlling for macroeconomic factors, financial crises, the Too-Big-to-Fail effect, domestic financial development, and concerns due to systemic risk and information spillovers. The article also shows that the Too-Many-to-Fail effect is stronger for larger banks and when there is a large government budget deficit. (JEL E58, F30, G21, G28)</description><author>Brown, Craig O.; Dinc, I. Serdar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset-Backed Securities: Costs and Benefits of "Bankruptcy Remoteness"</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ayotte, Kenneth; Gaon, Stav
This article focuses on a key property of asset-backed securities (ABS); namely, that ABS are designed to achieve "bankruptcy remoteness" of securitized assets from the borrowing firm. This provides lenders with protection from dilution that is not available with contracts such as secured debt. ABS allows firms to commit to more efficient investment decisions in bankruptcy. Securitization of replaceable assets (such as receivables) prevents inefficient continuation, but securitization of necessary assets can produce ex-post inefficiency, which favors secured debt. We test a prediction of our model using the LTV Steel bankruptcy, in which bankruptcy remoteness was successfully challenged. We find that ABS spreads for Chapter 11-eligible securitizers increased significantly more than spreads for Chapter 11-ineligible securitizers following LTV. (JEL G32, G33, K29)</description><author>Ayotte, Kenneth; Gaon, Stav</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What You Sell Is What You Lend? Explaining Trade Credit Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Burkart, Mike; Ellingsen, Tore
We relate trade credit to product characteristics and aspects of bank-firm relationships and document three main empirical regularities. First, the use of trade credit is associated with the nature of the transacted good. In particular, suppliers of differentiated products and services have larger accounts receivable than suppliers of standardized goods and firms buying more services receive cheaper trade credit for longer periods. Second, firms receiving trade credit secure financing from relatively uninformed banks. Third, a majority of the firms in our sample appear to receive trade credit at low cost. Additionally, firms that are more creditworthy and have some buyer market power receive larger early payment discounts. (JEL G32)</description><author>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Burkart, Mike; Ellingsen, Tore</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of a Strong Bank-Firm Relationship on the Borrowing Firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dass, Nishant; Massa, Massimo
Commercial banks acquire inside information about the firms they lend to. We study the impact of this informationally privileged position on the borrowing firm using a broad panel of U.S. firms over the 1993-2004 period. We measure the strength of the bank-firm relationship by bank-firm proximity, size of the loan, and the lender's insider potential. We show that a stronger relationship, by inducing better monitoring, improves the borrower's corporate governance. Simultaneously, it makes the bank a potentially more informed agent in the equity market. This information asymmetry increases adverse selection for the other market participants and lowers the firm's stock liquidity. This trade-off between improved corporate governance and greater information asymmetry affects the firm's value. Our results have normative implications for the role of banks in the development of financial markets. (JEL G10, G21, G30, G34)</description><author>Dass, Nishant; Massa, Massimo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Are Analyst Recommendation Changes Influential?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loh, Roger K.; Stulz, Rene M.
The existing literature measures the contribution of analyst recommendation changes using average stock-price reactions. With such an approach, recommendation changes can have a significant impact even if no recommendation has a visible stock-price impact. Instead, we call a recommendation change influential only if it affects the stock price of the affected firm visibly. We show that only 12% of recommendation changes are influential. Recommendation changes are more likely to be influential if they are from leader, star, previously influential analysts, issued away from consensus, accompanied by earnings forecasts, and issued on growth, small, high institutional ownership, or high forecast dispersion firms. (JEL G14, G20, G24)</description><author>Loh, Roger K.; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder Activism and CEO Pay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ertimur, Yonca; Ferri, Fabrizio; Muslu, Volkan
We study 134 vote-no campaigns and 1,198 shareholder proposals related to executive pay between 1997 and 2007. Union pension funds sponsor most of these initiatives, yet their targeting criteria do not appear to reflect labor-related motives. Shareholders favor proposals related to the pay-setting process (e.g., subject severance pay to shareholder approval) over proposals that micromanage pay level or structure. While activists target firms with high CEO pay (whether excessive or not), voting support is higher only at firms with excess CEO pay. Firms with excess CEO pay targeted by vote-no campaigns experience a significant reduction in CEO pay ($7.3 million). Our findings contribute to the debate on "say on pay" and other reforms empowering shareholders. (JEL G34, M12, G23, J50)</description><author>Ertimur, Yonca; Ferri, Fabrizio; Muslu, Volkan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are US CEOs Paid More Than U.K. CEOs? Inferences from Risk-adjusted Pay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Conyon, Martin J.; Core, John E.; Guay, Wayne R.
We compute and compare risk-adjusted CEO pay in the United States and United Kingdom, where the risk adjustment is based on estimated risk premiums stemming from the equity incentives borne by CEOs. Controlling for firm and industry characteristics, we find that U.S. CEOs have higher pay, but also bear much higher stock and option incentives than U.K. CEOs. Using reasonable estimates of risk premiums, we find that risk-adjusted U.S. CEO pay does not appear to be large compared to that of U.K. CEOs. We also examine differences in pay and equity incentives between a sample of non-U.K. European CEOs and a matched sample of U.S. CEOs, and find that risk-adjusting pay may explain about half of the apparent higher pay for U.S. CEOs. (JEL G31, G34, M41)</description><author>Conyon, Martin J.; Core, John E.; Guay, Wayne R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fuzzy Math, Disclosure Regulation and Market Outcomes: Evidence from Truth-in-Lending Reform</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stango, Victor; Zinman, Jonathan
We posit that consumer lenders shroud interest rates and market "low monthly payments" to price discriminate on "fuzzy math" or "payment/interest bias": consumers' pervasive tendency to underestimate borrowing costs when an interest rate is not disclosed. We test whether mandated disclosure changes lenders' ability to price discriminate using within-household interactions between payment/interest bias and policy-induced variation in the strength of Truth-in-Lending Act (TILA) enforcement across lenders and time. Weak TILA enforcement substantially widens the gap between rates paid by more-biased and less-biased borrowers. TILA compliance costs appear to increase interest rates overall, making the net effect on interest rates ambiguous. (JEL D01, D03, D10, D40, G20, K20, K42, L50)</description><author>Stango, Victor; Zinman, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Simple Robust Link Between American Puts and Credit Protection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carr, Peter; Wu, Liuren
We develop a simple robust link between deep out-of-the-money American put options on a company's stock and a credit insurance contract on the company's bond. We assume that the stock price stays above a barrier B before default but drops below a lower barrier A after default, thus generating a default corridor [A, B] that the stock price can never enter. Given the presence of this default corridor, a spread between two co-terminal American put options struck within the corridor replicates a pure credit contract, paying off when and only when default occurs prior to the option expiry. (JEL C13, C51, G12, G13)</description><author>Carr, Peter; Wu, Liuren</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pay for Performance? CEO Compensation and Acquirer Returns in BHCs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Minnick, Kristina; Unal, Haluk; Yang, Liu
We examine how managerial incentives affect acquisition decisions in the banking industry. We find that higher pay-for-performance sensitivity (PPS) leads to value-enhancing acquisitions. Banks whose CEOs have higher PPS have significantly better abnormal stock returns around the time of the acquisition announcements. On average, acquirers in the high-PPS group outperform their counterparts in the low-PPS group by 1.4% in a three-day window around the announcement. Higher PPS helps reduce the incentives for making value-destroying acquisitions, while at the same time promotes value-enhancing acquisitions. The positive market reaction can be rationalized by post-merger performance. Following acquisitions, banks with higher PPS experience greater improvements in their operating performance. We show that the effect of PPS is mainly evident in small and medium-sized banks, but is not present in large banks. (JEL G21, G34)</description><author>Minnick, Kristina; Unal, Haluk; Yang, Liu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internal Capital Markets and Corporate Politics in a Banking Group</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Huang, Rocco; Sautner, Zacharias
We analyze proprietary internal capital allocation data from a large retail banking group consisting of member banks and a headquarters organization. We find that capital allocations from headquarters compensate for deposit shortfalls on the bank level, suggesting that the headquarters offers deposit smoothing to member banks. We then analyze how the distribution of influence within the group relates to capital allocations and lending behavior. More influential banks are allocated more funds from headquarters, and their loan growth is less sensitive to their deposit base. The effects of influence are stronger if banks have a greater demand for deposit smoothing. (JEL G21, G31, G32)</description><author>Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Huang, Rocco; Sautner, Zacharias</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Do Banks Listen to Their Analysts? Evidence from Mergers and Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haushalter, David; Lowry, Michelle
We examine the conflicts of interest and the flow of information between divisions of financial institutions. Using data on analyst recommendations and stockholdings of investment banks advising acquirers in mergers, we find evidence that information from investment banking flows to other divisions of the bank. Specifically, following a merger announcement, changes in a bank's stockholdings of the acquirer are positively associated with changes in recommendations by its analyst. This relationship, however, does not exist before the merger announcement. Additional tests show that the relationship between stockholdings and recommendations following a merger announcement is strongest when conflicts of interest for analysts are likely the smallest. (JEL G24, G34)</description><author>Haushalter, David; Lowry, Michelle</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Peso Problems Explain the Returns to the Carry Trade?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Burnside, Craig; Eichenbaum, Martin; Kleshchelski, Isaac; Rebelo, Sergio
We study the properties of the carry trade, a currency speculation strategy in which an investor borrows low-interest-rate currencies and lends high-interest-rate currencies. This strategy generates payoffs that are on average large and uncorrelated with traditional risk factors. We argue that these payoffs reflect a peso problem. The underlying peso event features high values of the stochastic discount factor rather than very large negative payoffs.</description><author>Burnside, Craig; Eichenbaum, Martin; Kleshchelski, Isaac; Rebelo, Sergio</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inheriting Losers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jin, Li; Scherbina, Anna
We show that new managers who take over mutual fund portfolios sell off inherited momentum losers at higher rates than stocks in any other momentum decile, even after adjusting for concurrent trades in these stocks by continuing fund managers. This behavior is observed regardless of fund characteristics and is stronger when new managers are external hires. The tendency of continuing fund managers to hold on to losers could be consistent with either a behavior bias stemming from an inability to ignore the sunk costs associated with the stocks' past underperformance or a conscious desire to protect their careers by not admitting prior mistakes. Furthermore, we present evidence that selling off loser stocks helps improve fund performance.</description><author>Jin, Li; Scherbina, Anna</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Staying, Dropping, or Switching: The Impacts of Bank Mergers on Small Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Degryse, Hans; Masschelein, Nancy; Mitchell, Janet
Assessing the impacts of bank mergers on small firms requires separating borrowers with single versus multiple banking relationships and distinguishing the three alternatives of "staying," "dropping," and "switching" of relationships. Single-relationship borrowers who "switch" to another bank following a merger will be less harmed than those whose relationship is "dropped" and not replaced. Using Belgian data, we find that single-relationship borrowers of target banks are more likely than other borrowers to be dropped. We track postmerger performance and show that many dropped target-bank borrowers are harmed by the merger. Multiple-relationship borrowers are less harmed, as they can better hedge against relationship discontinuations. (JEL G21, G28, G34)</description><author>Degryse, Hans; Masschelein, Nancy; Mitchell, Janet</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Bank Mergers on Loan Prices: Evidence from the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erel, Isil
Bank mergers can increase or decrease loan spreads, depending on whether the increased market power outweighs efficiency gains. Using proprietary loan-level data for U.S. commercial banks, I find that, on average, mergers reduce loan spreads, with the magnitude of the reduction being larger when postmerger cost savings increase. My results suggest that the relation between spreads and the extent of the market overlap between merging banks is nonmonotonic. The market overlap increases cost savings and consequently lowers spreads, but when the overlap is sufficiently large, spreads increase, potentially due to the market-power effect dominating the cost savings. Furthermore, the average reduction in spreads is significant for small businesses. (JEL G21, G28, G34)</description><author>Erel, Isil</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Capital and Value in the Cross-Section</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mehran, Hamid; Thakor, Anjan
We develop a dynamic model of bank capital structure in an acquisitions context which predicts: (i) total bank value and the bank's equity capital are positively correlated in the cross-section, and (ii) the various components of bank value are also positively cross-sectionally related to bank capital. Our empirical tests provide strong support for these predictions. The results are robust to a variety of alternative explanations-growth prospects, desire to acquire toe-hold positions, desire of capital-starved acquirers to buy capital-rich targets, market timing, pecking order, the effect of banks with binding capital requirements, Too Big To Fail, target profitability, risk, and mechanical effects. (JEL G21, G28, G32, G34)</description><author>Mehran, Hamid; Thakor, Anjan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Crisis Resolution and Bank Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Shin, Hyun Song; Yorulmazer, Tanju
What is the effect of financial crises and their resolution on banks' choice of liquidity? When banks have relative expertise in employing risky assets, the market for these assets clears only at fire-sale prices following a large number of bank failures. The gains from acquiring assets at fire-sale prices make it attractive for banks to hold liquid assets. The resulting choice of bank liquidity is countercyclical, inefficiently low during economic booms but excessively high during crises. We present evidence consistent with these predictions. While interventions to resolve banking crises may be desirable ex post, they affect bank liquidity in subtle ways: Liquidity support to failed banks or unconditional support to surviving banks reduces incentives to hold liquidity, whereas support to surviving banks conditional on their liquid asset holdings has the opposite effect.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Shin, Hyun Song; Yorulmazer, Tanju</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Effects of Central Bank Intervention on the Interbank Market During the Subprime Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brunetti, Celso; di Filippo, Mario; Harris, Jeffrey H.
We explore whether central bank intervention improves liquidity in the interbank market during the current subprime crisis with unique trade and quote data from the e-MID, the only regulated electronic interbank market in the world. Central bank intervention consistently creates greater uncertainty in the interbank market. Prior to the crisis, the cover-to-bid ratio effectively conveys good and bad news from the central bank, but this link is broken during the crisis, suggesting that standard (and special) interventions that do not specifically target interbank asymmetric information fail to improve market liquidity. Our results suggest that the central bank should release stress tests for individual banks, provide interbank loan guarantees, or engage in direct asset purchases rather than simply providing more capital when counterparty risk poses systemic risk to the interbank market.</description><author>Brunetti, Celso; di Filippo, Mario; Harris, Jeffrey H.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Composition Matters: Capital Inflows and Liquidity Crunch During a Global Economic Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tong, Hui; Wei, Shang-Jin
This article studies whether the volume and composition of capital flows affect the degree of credit crunch during the 2007-2009 crisis. Using data on 3,823 firms in 24 emerging countries, we find that, on average, the decline in stock prices was more severe for firms that are intrinsically more dependent on external finance for working capital. Interestingly, while the volume of capital flows per se has no significant effect, the composition matters a lot. In particular, greater dependence on non-FDI capital inflows before the crisis worsens the credit crunch during the crisis, while exposure to FDI alleviates the liquidity constraint.</description><author>Tong, Hui; Wei, Shang-Jin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Corporate Loan Pricing Following the Subprime Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Santos, Joao A. C.
The massive losses that banks incurred with the meltdown of the subprime mortgage market have raised concerns about their ability to continue lending to corporations. We investigate these concerns. We find that firms paid higher loan spreads during the subprime crisis. Importantly, the increase in loan spreads was higher for firms that borrowed from banks that incurred larger losses. These results hold after we control for firm-, bank-, and loan-specific factors, and account for endogeneity of bank losses. These findings, together with our evidence that borrowers took out smaller loans during the crisis when they borrowed from banks that incurred larger losses, lend support to the concerns about bank lending following their subprime losses.</description><author>Santos, Joao A. C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization and Mortgage Renegotiation: Evidence from the Great Depression</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghent, Andra C.
We use loan-level data from the New York City metropolitan area to examine the extent to which lenders attempted to prevent foreclosures with concessionary modifications during the Great Depression. We find no principal forgiveness in the sample and only a handful of concessionary mortgage modifications of other types. Far more mortgages terminated through foreclosure than received any sort of concessionary modification. The results indicate that there are significant impediments to renegotiation of residential mortgages beyond securitization. As such, less renegotiation seems unlikely to be a major cost of securitization of residential mortgages.</description><author>Ghent, Andra C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Academic Analysis of the 2008 Financial Crisis: Round 1</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spiegel, Matthew
Academics responded to the challenges posed by the 2008 financial crisis with a flurry of studies. This collection of articles is just the academic community's first look into it. The articles begin with an examination at the last national housing price crash: the great depression of the 1930s. This is followed by articles looking at the current mortgage market and how it behaved. Did modern innovations reflect or add to the downturn? The next set of papers examines how non-financial firms were impacted by the crash. To what degree did credit worthy firms nevertheless find themselves without access to capital? The papers then end with a look into how the banking sector itself fared throughout this period.</description><author>Spiegel, Matthew</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Margin-based Asset Pricing and Deviations from the Law of One Price</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garleanu, Nicolae; Pedersen, Lasse Heje
In a model with heterogeneous-risk-aversion agents facing margin constraints, we show how securities' required returns increase in both their betas and their margin requirements. Negative shocks to fundamentals make margin constraints bind, lowering risk-free rates and raising Sharpe ratios of risky securities, especially for high-margin securities. Such a funding-liquidity crisis gives rise to "bases," that is, price gaps between securities with identical cash-flows but different margins. In the time series, bases depend on the shadow cost of capital, which can be captured through the interest-rate spread between collateralized and uncollateralized loans and, in the cross-section, they depend on relative margins. We test the model empirically using the credit default swap-bond bases and other deviations from the Law of One Price, and use it to evaluate central banks' lending facilities.</description><author>Garleanu, Nicolae; Pedersen, Lasse Heje</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity Management and Corporate Investment During a Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campello, Murillo; Giambona, Erasmo; Graham, John R.; Harvey, Campbell R.
This article uses a unique dataset to study how firms managed liquidity during the 2008-2009 financial crisis. Our analysis provides new insights on interactions between internal liquidity, external funds, and real corporate decisions, such as investment and employment. We first describe how companies used credit lines during the crisis (access, size of facilities, and drawdown activity), the characteristics of these facilities (fees, markups, maturity, and collateral), and whether managers had difficulties in renewing or initiating lines. We also describe the dynamics of credit line violations and the outcome of subsequent renegotiations. We show how companies substitute between credit lines and internal liquidity (cash and profits) when facing a severe credit shortage. Looking at real-side decisions, we find that credit lines are associated with greater spending when companies are not cash-strapped. Firms with limited access to credit lines, in contrast, appear to choose between saving and investing during the crisis. Our evidence indicates that credit lines eased the impact of the financial crisis on corporate spending.</description><author>Campello, Murillo; Giambona, Erasmo; Graham, John R.; Harvey, Campbell R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Influence of the Home Owners' Loan Corporation on Housing Markets During the 1930s</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fishback, Price V.; Flores-Lagunes, Alfonso; Horrace, William C.; Kantor, Shawn; Treber, Jaret
Problems with mortgage financing are widely considered to be a major cause of the recent financial meltdown. Several modern programs have been designed to mimic the Home Owners' Loan Corporation (HOLC) of the 1930s. We analyze the impact of the HOLC on the nonfarm rental and owned home markets for over 2,800 counties in the United States in the 1930s. In sparsely populated counties, where financial markets were not as well developed as in larger cities, the HOLC stimulated demand for owned housing more than it influenced supply. In rental markets the HOLC appears to have contributed to an increase in supply.</description><author>Fishback, Price V.; Flores-Lagunes, Alfonso; Horrace, William C.; Kantor, Shawn; Treber, Jaret</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Privatization and Risk Sharing: Evidence from the Split Share Structure Reform in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Kai; Wang, Tan; Cheung, Yan-Leung; Jiang, Ping
We study the share privatization process in China to investigate whether and how the removal of market frictions is associated with efficiency gains. Prior to the reform, domestic A-shares were divided into tradable and non-tradable shares. As a result of the reform, holders of non-tradable shares compensated holders of tradable shares in order to make their shares tradable. We show that size is positively associated with both the gain in risk sharing and the price impact of more shares coming on the market as a result of the reform. Our study highlights the role of risk sharing in China's share issue privatization process. (JEL G11, G12, G18, G32)</description><author>Li, Kai; Wang, Tan; Cheung, Yan-Leung; Jiang, Ping</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Governance Through Trading and Intervention: A Theory of Multiple Blockholders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex; Manso, Gustavo
Traditional theories argue that governance is strongest under a single large blockholder, as she has high incentives to undertake value-enhancing interventions. However, most firms are held by multiple small blockholders. This article shows that, while such a structure generates free-rider problems that hinder intervention, the same coordination difficulties strengthen a second governance mechanism: disciplining the manager through trading. Since multiple blockholders cannot coordinate to limit their orders and maximize combined trading profits, they trade competitively, impounding more information into prices. This strengthens the threat of disciplinary trading, inducing higher managerial effort. The optimal blockholder structure depends on the relative effectiveness of manager and blockholder effort, the complementarities in their outputs, information asymmetry, liquidity, monitoring costs, and the manager's contract. (JEL D82, G14, G32)</description><author>Edmans, Alex; Manso, Gustavo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance Propagation through Overlapping Directors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bouwman, Christa H. S.
How are governance practices propagated across firms? This article proposes, and empirically verifies, that observed governance practices are partly the outcome of network effects among firms with common directors. While firms attempt to select directors whose other directorships are at firms with similar governance practices ("familiarity effect"), this matching of governance practices is imperfect because other factors also affect the director choice. This generates an "influence effect" as directors acquainted with different practices at other firms influence the firm's governance to move toward the practices of those other firms. These network effects cause governance practices to converge. (JEL D80, G32, 034, R10)</description><author>Bouwman, Christa H. S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Private Equity Advantage: Leveraged Buyout Firms and Relationship Banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ivashina, Victoria; Kovner, Anna
This article examines the impact of leveraged buyout firms' bank relationships on the terms of their syndicated loans. We examine a sample of 1,590 loans financing private equity sponsored leveraged buyouts between 1993 and 2005, and find that private equity firms' bank relationships are an important factor in cross-sectional variation in the loan interest rate and covenant structure. Our results indicate that bank relationships formed through repeated interactions reduce inefficiencies from information asymmetry and allow leveraged buyouts sponsored by private equity firms to occur on favorable loan terms. A one-standard-deviation increase in bank relationship strength is associated with an 8-basis-point (3%) decrease in the spread and a 0.21-basis-point (4%) increase in the maximum debt to EBITDA covenant. We also find evidence that banks price loans to cross-sell other fee business. A one-standard-deviation increase in both bank relationship strength and cross-selling potential translates into as much as a 4-percentage-point increase in equity return to the leveraged buyout firm. (JEL G20, G21, G23, G24, G32)</description><author>Ivashina, Victoria; Kovner, Anna</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short Arbitrage, Return Asymmetry, and the Accrual Anomaly</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, David; Teoh, Siew Hong; Yu, Jeff Jiewei
We find a positive association between short selling and accruals during 1988-2009, and that asymmetry between the up- and downsides of the accrual anomaly is stronger when constraints on short arbitrage are more severe (low availability of loanable shares as proxied by institutional holdings). Short arbitrage occurs primarily among firms in the top accrual decile. Asymmetry is present only on NASDAQ. Thus, there is short arbitrage of the accrual anomaly, but short-sale constraints limit its effectiveness. (JEL G14, G11)</description><author>Hirshleifer, David; Teoh, Siew Hong; Yu, Jeff Jiewei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Implications of Data Screens on Merger and Acquisition Analysis: A Large Sample Study of Mergers and Acquisitions from 1992 to 2009</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Netter, Jeffry; Stegemoller, Mike; Wintoki, M. Babajide
We analyze a comprehensive set of mergers and acquisitions from SDC data from 1992 through 2009. We do not impose common restrictions such as excluding private bidders, small targets, or deals without a deal value. We show a broader scope of mergers and acquisitions activity than that implied in the literature, which generally oversamples larger deals involving public firms. Further, some of our results differ from the extant literature. For example, the finding that mergers occur in waves is attenuated with a greater presence of smaller and/or non-public firms. Also, acquirers gain in most takeovers despite a threefold decline over the sample period in acquirer returns. (JEL G14, G34)</description><author>Netter, Jeffry; Stegemoller, Mike; Wintoki, M. Babajide</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Market Competition and Capital Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Franklin; Carletti, Elena; Marquez, Robert
Empirical evidence suggests that banks hold capital in excess of regulatory minimums. This did not prevent the financial crisis and underlines the importance of understanding bank capital determination. Market discipline is one of the forces that induces banks to hold positive capital. The literature has focused on the liability side. We develop a simple theory based on monitoring to show that discipline from the asset side can also be important. In perfectly competitive markets, banks can find it optimal to use costly capital rather than the interest rate on the loan to commit to monitoring because it allows higher borrower surplus. (JEL G21, G28)</description><author>Allen, Franklin; Carletti, Elena; Marquez, Robert</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of Bank Capital and the Structure of the Banking Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Franklin; Fulghieri, Paolo; Mehran, Hamid
The critical role played by financial institutions in the recent financial crises has generated renewed interest on the corporate finance of the banking firm and the impact of the banking sector on the real economy. This paper introduces the special issue of the Review of Financial Studies dedicated to "The Value of Bank Capital and the Structure of the Banking Industry." The special issue combines papers presented at the conference on "Corporate Finance of Financial Intermediaries" in September 2006, which was jointly organized by the Federal Reserve Bank of New York, the Wharton Financial Institutions Center of the University of Pennsylvania, and the Review of Financial Studies, with other related papers. (JEL G21)</description><author>Allen, Franklin; Fulghieri, Paolo; Mehran, Hamid</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity Biases and the Pricing of Cross-sectional Idiosyncratic Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Yufeng; Lesmond, David
We model a microstructure effect on daily security returns, embodied by zero returns and the bid-ask spread, and derive a closed-form solution for the resulting bias in the estimated idiosyncratic volatility. Our empirical tests show that controlling for the bias eliminates the ability of idiosyncratic volatility estimates to predict future returns. We also find a significant reduction in the pricing ability of idiosyncratic volatility after exogenous shocks to liquidity evidenced in the 1997 reduction in the quotes to sixteenths and the 2001 decimalization. Finally, minimizing liquidity's influence on the estimated idiosyncratic volatility, by orthogonalizing the percentage of zero-return and spread effects on the estimated idiosyncratic volatility, demonstrates that the resulting idiosyncratic volatility estimate has little pricing ability.</description><author>Han, Yufeng; Lesmond, David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>All the News That's Fit to Reprint: Do Investors React to Stale Information?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tetlock, Paul C.
This article tests whether stock market investors appropriately distinguish between new and old information about firms. I define the staleness of a news story as its textual similarity to the previous ten stories about the same firm. I find that firms' stock returns respond less to stale news. Even so, a firm's return on the day of stale news negatively predicts its return in the following week. Individual investors trade more aggressively on news when news is stale. The subsequent return reversal is significantly larger in stocks with above-average individual investor trading activity. These results are consistent with the idea that individual investors overreact to stale information, leading to temporary movements in firms' stock prices.</description><author>Tetlock, Paul C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Impact of Hedge Fund Activism on the Target Firm's Existing Bondholders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klein, April; Zur, Emanuel
In contrast to previous studies documenting positive abnormal returns to target shareholders, we find that hedge fund activism significantly reduces bondholders' wealth. The average excess bond return is -3.9% around the initial 13D filing, and is an additional -4.5% over the remaining year. Excess bond returns are related inversely to subsequent changes in cash and assets (loss of collateral effects) and directly to changes in total debt. Confrontational campaigns and the acquisition of at least one seat on the target's board elicit more negative bond returns. We also find an expropriation of wealth from the bondholder to the shareholder.</description><author>Klein, April; Zur, Emanuel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge Funds: Pricing Controls and the Smoothing of Self-reported Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cassar, Gavin; Gerakos, Joseph
We investigate the extent to which hedge fund managers smooth self-reported returns. In contrast to prior research on the "anomalous" properties of hedge fund returns, we observe the mechanisms used to price the fund's investment positions and report the fund's performance to investors, thereby allowing us to differentiate between asset illiquidity and misreporting-based explanations. We find that funds using less verifiable pricing sources and funds that provide managers with greater discretion in pricing investment positions are more likely to have returns consistent with intentional smoothing. Traditional controls, however, such as removing the manager from the setting and reporting of the fund's net asset value and the use of reputable auditors and administrators, are not associated with lower levels of smoothing. With respect to asset illiquidity versus misreporting, investment style and portfolio characteristics explain 14.0-24.3% of the variation in our smoothing measures, and pricing controls explain an additional 4.1-8.8%, suggesting that asset illiquidity is the major factor driving the anomalous properties of self-reported hedge fund returns.</description><author>Cassar, Gavin; Gerakos, Joseph</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Participation Constraints in the Stock Market: Evidence from Unexpected Inheritance Due to Sudden Death</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andersen, Steffen; Nielsen, Kasper Meisner
We use a natural experiment to investigate the impact of participation constraints on individuals' decisions to invest in the stock market. Unexpected inheritance due to sudden deaths results in exogenous variation in financial wealth, and allows us to examine whether fixed entry and ongoing participation costs cause non-participation. We have three key findings. First, windfall wealth has a positive effect on participation. Second, the majority of households do not react to sizeable windfalls by entering the stock market, but hold on to substantial safe assets-even over longer horizons. Third, the majority of households inheriting stock holdings actively sell the entire portfolio. Overall, these findings suggest that participation by many individuals is unlikely to be constrained by financial participation costs.</description><author>Andersen, Steffen; Nielsen, Kasper Meisner</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do (Some) Households Trade So Much?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Linnainmaa, Juhani T.
When agents can learn about their abilities as active investors, they rationally "trade to learn" even if they expect to lose from active investing. The model used to develop this insight draws conclusions that are consistent with empirical study of household trading behavior: Households' portfolios underperform passive investments; their trading intensity depends on past performance; and they begin by trading small sums of money. Using household data from Finland, the article estimates a structural model of learning and trading. The estimated model shows that investors trade to learn even if they are pessimistic about their abilities as traders. It also demonstrates that realized returns are significantly downward-biased measures of investors' true abilities.</description><author>Linnainmaa, Juhani T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Investors Learn from Experience? Evidence from Frequent IPO Investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiang, Yao-Min; Hirshleifer, David; Qian, Yiming; Sherman, Ann E.
We examine how experience affects the decisions of individual investors and institutions in IPO auctions to bid in subsequent auctions, and their bidding returns. We track bidding histories for all 31,476 individual investors and 1,232 institutional investors across all 84 IPO auctions during the period from 1995 to 2000 in Taiwan. For individual bidders, (1) high returns in previous IPO auctions increase the likelihood of participating in future auctions; (2) bidders' returns decrease as they participate in more auctions; (3) auction selection ability deteriorates with experience; and (4) those with greater experience bid more aggressively. These findings are consistent with naive reinforcement learning wherein individuals become unduly optimistic after receiving good returns. In sharp contrast, there is little sign that institutional investors exhibit such behavior.</description><author>Chiang, Yao-Min; Hirshleifer, David; Qian, Yiming; Sherman, Ann E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Behavioral Biases Adversely Affect the Macro-economy?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korniotis, George M.; Kumar, Alok
We investigate whether the adverse effects of investors' behavioral biases extend beyond the domain of financial markets to the broad macro-economy. Focusing on the income risk-sharing role of financial markets, we find that risk sharing is higher (more than double) in U.S. states where investors are more sophisticated and exhibit weaker behavioral biases. The potential for risk sharing varies geographically, but states with better risk-sharing opportunities are able to achieve higher levels of risk sharing only when investors in those states are more sophisticated. Collectively, these results indicate that investors' aggregate behavioral biases and their lack of financial sophistication adversely affect the local macro-economy.</description><author>Korniotis, George M.; Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed and Uninformed Investment in Housing: The Downside of Diversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Loutskina, Elena; Strahan, Philip E.
Mortgage lenders that concentrate in a few markets invest more in information collection than diversified lenders. Concentrated lenders focus on the information-intensive jumbo market and on high-risk borrowers. They are better positioned to price risks and, thus, ration credit less. Adverse selection, however, leads to higher retention of mortgages relative to diversified lenders. Finally, concentrated lenders have higher profits than diversified lenders, their profits vary less systematically, and their stock prices fell less during the 2007-2008 credit crisis. The results imply that geographic diversification led to a decline in screening by lenders, which likely played a role in the 2007-2008 crisis.</description><author>Loutskina, Elena; Strahan, Philip E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stochastic House Appreciation and Optimal Mortgage Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Piskorski, Tomasz; Tchistyi, Alexei
We characterize the optimal mortgage contract in a continuous-time setting with stochastic growth in house price and income, costly foreclosure, and a risky borrower who requires incentives to repay his debt. We show that many features of subprime loans can be consistent with properties of the optimal contract and that, when house prices decline, mortgage modification can create value for borrowers and lenders. Our model provides a number of empirical predictions that relate the features of mortgage contracts originated in a housing boom and the extent of their modification in a slump to location and borrowers' characteristics.</description><author>Piskorski, Tomasz; Tchistyi, Alexei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Risk-taking, Securitization, Supervision, and Low Interest Rates: Evidence from the Euro-area and the US Lending Standards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maddaloni, Angela; Peydro, Jose-Luis
Using a unique dataset of the Euro-area and the U.S. bank lending standards, we find that low (monetary policy) short-term interest rates soften standards for household and corporate loans. This softening-especially for mortgages-is amplified by securitization activity, weak supervision for bank capital, and low monetary policy rates for an extended period. Conversely, low long-term interest rates do not soften lending standards. Finally, countries with softer lending standards before the crisis related to negative Taylor rule residuals experienced a worse economic performance afterward. These results help shed light on the origins of the crisis and have important policy implications.</description><author>Maddaloni, Angela; Peydro, Jose-Luis</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition, Risk-shifting, and Public Bail-out Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gropp, Reint; Hakenes, Hendrik; Schnabel, Isabel
This article empirically investigates the competitive effects of government bail-out policies. We construct a measure of bail-out perceptions by using rating information. From there, we construct the market shares of insured competitor banks for any given bank, and analyze the impact of this variable on banks' risk-taking behavior, using a large sample of banks from OECD countries. Our results suggest that government guarantees strongly increase the risk-taking of competitor banks. In contrast, there is no evidence that public guarantees increase the protected banks' risk-taking, except for banks that have outright public ownership. These results have important implications for the effects of the recent wave of bank bail-outs on banks' risk-taking behavior.</description><author>Gropp, Reint; Hakenes, Hendrik; Schnabel, Isabel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Originate-to-distribute Model and the Subprime Mortgage Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Purnanandam, Amiyatosh
An originate-to-distribute (OTD) model of lending, where the originator of a loan sells it to various third parties, was a popular method of mortgage lending before the onset of the subprime mortgage crisis. We show that banks with high involvement in the OTD market during the pre-crisis period originated excessively poor-quality mortgages. This result is not explained away by differences in observable borrower quality, geographical location of the property, or the cost of capital of high- and low-OTD banks. Instead, our evidence supports the view that the originating banks did not expend resources in screening their borrowers. The effect of OTD lending on poor mortgage quality is stronger for capital-constrained banks. Overall, we provide evidence that lack of screening incentives coupled with leverage-induced risk-taking behavior significantly contributed to the current subprime mortgage crisis.</description><author>Purnanandam, Amiyatosh</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the Subprime Mortgage Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demyanyk, Yuliya; Van Hemert, Otto
Using loan-level data, we analyze the quality of subprime mortgage loans by adjusting their performance for differences in borrower characteristics, loan characteristics, and macroeconomic conditions. We find that the quality of loans deteriorated for six consecutive years before the crisis and that securitizers were, to some extent, aware of it. We provide evidence that the rise and fall of the subprime mortgage market follows a classic lending boom-bust scenario, in which unsustainable growth leads to the collapse of the market. Problems could have been detected long before the crisis, but they were masked by high house price appreciation between 2003 and 2005.</description><author>Demyanyk, Yuliya; Van Hemert, Otto</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Differences in Governance Practices between U.S. and Foreign Firms: Measurement, Causes, and Consequences (Reprinted from The Review of Financial Studies, vol 22, pg 3131-3169, 2009)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, Reena; Erel, Isil; Stulz, Rene; Williamson, Rohan
We construct a firm-level governance index that increases with minority shareholder protection. Compared with U.S. matching firms, only 12.68% of foreign firms have a higher index. The value of foreign firms falls as their index decreases relative to the index of matching U.S. firms. Our results suggest that lower country-level investor protection and other country characteristics make it suboptimal for foreign firms to invest as much in governance as U.S. firms do. Overall, we find that minority shareholders benefit from governance improvements and do so partly at the expense of controlling shareholders. (JEL 032, 034, G38)</description><author>Aggarwal, Reena; Erel, Isil; Stulz, Rene; Williamson, Rohan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The "Antidirector Rights Index" Revisited</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spamann, Holger
The "antidirector rights index" has been used as a measure of shareholder protection in over a hundred articles since it was introduced by La Porta et al. ("Law and Finance." 1998, Journal of Political Economy 106: 1113-55). A thorough reexamination of the legal data, however, leads to corrections for thirty-three of the forty-six countries analyzed. The correlation between corrected and original values is only 0.53. Consequently, many empirical results established using the original index may not be replicable with corrected values. In particular, the corrected index fails to support three widely influential claims: that shareholder protection is higher in common than in civil law countries; that shareholder protection predicts stock market size or ownership dispersion; and that weak corporate governance explains the extent of exchange rate depreciation during the Asian financial crisis of 1997-1998. (JEL G38, K22, P51)</description><author>Spamann, Holger</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Envious CEOs Cause Merger Waves?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goel, Anand M.; Thakor, Anjan V.
We develop a theory which shows that merger waves can arise even when the shocks that precipitated the initial mergers in the wave are idiosyncratic. The analysis predicts that the earlier acquisitions produce higher bidder returns, involve smaller targets, and result in higher compensation gains for the acquirer's top management team than the later acquisitions in the wave. We find strong empirical support for these predictions. The model also generates additional predictions, some of which remain to be tested. (JEL G34)</description><author>Goel, Anand M.; Thakor, Anjan V.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Visibility and the Decision to Go Private</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mehran, Hamid; Peristiani, Stavros
A large fraction of the companies that went private between 1990 and 2007 were fairly young public firms, often with the same management team making the crucial restructuring decisions at both the time of the initial public offering (IPO) and the buyout. This article investigates the determinants of the decision to go private over a firm's entire public life cycle. Our evidence reveals that firms with declining growth in analyst coverage, falling institutional ownership, and low stock turnover were more likely to go private and opted to do so sooner. We argue that a primary reason behind the decision of IPO firms to abandon their public listing was a failure to attract a critical mass of financial visibility and investor interest. (JEL G34)</description><author>Mehran, Hamid; Peristiani, Stavros</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Law Affects Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haselmann, Rainer; Pistor, Katharina; Vig, Vikrant
The paper investigates the effect of legal change on the lending behavior of banks in twelve transition economies. First, we find that banks increase the supply of credit subsequent to legal change. Second, changes in collateral law matter more for increases in bank lending than do changes in bankruptcy law. We attribute this finding to the different functions of collateral and bankruptcy law. While the former enhances the likelihood that individual creditors can realize their claims against a debtor, the latter ensures an orderly process for resolving multiple, and often conflicting, claims after a debtor has become insolvent. Finally, we find that foreign-owned banks respond more strongly to legal change than incumbents. (JEL F34, F37, G21, G28, G33, K39)</description><author>Haselmann, Rainer; Pistor, Katharina; Vig, Vikrant</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evidence on the Dark Side of Internal Capital Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ozbas, Oguzhan; Scharfstein, David S.
This article documents differences between the Q-sensitivity of investment of stand-alone firms and unrelated segments of conglomerate firms. Unrelated segments exhibit lower Q-sensitivity of investment than stand-alone firms. This fact is driven by unrelated segments of conglomerate firms that tend to invest less than stand-alone firms in high-Q industries. This finding is robust to matching on industry, year, size, age, and profitability. The differences are more pronounced in conglomerates in which top management has small ownership stakes, suggesting that agency problems explain the investment behavior of conglomerates. (JEL D21, D23, G31)</description><author>Ozbas, Oguzhan; Scharfstein, David S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholders at the Gate? Institutional Investors and Cross-Border Mergers and Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Massa, Massimo; Matos, Pedro
We study the role of institutional investors in cross-border mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;As). We find that foreign institutional ownership is positively associated with the intensity of cross-border M&amp;A activity worldwide. Foreign institutional ownership increases the probability that a merger deal is cross-border, successful, and the bidder takes full control of the target firm. This relation is stronger in countries with weaker legal institutions and in less developed markets, suggesting some substitutability between local governance and foreign institutional investors. The results are consistent with the hypothesis that foreign institutional investors act as facilitators in the international market for corporate control; they build bridges between firms and reduce transaction costs and information asymmetry between bidder and target. We conclude that cross-border portfolio investments of institutional money managers and cross-border M&amp;As are complements in promoting financial integration worldwide. (JEL G15, G23, G34)</description><author>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Massa, Massimo; Matos, Pedro</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Levered Equity Risk Premium and Credit Spreads: A Unified Framework</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhamra, Harjoat S.; Kuehn, Lars-Alexander; Strebulaev, Ilya A.
We embed a structural model of credit risk inside a dynamic continuous-time consumption-based asset pricing model, which allows us to price equity and corporate debt in a unified framework. Our key economic assumptions are that the first and second moments of earnings and consumption growth depend on the state of the economy, which switches randomly, creating intertemporal risk, which agents prefer to resolve sooner rather than later, because they have Epstein-Zin-Weil preferences. Agents optimally choose dynamic capital structure and default times. For a dynamic cross-section of firms, our model endogenously generates a realistic average term structure and time series of actual default probabilities and credit spreads, together with a reasonable levered equity risk premium, which varies with macroeconomic conditions. (JEL E44, G12, G32, G33)</description><author>Bhamra, Harjoat S.; Kuehn, Lars-Alexander; Strebulaev, Ilya A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning by Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Seru, Amit; Shumway, Tyler; Stoffman, Noah
Using a large sample of individual investor records over a nine-year period, we analyze survival rates, the disposition effect, and trading performance at the individual level to determine whether and how investors learn from their trading experience. We find evidence of two types of learning: some investors become better at trading with experience, while others stop trading after realizing that their ability is poor. A substantial part of overall learning by trading is explained by the second type. By ignoring investor attrition, the existing literature significantly overestimates how quickly investors become better at trading. (JEL D10, G10)</description><author>Seru, Amit; Shumway, Tyler; Stoffman, Noah</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Can Life Cycle Investors Benefit from Time-Varying Bond Risk Premia?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Koijen, Ralph S. J.; Nijman, Theo E.; Werker, Bas J. M.
We study the importance of time-varying bond risk premia in a consumption and portfolio-choice problem for a life-cycle investor facing short-sales and borrowing constraints. Tilts in the optimal asset allocation in response to changes in bond risk premia exhibit pronounced life-cycle patterns. We find that the investor is willing to pay an annual fee up to 1% to implement a strategy that optimally conditions on prevailing bond risk premia in addition to her age and wealth. To solve our model, we extend recently developed simulation-based techniques to life-cycle problems featuring multiple state variables and multiple risky assets. (JEL G11)</description><author>Koijen, Ralph S. J.; Nijman, Theo E.; Werker, Bas J. M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market-Based Corrective Actions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bond, Philip; Goldstein, Itay; Prescott, Edward Simpson
Many economic agents take corrective actions based on information inferred from market prices of firms' securities. Examples include directors and activists intervening in the management of firms and bank supervisors taking actions to improve the health of financial institutions. We provide an equilibrium analysis of such situations in light of a key problem: if agents use market prices when deciding on corrective actions, prices adjust to reflect this use and potentially become less revealing. We show that market information and agents' information are complementary, and discuss measures that can increase agents' ability to learn from market prices. (JEL D53, D80, G14, G21, G28, G34)</description><author>Bond, Philip; Goldstein, Itay; Prescott, Edward Simpson</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Out-of-Sample Equity Premium Prediction: Combination Forecasts and Links to the Real Economy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rapach, David E.; Strauss, Jack K.; Zhou, Guofu
Welch and Goyal (2008) find that numerous economic variables with in-sample predictive ability for the equity premium fail to deliver consistent out-of-sample forecasting gains relative to the historical average. Arguing that model uncertainty and instability seriously impair the forecasting ability of individual predictive regression models, we recommend combining individual forecasts. Combining delivers statistically and economically significant out-of-sample gains relative to the historical average consistently over time. We provide two empirical explanations for the benefits of forecast combination: (i) combining forecasts incorporates information from numerous economic variables while substantially reducing forecast volatility; (ii) combination forecasts are linked to the real economy. (JEL C22, C53, G11, G12)</description><author>Rapach, David E.; Strauss, Jack K.; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Idiosyncratic Volatility Puzzle: Time Trend or Speculative Episodes?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brandt, Michael W.; Brav, Alon; Graham, John R.; Kumar, Alok
Campbell, Lettau, Malkiel, and Xu (2001) document a positive trend in idiosyncratic volatility during the 1962-1997 period. We show that by 2003 volatility falls back to pre-1990s levels. Furthermore, we show that the increase and subsequent reversal is concentrated among firms with low stock prices and high retail ownership. This evidence suggests that the increase in idiosyncratic volatility through the 1990s was not a time trend but, rather, an episodic phenomenon, at least partially associated with retail investors. Results from cross-sectional regressions, conditional trend estimation, stock-split events, and "attention-grabbing" events are consistent with a retail trading effect. (JEL G11, G12, G14)</description><author>Brandt, Michael W.; Brav, Alon; Graham, John R.; Kumar, Alok</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Analysts Herd? An Analysis of Recommendations and Market Reactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jegadeesh, Narasimhan; Kim, Woojin
This article develops and implements a new test to investigate whether sell-side analysts herd around the consensus when they make stock recommendations. Our empirical results support the herding hypothesis. Stock price reactions following recommendation revisions are stronger when the new recommendation is away from the consensus than when it is closer to it, indicating that the market recognizes analysts' tendency to herd. We find that analysts from larger brokerages, analysts following stocks with smaller dispersion across recommendations, and analysts who make less frequent revisions are more likely to herd. (JEL G14, G20, D82, D83)</description><author>Jegadeesh, Narasimhan; Kim, Woojin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Foreigners Invest Less in Poorly Governed Firms? (Reprinted from The Review of Financial Studies, vol 22, pg 3245-3285, 2009)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leuz, Christian; Lins, Karl V.; Warnock, Francis E.
As domestic sources of outside finance are limited in many countries around the world, it is important to understand factors that influence whether foreign investors provide capital to a country's firms. We study 4,409 firms from twenty-nine countries to assess whether and why concerns about corporate governance result in fewer foreign holdings. We find that foreigners invest less in firms that reside in countries with poor outsider protection and disclosure and have ownership structures that are conducive to governance problems. This effect is particularly pronounced when earnings are opaque, indicating that information asymmetry and monitoring costs faced by foreign investors likely drive the results. (JEL G11, 015, 032, G34)</description><author>Leuz, Christian; Lins, Karl V.; Warnock, Francis E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Returns to Shareholder Activism: Evidence from a Clinical Study of the Hermes UK Focus Fund (Reprinted from The Review of Financial Studies, vol 22, pg 3093-3129, 2009)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becht, Marco; Franks, Julian; Mayer, Colin; Rossi, Stefano
This article reports a unique analysis of private engagements by an activist fund. It is based on data made available to us by Hermes, the fund manager owned by the British Telecom Pension Scheme, on engagements with management in companies targeted by its UK Focus Fund. In contrast with most previous studies of activism, we report that the fund executes shareholder activism predominantly through private interventions that would be unobservable in studies purely relying on public information. The fund substantially outperforms benchmarks and we estimate that abnormal returns are largely associated with engagements rather than stock picking. (JEL G32)</description><author>Becht, Marco; Franks, Julian; Mayer, Colin; Rossi, Stefano</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Pensions Affect Corporate Capital Structure Decisions?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shivdasani, Anil; Stefanescu, Irina
This article examines the capital structure implications of defined benefit corporate pension plans. The magnitude of the liabilities arising from these pension plans is substantial. We show that leverage ratios for firms with pension plans are about 35% higher when pension assets and liabilities are incorporated into the capital structure. We estimate that the tax shields from pension contributions are about a third of those from interest payments. Pension contributions have a modest effect in lowering firms' marginal corporate tax rates. Once pensions are considered, firms are less conservative in their choice of leverage than has been previously thought. We show that firms incorporate the magnitude of their pension assets and liabilities into their capital structure decisions. (JEL G32, H20, J33)</description><author>Shivdasani, Anil; Stefanescu, Irina</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Special Issue: Corporate Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spiegel, Matthew
nan</description><author>Spiegel, Matthew</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The State of Corporate Governance Research</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bebchuk, Lucian A.; Weisbach, Michael S.
This article, which introduces the special issue on corporate governance cosponsored by the Review of Financial Studies and the National Bureau of Economic Research (NBER), reviews and comments on the state of corporate governance research. The special issue features seven articles on corporate governance that were presented in a meeting of the NBER's corporate governance project. Each of the articles represents state-of-the-art research in an important area of corporate governance research. For each of these areas, we discuss the importance of the area and the questions it focuses on, how the article in the special issue makes a significant contribution to this area, and what we do and do not know about the area. We discuss in turn work on shareholders and shareholder activism, directors, executives and their compensation, controlling shareholders, comparative corporate governance, cross-border investments in global capital markets, and the political economy of corporate governance. (JEL G34)</description><author>Bebchuk, Lucian A.; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Do Independent Directors Know? Evidence from Their Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ravina, Enrichetta; Sapienza, Paola
We compare the trading performance of independent directors and other executives. The findings reveal that independent directors earn positive substantial abnormal returns when they purchase their company stock, and that the difference from the same firm's executives is relatively small at most horizons. We also find that executives and independent directors make higher returns in firms with the weakest governance, the gap between these two widens in such firms, and that independent directors sitting on the audit committee earn higher returns than other independent directors at the same firm. Independent directors also earn significantly abnormal returns when they sell the company stock in a window before bad news and around earnings restatements. (JEL G3, G34, K22)</description><author>Ravina, Enrichetta; Sapienza, Paola</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wall Street and Main Street: What Contributes to the Rise in the Highest Incomes?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaplan, Steven N.; Rauh, Joshua
We study how much of the top end of the income distribution is represented by four sectors non-financial-firm top executives (Main Street); investment bankers and hedge, private equity, and mutual fund investors (Wall Street); corporate lawyers; and athletes and celebrities. Wall Street individuals comprise a higher percentage of the top income brackets than nonfinancial executives of public companies. While top executives' representation in the top brackets has increased from 1994 to 2004, Wall Street's representation has likely increased even more. We discuss the implications of our findings for different explanations for the increased skewness at the highest income levels. (JEL D31, G34, J33, M52)</description><author>Kaplan, Steven N.; Rauh, Joshua</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extreme Governance: An Analysis of Dual-Class Firms in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gompers, Paul A.; Ishii, Joy; Metrick, Andrew
We construct a comprehensive list of dual-class firms in the United States and use this list to analyze the relationship between insider ownership and firm value. Our data have two useful features. First, since dual-class stock separates cash-flow rights from voting rights, we can separately identify the impact of each. Second, we address endogeneity concerns by using exogenous predictors of dual-class status as instruments. In single-stage regressions, we find strong evidence that firm value is increasing in insiders' cash-flow rights and decreasing in insider voting rights. In instrumental variable regressions, the point estimates are similar but the significance levels are lower. (JEL G32, G34)</description><author>Gompers, Paul A.; Ishii, Joy; Metrick, Andrew</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Protection and Interest Group Politics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bebchuk, Lucian A.; Neeman, Zvika
We model how three groups-insiders in existing public companies, institutional investors, and entrepreneurs planning to take firms public-compete for influence over politicians setting the level of investor protection. We identify factors that push toward suboptimal investor protection, including corporate insiders' ability to use public firms' assets to influence politicians, and institutional investors' inability to capture fully the value of investor protection for outside investors. Entrepreneurs and public firms' interest in raising equity capital does not fully eliminate the distortions arising from insiders seeking to extract rents from capital in place. Our analysis produces many testable predictions concerning how investor protection varies over time and around the world. (JEL D72, G20, G30, K22, 016)</description><author>Bebchuk, Lucian A.; Neeman, Zvika</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Agency and Bond Covenants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chava, Sudheer; Kumar, Praveen; Warga, Arthur
Based on an analysis of the agency risk for bondholders from managerial entrenchment and fraud, we derive and test refutable hypotheses about the influence of managerial agency risk on bond covenants, using a comprehensive database of corporate bonds from the 1993-2007 period. Managerial entrenchment and the risk of managerial fraud significantly influence the use of covenants, in the direction predicted by the agency-theoretic framework. Our analysis highlights the varied effects of entrenchment on different types of agency risks faced by bondholders: Entrenched managers aggravate investment risk, but ameliorate risk from shareholder opportunism. Covenant use also responds efficiently to the quality of information available regarding the risk of managerial fraud. (JEL D82, G32. G34)</description><author>Chava, Sudheer; Kumar, Praveen; Warga, Arthur</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lending Relationships and Information Rents: Do Banks Exploit Their Information Advantages?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schenone, Carola
In the process of lending to a firm, a bank acquires proprietary firm-specific information that is unavailable to nonlenders. This asymmetric evolution of information between lenders and prospective lenders grants the former an information monopoly. This article empirically investigates whether relationship banks exploit this advantage by charging higher interest rates than those that would prevail were all banks symmetrically informed. My identification strategy hinges on the notion that large information shocks that level the playing field among banks erode the relationship bank's information monopoly. I use the borrower's initial public offering (IPO) as such an information-releasing event, and build a panel dataset in which the unit of observation is a firm's lending relationships before and after its IPO. Prior to a firm's IPO, I find a U-shaped relation between borrowing rates and relationship intensity. After the IPO, interest rates are decreasing in relationship intensity. Furthermore, mean interest rates drop after an IPO. The results are robust to firm and loan-year fixed effects, and to controls for firm leverage pre- and post-IPO. Thus, the reported interest rate pattern is clean of any confounding effects that might arise from changes in financial risk. (JEL D82, G21, G24, G32)</description><author>Schenone, Carola</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endogenous Entry and Partial Adjustment in IPO Auctions: Are Institutional Investors Better Informed?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiang, Yao-Min; Qian, Yiming; Sherman, Ann E.
Using a unique dataset of complete bid information for every IPO auction in Taiwan during 1995-2000, we examine the behaviors and returns of two groups-institutional and retail investors in a setting in which underwriters do not have pricing or allocation discretion. We find that the bids of institutional investors are generally consistent with the predictions of IPO auction theory for informed bidders, while those of individual investors are not. Specifically, returns are higher when more institutional investors enter the auction or bid higher prices, suggesting institutional investors are informed and are also able to shave bids adequately. However, individual investors as a group exhibit return-chasing behavior, are uninformed, and systematically overbid. (JEL G24, G28, G32)</description><author>Chiang, Yao-Min; Qian, Yiming; Sherman, Ann E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Evolution of Corporate Ownership after IPO: The Impact of Investor Protection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foley, C. Fritz; Greenwood, Robin
Panel data on corporate ownership in thirty-four countries between 1995 and 2006 reveal that newly public firms have concentrated ownership regardless of the level of investor protection. After listing, firms in countries with strong investor protection are more likely to experience decreases in ownership concentration; these decreases occur in response to growth opportunities, and they are associated with new share issuance. We conclude that ownership concentration falls after listing in countries with strong investor protection, because firms in these countries continue to raise capital and grow, diluting blockholders as a consequence. (JEL G32, K22, G43)</description><author>Foley, C. Fritz; Greenwood, Robin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internal Governance Mechanisms and Operational Performance: Evidence from Index Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, John C.; Mansi, Sattar A.; Nishikawa, Takeshi
We provide new evidence linking board characteristics and performance. Using manually collected governance data from the mutual fund industry, we find an inverse relation between board size and fund performance. We also find evidence that organizational form plays an important role in determining operational performance. Overall, the results are consistent with the notion that there may not be a single optimal board structure that is applicable to all funds, that attempts to regulate board attributes should he considered with caution, and that sponsor-level factors are important board structure considerations. (JEL G20, G32, G34)</description><author>Adams, John C.; Mansi, Sattar A.; Nishikawa, Takeshi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Asset Allocation: Portfolio Decomposition Formula and Applications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Detemple, Jerome; Rindisbacher, Marcel
A new decomposition of the optimal portfolio, in dynamic models with von Neumann-Morgenstern preferences and Ito prices, is established. The formula rests on a change of numeraire that uses pure discount bonds as units of account. The dynamic hedging demand has two components. The first hedge insures against fluctuations in an optimally designed bond with a maturity date matching the investor's horizon. The second hedge immunizes against fluctuations in the market price of risk in the bond numeraire. Various applications are examined. New results concerning the behavior of extremely risk-averse individuals, the demand for bonds and its long-horizon limit, and the optimal portfolio in incomplete markets are derived.</description><author>Detemple, Jerome; Rindisbacher, Marcel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Determinants of Stock and Bond Return Comovements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baele, Lieven; Bekaert, Geert; Inghelbrecht, Koen
We study the economic sources of stock-bond return comovements and their time variation using a dynamic factor model. We identify the economic factors employing a semistructural regime-switching model for state variables such as interest rates, inflation, the output gap, and cash flow growth. We also view risk aversion, uncertainty about inflation and output, and liquidity proxies as additional potential factors. We find that macroeconomic fundamentals contribute little to explaining stock and bond return correlations but that other factors, especially liquidity proxies, play a more important role. The macro factors are still important in fitting bond return volatility, whereas the "variance premium" is critical in explaining stock return volatility. However, the factor model primarily fails in fitting covariances.</description><author>Baele, Lieven; Bekaert, Geert; Inghelbrecht, Koen</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Market Portfolio May Be Mean/Variance Efficient After All</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Levy, Moshe; Roll, Richard
Numerous studies have examined the mean/variance efficiency of various market proxies by employing sample parameters and have concluded that these proxies are inefficient. These findings cast doubt about the capital asset pricing model (CAPM), one of the cornerstones of modern finance. This study adopts a reverse-engineering approach: given a particular market proxy, we find the minimal variations in sample parameters required to ensure that the proxy is mean/variance efficient. Surprisingly, slight variations in parameters, well within estimation error bounds, suffice to make the proxy efficient. Thus, many conventional market proxies could be perfectly consistent with the CAPM and useful for estimating expected returns.</description><author>Levy, Moshe; Roll, Richard</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Convertible Bond Arbitrageurs as Suppliers of Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Darwin; Getmansky, Mila; Henderson, Brian; Tookes, Heather
This article examines the potential impact of capital supply on security issuance. We focus on the role of convertible bond arbitrageurs as suppliers of capital to convertible bond issuers. We estimate a simultaneous equations model of demand and supply of convertible bond capital, linking the time series of aggregate convertible bond issuance to measures of capital supply: convertible bond arbitrage hedge fund flows, returns, and a proxy for arbitrageurs' use of leverage. We find that issuance is positively and significantly related to increases in all three supply measures. To provide further interpretation, we use the September/October 2008 short-selling ban as a natural experiment to examine the impact of an exogenous shock to the supply of capital from arbitrageurs. Results from both empirical approaches provide evidence that the supply of capital from convertible bond arbitrageurs impacts issuance.</description><author>Choi, Darwin; Getmansky, Mila; Henderson, Brian; Tookes, Heather</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Default Risk Negatively Related to Stock Returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chava, Sudheer; Purnanandam, Amiyatosh
We find a positive cross-sectional relationship between expected stock returns and default risk, contrary to the negative relationship estimated by prior studies. Whereas prior studies use noisy ex post realized returns to estimate expected returns, we use ex ante estimates based on the implied cost of capital. The results suggest that investors expected higher returns for bearing default risk, but they were negatively surprised by lower-than-expected returns on high default risk stocks in the 1980s. We also extend the sample compared with prior studies and find that the evidence based on realized returns is considerably weaker in the 1952-1980 period.</description><author>Chava, Sudheer; Purnanandam, Amiyatosh</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information, the Cost of Credit, and Operational Efficiency: An Empirical Study of Microfinance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garmaise, Mark J.; Natividad, Gabriel
We provide direct evidence on the impact of asymmetric information on both financing and operating activities through a study of credit evaluations of microfinance institutions (MFIs). We employ a regression discontinuity model that exploits the eligibility criteria of an evaluation subsidy offered by a nonprofit consortium. Evaluations dramatically cut the cost of financing. This effect is strongest for commercial lenders and for short-term MFI-lender relationships. The impact of evaluations on the supply of finance is mixed. Evaluated MFIs lend more efficiently, extending more loans per employee.</description><author>Garmaise, Mark J.; Natividad, Gabriel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do Firms Use Private Equity to Opt Out of Public Markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bharath, Sreedhar T.; Dittmar, Amy K.
We investigate how firms weigh the costs and benefits of being public in the decision to opt out of the public market and go private. We draw on previous studies of going private and on the subsequent well-developed theoretical literature on why firms go public to develop our hypotheses. We employ a comprehensive sample of going-private transactions from 1980 to 2004 in the United States and examine how these firms differ over their public life (from IPO to going private) relative to a sample of firms that went and remained public. Our results provide strong support for the importance of information and liquidity considerations in being a public firm. These factors are evident at the IPO, on average thirteen years before the going-private decision. Access to capital and control considerations become increasingly important in the choice of going private over the public life of the firm.</description><author>Bharath, Sreedhar T.; Dittmar, Amy K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance-Sensitive Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Manso, Gustavo; Strulovici, Bruno; Tchistyi, Alexei
This article studies performance-sensitive debt (PSD), the class of debt obligations whose interest payments depend on some measure of the borrower's performance. We demonstrate that the existence of PSD obligations cannot be explained by the trade-off theory of capital structure, as PSD leads to earlier default and lower equity value compared to fixed-rate debt of the same market value. We show that, consistent with the pecking-order theory, PSD can be used as an inexpensive screening device, and we find empirically that firms choosing PSD loans are more likely to improve their credit ratings than firms choosing fixed-interest loans. We also develop a method to value PSD obligations allowing for general payment profiles and obtain closed-form pricing formulas for step-up bonds and linear PSD.</description><author>Manso, Gustavo; Strulovici, Bruno; Tchistyi, Alexei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Going-Public Decision and the Product Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; He, Shan; Nandy, Debarshi K.
At what point in a firm's life should it go public? How do a firm's ex ante product market characteristics relate to its going-public decision? Further, what are the implications of a firm going public on its post-IPO operating and product market performance? In this article, we answer the above questions by conducting the first large sample study of the going-public decisions of U.S. firms in the literature. We use the Longitudinal Research Database (LRD) of the U.S. Census Bureau, which covers the entire universe of private and public U.S. manufacturing firms. Our findings can be summarized as follows. First, a private firm's product market characteristics (total factor productivity [TFP], size, sales growth, market share, industry competitiveness, capital intensity, and cash flow riskiness) significantly affect its likelihood of going public after controlling for its access to private financing (venture capital or bank loans). Second, private firms facing less information asymmetry and those with projects that are cheaper for outsiders to evaluate are more likely to go public. Third, as more firms in an industry go public, the concentration of that industry increases in subsequent years. The above results are robust to controlling for the interactions between various product market and firm-specific variables. Fourth, IPOs of firms occur at the peak of their productivity cycle: the dynamics of TFP and sales growth exhibit an inverted U-shaped pattern, both in our univariate analysis and in our multivariate analysis using firms that remained private throughout as a benchmark. Finally, sales, capital expenditures, and other performance variables exhibit a consistently increasing pattern over the years before and after the IPO. The last two findings are consistent with the view that the widely documented post-IPO operating underperformance of firms is due to the real investment effects of going public rather than being due to earnings management immediately prior to the IPO.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; He, Shan; Nandy, Debarshi K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Evidence on Measuring Financial Constraints: Moving Beyond the KZ Index</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hadlock, Charles J.; Pierce, Joshua R.
We collect detailed qualitative information from financial filings to categorize financial constraints for a random sample of firms from 1995 to 2004. Using this categorization, we estimate ordered logit models predicting constraints as a function of different quantitative factors. Our findings cast serious doubt on the validity of the KZ index as a measure of financial constraints, while offering mixed evidence on the validity of other common measures of constraints. We find that firm size and age are particularly useful predictors of financial constraint levels, and we propose a measure of financial constraints that is based solely on these firm characteristics.</description><author>Hadlock, Charles J.; Pierce, Joshua R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Which Firms Follow the Market? An Analysis of Corporate Investment Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakke, Tor-Erik; Whited, Toni M.
We test whether stock market mispricing or private investor information in stock prices affects corporate investment. We develop an econometric methodology that disentangles stock-price movements that are relevant for investment from those that are not. We combine this decomposition with proxies for private information and mispricing to devise unbiased tests for the effects of mispricing and information on investment. We depart from much of the literature by finding that stock market mispricing does not affect investment, especially that of large firms and firms subject to mispricing. In contrast, we confirm previous evidence that managers incorporate private investor information when making investment decisions.</description><author>Bakke, Tor-Erik; Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Repeated Signaling and Firm Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hennessy, Christopher A.; Livdan, Dmitry; Miranda, Bruno
As an alternative to the pecking order, we develop a dynamic calibratable model where the firm avoids mispricing via signaling. The model is rich, featuring endogenous investment, debt, default, dividends, equity flotations, and share repurchases. In equilibrium, firms with negative private information have negative leverage, issue equity, and overinvest. Firms signal positive information by substituting debt for equity. Default costs induce such firms to underinvest. Model simulations reveal that repeated signaling can account for countercyclical leverage, leverage persistence, volatile procylical investment, and correlation between size and leverage. The model generates other novel predictions. Investment rates are the key predictor of abnormal announcement returns in simulated data, with leverage only predicting returns unconditionally. Firms facing asymmetric information actually exhibit higher mean Q ratios and investment rates.</description><author>Hennessy, Christopher A.; Livdan, Dmitry; Miranda, Bruno</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economic Consequences of IPO Spinning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Xiaoding; Ritter, Jay R.
Using a sample of fifty-six companies going public in 1996-2000 in which top executives received allocations of other hot initial public offerings (IPOs) from the bookrunner, a practice known as spinning, we examine the consequences of spinning. The fifty-six IPOs had first-day returns that were, on average, 23% higher than similar IPOs. The profits collected by these executives were only a small fraction of the incremental amount of money left on the table by their companies when they went public. These companies were dramatically less likely to switch investment bankers in a follow-on offer: only 6% of issuers whose executives were spun switched underwriters, whereas 31% of other issuers switched. These findings suggest that the spinning of executives accomplished its goal of affecting corporate decisions.</description><author>Liu, Xiaoding; Ritter, Jay R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Flexibility and the Optimality of Pay for Sector Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Milbourn, Todd; Song, Fenghua
While standard contract theory suggests that a Chief Executive Officer (CEO) should be paid relative to a benchmark that removes the effects of sector performance, there is evidence that CEO pay is strongly and positively related to such sector performance. In this article, we offer an explanation. We model a CEO charged with selecting the firm's strategy that determines the firm's exposure to sector performance. To incentivize the CEO to choose optimally, pay contracts will be positively and sometimes asymmetrically related to sector performance. Consistent with our predictions, the empirical analysis indicates that the observed sensitivity of pay to sector performance is almost fully confined to multisegment firms and is greater in firms that offer greater strategic flexibility to alter sector exposure, for more talented CEOs and for CEOs as compared to their subordinate executives. Our evidence is robust to alternate explanations such as CEO entrenchment.</description><author>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Milbourn, Todd; Song, Fenghua</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive Compensation: A New View from a Long-Term Perspective, 1936-2005</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frydman, Carola; Saks, Raven E.
We analyze the long-run trends in executive compensation using a new dataset of top officers of large firms from 1936 to 2005. The median real value of compensation was remarkably flat from the late 1940s to the 1970s, revealing a weak relationship between pay and aggregate firm growth. By contrast, this correlation was much stronger in the past thirty years. This historical perspective also suggests that compensation arrangements have often helped to align managerial incentives with those of shareholders because executive wealth was sensitive to firm performance for most of our sample. These new facts pose a challenge to several common explanations for the rise in executive pay since the 1980s.</description><author>Frydman, Carola; Saks, Raven E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option Valuation with Conditional Heteroskedasticity and Nonnormality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Peter; Elkamhi, Redouane; Feunou, Bruno; Jacobs, Kris
We provide results for the valuation of European-style contingent claims for a large class of specifications of the underlying asset returns. Our valuation results obtain in a discrete time, infinite state space setup using the no-arbitrage principle and an equivalent martingale measure (EMM). Our approach allows for general forms of heteroskedasticity in returns, and valuation results for homoskedastic processes can be obtained as a special case. It also allows for conditional nonnormal return innovations, which is critically important because heteroskedasticity alone does not suffice to capture the option smirk. We analyze a class of EMMs for which the resulting risk-neutral return dynamics are from the same family of distributions as the physical return dynamics. In this case, our framework nests the valuation results obtained by Duan (1995) and Heston and Nandi (2000) by allowing for a time-varying price of risk and nonnormal innovations. We provide extensions of these results to more general EMMs and to discrete-time stochastic volatility models, and we analyze the relation between our results and those obtained for continuous-time models.</description><author>Christoffersen, Peter; Elkamhi, Redouane; Feunou, Bruno; Jacobs, Kris</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Discrete-Time Affine Term Structure Models with Generalized Market Prices of Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Le, Anh; Singleton, Kenneth J.; Dai, Qiang
This article develops a rich class of discrete-time, nonlinear dynamic term structure models (DTSMs). Under the risk-neutral measure, the distribution of the state vector X(t) resides within a family of discrete-time affine processes that nests the exact discrete-time counterparts of the entire class of continuous-time models in Duffie and Kan (1996) and Dai and Singleton (2000). Under the historical distribution, our approach accommodates nonlinear (nonaffine) processes while leading to closed-form expressions for the conditional likelihood functions for zero-coupon bond yields. As motivation for our framework, we show that it encompasses many of the equilibrium models with habit-based preferences or recursive preferences and long-run risks. We illustrate our methods by constructing maximum likelihood estimates of a nonlinear discrete-time DTSM with habit-based preferences in which bond prices are known in closed form. We conclude that habit-based models, as typically parameterized in the literature, do not match key features of the conditional distribution of bond yields.</description><author>Le, Anh; Singleton, Kenneth J.; Dai, Qiang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Immobility and Foreign Portfolio Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrade, Sandro C.; Chhaochharia, Vidhi
We examine how residents of the United States allocate their stock portfolios internationally. We find that a large U. S. Foreign Direct Investment (FDI) position in a destination country in 1990 is associated with a relatively large stock portfolio position in that country in the 2001-2006 period. Moreover, a change in the U.S. FDI position from 1980 to 1990 helps predict the change in the U.S. Foreign Portfolio Investment position from 1994 to 2006. These results are rationalized by Van Nieuwerburgh and Veldkamp's (2009) equilibrium model of learning and portfolio choice under an information processing constraint. FDI establishes marginal differences in the endowments of information about different countries, which later translate into differences in stock portfolio holdings. We control for cross-country differences in capital controls, proximity along different dimensions, corporate governance, and economic and capital market development. Our results also hold for the G6 countries collectively.</description><author>Andrade, Sandro C.; Chhaochharia, Vidhi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Side-by-Side Management of Hedge Funds and Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nohel, Tom; Wang, Z. Jay; Zheng, Lu
We examine situations where the same fund manager simultaneously manages mutual funds and hedge funds. We refer to this as side-by-side management. We document 344 such cases involving 693 mutual funds and 538 hedge funds. Proponents of this practice argue that it is essential to hire and retain star performers. Detractors argue that the temptation for abuse is high, and the practice should be banned. Our analysis based on various performance metrics shows that side-by-side mutual fund managers significantly outperform peer funds, consistent with this privilege being granted primarily to star performers. Interestingly, side-by-side hedge fund managers are at best on par with their style category peers, casting further doubt on the idea that conflicts of interest undermine mutual fund investors. Thus, we find no evidence of welfare loss for mutual fund investors due to exploitation of conflicts of interest.</description><author>Nohel, Tom; Wang, Z. Jay; Zheng, Lu</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment under Uncertainty, Heterogeneous Beliefs, and Agency Conflicts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giat, Yahel; Hackman, Steven T.; Subramanian, Ajay
We develop a structural model to investigate the effects of asymmetric beliefs and agency conflicts on dynamic principal agent relationships. Optimism has a first-order effect on incentives, investments, and output, which could reconcile the private equity puzzle. Asymmetric beliefs cause optimal contracts to have features consistent with observed venture capital and research and development (R&amp;D) contracts. We derive testable implications for the effects of project characteristics on contractual features. We calibrate our model to data on pharmaceutical R&amp;D projects and show that optimism indeed significantly influences project values. Permanent and transitory components of risk have opposing effects on project values and durations. (JEL D83, D86, 030)</description><author>Giat, Yahel; Hackman, Steven T.; Subramanian, Ajay</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Private Equity Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Metrick, Andrew; Yasuda, Ayako
This article analyzes the economics of the private equity industry using a novel model and dataset. We obtain data from a large investor in private equity funds, with detailed records on 238 funds raised between 1993 and 2006. We build a model to estimate the expected revenue to managers as a function of their investor contracts, and we test how this estimated revenue varies across the characteristics of our sample funds. Among our sample funds, about two-thirds of expected revenue comes from fixed-revenue components that are not sensitive to performance. We find sharp differences between venture capital ( VC) and buyout (BO) funds. BO managers build on their prior experience by increasing the size of their funds faster than VC managers do. This leads to significantly higher revenue per partner and per professional in later BO funds. The results suggest that the BO business is more scalable than the VC business and that past success has a differential impact on the terms of their future funds.</description><author>Metrick, Andrew; Yasuda, Ayako</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Housing Wealth and Consumption Growth: Evidence from a Large Panel of Households</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gan, Jie
This article uses a large panel dataset that tracks the housing wealth and credit card spending of 12,793 individuals in Hong Kong to study the relationship between housing wealth and household consumption. I identify a significant effect of housing wealth on consumption. A pure wealth effect can explain part of the sensitivity: households with multiple houses have much stronger consumption responses. Consistent with a relaxation of the credit constraints, mortgage refinancing significantly increases households' consumption sensitivities. However, for the majority of the households that do not refinance, consumption sensitivity appears to be due to a reduction in precautionary saving.</description><author>Gan, Jie</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Real Estate Holdings and the Cross-Section of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tuzel, Selale
This article explores the link between the composition of firms' capital and stock returns. I develop a general equilibrium production economy where firms use two factors: real estate and other capital. Investment is subject to asymmetric adjustment costs. Because real estate depreciates slowly, firms with high real estate holdings are more vulnerable to bad productivity shocks and hence are riskier and have higher expected returns. This prediction is supported empirically. I find that the returns of firms with a high share of real estate capital exceed that of low real estate firms by 3-6% annually, adjusted for exposures to the market return, size, value, and momentum factors. Moreover, conditional beta estimates reveal that these firms indeed have higher market betas, and the spread between the betas of high and low real estate firms is countercyclical.</description><author>Tuzel, Selale</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ambiguity in Asset Markets: Theory and Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bossaerts, Peter; Ghirardato, Paolo; Guarnaschelli, Serena; Zame, William R.
This paper studies the impact of ambiguity and ambiguity aversion on equilibrium asset prices and portfolio holdings in competitive financial markets. It argues that attitudes toward ambiguity are heterogeneous across the population, just as attitudes toward risk are heterogeneous across the population, but that heterogeneity of attitudes toward ambiguity has different implications than heterogeneity of attitudes toward risk. In particular, when some state probabilities are not known, agents who are sufficiently ambiguity averse find open sets of prices for which they refuse to hold an ambiguous portfolio. This suggests a different cross section of portfolio choices, a wider range of state price/probability ratios, and different rankings of state price/probability ratios than would be predicted if state probabilities were known. Experiments confirm all of these suggestions. Our findings contradict the claim that investors who have cognitive biases do not affect prices because they are inframarginal: ambiguity-averse investors have an indirect effect on prices because they change the per capita amount of risk that is to be shared among the marginal investors. Our experimental data also suggest a positive correlation between risk aversion and ambiguity aversion that might explain the "value effect" in historical data. (JEL G11, G12, C92, D53)</description><author>Bossaerts, Peter; Ghirardato, Paolo; Guarnaschelli, Serena; Zame, William R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Does the Law of One Price Fail? An Experiment on Index Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, James J.; Laibson, David; Madrian, Brigitte C.
We evaluate why individuals invest in high-fee index funds. In our experiments, subjects each allocate $10,000 across four S&amp;P 500 index funds and are rewarded for their portfolio's subsequent return. Subjects overwhelmingly fail to minimize fees. We reject the hypothesis that subjects buy high-fee index funds because of bundled nonportfolio services. Search costs for fees matter, but even when we eliminate these costs, fees are not minimized. Instead, subjects place high weight on annualized returns since inception. Fees paid decrease with financial literacy. Interestingly, subjects who choose high-fee funds sense they are making a mistake. (JEL C91, D03, D14, G11, G23)</description><author>Choi, James J.; Laibson, David; Madrian, Brigitte C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heterogeneous Expectations and Bond Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xiong, Wei; Yan, Hongjun
This paper presents a dynamic equilibrium model of bond markets in which two groups of agents hold heterogeneous expectations about future economic conditions. The heterogeneous expectations cause agents to take on speculative positions against each other and therefore generate endogenous relative wealth fluctuation. The relative wealth fluctuation amplifies asset price volatility and contributes to the time variation in bond premia. Our model shows that a modest amount of heterogeneous expectations can help explain several puzzling phenomena, including the "excessive volatility" of bond yields, the failure of the expectations hypothesis, and the ability of a tent-shaped linear combination of forward rates to predict bond returns. (JEL D50, D90, G12)</description><author>Xiong, Wei; Yan, Hongjun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Improved Estimates of Higher-Order Comoments and Implications for Portfolio Selection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martellini, Lionel; Ziemann, Volker
In the presence of nonnormally distributed asset returns, optimal portfolio selection techniques require estimates for variance-covariance parameters, along with estimates for higher-order moments and comoments of the return distribution. This is a formidable challenge that severely exacerbates the dimensionality problem already present with mean-variance analysis. This article extends the existing literature, which has mostly focused on the covariance matrix, by introducing improved estimators for the coskewness and cokurtosis parameters. We find that the use of these enhanced estimates generates a significant improvement in investors' welfare. We also find that it is only when improved estimators are used that portfolio selection with higher-order moments dominates mean-variance analysis from an out-of-sample perspective.</description><author>Martellini, Lionel; Ziemann, Volker</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium Asset Pricing and Portfolio Choice Under Asymmetric Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Biais, Bruno; Bossaerts, Peter; Spatt, Chester
We analyze theoretically and empirically the implications of information asymmetry for equilibrium asset pricing and portfolio choice. In our partially revealing dynamic rational expectations equilibrium, portfolio separation fails, and indexing is not optimal. We show how uninformed investors should structure their portfolios, using the information contained in prices to cope with winner's curse problems. We implement empirically this price-contingent portfolio strategy. Consistent with our theory, the strategy outperforms economically and statistically the index. While momentum can arise in the model, in the data, the momentum strategy does not outperform the price-contingent strategy, as predicted by the theory. (JEL G11, G12, G14, D53)</description><author>Biais, Bruno; Bossaerts, Peter; Spatt, Chester</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insider Trades and Demand by Institutional and Individual Investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sias, Richard W.; Whidbee, David A.
There is a strong inverse relation between insider trading and institutional demand the same quarter and over the previous year. Our analysis suggests a combination of factors contribute to this relation. First, institutional investors are more likely to provide the liquidity necessary for insiders to trade. Second, insiders are more likely to buy low valuation and low lag return stocks while institutions are attracted to the opposite security characteristics. Last, the results are consistent with the hypothesis that insiders are more likely to view their securities as overvalued (undervalued) following a period when institutions were net buyers (sellers). (JEL G12, G14)</description><author>Sias, Richard W.; Whidbee, David A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Market Price of Aggregate Risk and the Wealth Distribution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chien, YiLi; Lustig, Hanno
We introduce limited liability in a model with a continuum of ex ante identical agents who face aggregate and idiosyncratic income risk. These agents can trade a complete menu of contingent claims, but they cannot commit to honor their promises, and their shares in a Lucas tree serve as collateral to back up their state-contingent promises. The limited-liability option gives rise to a second risk factor, in addition to aggregate consumption growth risk. This liquidity risk is created by binding solvency constraints, and it is measured by the growth rate of one moment of the wealth distribution. The economy is said to experience a negative liquidity shock when this growth rate is high and a large fraction of agents faces severely binding solvency constraints. The adjustment to the Breeden-Lucas stochastic discount factor induces substantial time variation in equity risk-premims that is consistent with the data at business cycle frequencies. (JEL G12, E44)</description><author>Chien, YiLi; Lustig, Hanno</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Return Dynamics and Learning</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Branch, William A.; Evans, George W.
This article advocates a theory of expectation formation that incorporates many of the central motivations of behavioral finance theory while retaining much of the discipline of the rational expectations approach. We provide a framework in which agents, in an asset pricing model, underparameterize their forecasting model in a spirit similar to Hong, Stein, and Yu (2007) and Barberis, Shleifer, and Vishny (1998), except that the parameters of the forecasting model and the choice of predictor are determined jointly in equilibrium. We show that multiple equilibria can exist even if agents choose only models that maximize (risk-adjusted) expected profits. A real-time learning formulation yields endogenous switching between equilibria. We demonstrate that a real-time learning version of the model, calibrated to U.S. stock data, is capable of reproducing regime-switching returns and volatilities, as recently identified by Guidolin and Timmermann (2007). (JEL G12, G14, D82, D83)</description><author>Branch, William A.; Evans, George W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Demand Curves for Currencies Slope Down? Evidence from the MSCI Global Index Change</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hau, Harald; Massa, Massimo; Peress, Joel
Traditional portfolio balance theory derives a downward sloping currency demand function from limited international asset substitutability. Historically, this theory enjoyed little empirical support. We provide direct evidence by examining the exchange rate effect of a major redefinition of the MSCI Global Equity Index in 2001 and 2002. The index redefinition implied large changes in the representation of different countries in the MSCI Global Equity Index and therefore produced strong exogenous equity flows by index funds. Our event study reveals that countries with a relatively increasing equity representation experienced a relative currency appreciation upon announcement of the index change. Moreover, stock markets that are upweighted (downweighted) feature a higher (lower) permanent comovement of their currency with the basket of other MSCI currencies. (JEL F21, F31, G11, G15)</description><author>Hau, Harald; Massa, Massimo; Peress, Joel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Excess Comovement in International Equity Markets: Evidence from Cross-border Mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brealey, Richard A.; Cooper, Ian A.; Kaplanis, Evi
Using a large sample of cross-border mergers, we measure the effect of a change in location on systematic risk. When a target firm's location moves, a large part of its systematic risk switches from being related to its home equity market to that of the acquirer. On average, the change in betas is equivalent to an excess shift of about 0.5 in the target's beta from its home market to that of the acquirer. We test whether the change in systematic risk can be explained by fundamental factors related to changes in the operations of the firm or merger synergy and find that it cannot. (JEL F23, F36, G12, G15, G34)</description><author>Brealey, Richard A.; Cooper, Ian A.; Kaplanis, Evi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Value of Control in Emerging Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chari, Anusha; Ouimet, Paige P.; Tesar, Linda L.
When a developed-country multinational firm acquires majority control of a firm in an emerging market, there is an economically large and statistically significant increase in the acquiring firm's stock price. In 1986-2006, developed-market acquirers experienced positive and significant abnormal returns of 1.16%, on average, over a three-day event window. Positive acquirer returns and dollar value gains appear unique to emerging-market mergers and acquisitions and are not replicated when the same developed-market acquirers take over firms in developed markets. The size of the stock price increase is more pronounced (a) the weaker the contracting environment in the emerging market and (b) for industries with high asset intangibility. (JEL G15, G34)</description><author>Chari, Anusha; Ouimet, Paige P.; Tesar, Linda L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio Performance and Agency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dybvig, Philip H.; Farnsworth, Heber K.; Carpenter, Jennifer N.
In this paper we analyze the optimal contract for a portfolio manager who can exert effort to improve the quality of a private signal about future market prices. We assume complete markets over states distinguished by asset payoffs and place no restrictions on the form of the contract. We show that trading restrictions are essential because they prevent the manager from undoing the incentive effects of performance-based fees. We provide conditions under which simple benchmarking emerges as optimal compensation. Additional incentives to take risk are necessary when information can be manipulated or else the manager will understate information to offset the benchmarking.</description><author>Dybvig, Philip H.; Farnsworth, Heber K.; Carpenter, Jennifer N.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Investment and Financing under Personal Taxation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morellec, Erwan; Schuerhoff, Norman
In this paper we examine the effects of capital gains taxation on firms' investment and financing decisions. We develop a real-options model in which the timing of investment, the decision to default, and the firm's capital structure are endogenously and jointly determined. Our analysis demonstrates that the asymmetric taxation of capital gains and losses fosters investment by eroding the option value of waiting. It also shows that firms controlled by taxable investors employ more equity financing, the higher the firm's stock price and the worse the firm's historical performance. Using a large sample of U.S. industrial firms that are owned by taxable investors between 1970 and 2008, we present new evidence on corporate investment and financing policies, which is supportive of the model's predictions.</description><author>Morellec, Erwan; Schuerhoff, Norman</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Return Reversals, Idiosyncratic Risk, and Expected Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Wei; Liu, Qianqiu; Rhee, S. Ghon; Zhang, Liang
The empirical evidence on the cross-sectional relation between idiosyncratic risk and expected stock returns is mixed. We demonstrate that the omission of the previous month's stock returns can lead to a negatively biased estimate of the relation. The magnitude of the omitted variable bias depends on the approach to estimating the conditional idiosyncratic volatility. Although a negative relation exists when the estimate is based on daily returns, it disappears after return reversals are controlled for. Return reversals can explain both the negative relation between value-weighted portfolio returns and idiosyncratic volatility and the insignificant relation between equal-weighted portfolio returns and idiosyncratic volatility. In contrast, there is a significantly positive relation between the conditional idiosyncratic volatility estimated from monthly data and expected returns. This relation remains robust after controlling for return reversals.</description><author>Huang, Wei; Liu, Qianqiu; Rhee, S. Ghon; Zhang, Liang</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected Idiosyncratic Skewness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyer, Brian; Mitton, Todd; Vorkink, Keith
We test the prediction of recent theories that stocks with high idiosyncratic skewness should have low expected returns. Because lagged skewness alone does not adequately forecast skewness, we estimate a cross-sectional model of expected skewness that uses additional predictive variables. Consistent with recent theories, we find that expected idiosyncratic skewness and returns are negatively correlated. Specifically, the Fama-French alpha of a low-expected-skewness quintile exceeds the alpha of a high-expected-skewness quintile by 1.00% per month. Furthermore, the coefficients on expected skewness in Fama-MacBeth cross-sectional regressions are negative and significant. In addition, we find that expected skewness helps explain the phenomenon that stocks with high idiosyncratic volatility have low expected returns.</description><author>Boyer, Brian; Mitton, Todd; Vorkink, Keith</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Linkages and Correlated Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colla, Paolo; Mele, Antonio
In a market with informationally connected traders, the dynamics of volume, price informativeness, price volatility, and liquidity are severely affected by the information linkages every trader experiences with his peers. We show that in the presence of information linkages among traders, volume and price informativeness increase. Moreover, we find that information linkages improve or damage market depth, and lower or boost the Traders' profits, according to whether these linkages convey positively or negatively correlated signals. Finally, our model predicts patterns of trade correlation consistent with those identified in the empirical literature: trades generated by "neighbor" traders are positively correlated and trades generated by "distant" traders are negatively correlated.</description><author>Colla, Paolo; Mele, Antonio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Constraints, Investment, and the Value of Cash Holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Denis, David J.; Sibilkov, Valeriy
Previous studies report that cash holdings are more valuable for financially constrained firms than for unconstrained firms. We examine (i) why this is so and (ii) why some constrained firms appear to hold too little cash. Our results indicate that greater cash holdings are associated with higher levels of investment for constrained firms with high hedging needs and that the association between investment and value is stronger for constrained firms than for unconstrained firms. These findings imply that higher cash holdings allow constrained firms to undertake value-increasing projects that might otherwise be bypassed. We further find that some constrained firms exhibit low cash holdings because of persistently low cash flows. Overall, our findings support the view that greater cash holdings of constrained firms are a value-increasing response to costly external financing.</description><author>Denis, David J.; Sibilkov, Valeriy</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ex-dividend Arbitrage in Option Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hao, Jia; Kalay, Avner; Mayhew, Stewart
We examine the behavior of call options surrounding the underlying stock's ex-dividend date. The evidence is inconsistent with the predictions of a rational exercise policy; a significant fraction of the open interest remains unexercised, resulting in a windfall gain to option writers. This triggers a sophisticated trading scheme that enables short-term traders to receive a significant fraction of the gains. The trading scheme inflates reported volume and distorts its traditional relations to liquidity. The dramatic increases in the volume of trade on the last cum-dividend day are facilitated by limitations on transaction costs passed by the various option exchanges.</description><author>Hao, Jia; Kalay, Avner; Mayhew, Stewart</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Growth or Glamour? Fundamentals and Systematic Risk in Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, John Y.; Polk, Christopher; Vuolteenaho, Tuomo
The cash flows of growth stocks are particularly sensitive to temporary movements in aggregate stock prices, driven by shocks to market discount rates, while the cash flows of value stocks are particularly sensitive to permanent movements, driven by shocks to aggregate cash flows. Thus, the high betas of growth (value) stocks with the market's discount-rate (cash-flow) shocks are determined by the cash-flow fundamentals of growth and value companies. Growth stocks are not merely "glamour stocks" whose systematic risks are purely driven by investor sentiment. More generally, the systematic risks of individual stocks with similar accounting characteristics are primarily driven by the systematic risks of their fundamentals.</description><author>Campbell, John Y.; Polk, Christopher; Vuolteenaho, Tuomo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Variance Risk-Premium Dynamics: The Role of Jumps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Todorov, Viktor
Using high-frequency stock market data and (synthetic) variance swap rates, this paper identifies and investigates the temporal variation in the market variance risk-premium. The variance risk is manifest in two salient features of financial returns: stochastic volatility and jumps. The pricing of these two components is analyzed in a general semiparametric framework. The key empirical results imply that investors' fears of future jumps are especially sensitive to recent jump activity and that their willingness to pay for protection against jumps increases significantly immediately after the occurrence of jumps. This in turn suggests that time-varying risk aversion, as previously documented in the literature, is primarily driven by large, or extreme, market moves. The dynamics of risk-neutral jump intensity extracted from deep out-of-the-money put options confirms these findings.</description><author>Todorov, Viktor</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Marital Status and Children on Savings and Portfolio Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Love, David A.
This paper investigates the impact of demographic shocks on optimal decisions about saving, life insurance, and, most centrally, asset allocation. The analysis indicates that marital-status transitions can have important effects on optimal household decisions, particularly in the cases of widowhood and divorce. Children also play a fundamental role in portfolio choice; in addition to leading to substantially different average allocations, they also have strong interaction effects with changes in marital status. Panel data evidence on stockholding suggests that changes in marital status and children matter empirically as well, but not always in the manner that the model predicts.</description><author>Love, David A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expanding Credit Access: Using Randomized Supply Decisions to Estimate the Impacts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karlan, Dean; Zinman, Jonathan
Expanding access to commercial credit is a key ingredient of financial development strategies. There is less consensus on whether expanding access to consumer credit helps borrowers, particularly when loans are extended at high interest rates. Popular skepticism about "unproductive," "usurious" lending is fueled by research highlighting behavioral biases that may induce overborrowing. We estimate the impacts of expanding access to consumer credit at a 200% annual percentage rate (APR) using a field experiment and follow-up data collection. The randomly assigned marginal loans produced significant net benefits for borrowers across a wide range of outcomes. There is also some evidence that the loans were profitable.</description><author>Karlan, Dean; Zinman, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effectiveness of Reputation as a Disciplinary Mechanism in Sell-Side Research (vol 22, pg 3735, 2009)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fang, Lily; Yasuda, Ayako
nan</description><author>Fang, Lily; Yasuda, Ayako</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Price Risk on Housing Demand: Empirical Evidence from U.S. Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Lu
This article examines how price risk affects housing demand. It identifies two relevant channels: a financial risk effect that reduces demand, and a hedging effect that increases demand since current homes may hedge future housing costs. The latter dominates when hedging incentives are strong, namely when the likelihood of moving up the housing ladder is high and the tendency to move across markets is low. For households with weak hedging incentives, the article finds negative effects of price risk on the timing and size of home purchases, but positive effects for households with strong hedging incentives. (JEL C33, D12, D91, J61, R21)</description><author>Han, Lu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Do Household Portfolio Shares Rise in Wealth?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wachter, Jessica A.; Yogo, Motohiro
We develop a life-cycle consumption and portfolio choice model in which households have nonhomothetic utility over two types of goods, basic and luxury. We calibrate the model to match the cross-sectional and life-cycle variation in the basic expenditure share in the Consumer Expenditure Survey. The model explains the degree to which the portfolio share in risky assets rises in wealth in the cross-section of households in the Survey of Consumer Finances. For a given household, the portfolio share can fall in response to an increase in wealth, even though the model implies decreasing relative risk aversion. (JEL D11, D12, G11)</description><author>Wachter, Jessica A.; Yogo, Motohiro</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Event Study Testing with Cross-sectional Correlation of Abnormal Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kolari, James W.; Pynnonen, Seppo
This article examines the issue of cross-sectional correlation in event studies. When there is event-date clustering, we find that even relatively low cross-correlation among abnormal returns is serious in terms of over-rejecting the null hypothesis of zero average abnormal returns. We propose a new test statistic that modifies the t-statistic of Boehmer, Musumeci, and Poulsen (1991) to take into account cross-correlation and show that it performs well in competition with others, including the portfolio approach, which is less powerful than other alternatives under study. Also, our statistic is readily useable to test multiple-day cumulative abnormal returns. (JEL G14, C10, C15)</description><author>Kolari, James W.; Pynnonen, Seppo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>SEO Risk Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlson, Murray; Fisher, Adlai; Giammarino, Ron
We theoretically and empirically investigate firm-level risk dynamics around seasoned equity offerings (SEOs). Empirically, beta increases before SEOs and decreases gradually thereafter. Using real options theory, commitment-to-invest generates a gradual post-issuance beta decline whereas instantaneous investment and time-to-build do not. In a behavioral theory, systematic mispricing can cause increasing pre-issuance and decreasing post-issuance risk but idiosyncratic mispricing cannot. In the empirical cross-section, investment, own-firm runup, SEO proceeds, and primary issuance associated with the real options theory predict beta declines. Sentiment proxies have weaker effects in the full sample, but are significant in a post-1996 subsample. SEOs coincide with low firm- and market-volatility, suggesting volatility-timing in corporate decisions. (JEL G14, G31, G32)</description><author>Carlson, Murray; Fisher, Adlai; Giammarino, Ron</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Judicial Discretion in Corporate Bankruptcy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gennaioli, Nicola; Rossi, Stefano
We study a demand-and-supply model of judicial discretion in corporate bankruptcy. On the supply side, we assume that bankruptcy courts may be biased for debtors or creditors, and subject to career concerns. On the demand side, we assume that debtors (and creditors) can engage in forum shopping at some cost. A key finding is that stronger creditor protection in reorganization improves judicial incentives to resolve financial distress efficiently, preventing a "race to the bottom" toward inefficient uses of judicial discretion. The comparative statics of our model shed light on a lot of evidence on U.S. bankruptcy and yield novel predictions on how bankruptcy codes should affect firm-level outcomes. (JEL G33, K22)</description><author>Gennaioli, Nicola; Rossi, Stefano</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Control of Corporate Decisions: Shareholders vs. Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harris, Milton; Raviv, Artur
This article addresses the issue of whether shareholders would be better off with enhanced control over corporate decisions. The issue has been hotly debated in the recent literature. Our main contribution is to use formal modeling to uncover some factors overlooked in these arguments. For example, we show that claims that shareholder control would reduce value because shareholders lack sufficient information to make important decisions or because they have a non-value-maximizing agenda are flawed. We also show, however, that even if shareholders seek to maximize firm value and can delegate decisions to management, shareholders should not control all major decisions. (JEL G30, G34, G38)</description><author>Harris, Milton; Raviv, Artur</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentives, Targeting, and Firm Performance: An Analysis of Non-executive Stock Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hochberg, Yael V.; Lindsey, Laura
We examine whether options granted to non-executive employees affect firm performance. Using new data on option programs, we explore the link between broad-based option programs, option portfolio implied incentives, and firm operating performance, utilizing an instrumental variables approach to identify causal effects. Firms whose employee option portfolios have higher implied incentives exhibit higher subsequent operating performance. Intuitively, the implied incentive-performance relation is concentrated in firms with fewer employees and in firms with higher growth opportunities. Additionally, the effect is concentrated in firms that grant options broadly to non-executive employees, consistent with theories of cooperation and mutual monitoring among co-workers. (JEL J33, D23, G30, 039, 141, M40, M52, M54)</description><author>Hochberg, Yael V.; Lindsey, Laura</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Shareholders Are Creditors: Effects of the Simultaneous Holding of Equity and Debt by Non-commercial Banking Institutions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Wei; Li, Kai; Shao, Pei
This article provides a comprehensive analysis of a new and increasingly important phenomenon: the simultaneous holding of both equity and debt claims of the same company by non-commercial banking institutions ("dual holders"). The presence of dual holders offers a unique opportunity to assess the existence and magnitude of shareholder-creditor conflicts. We find that syndicated loans with dual holder participation have loan yield spreads that are 18-32 bps lower than those without. The difference remains economically significant after controlling for the selection effect. Further investigation of dual holders' investment horizons and changes in borrowers' credit quality lends support to the hypothesis that incentive alignment between shareholders and creditors plays an important role in lowering loan yield spreads.</description><author>Jiang, Wei; Li, Kai; Shao, Pei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Competition Reduce the Risk of Bank Failure?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martinez-Miera, David; Repullo, Rafael
A large theoretical literature shows that competition reduces banks' franchise values and induces them to take more risk. Recent research contradicts this result: When banks charge lower rates, their borrowers have an incentive to choose safer investments, so they will in turn be safer. However, this argument does not take into account the fact that lower rates also reduce the banks' revenues from performing loans. This paper shows that when this effect is taken into account, a U-shaped relationship between competition and the risk of bank failure generally obtains.</description><author>Martinez-Miera, David; Repullo, Rafael</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Line Usage, Checking Account Activity, and Default Risk of Bank Borrowers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Norden, Lars; Weber, Martin
Information on borrower quality is a fundamental issue in debt contracting, corporate and consumer finance, and financial intermediation. We investigate the link between account activity and information production on borrower risk. Based on a unique data set, we find that credit line usage, limit violations, and cash inflows exhibit abnormal patterns approximately 12 months before default events. Measures of account activity substantially improve default predictions and are especially helpful for monitoring small businesses and individuals. Furthermore, early warning indications result in higher loan spreads, and in a higher likelihood of limit reductions and complete write-offs. Our study shows that account activity provides a real-time window into the borrower's cash flows, thus explaining why banks have an advantage in providing certain types of debt financing.</description><author>Norden, Lars; Weber, Martin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Information Content of Bank Loan Covenants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demiroglu, Cem; James, Christopher M.
This article examines the determinants of financial covenant thresholds in bank loan agreements and information conveyed through the selection of tight financial covenants. We find that riskier firms and firms with fewer investment opportunities select tighter financial covenants. We also find that selection of tight covenants is associated with improvements in the covenant variable and declines in investment spending and net debt issuance. We observe these changes also for borrowers that do not breach their covenants, suggesting that they are not simply the result of creditor influence conditional on a technical default. Furthermore, we find that violations of tightly set covenants have significantly less of an impact on the borrower's investment spending and net debt issuance than violations of loosely set covenants. Overall, our results suggest that the selection of tight covenants conveys information concerning future changes in covenant variables, investment and financial policies, and the outcome of covenant violations.</description><author>Demiroglu, Cem; James, Christopher M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk and Return Characteristics of Venture Capital-Backed Entrepreneurial Companies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korteweg, Arthur; Sorensen, Morten
Valuations of entrepreneurial companies are only observed occasionally, albeit more frequently for well-performing companies. Consequently, estimators of risk and return must correct for sample selection to obtain consistent estimates. We develop a general model of dynamic sample selection and estimate it using data from venture capital investments in entrepreneurial companies. Our selection correction leads to markedly lower intercepts and higher estimates of risks compared to previous studies. The methodology is generally applicable to estimating risk and return in illiquid markets with endogenous trading.</description><author>Korteweg, Arthur; Sorensen, Morten</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Market Synergies and Competition in Mergers and Acquisitions: A Text-Based Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoberg, Gerard; Phillips, Gordon
We use text-based analysis of 10-K product descriptions to examine whether firms exploit product market synergies through asset complementarities in mergers and acquisitions. Transactions are more likely between firms that use similar product market language. Transaction stock returns, ex post cash flows, and growth in product descriptions all increase for transactions with similar product market language, especially in competitive product markets. These gains are larger when targets are less similar to acquirer rivals and when targets have unique products. Our findings are consistent with firms merging and buying assets to exploit synergies to create new products that increase product differentiation.</description><author>Hoberg, Gerard; Phillips, Gordon</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pay (Be)for(e) Performance: The Signing Bonus as an Incentive Device</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Van Wesep, Edward Dickersin
The signing bonus is one of the most common elements of compensation packages for white-collar employees but has received little theoretical and empirical attention. This article investigates the use of a signing bonus as a tool for firms to signal to prospective employees: when they are uncertain regarding their fit with the firm, the signing bonus can serve as a credible signal of the firm's belief of said fit. The theory suggests that we should expect signing bonuses to be more common and larger when the economy is stronger, when employees are less certain of how well they will fit at the firm, when the quality of fit (known to the firm) is higher, and when performance pay is present. Employees receiving a signing bonus work harder, so the signing bonus also serves as an incentive device. This article also presents the first broad empirical look at the use of the signing bonus across industries and time. Evidence is consistent with the theory.</description><author>Van Wesep, Edward Dickersin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock and Option Grants with Performance-based Vesting Provisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bettis, Carr; Bizjak, John; Coles, Jeffrey; Kalpathy, Swaminathan
We assemble a sample of 983 equity-based awards that include either an accelerated- or a contingent-vesting provision tied to firm performance and explore the frequency, contractual nature, usage, and implications of such awards. We find that performance-vesting (p-v) provisions specify meaningful performance hurdles and provide significant incentives for executives. The propensity to use p-v provisions is positively related to the arrival of a new CEO and the proportion of outsiders on the board of directors and negatively related to prior stock performance. Performance-vesting firms have significantly better subsequent operating performance than control firms. Abnormal accounting performance does not arise from earnings management or discernible differences in financial or investment policy.</description><author>Bettis, Carr; Bizjak, John; Coles, Jeffrey; Kalpathy, Swaminathan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Institutional Investors in Initial Public Offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Hu, Gang; Huang, Jiekun
In this article, we use a large sample of transaction-level institutional trading data to analyze the role of institutional investors in initial public offerings (IPOs). The theoretical literature on IPOs has long argued that institutional investors possess private information about IPOs and that underpricing is a mechanism for compensating them to reveal this private information. We study whether institutions indeed have private information about IPOs, retain their information advantage in post-IPO trading, and are able to realize significant profits from their participation in IPOs. We also study institutional IPO allocations and allocation sales to analyze whether institutions play an important role in supporting IPOs in the aftermarket and are rewarded by underwriters for playing such a role. We find that institutions sell 70.2% of their IPO allocations in the first year, fully realize the "money left on the table," and do not dissipate these profits in post-IPO trading. Further, institutions hold allocations in IPOs with weaker post-issue demand for a longer period, and they are rewarded for this by underwriters with more IPO allocations. Finally, institutional trading has predictive power for long-run IPO performance, especially in IPOs in which they received allocations; however, this predictive power decays over time. Overall, our results suggest that institutional investors possess significant private information about IPOs, play an important supportive role in the IPO aftermarket, and receive considerable compensation for their participation in IPOs.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Hu, Gang; Huang, Jiekun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Market Efficiency Measures Yield Correct Inferences? A Comparison of Developed and Emerging Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, John M.; Kelly, Patrick J.; Nardari, Federico
Using data from 56 markets, we find that short-term reversal, post-earnings drift, and momentum strategies earn similar returns in emerging and developed markets. Variance ratios and market delay measures often show greater deviations from random walk pricing in developed markets. Conceptually, we show that commonly used efficiency tests can yield misleading inferences because they do not control for the information environment. Our evidence corrects misperceptions that emerging markets feature larger trading profits and higher return autocorrelation, highlights crucial limitations of weak and semi-strong form efficiency measures, and points to the importance of measuring informational aspects of efficiency. (JEL F30, G14, G15)</description><author>Griffin, John M.; Kelly, Patrick J.; Nardari, Federico</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Design of Corporate Debt Structure and Bankruptcy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>von Thadden, Ernst-Ludwig; Bergloef, Erik; Roland, Gerard
This article integrates the problem of designing corporate bankruptcy rules into a theory of optimal debt structure. We show that, in an optimal contracting framework with imperfect renegotiation, having multiple creditors increases a firm's debt capacity while increasing its incentives to default strategically. The optimal debt contract gives creditors claims that are jointly inconsistent in case of default. Bankruptcy rules are therefore a necessary part of the overall financing contract, to make claims consistent and to prevent a value-reducing run for the assets of the firm. We characterize these rules, with predictions about the allocation of security rights, the right to trigger bankruptcy, and the symmetry of treatment of creditors in default. (JEL G30, K20)</description><author>von Thadden, Ernst-Ludwig; Bergloef, Erik; Roland, Gerard</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Correlation and Default Clustering in Credit Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berndt, Antje; Ritchken, Peter; Sun, Zhiqiang
We establish Markovian models in the Heath, Jarrow, and Morton (1992) paradigm that permit an exponential affine representation of riskless and risky bond prices while offering significant flexibility in the choice of volatility structures. Estimating models in our family is typically no more difficult than in the workhorse affine family. Besides diffusive and jump-induced default correlations, defaults can impact the credit spreads of surviving firms, allowing for a greater clustering of defaults. Numerical implementations highlight the importance of incorporating interest rate credit spread correlations, credit spread impact factors, and the full credit spread curve when building a unified framework for pricing credit derivatives. (JEL C32, C51, G12)</description><author>Berndt, Antje; Ritchken, Peter; Sun, Zhiqiang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The "Dominant Bank Effect:" How High Lender Reputation Affects the Information Content and Terms of Bank Loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ross, David Gaddis
Three large banks control over half of the U.S. commercial loan market by volume through the syndication process. Using attributes of a borrower's location to instrument for lender borrower matching, I show that the borrower stock price response to a loan announcement is more favorable if one of these dominant banks is the lender, especially if the borrower is "opaque." I then show that these banks charge lower interest rates and are more likely to lend without the protection of a borrowing base. The results suggest that the dominant banks have a particularly high reputation for screening and monitoring borrowers. (JEL G21, L14)</description><author>Ross, David Gaddis</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distance and Private Information in Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit; Hauswald, Robert
We study the effects of physical distance on the acquisition and use of private information in informationally opaque credit markets. Using a unique data set of all loan applications by small firms to a large bank, we show that borrower proximity facilitates the collection of soft information, leading to a trade-off in the availability and pricing of credit, which is more readily accessible to nearby firms albeit at higher interest rates ceteris paribus. Analyzing loan rates and firms' decision to switch lenders provides further evidence for banks' strategic use of private information. However, distance erodes our lender's ability to collect proprietary intelligence and to carve out local captive markets, suggesting that the requisite soft information is primarily local. (JEL G21, L11, L14, D44)</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; Hauswald, Robert</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing under Extreme Risk: Contract Terms and Returns to Private Investments in Public Equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaplinsky, Susan; Haushalter, David
We study financial contracting using transactions from the private investments in public equity market. Our tests show that the use of terms that are contingent on an issuer's future performance increases with issuer risk. Among issuers with poorer stock performance, higher cash burn rates, and more uncertain investment prospects, purchase discount-only contracts are uncommon and contracts with contingent terms are frequently used. Our evidence also supports arguments that issuer bargaining power with investors erodes as financing alternatives grow more limited. In particular, terms that can transfer control to investors are most commonly used by issuers in the weakest financial condition. (JEL 024, 032)</description><author>Chaplinsky, Susan; Haushalter, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Information Content of IPO Prospectuses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanley, Kathleen Weiss; Hoberg, Gerard
Using word content analysis, we decompose information in the initial public offering prospectus into its standard and informative components. Greater informative content, as a proxy for premarket due diligence, results in more accurate offer prices and less underpricing, because it decreases the issuing firm's reliance on bookbuilding to price the issue. The opposite is true for standard content. Greater content from high reputation underwriters and issuing firm managers, through Management's Discussion and Analysis, contribute to the informativeness of the prospectus. Our results suggest that premarket due diligence and disclosure by underwriters and issuers can serve as a substitute for costly bookbuilding. (JEL G14, G24, G30, G32)</description><author>Hanley, Kathleen Weiss; Hoberg, Gerard</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Outstanding Debt and the Household Portfolio</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, Thomas A.; Shabani, Reza
This article examines the effect of household debt on investment decisions. We alter a simple portfolio choice model to allow households to retire outstanding debt and realize a risk-free rate of return equal to the interest rate on that debt. Using the Survey of Consumer Finances, we find that households with mortgage debt are 10% less likely to own stocks and 37% less likely to own bonds compared to similar households with no mortgage debt. We calculate the costs of nonoptimal investment in the presence of various forms of household debt. We find that 26% of households should forgo equity market participation on account of the high interest rates they pay on their debt. (JEL D03, D12, D14, G11, G12)</description><author>Becker, Thomas A.; Shabani, Reza</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Temporary versus Permanent Shocks: Explaining Corporate Financial Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorbenko, Alexander S.; Strebulaev, Ilya A.
We investigate corporate financial policies in the presence of both temporary and permanent shocks to firms' cash flows. In our framework, cash flows can be negative and are imperfectly correlated with firm value, and earnings volatility differs from asset volatility. These results are consistent with empirical stylized facts. They are also contrary to the implications of existing dynamic capital structure models that allow only for permanent shocks to cash flows. Temporary shocks increase the importance of financial flexibility and may provide an intuitively simple and realistic explanation of empirically observed financial conservatism and low leverage phenomena. The theoretical framework developed in this article general enough to be used in various corporate finance applications. (JEL G12, G32, G33)</description><author>Gorbenko, Alexander S.; Strebulaev, Ilya A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-Run Risk through Consumption Smoothing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaltenbrunner, Georg; Lochstoer, Lars A.
We examine how long-run consumption risk arises endogenously in a standard production economy model where the representative agent has Epstein-Zin preferences. We show that even when technology growth is i.i.d., optimal consumption smoothing induces long-run risk-highly persistent variation in expected consumption growth. As a consequence, the model can account for a high price of risk, although both consumption growth volatility and the coefficient of relative risk aversion are low. The asset pricing implications of endogenous long-run risk depend crucially on the persistence of technology shocks and investors' preference for the timing of resolution of uncertainty. (JEL E21, E23, E30, G12)</description><author>Kaltenbrunner, Georg; Lochstoer, Lars A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Volatility Dynamics for the S&amp;P500: Evidence from Realized Volatility, Daily Returns, and Option Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Peter; Jacobs, Kris; Mimouni, Karim
Most recent empirical option valuation studies build on the affine square root (SQR) stochastic volatility model. The SQR model is a convenient choice, because it yields closed-form solutions for option prices. We investigate alternatives to the SQR model, by comparing its empirical performance with that of five different but equally parsimonious stochastic volatility models. We provide empirical evidence from three different sources: realized volatilities, S&amp;P500 returns, and an extensive panel of option data. The three sources of data all point to the same conclusion: the best volatility specification is one with linear rather than square root diffusion for variance. This model captures the stylized facts in realized volatilities, it performs well in fitting various samples of index returns, and it has the lowest option implied volatility mean squared error in and out of sample. (JEL G12)</description><author>Christoffersen, Peter; Jacobs, Kris; Mimouni, Karim</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measurement Errors in Investment Equations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, Heitor; Campello, Murillo; Galvao, Antonio F.
We use Monte Carlo simulations and real data to assess the performance of methods dealing with measurement error in investment equations. Our experiments show that fixed effects, error heteroscedasticity, and data skewness severely affect the performance and reliability of methods found in the literature. Estimators that use higher-order moments return biased coefficients for (both) mismeasured and perfectly measured regressors. These estimators are also very inefficient. Instrumental-variable-type estimators are more robust and efficient, although they require restrictive assumptions. We estimate empirical investment models using alternative methods. Real-world investment data contain firm-fixed effects and heteroscedasticity, causing high-order moments estimators to deliver coefficients that are unstable and not economically meaningful. Instrumental variables methods yield estimates that are robust and conform to theoretical priors. Our analysis provides guidance for dealing with measurement errors under circumstances researchers are likely to find in practice.</description><author>Almeida, Heitor; Campello, Murillo; Galvao, Antonio F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reward for Luck in a Dynamic Agency Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoffmann, Florian; Pfeil, Sebastian
This article studies a continuous time principal-agent problem of a firm whose cash flows are determined by the manager's unobserved effort. The firm's cash flows are further subject to persistent and publicly observable shocks that are beyond the manager's control. While standard contracting models predict that compensation should optimally filter out these shocks, empirical evidence suggests otherwise. In line with this evidence, our model predicts that the manager is "rewarded for luck."</description><author>Hoffmann, Florian; Pfeil, Sebastian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Solving Consumption and Portfolio Choice Problems: The State Variable Decomposition Method</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garlappi, Lorenzo; Skoulakis, Georgios
We develop a new solution method for a broad class of discrete-time dynamic portfolio choice problems. The method efficiently approximates conditional expectations of the value function by using (i) a decomposition of the state variables into a component observable by the investor and a stochastic deviation; and (ii) a Taylor expansion of the value function. We illustrate the accuracy of the method in handling several realistic features of portfolio choice problems such as intermediate consumption, multiple assets, multiple state variables, portfolio constraints, non-time-separable preferences, and nonredundant endogenous state variables. We finally use the method to solve a realistic large-scale life-cycle portfolio choice and consumption problem with predictable expected returns and recursive preferences.</description><author>Garlappi, Lorenzo; Skoulakis, Georgios</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Financing-Based Misvaluation Factor and the Cross-Section of Expected Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, David; Jiang, Danling
Behavioral theories suggest that investor misperceptions and market mispricing will be correlated across firms. We use equity and debt financing to identify common misvaluation across firms. A zero-investment portfolio (UMO, undervalued minus overvalued) built from repurchase and issue firms captures comovement in returns beyond that in some standard multifactor models, and substantially improves the Sharpe ratio of the tangency portfolio. Loadings on UMO incrementally predict the cross-section of returns on both portfolios and individual stocks, even among firms not recently involved in external financing activities. Further evidence suggests that UMO loadings proxy for the common component of a stock's misvaluation.</description><author>Hirshleifer, David; Jiang, Danling</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Mispricing Return Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brennan, Michael J.; Wang, Ashley W.
We show that, when stock prices are subject to stochastic mispricing errors, expected rates of return may depend not only on the fundamental risk that is captured by a standard asset pricing model, but also on the type and degree of asset mispricing, even when the mispricing is zero on average. Empirically, the mispricing induced return premium, either estimated using a Kalman filter or proxied by the volatility and variance ratio of residual returns, is shown to be significantly associated with realized risk-adjusted returns.</description><author>Brennan, Michael J.; Wang, Ashley W.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected Returns and Expected Growth in Rents of Commercial Real Estate</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Plazzi, Alberto; Torous, Walter; Valkanov, Rossen
Commercial real estate expected returns and expected rent growth rates are time-varying. Relying on transactions data from a cross-section of U.S. metropolitan areas, we find that up to 30% of the variability of realized returns to commercial real estate can be accounted for by expected return variability, while expected rent growth rate variability explains up to 45% of the variability of realized rent growth rates. The cap rate-that is, the rent-price ratio in commercial real estate-captures fluctuations in expected returns for apartments and retail properties, as well as industrial properties. For offices, by contrast, cap rates do not forecast (in-sample) returns even though expected returns on offices are also time-varying. As implied by the present value relation, cap rates marginally forecast office rent growth but not rent growth of apartments, retail properties, and industrial properties. We link these differences in in-sample predictability to differences in the stochastic properties of the underlying commercial real estate data-generating processes. Also, rent growth predictability is observed mostly in locations characterized by higher population density and stringent land-use restrictions. The opposite is true for return predictability. The dynamic portfolio implications of time-varying commercial real estate returns are also explored in the context of a portfolio manager investing in the aggregate stock market and Treasury bills, as well as commercial real estate.</description><author>Plazzi, Alberto; Torous, Walter; Valkanov, Rossen</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Public Financial News Resolve Asymmetric Information?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tetlock, Paul C.
I use uniquely comprehensive data on financial news events to test four predictions from an asymmetric information model of a firm's stock price. Certain investors trade on information before it becomes public; then, public news levels the playing field for other investors, increasing their willingness to accommodate a persistent liquidity shock. Empirically, I measure public information using firms' stock returns on news days in the Dow Jones archive. I find four patterns in postnews returns and trading volume that are consistent with the asymmetric information model's predictions. Some evidence is, moreover, inconsistent with alternative theories in which traders interpret news differently for rational or behavioral reasons.</description><author>Tetlock, Paul C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Originator Performance, CMBS Structures, and the Risk of Commercial Mortgages</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Titman, Sheridan; Tsyplakov, Sergey
This article examines information and incentive problems that can exist in the market for commercial mortgages that are pooled and repackaged as commercial mortgage-backed securities (CMBSs). We find that mortgages that are originated by institutions with large negative stock returns in the quarters prior to the origination date tend to have higher credit spreads and default more than other mortgages with similar observable characteristics. Properties financed with these mortgages also exhibit weaker post-securitization operating performance. In addition, stock price loser institutions are anxious to securitize mortgages they originate more quickly. Finally we find that credit rating agencies require higher levels of subordination for CMBS pools (i.e., view these pools as riskier) that include more mortgages originated by underperforming originators. This evidence is consistent with reputation models in which poorly performing originators have less incentive to carefully evaluate the credit quality of prospective borrowers, thereby letting relatively riskier mortgages pass through their weaker screening standards.</description><author>Titman, Sheridan; Tsyplakov, Sergey</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Replacement Under Private Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Inderst, Roman; Mueller, Holger M.
This article examines the optimal CEO compensation and replacement policy when the CEO is privately informed about the firm's continuation value under his leadership. Ex ante moral hazard implies that the CEO must receive ex post quasi rents, which endogenously biases him toward continuation. Our model shows that to induce "bad" CEOs to quit, it may be best to make continuation costly (through steep incentive pay) rather than simply rewarding quitting (through severance pay). Incentive pay makes continuation attractive for "good" CEOs, who can expect high future on-the-job pay, but unattractive for "bad" CEOs, who may instead prefer to take their outside option payoff. Our model generates novel empirical implications that jointly relate CEO compensation and turnover to corporate governance, firm size, cash-flow risk, and the informativeness of performance measurement. (JEL G34)</description><author>Inderst, Roman; Mueller, Holger M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Mean-Variance Asset Allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basak, Suleyman; Chabakauri, Georgy
We solve the dynamic mean-variance portfolio problem and derive its time-consistent solution using dynamic programming. Previous literature, in contrast, only determines either myopic or precommitment (committing to follow the initially optimal policy) solutions. We provide a fully analytical simple characterization of the dynamically optimal mean-variance portfolios within a general incomplete-market economy. We also identify a probability measure that incorporates intertemporal hedging demands and facilitates tractability. We illustrate this by easily computing portfolios explicitly under various stochastic investment opportunities. A calibration exercise shows that the mean variance hedging demands are economically significant. (JEL G11, D81, C61)</description><author>Basak, Suleyman; Chabakauri, Georgy</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Representative Agent of an Economy with External Habit Formation and Heterogeneous Risk Aversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xiouros, Costas; Zapatero, Fernando
In this article, we derive an analytic expression for the representative agent of a large class of economies populated by agents with "catching up with the Joneses" preferences, but who exhibit heterogeneous risk aversion. As Chan and Kogan (2002) show numerically, the representative agent has stochastic risk that moves countercyclically to the state variable. However, we show that heterogeneity of risk aversion alone is insufficient for explaining empirical regularities-namely the variability of the Sharpe ratio-that Campbell and Cochrane (1999) obtain in a model of a representative agent with stochastic risk aversion. (JEL D53, E43, G12)</description><author>Xiouros, Costas; Zapatero, Fernando</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Formal versus Informal Finance: Evidence from China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ayyagari, Meghana; Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Maksimovic, Vojislav
The fast growth of Chinese private sector firms is taken as evidence that informal finance can facilitate firm growth better than formal banks in developing countries. We examine firm financing patterns and growth using a database of twenty-four hundred Chinese firms. While a relatively small percentage of firms utilize bank loans, bank financing is associated with faster growth whereas informal financing is not. Controlling for selection, we find that firms with bank financing grow faster than similar firms without bank financing and that our results are not driven by bank corruption or the selection of firms that have accessed the formal financial system. Our findings question whether reputation and relationship-based financing are responsible for the performance of the fastest-growing firms in developing countries. (JEL G21, G30, O16, O17)</description><author>Ayyagari, Meghana; Demirguc-Kunt, Asli; Maksimovic, Vojislav</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Mortgage Design</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Piskorski, Tomasz; Tchistyi, Alexei
This article studies optimal mortgage design in a continuous-time setting with volatile and privately observable income, costly foreclosure, and a stochastic market interest rate. We show that the features of the optimal mortgage are consistent with an option adjustable-rate mortgage (option ARM). Under the optimal contract, the borrower is given discretion of how much to repay until his balance reaches a certain limit. The default rates and interest rate payment on the mortgage correlate positively with the market interest rate. Gains from using the optimal contract relative to simpler mortgages are the biggest for those who face more income variability, buy pricey houses given their income level, or make little or no down payment. Our model thus may help to explain a high concentration of option ARMs among riskier borrowers. (JEL G20, G21, G33)</description><author>Piskorski, Tomasz; Tchistyi, Alexei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Market Liquidity and the Long-run Stock Performance of Debt Issuers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Butler, Alexander W.; Wan, Hong
Previous studies document that the stock returns of bond-issuing firms significantly underperform matched peers over the three to five years following issuance. We revisit this phenomenon and show that the underperformance is the result of an omitted return factor (a "bad model problem"). Debt issuers have significantly higher stock market liquidity than size and book-to-market matched counterparts, and differences in liquidity are largest for the worst-performing groups of issuers. When we additionally match on liquidity or when we include a liquidity factor in the model for expected returns, the evidence of underperformance disappears. (JEL G12, G14, 032)</description><author>Butler, Alexander W.; Wan, Hong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Acquisition Values and Optimal Financial (In)Flexibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hege, Ulrich; Hennessy, Christopher
This article analyzes optimal financial contracts for an incumbent and potential entrant accounting for prospective asset mergers. Exercising a first-mover advantage, the incumbent increases his share of surplus by issuing public debt that appreciates in the event of merger. Incumbent debt reduces the equilibrium value of entrant assets and thus reduces the return to (likelihood of) entry through two channels: venture capitalists recover less in default and ownership rights provide weaker managerial incentives. High incumbent leverage has a countervailing cost, since the resulting debt overhang prevents ex post efficient mergers if merger surplus is low. Event risk covenants limiting counterparty debt are optimal for the incumbent, further limiting the entrant's share of merger surplus. A poison-put covenant is also optimal for the incumbent, allowing him to extract the same surplus with lower debt face value. (JEL G32, G34)</description><author>Hege, Ulrich; Hennessy, Christopher</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>