<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>RFS5</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Dividend Stickiness and Strategic Pooling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guttman, Ilan; Kadan, Ohad; Kandel, Eugene
We argue that dividend stickiness, the tendency of managers to keep dividends unchanged, implies that managers use a partially pooling dividend policy. We offer a model that demonstrates how such a policy can evolve endogenously in equilibrium. An informed manager who cares about the firm's intrinsic value as well as short-term stock price allocates earnings between investments and dividends. We show that there is a continuum of equilibria in which the dividend is constant for a range of realized earnings. Compared with the standard separating equilibrium, this partial pooling behavior induces higher firm value and lower underinvestment. We offer new empirical implications relating the pooling nature of dividend stickiness to the information environment of the firm, dividend prediction models, managerial incentives, and investment.</description><author>Guttman, Ilan; Kadan, Ohad; Kandel, Eugene</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interim News and the Role of Proxy Voting Advice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, Cindy R.; Chen, Mark A.; Seppi, Duane J.; Spatt, Chester S.
This article examines the information content and consequences of third-party voting advice that arrives as news at an interim stage in corporate proxy contests. We first document significant stock returns around announcements of proxy vote recommendations. We then develop a multi-equation empirical procedure for disentangling the price impact of prediction effects (changes in contest outcome probabilities) from the price impact of certification effects (changes in outcome-contingent valuations). Both effects are present in the data: Voting advice is both predictive about contest outcomes and informative about the ability of dissidents to add value. Consequently, proxy advice plays a dual informational role.</description><author>Alexander, Cindy R.; Chen, Mark A.; Seppi, Duane J.; Spatt, Chester S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Structure and Debt Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rauh, Joshua D.; Sufi, Amir
Using a novel dataset that records individual debt issues on the balance sheets of public firms, we demonstrate that traditional capital structure studies that ignore debt heterogeneity miss substantial capital structure variation. Relative to high-credit-quality firms, low-credit-quality firms are more likely to have a multi-tiered capital structure consisting of both secured bank debt with tight covenants and subordinated non-bank debt with loose covenants. We discuss the extent to which these findings are consistent with existing theoretical models of debt structure in which firms simultaneously use multiple debt types to reduce incentive conflicts.</description><author>Rauh, Joshua D.; Sufi, Amir</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short Selling Around Seasoned Equity Offerings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henry, Tyler R.; Koski, Jennifer L.
We use daily short-selling data to examine whether short selling around seasoned equity offerings (SEOs) reflects informed or manipulative trading. Around SEO announcements, we find no evidence of informed short selling. Around issue dates, higher levels of pre-issue short selling are significantly related to larger issue discounts for non-shelf-registered offerings. This evidence is consistent with manipulative trading. We show that SEC Rule 105 constrains some but not all manipulative trading. Our results reverse previous research that uses monthly short-interest data, because daily data allow more powerful tests. Our evidence helps explain the increased popularity of shelf registrations. Although short selling usually enhances price efficiency, we document a situation where short selling reduces price efficiency.</description><author>Henry, Tyler R.; Koski, Jennifer L.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrepreneurial Finance and Nondiversifiable Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hui; Miao, Jianjun; Wang, Neng
We develop a dynamic incomplete-markets model of entrepreneurial firms, and demonstrate the implications of nondiversifiable risks for entrepreneurs' interdependent consumption, portfolio allocation, financing, investment, and business exit decisions. We characterize the optimal capital structure via a generalized tradeoff model where risky debt provides significant diversification benefits. Nondiversifiable risks have several important implications: More risk-averse entrepreneurs default earlier, but choose higher leverage; lack of diversification causes entrepreneurial firms to underinvest relative to public firms, and risky debt partially alleviates this problem; and entrepreneurial risk aversion can overturn the risk-shifting incentives induced by risky debt. We also analytically characterize the idiosyncratic risk premium.</description><author>Chen, Hui; Miao, Jianjun; Wang, Neng</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Regulations Based on Credit Ratings Affect a Firm's Cost of Capital?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kisgen, Darren J.; Strahan, Philip E.
In February 2003, the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission officially certified a fourth credit rating agency, Dominion Bond Rating Service (DBRS), for use in bond investment regulations. After DBRS certification, bond yields change in the direction implied by the firm's DBRS rating relative to its ratings from other certified rating agencies. A one-notch-higher DBRS rating corresponds to a 39-basis-point reduction in a firm's debt cost of capital. The impact on yields is driven by cases where the DBRS rating is better than other ratings and is larger among bonds rated near the investment-grade cutoff. These findings indicate that ratings-based regulations on bond investment affect a firm's cost of debt capital.</description><author>Kisgen, Darren J.; Strahan, Philip E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Aggregate Dynamics of Capital Structure and Macroeconomic Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhamra, Harjoat S.; Kuehn, Lars-Alexander; Strebulaev, Ilya A.
We study the impact of time-varying macroeconomic conditions on optimal dynamic capital structure for a cross-section of firms. Our structural-equilibrium framework embeds a contingent-claim corporate financing model within a consumption-based asset-pricing model. We investigate the effect of macroeconomic conditions on asset valuation and optimal corporate policies, and of preferences on capital structure. While capital structure is pro-cyclical at dates when firms re-lever, it is counter-cyclical in aggregate dynamics, consistent with empirical evidence. We also find that financially constrained firms choose more pro-cyclical policies and that leverage accounts for most of the macroeconomic risk relevant for predicting defaults, but is a poor measure of how preferences impact capital structure.</description><author>Bhamra, Harjoat S.; Kuehn, Lars-Alexander; Strebulaev, Ilya A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dollars Dollars Everywhere, Nor Any Dime to Lend: Credit Limit Constraints on Financial Sector Absorptive Capacity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khwaja, Asim Ijaz; Mian, Atif; Zia, Bilal
We exploit an unexpected inflow of liquidity in an emerging market to study how capital is intermediated to firms. We find that backward-looking credit limit constraints imposed by banks make it difficult for firms to borrow, despite readily available bank liquidity, healthy aggregate demand, and a sharply falling cost of capital. The resulting aggregate failure to extend and retain capital in the economy suggests that agency costs that force banks to rely on sticky balance-sheet-based credit limits prevent emerging economies from effectively intermediating capital.</description><author>Khwaja, Asim Ijaz; Mian, Atif; Zia, Bilal</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multinationals as Arbitrageurs: The Effect of Stock Market Valuations on Foreign Direct Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baker, Malcolm; Foley, C. Fritz; Wurgler, Jeffrey
Empirical evidence of imperfect integration across world capital markets suggests a role for cross-border arbitrage by multinationals. Consistent with multinational arbitrage as a determinant of foreign direct investment (FDI) patterns, we find that FDI flows increase sharply with source-country stock market valuations-025EFparticularly the component of valuations that is predicted to revert the next year, and particularly in the presence of capital account restrictions that limit other mechanisms of cross-country arbitrage. The results suggest the existence of a cheap financial capital channel in which FDI flows reflect, in part, the use of relatively low-cost capital available to overvalued parents in the source country.</description><author>Baker, Malcolm; Foley, C. Fritz; Wurgler, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Big Business Owners in Politics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bunkanwanicha, Pramuan; Wiwattanakantang, Yupana
This paper investigates a little studied but common mechanism that firms use to obtain state favors: business owners themselves seeking election to top office. Using Thailand as a research setting, we find that the more business owners rely on government concessions or the wealthier they are, the more likely they are to run for top office. Once in power, the market valuation of their firms increases dramatically. Surprisingly, the political power does not influence the financing strategies of their firms. Instead, business owners in top offices use their policy-decision powers to implement regulations and public policies favorable to their firms. Such policies hinder not only domestic competitors but also foreign investors. As a result, these politically connected firms are able to capture more market share.</description><author>Bunkanwanicha, Pramuan; Wiwattanakantang, Yupana</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Fraudulent Accounting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kedia, Simi; Philippon, Thomas
We argue that earnings management and fraudulent accounting have important economic consequences. In a model where the costs of earnings management are endogenous, we show that in equilibrium, low-productivity firms hire and invest too much in order to pool with high productivity firms. This behavior distorts the allocation of economic resources in the economy. We test the predictions of the model using firm-level data. We show that during periods of suspicious accounting, firms hire and invest excessively, while managers exercise options. When the misreporting is detected, firms shed labor and capital and productivity improves. Our firm-level results hold both before and after the market crash of 2000. In the aggregate, our model provides a novel explanation for periods of jobless and investment-less growth.</description><author>Kedia, Simi; Philippon, Thomas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Liquidity and Funding Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brunnermeier, Markus K.; Pedersen, Lasse Heje
We provide a model that links an asset's market liquidity (i.e., the ease with which it is traded) and traders' funding liquidity (i.e., the ease with which they can obtain funding). Traders provide market liquidity, and their ability to do so depends on their availability of funding. Conversely, traders' funding, i.e., their capital and margin requirements, depends on the assets' market liquidity. We show that, under certain conditions, margins are destabilizing and market liquidity and funding liquidity are mutually reinforcing, leading to liquidity spirals. The model explains the empirically documented features that market liquidity (i) can suddenly dry up, (ii) has commonality across securities, (iii) is related to volatility, (iv) is subject to "flight to quality," and (v) co-moves with the market. The model provides new testable predictions, including that speculators' capital is a driver of market liquidity and risk premiums.</description><author>Brunnermeier, Markus K.; Pedersen, Lasse Heje</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multiple-Predictor Regressions: Hypothesis Testing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amihud, Yakov; Hurvich, Clifford M.; Wang, Yi
We propose a new hypothesis-testing method for multipredictor regressions in small samples, where the dependent variable is regressed on lagged variables that are autoregressive. The new test is based on the augmented regression method (Amihud and Hurvich, 2004), which produces reduced-bias coefficients and is easy to implement. The method's usefulness is demonstrated by simulations and by testing a model where stock returns are predicted by two variables, income-to-consumption and dividend yield.</description><author>Amihud, Yakov; Hurvich, Clifford M.; Wang, Yi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating Standard Errors in Finance Panel Data Sets: Comparing Approaches</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Petersen, Mitchell A.
In corporate finance and asset pricing empirical work, researchers are often confronted with panel data. In these data sets, the residuals may be correlated across firms or across time, and OLS standard errors can be biased. Historically, researchers in the two literatures have used different solutions to this problem. This paper examines the different methods used in the literature and explains when the different methods yield the same (and correct) standard errors and when they diverge. The intent is to provide intuition as to why the different approaches sometimes give different answers and give researchers guidance for their use.</description><author>Petersen, Mitchell A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do IPOs Affect the Prices of Other Stocks ? Evidence from Emerging Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Braun, Matias; Larrain, Borja
We show that the introduction of a large asset permanently affects the prices of existing assets in a market. Using data from 254 initial public offerings (IPOs) in 22 emerging markets, we find that portfolios that covary highly with the IPO experience a decline in prices relative to other portfolios during the month of the issue. The effects are stronger when the IPO is issued in a market that is less integrated internationally and when the IPO is bigger. This evidence is consistent with the idea that shocks to asset supply have a significant effect on asset prices.</description><author>Braun, Matias; Larrain, Borja</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO Pricing and Allocation: A Survey of the Views of Institutional Investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jenkinson, Tim; Jones, Howard
Despite the central importance of investors to all initial public offering (IPO) theories, relatively little is known about their role in practice. This article is based on a survey of how institutional investors assess IPOs, what information they provide to the investment banking syndicate, and the factors they believe influence allocations. We find that investor characteristics, in particular brokerage relationships with the bookrunner, are perceived to be the most important factors influencing allocations, which supports the view that IPO allocations are part of implicit quid pro quo deals with investment banks. The survey raises doubts as to the extent of information production or revelation.</description><author>Jenkinson, Tim; Jones, Howard</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Choice of Corporate Liquidity and Corporate Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yun, Hayong
In this paper, I study how corporate governance influences firms' choices between cash and lines of credit. Stakeholders may disagree about firms' liquidity choices because they differ in the allocation of ex-post control rights for the firms' liquidity reserves. Using state-level changes in takeover protection as exogenous shocks to corporate governance, I find that firms increase cash relative to lines of credit when the threat of takeover weakens. Consistent with the theory, this tendency is weaker for firms with good internal governance. Overall, my findings suggest the choice of corporate liquidity is a channel through which corporate governance works.</description><author>Yun, Hayong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Takeovers and the Cross-Section of Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Nair, Vinay B.; John, Kose
This paper considers the impact of the takeover likelihood on firm valuation. If firms are more likely to acquire when there is more free cash or lower required rates of return, the targets become more sensitive to shocks to cash flows or the price of risk. Ceteris paribus, firms exposed to takeovers have different rates of return than protected firms. Using takeover likelihood estimates, we create a "takeover factor," buying (selling) firms with a high (low) takeover likelihood, which generates "abnormal" returns. Several tests confirm that the takeover factor helps explaining cross-sectional differences in equity returns and is related to takeover activity.</description><author>Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Nair, Vinay B.; John, Kose</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Myth of Diffuse Ownership in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Holderness, Clifford G.
This article offers evidence on the ownership concentration at a representative sample of U.S. public firms. Ninety-six percent of these firms have blockholders; these blockholders in aggregate own an average 39% of the common stock. The ownership of U.S. firms is similar to and by some measures more concentrated than the ownership of firms in other countries. These findings challenge current thinking on a number of issues, ranging from the nature of the agency conflict in domestic corporations to the relationship between ownership concentration and legal protections for investors around the world.</description><author>Holderness, Clifford G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Analysts' Performance: Sector Versus Country Specialization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sonney, Frederic
Brokerage houses normally structure their research activities along either country or sector lines. I investigate whether organizational structure affects the quality of financial analysts' earnings forecasts. Specifically, I compare the performance of country-specialized financial analysts with that of sector-specialized financial analysts. The former issue forecasts considerably more accurately than the latter. Country specialists benefit from an informational advantage over sector specialists. A superior knowledge of country-specific factors, as well as geographical proximity between analysts and the firms they cover, are significant determinants of this advantage.</description><author>Sonney, Frederic</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Margin Trading, Overpricing, and Synchronization Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhojraj, Sanjeev; Bloomfield, Robert J.; Tayler, William B.
We provide experimental evidence that relaxing margin restrictions to allow more short selling can exacerbate overpricing, even though it reduces equilibrium price levels. This is because smart-money traders initially profit more by front-running optimistic investor sentiment than by disciplining prices. When short selling is not possible, competitive pressures among arbitrageurs rapidly drive prices to the equilibrium. However, the risk of margin calls slows the convergence process, because arbitrageurs who sell short too early face substantial losses if they are unable to synchronize their trades with other arbitrageurs (as in Abreu and Brunnermeier. 2002. Journal of Financial Economics 66(2-3):341-60; 2003. Econometrica 71(1):173-204).</description><author>Bhojraj, Sanjeev; Bloomfield, Robert J.; Tayler, William B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A General Stochastic Volatility Model for the Pricing of Interest Rate Derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Trolle, Anders B.; Schwartz, Eduardo S.
We develop a tractable and flexible stochastic volatility multifactor model of the term structure of interest rates. It features unspanned stochastic volatility factors, correlation between innovations to forward rates and their volatilities, quasi-analytical prices of zero-coupon bond options, and dynamics of the forward rate curve, under both the actual and risk-neutral measures, in terms of a finite-dimensional affine state vector. The model has a very good fit to an extensive panel dataset of interest rates, swaptions, and caps. In particular, the model matches the implied cap skews and the dynamics of implied volatilities.</description><author>Trolle, Anders B.; Schwartz, Eduardo S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Systematic Risk and the Price Structure of Individual Equity Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duan, Jin-Chuan; Wei, Jason
This study demonstrates the impact of systematic risk on the prices of individual equity options. The option prices are characterized by the level and slope of implied volatility curves, and the systematic risk is measured as the proportion of systematic variance in the total variance. Using daily option quotes on the S, and P 100 index and its 30 largest component stocks, we show that after controlling for the underlying asset's total risk, a higher amount of systematic risk leads to a higher level of implied volatility and a steeper slope of the implied volatility curve. Thus, systematic risk proportion can help differentiate the price structure across individual equity options.</description><author>Duan, Jin-Chuan; Wei, Jason</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Failure Is an Option: Impediments to Short Selling and Options Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Evans, Richard B.; Geczy, Christopher C.; Musto, David K.; Reed, Adam V.
Regulations allow market makers to short sell without borrowing stock, and the transactions of a major options market maker show that in most hard-to-borrow situations, it chooses not to borrow and instead fails to deliver stock to its buyers. A part of the value of failing passes through to options prices: when failing is cheaper than borrowing, the relation between borrowing costs and options prices is significantly weaker. The remaining value is profit to the market maker, and its ability to profit despite competition between market makers appears to result from the cost advantage of larger market makers.</description><author>Evans, Richard B.; Geczy, Christopher C.; Musto, David K.; Reed, Adam V.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Versus Naive Diversification: How Inefficient is the 1/N Portfolio Strategy?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeMiguel, Victor; Garlappi, Lorenzo; Uppal, Raman
We evaluate the out-of-sample performance of the sample-based mean-variance model, and its extensions designed to reduce estimation error, relative to the naive 1/N portfolio. Of the 14 models we evaluate across seven empirical datasets, none is consistently better than the 1/N rule in terms of Sharpe ratio, certainty-equivalent return, or turnover, which indicates that, out of sample, the gain from optimal diversification is more than offset by estimation error. Based on parameters calibrated to the US equity market, our analytical results and simulations show that the estimation window needed for the sample-based mean-variance strategy and its extensions to outperform the 1/N benchmark is around 3000 months for a portfolio with 25 assets and about 6000 months for a portfolio with 50 assets. This suggests that there are still many "miles to go" before the gains promised by optimal portfolio choice can actually be realized out of sample.</description><author>DeMiguel, Victor; Garlappi, Lorenzo; Uppal, Raman</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distinguishing the Effect of Overconfidence from Rational Best-Response on Information Aggregation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kogan, Shimon
This article studies the causal effect of individuals' overconfidence and bounded rationality on information aggregation by using a new multiperiod game in which agents are rewarded for submitting accurate estimates of an unknown asset's value based on (i) their private information and (ii) others' past estimates. By carrying out laboratory sessions of this game in which subjects' overconfidence is a treatment variable, I find that overconfidence affects the information aggregation process by increasing the dispersion of estimates and decreasing the rate of estimates' convergence. However, even when subjects are not overconfident, qualitatively similar deviations from the fully rational model predictions are observed. I show that this can be explained by subjects' strategic response to errors.</description><author>Kogan, Shimon</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insider Trading Laws and Stock Price Informativeness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernandes, Nuno; Ferreira, Miguel A.
We investigate the relation between a country's first-time enforcement of insider trading laws and stock price informativeness using data from 48 countries over 1980-2003. Enforcement of insider trading laws improves price informativeness, as measured by firm-specific stock return variation, but this increase is concentrated in developed markets. In emerging market countries, price informativeness changes insignificantly after the enforcement, as the important contribution of insiders in impounding information into stock prices largely disappears. The enforcement does not achieve the goal of improving price informativeness in countries with poor legal institutions. It does turn some private information into public information, thereby reducing the cost of equity in emerging markets.</description><author>Fernandes, Nuno; Ferreira, Miguel A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ambiguity and Nonparticipation: The Role of Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easley, David; O'Hara, Maureen
We investigate the implications of ambiguity aversion for performance and regulation of markets. In our model, agents' decision making may incorporate both risk and ambiguity, and we demonstrate that nonparticipation arises from the rational decision by some traders to avoid ambiguity. In equilibrium, these participation decisions affect the equilibrium risk premium, and distort market performance when viewed from the perspective of traditional asset pricing models. We demonstrate how regulation, particularly regulation of unlikely events, can moderate the effects of ambiguity, thereby increasing participation and generating welfare gains. Our analysis demonstrates how legal systems affect participation in financial markets through their influence on ambiguity.</description><author>Easley, David; O'Hara, Maureen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentives and Mutual Fund Performance: Higher Performance or Just Higher Risk Taking ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, Massimo; Patgiri, Rajdeep
We study the impact of contractual incentives on the performance of mutual funds. We find that high-incentive contracts induce managers to take more risk and reduce the funds' probability of survival. Yet, funds with high-incentive contracts deliver higher risk-adjusted return, and the superior performance remains persistent. The top incentive quintile of funds outperforms the bottom quintile by 2.70% per year. Moreover, high-incentive winner funds from one year have a positive alpha of 0.41% per month in the following year. Focusing on funds' holdings, we show that active portfolio rebalancing is the main channel through which incentives increase performance.</description><author>Massa, Massimo; Patgiri, Rajdeep</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dividends and Corporate Shareholders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barclay, Michael J.; Holderness, Clifford G.; Sheehan, Dennis P.
Corporations uniquely have a tax preference for cash dividends. Nevertheless, dividends do not increase following trades of large-percentage blocks of stock from individuals to corporations. Moreover, although one-third of firms have corporate blockholders, 68% of these firms pay no dividends, and ownership is not clustered at levels that increase the tax benefits of dividends. These findings are not driven by the investing firms' tax rates or by agency problems. Instead, operating companies expand the target firms and pursue joint ventures. Dividends are lower with these investors. Financial investors are not attracted to dividend-paying firms and tend to be passive.</description><author>Barclay, Michael J.; Holderness, Clifford G.; Sheehan, Dennis P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Long-Term Effects of Cross-Listing, Investor Recognition, and Ownership Structure on Valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>King, Michael R.; Segal, Dan
We show that investor recognition and bonding associated with a U.S. cross-listing are distinct effects using a sample of Canadian firms. In contrast to the post-listing decline documented in the literature, we find that cross-listed firms with a single class of shares enjoy a permanent increase in valuation if they attract and maintain investor recognition over time. Valuations of firms that fail to widen their U.S. shareholder base return to pre-listing levels within two years. Cross-listed firms with dual-class shares exhibit a permanent increase in valuation regardless of the level of U.S. investor holdings, consistent with firm-level bonding.</description><author>King, Michael R.; Segal, Dan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment, Financing Constraints, and Internal Capital Markets: Evidence from the Advertising Expenditures of Multinational Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fee, C. Edward; Hadlock, Charles J.; Pierce, Joshua R.
We find a significant positive relation between a firm's advertising spending in the United States and its contemporaneous foreign cash flow. This relation holds even after controlling for factors that should be related to the optimal level of domestic advertising, and it is stronger for subsets of firms that we expect to be relatively more financially constrained. Our evidence supports the hypothesis that there is a causal and economically substantial link between cash flow and investment spending, even for intangible investments such as advertising. Our evidence also suggests that firms have active internal capital markets in which capital is moved across geographic regions.</description><author>Fee, C. Edward; Hadlock, Charles J.; Pierce, Joshua R.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Politically Connected Boards Affect Firm Value ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldman, Eitan; Rocholl, Joerg; So, Jongil
This article explores whether political connections are important in the United States. The article uses an original hand-collected data set on the political connections of board members of S&amp;P 500 companies to sort companies into those connected to the Republican Party and those connected to the Democratic Party. The analysis shows a positive abnormal stock return following the announcement of the nomination of a politically connected individual to the board. This article also analyzes the stock-price response to the Republican win of the 2000 presidential election and finds that companies connected to the Republican Party increase in value, and companies connected to the Democratic Party decrease in value.</description><author>Goldman, Eitan; Rocholl, Joerg; So, Jongil</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Introducing a Non-Redundant Derivative on the Volatility of Stock-Market Returns When Agents Differ in Risk Aversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhamra, Harjoat S.; Uppal, Raman
We study the effect of introducing a nonredundant derivative on the volatilities of the stock market return and the locally risk-free interest rate. Our analysis uses a standard, frictionless, full-information, dynamic, continuous-time, general-equilibrium, Lucas endowment economy in which there are two classes of agents who have time-additive power utility functions and differ only in their risk aversion. Our main result is to show analytically that if the intensity of the precautionary demand for savings is not too high, then the introduction of a nonredundant derivative increases the volatility of stock market returns. Furthermore, in the economy with the derivative, the volatility of stock market returns can be substantially greater than that of aggregate dividend growth (fundamental volatility). We also show that the volatility of the locally risk-free interest rate increases with the introduction of the derivative.</description><author>Bhamra, Harjoat S.; Uppal, Raman</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Noise Trading Affects Markets: An Experimental Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bloomfield, Robert; O'Hara, Maureen; Saar, Gideon
We use a laboratory market to investigate the behavior of traders who lack informational advantages and have no exogenous reason to trade. We find that these uninformed traders behave largely as irrational contrarian "noise traders," trading against recent price movements to their own detriment. The uninformed traders provide some benefits to the market: increasing market volume and depth, while reducing bid-ask spreads and the temporary price impact of trades. However, their noise trading also diminishes the ability of market prices to adjust to new information. A securities transaction tax reduces uninformed trader activity, but it reduces informed trader activity by approximately the same amount; as a result, the tax does not alter the impact of noise trading on the informational efficiency of the market.</description><author>Bloomfield, Robert; O'Hara, Maureen; Saar, Gideon</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Returns and the Listing Choice of Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baruch, Shmuel; Saar, Gideon
We propose a mechanism that relates asset returns to the firm's optimal listing choice. We use a theoretical model to show that a stock will be more liquid when it is listed on a market where "similar" securities are traded. We empirically examine the implications of our model using New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) and Nasdaq securities. We find that the return patterns of stocks that switch markets become more similar to the return patterns of securities listed on the new market prior to the switch. Stocks that are eligible to switch but stay put are more similar to securities listed on their market than to securities listed on the other market. Our results suggest that managers make listing decisions that enhance the liquidity of their firms' stocks.</description><author>Baruch, Shmuel; Saar, Gideon</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Differences in Governance Practices between US and Foreign Firms: Measurement, Causes, and Consequences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aggarwal, Reena; Erel, Isil; Stulz, Rene; Williamson, Rohan
We construct a firm-level governance index that increases with minority shareholder protection. Compared with U.S. matching firms, only 12.68% of foreign firms have a higher index. The value of foreign firms falls as their index decreases relative to the index of matching U.S. firms. Our results suggest that lower country-level investor protection and other country characteristics make it suboptimal for foreign firms to invest as much in governance as U.S. firms do. Overall, we find that minority shareholders benefit from governance improvements and do so partly at the expense of controlling shareholders.</description><author>Aggarwal, Reena; Erel, Isil; Stulz, Rene; Williamson, Rohan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Are US Family Firms Controlled ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Villalonga, Belen; Amit, Raphael
In large U.S. corporations, founding families are the only blockholders whose control rights on average exceed their cash-flow rights. We analyze how they achieve this wedge, and at what cost. Indirect ownership through trusts, foundations, limited partnerships, and other corporations is prevalent but rarely creates a wedge (a pyramid). The primary sources of the wedge are dual-class stock, disproportionate board representation, and voting agreements. Each control-enhancing mechanism has a different impact on value. Our findings suggest that the potential agency conflict between large shareholders and public shareholders in the United States is as relevant as elsewhere in the world.</description><author>Villalonga, Belen; Amit, Raphael</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrepreneurial Learning, the IPO Decision, and the Post-IPO Drop in Firm Profitability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pastor, Lubos; Taylor, Lucian A.; Veronesi, Pietro
We develop a model of the optimal initial public offering (IPO) decision in the presence of learning about the average profitability of a private firm. The entrepreneur trades off diversification benefits of going public against benefits of private control. Going public is optimal when the firm's expected future profitability is sufficiently high. The model predicts that firm profitability should decline after the IPO, on average, and that this decline should be larger for firms with more volatile profitability and firms with less uncertain average profitability. These predictions are supported empirically in a sample of 7183 IPOs in the United States between 1975 and 2004.</description><author>Pastor, Lubos; Taylor, Lucian A.; Veronesi, Pietro</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Shareholder Rights Affect the Cost of Bank Loans ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chava, Sudheer; Livdan, Dmitry; Purnanandam, Amiyatosh
Using a large sample of bank loans issued to U.S. firms between 1990 and 2004, we find that lower takeover defenses (as proxied by the lower G-index of Gompers, Ishii, and Metrick 2003) significantly increase the cost of loans for a firm. Firms with lowest takeover defense (democracy) pay a 25% higher spread on their bank loans as compared with firms with the highest takeover defense (dictatorship), after controlling for various firm and loan characteristics. Further investigations indicate that banks charge a higher loan spread to firms with higher takeover vulnerability mainly because of their concern about a substantial increase in financial risk after the takeover. Our results have important implications for understanding the link between a firm's governance structure and its cost of capital. Our study suggests that firms that rely too much on corporate control market as a governance device are punished by costlier bank loans.</description><author>Chava, Sudheer; Livdan, Dmitry; Purnanandam, Amiyatosh</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Financial Innovation in Segmented Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rahi, Rohit; Zigrand, Jean-Pierre
We study an equilibrium model with restricted investor participation in which strategic arbitrageurs reap profits by exploiting mispricings across different market segments. We endogenize the asset structure as the outcome of a security design game played by the arbitrageurs. The equilibrium asset structure depends realistically upon considerations such as depth and gains from trade. It is neither complete nor socially optimal in general; the degree of inefficiency depends upon the heterogeneity of investors.</description><author>Rahi, Rohit; Zigrand, Jean-Pierre</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government Control of Privatized Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bortolotti, Bernardo; Faccio, Mara
We study the change in government control of privatized firms in OECD (Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development) countries. At the end of 2000, after the largest privatization wave in history, governments retained control of 62.4% of privatized firms. In civil law countries, governments tend to retain large ownership positions, whereas in common law countries they typically use golden shares. When we combine these two mechanisms, we find no association between a country's legal tradition and the extent of government control. Rather, we document more prevalent government influence over privatized firms in countries with proportional electoral rules and with a centralized system of political authority.</description><author>Bortolotti, Bernardo; Faccio, Mara</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Liquidity Creation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berger, Allen N.; Bouwman, Christa H. S.
Although the modem theory of financial intermediation portrays liquidity creation as an essential role of banks, comprehensive measures of bank liquidity creation do not exist. We construct four measures and apply them to data on virtually all U.S. banks from 1993 to 2003. We find that bank liquidity creation increased every year and exceeded $2.3 trillion in 2003. Large banks, multibank holding company members, retail banks, and recently merged banks created the most liquidity. Bank liquidity creation is positively correlated with bank value. Testing recent theories of the relationship between capital and liquidity creation, we find that the relationship is positive for large banks and negative for small banks.</description><author>Berger, Allen N.; Bouwman, Christa H. S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effectiveness of Reputation as a Disciplinary Mechanism in Sell-Side Research</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fang, Lily; Yasuda, Ayako
We examine whether the quality differentials in earnings forecasts between reputable and nonreputable analysts vary with the severity of conflicts of interest. We measure personal reputation using the Institutional Investor All-American (AA) awards, and bank reputation using Carter-Manaster ranks. While both personal and bank reputation are associated with higher quality forecasts overall, their effectiveness against conflicts of interest differs. The severity of conflicts has a negative and significant effect on the performance of non-AAs at top-tier banks relative to other analysts, while it has a positive and significant effect on the performance of AAs at top-tier banks relative to others. Thus personal reputation is an effective disciplinary device against conflicts of interest, while bank reputation alone is not.</description><author>Fang, Lily; Yasuda, Ayako</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price Drift as an Outcome of Differences in Higher-Order Beliefs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Snehal; Kaniel, Ron; Kremer, Ilan
Motivated by the insight of Keynes (1936) on the importance of higher-order beliefs in financial markets, we examine the role of such beliefs in generating drift in asset prices. we show that in a dynamic setting, a higher-order difference of opinions is necessary for heterogeneous beliefs to generate price drift. Such drift does not arise in standard difference of opinion models, since investors' beliefs are assumed to be common knowledge. Our results stand in contrast to those of Allen, Morris, and Shin (2006) and others, as we argue that in rational expectation equilibria, heterogeneous beliefs, do not lead to price drift.</description><author>Banerjee, Snehal; Kaniel, Ron; Kremer, Ilan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Simulation-Based Estimation of Contingent-Claims Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phillips, Peter C. B.; Yu, Jun
A new methodology is proposed to estimate theoretical prices of financial contingent claims whose values are dependent on some other underlying financial assets. In the literature, the preferred choice of estimator is usually maximum likelihood (ML). ML has strong asymptotic justification but is not necessarily the best method in finite samples. This paper proposes a simulation-based method. When it is used in connection with ML, it can improve the finite-sample performance of the ML estimator while maintaining its good asymptotic properties. The method is implemented and evaluated here in the Black-Scholes option pricing model and in the Vasicek bond and bond option pricing model. It is especially favored when the bias in ML is large due to strong persistence in the data or strong nonlinearity in pricing functions. Monte Carlo studies show that the proposed procedures achieve bias reductions over ML estimation in pricing contingent claims when ML is biased. The bias reductions are sometimes accompanied by reductions in variance. Empirical applications to U.S. Treasury bills highlight the differences between the bond prices implied by the simulation-based approach and those delivered by ML. Some consequences for the statistical testing of contingent-claim pricing models are discussed.</description><author>Phillips, Peter C. B.; Yu, Jun</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Theory-Based Illiquidity and Asset Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, Tarun; Huh, Sahn-Wook; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
Many proxies of illiquidity have been used in the literature that relates illiquidity to asset prices. These proxies have been motivated from an empirical standpoint. In this study, we approach liquidity estimation from a theoretical perspective. Our method explicitly recognizes the analytic dependence of illiquidity on more primitive drivers such as trading activity and information asymmetry. More specifically, we estimate illiquidity using structural formulae in line with Kyle's (1985) lambda for a comprehensive sample of stocks. The empirical results provide evidence that theory-based estimates of illiquidity are priced in the cross-section of expected stock returns, even after accounting for risk factors, firm characteristics known to influence returns, and other illiquidity proxies prevalent in the literature.</description><author>Chordia, Tarun; Huh, Sahn-Wook; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information in Equity Markets with Ambiguity-Averse Investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Caskey, Judson A.
This paper shows that persistent mispricing is consistent with a market that includes ambiguity-averse investors. In particular, ambiguity-averse investors may prefer to trade based on aggregate signals that reduce ambiguity at the cost of a loss in information. Equilibrium prices may therefore fail to impound publicly available information. While this creates profit opportunities for ambiguity-neutral investors, ambiguity-averse investors perceive that the benefit of ambiguity reduction outweighs the cost of trading against investors who have superior information. The model can explain both underreaction, such as that evident in postearnings announcement drifts and momentum, and overreaction to accounting accruals.</description><author>Caskey, Judson A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional Investors and the Informational Efficiency of Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Kelley, Eric K.
Using a broad panel of NYSE-listed stocks between 1983 and 2004, we study the relation between institutional shareholdings and the relative informational efficiency of prices, measured as deviations from a random walk. Stocks with greater institutional ownership are priced more efficiently, and we show that variation in liquidity does not drive this result. One mechanism through which prices become more efficient is institutional trading activity. even when institutions trade passively. But efficiency is also directly related to institutional holdings, even after controlling for institutional trading, analyst coverage, short selling, variation in liquidity, and firm characteristics.</description><author>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Kelley, Eric K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Geography of Hedge Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Teo, Melvyn
This article analyzes the relationship between the risk-adjusted performance of hedge funds and their proximity to investments using data on Asia-focused hedge funds. I find, relative to an augmented Fung and Hsieh (2004) factor model, that hedge funds with a physical presence (head or research office) in their investment region outperform other hedge funds by 3.72% per year. The local information advantage is pervasive across all major geographical regions, but is strongest for emerging market funds and funds holding illiquid securities. These results are robust to adjustments for fund fees, serial correlation, backfill bias, and incubation bias. I show also that distant funds, especially those based in the United States and the United Kingdom, are able to raise more capital, charge higher fees, and set longer redemption periods, despite their underperformance relative to nearby funds. It appears that distant funds trade investment performance for better access to capital.</description><author>Teo, Melvyn</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Economic Evaluation of Empirical Exchange Rate Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Della Corte, Pasquale; Sarno, Lucio; Tsiakas, Ilias
This paper provides a comprehensive evaluation of the short-horizon predictive ability of economic fundamentals and forward premiums on monthly exchange-rate returns in a framework that allows for volatility timing. We implement Bayesian methods for estimation and ranking of a set of empirical exchange rate models, and construct combined forecasts based on Bayesian model averaging. More importantly, we assess the economic value of the in-sample and out-of-sample forecasting power of the empirical models, and find two key results: (1) a risk-averse investor will pay a high performance fee to switch from a dynamic portfolio strategy based on the random walk model to one that conditions on the forward premium with stochastic volatility innovations and (2) strategies based on combined forecasts yield large economic gains over the random walk benchmark. These two results are robust to reasonably high transaction costs.</description><author>Della Corte, Pasquale; Sarno, Lucio; Tsiakas, Ilias</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Model Comparison Using the Hansen-Jagannathan Distance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kan, Raymond; Robotti, Cesare
Although it is of interest to test whether or not a particular asset pricing model is literally true, a more useful task for empirical researchers is to determine how wrong a model is and to compare the performance of competing asset pricing models. In this paper, we propose a new methodology to test whether or not two competing linear asset pricing models have the same Hansen-Jagannathan distance. We show that the asymptotic distribution of the test statistic depends on whether the competing models are correctly specified or misspecified, and on whether the competing models are nested or non-nested. In addition, given the increasing interest in misspecified models, we propose a simple methodology for computing the standard errors of the estimated stochastic discount factor parameters that are robust to model misspecification. Using monthly data on 25 size and book-to-market ranked portfolios and the one-month T-bill, we show that the commonly used returns and factors are, for the most part, too noisy for us to conclude that one model is superior to the other models in terms of Hansen-Jagannathan distance. Specifically, there is little evidence that conditional and intertemporal capital asset pricing model (CAPM)-type specifications outperform the simple unconditional CAPM, In addition, we show that many of the macroeconomic factors commonly used in the literature are no longer priced once potential model misspecification is taken into account.</description><author>Kan, Raymond; Robotti, Cesare</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Parametric Portfolio Policies: Exploiting Characteristics in the Cross-Section of Equity Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brandt, Michael W.; Santa-Clara, Pedro; Valkanov, Rossen
We propose a novel approach to optimizing portfolios with large numbers of assets. We model directly the portfolio weight in each asset as a function of the asset's characteristics. The coefficients of this function are found by optimizing the investor's average utility of the portfolio's return over the sample period. Our approach is computationally simple and easily modified and extended to capture the effect of transaction costs, for example, produces sensible portfolio weights, and offers robust performance in and out of sample. In contrast, the traditional approach of first modeling the joint distribution of returns and then solving for the corresponding optimal portfolio weights is not only difficult to implement for a large number of assets but also yields notoriously noisy and unstable results. We present an empirical implementation for the universe of all stocks in the CRSP-Compustat data set, exploiting the size, value, and momentum anomalies.</description><author>Brandt, Michael W.; Santa-Clara, Pedro; Valkanov, Rossen</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Relation Between the Credit Spread Puzzle and the Equity Premium Puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Long; Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.
Structural models of default calibrated to historical default rates, recovery rates, and Sharpe ratios typically generate Baa-Aaa credit spreads that are significantly below historical values. However, this "credit spread puzzle" can be resolved if one accounts for the fact that default rates and Sharpe ratios strongly covary; both are high during recessions and low during booms. As a specific example, we investigate credit spread implications of the Campbell and Cochrane (1999) pricing kernel calibrated to equity returns and aggregate consumption data. Identifying the historical surplus consumption ratio from aggregate consumption data, we find that the implied level and time variation of spreads match historical levels well.</description><author>Chen, Long; Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Active Is Your Fund Manager? A New Measure That Predicts Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Petajisto, Antti
We introduce a new measure of active portfolio management, Active Share, which represents the share of portfolio holdings that differ from the benchmark index holdings. We compute Active Share for domestic equity mutual funds from 1980 to 2003. We relate Active Share to fund characteristics such as size, expenses, and turnover in the cross-section, and we also examine its evolution over time. Active Share predicts fund performance: funds with the highest Active Share significantly outperform their benchmarks, both before and after expenses, and they exhibit strong performance persistence. Nonindex funds with the lowest Active Share underperform their benchmarks.</description><author>Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Petajisto, Antti</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Returns to Shareholder Activism: Evidence from a Clinical Study of the Hermes UK Focus Fund</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becht, Marco; Franks, Julian; Mayer, Colin; Rossi, Stefano
This article reports a unique analysis of private engagements by an activist fund. It is based on data made available to us by Hermes, the fund manager owned by the British Telecom Pension Scheme, on engagements with management in companies targeted by its UK Focus Fund. In contrast with most previous studies of activism, we report that the fund executes shareholder activism predominantly through private interventions that would be unobservable in studies purely relying on public information. The fund substantially outperforms benchmarks and we estimate that abnormal returns are largely associated with engagements rather than stock picking.</description><author>Becht, Marco; Franks, Julian; Mayer, Colin; Rossi, Stefano</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Euro and Corporate Valuations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bris, Arturo; Koskinen, Yrjoe; Nilsson, Mattias
In this paper, we study the changes in corporate valuations induced by the adoption of the euro as the common currency in Europe. We use corporate-level data from seventeen European countries, of which eleven adopted the euro. We show that the introduction of the euro has increased Tobin's Q-ratios by 17.1% in the {euro-area} countries that previously had weak currencies. Part of the increase in corporate valuations is explained by the decrease in interest rates and by the decrease in the cost of equity. The increases in Tobin's Q are larger for firms that would be harmed by currency devaluations.</description><author>Bris, Arturo; Koskinen, Yrjoe; Nilsson, Mattias</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Asymmetric Information Drive Capital Structure Decisions ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bharath, Sreedhar T.; Pasquariello, Paolo; Wu, Guojun
Using a novel information asymmetry index based on measures of adverse selection developed by the market microstructure literature, we test whether information asymmetry is an important determinant of capital structure decisions, as suggested by the pecking order theory. Our index relies exclusively on measures of the market's assessment of adverse selection risk rather than on ex ante firm characteristics. We find that information asymmetry does affect the capital structure decisions of U.S. firms over the sample period 1973-2002. Our findings are robust to controlling for conventional leverage factors (size, tangibility, Q ratio, profitability), the sources of firms' financing needs, and such firm attributes as stock return volatility, stock turnover, and intensity of insider trading. For example, we estimate that on average, for every dollar of financing deficit to cover, firms in the highest adverse selection decile issue 30 cents of debt more than firms in the lowest decile. Overall, this evidence explains why the pecking order theory is only partially successful in explaining all of firms' capital structure decisions. It also suggests that the theory finds support when its basic assumptions hold in the data, as should reasonably be expected of any theory.</description><author>Bharath, Sreedhar T.; Pasquariello, Paolo; Wu, Guojun</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corruption, Political Connections, and Municipal Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Butler, Alexander W.; Fauver, Larry; Mortal, Sandra
We show that state corruption and political connections have strong effects on municipal bond sales and underwriting. Higher state corruption is associated with greater credit risk and higher bond yields. Corrupt states can eliminate the corruption yield penalty by purchasing credit enhancements. Underwriting fees were significantly higher during an era when underwriters made political contributions to win underwriting business. This pay-to-play underwriting fee premium exists only for negotiated bid bonds where underwriting business can be allocated on the basis of political favoritism. Overall, our results show a strong impact of corruption and political connections on financial market outcomes. (JEL D73, G20, G22, G24, H74)</description><author>Butler, Alexander W.; Fauver, Larry; Mortal, Sandra</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Loan Sales, Loan Contracting, and Lending Relationships</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drucker, Steven; Puri, Manju
This paper examines the secondary market for loan sales and, in particular, loan contract design as a mechanism to resolve informational issues in loan sales and associated costs and benefits. Using loan-level data, we find that sold loans contain additional covenants and more restrictive net worth covenants, particularly when agency and informational problems are more severe. Why do borrowers agree to incur the additional costs associated with loan sales? Our evidence suggests that these borrowers benefit through increased private debt availability. Further, loan sales go hand in hand with more durable lending relationships, suggesting that risk management aids continued relationship lending. (JEL G31, G32)</description><author>Drucker, Steven; Puri, Manju</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Time-Varying Risk Premiums and the Output Gap</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cooper, Ilan; Priestley, Richard
The output gap, a production-based macroeconomic variable, is a strong predictor of U. S. stock returns. It is a prime business cycle indicator that does not include the level of market prices, thus removing any suspicion that returns are forecastable due to a "fad" in prices being washed away. The output gap forecasts returns both in-sample and out-of-sample, and it is robust to a host of checks. We show that the output gap also has predictive power for excess stock returns in other G7 countries and U.S. excess bond returns. (JEL E44, G12, G14)</description><author>Cooper, Ilan; Priestley, Richard</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Filtering of Jump Diffusions: Extracting Latent States from Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johannes, Michael S.; Polson, Nicholas G.; Stroud, Jonathan R.
This paper provides an optimal filtering methodology in discretely observed continuous-time jump-diffusion models. Although the filtering problem has received little attention, it is useful for estimating latent states, forecasting volatility and returns, computing model diagnostics such as likelihood ratios, and parameter estimation. Our approach combines time-discretization schemes with Monte Carlo methods. It is quite general, applying in nonlinear and multivariate jump-diffusion models and models with nonanalytic observation equations. We provide a detailed analysis of the filter's performance, and analyze four applications: disentangling jumps from stochastic volatility, forecasting volatility, comparing models via likelihood ratios, and filtering using option prices and returns. (JEL C11, C13, C15, C51, C52, G11, G12, G17)</description><author>Johannes, Michael S.; Polson, Nicholas G.; Stroud, Jonathan R.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing Portfolio Efficiency with Conditioning Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferson, Wayne E.; Siegel, Andrew F.
We develop asset pricing models' implications for portfolio efficiency with conditioning information in the form of lagged instruments. A model identifies a portfolio that should be minimum-variance efficient with respect to the conditioning information. Our framework refines tests of portfolio efficiency by using the given conditioning information optimally. The optimal use of the lagged variables is economically important; by using the instruments optimally, we reject several efficiency hypotheses that are not otherwise rejected. The Sharpe ratios of a sample of hedge fund indexes appear consistent with the optimal use of conditioning information. (JEL G11, G12, G23)</description><author>Ferson, Wayne E.; Siegel, Andrew F.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Shifting versus Risk Management: Investment Policy in Corporate Pension Plans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rauh, Joshua D.
The asset allocation of defined benefit pension plans is a setting where both risk-shifting and risk-management incentives are likely be present. Empirically, firms with poorly funded pension plans and weak credit ratings allocate a greater share of pension fund assets to safer securities such as government debt and cash, whereas firms with well-funded pension plans and strong credit ratings invest more heavily in equity. These relations hold both in pooled regressions and within firms and plans over time. The incentive to limit costly financial distress plays a considerably larger role than risk shifting in explaining variation in pension fund investment policy among firms in the United States. (JEL G11, G23, G32)</description><author>Rauh, Joshua D.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The "Wall Street Walk" and Shareholder Activism: Exit as a Form of Voice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Admati, Anat R.; Pfleiderer, Paul
We examine whether a large shareholder can alleviate conflicts of interest between managers and shareholders through the credible threat of exit on the basis of private information. In our model, the threat of exit often reduces agency costs, but additional private information need not enhance the effectiveness of the mechanism. Moreover, the threat of exit can produce quite different effects depending on whether the agency problem involves desirable or undesirable actions from shareholders' perspective. Our results are consistent with empirical findings on the interaction between managers and minority large shareholders and have further empirical implications. (JEL D53, D82, G10, G30, G34)</description><author>Admati, Anat R.; Pfleiderer, Paul</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and Market Crashes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Jennifer; Wang, Jiang
In this paper, we develop an equilibrium model for stock market liquidity and its impact on asset prices when constant market presence is costly. We show that even when agents' trading needs are perfectly matched, costly market presence prevents them from synchronizing their trades and hence gives rise to endogenous order imbalances and the need for liquidity. Moreover, the endogenous liquidity need, when it occurs, is characterized by excessive selling of significant magnitudes. Such liquidity-driven selling leads to market crashes in the absence of any aggregate shocks. Finally, we show that illiquidity in the market leads to high expected returns, negative and asymmetric return serial correlation, and a positive relation between trading volume and future returns. We also propose new measures of liquidity based on its asymmetric impact on prices and demonstrate a negative relation between these measures and expected stock returns. (JEL D53, G12)</description><author>Huang, Jennifer; Wang, Jiang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Measures for Performance Evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cherny, Alexander; Madan, Dilip
This paper characterizes performance measures satisfying a set of proposed axioms. We develop four new measures consistent with the axioms and show that they improve on the economic properties of the Sharpe Ratio and the Gain-Loss Ratio. In our treatment, the performance measures, or the indexes of acceptability, are linked to positive expectations resulting from a stressed sampling of the cash-flow distribution. Theoretically, it is shown that the level of acceptability varies directly with the amount of stress tolerated. In an empirical application, the performance measures are applied to cash flows generated by writing options on the SPX and the FTSE. This exercise reveals that acceptability levels are U-shaped in the strike direction. (JEL G10, G13, G14)</description><author>Cherny, Alexander; Madan, Dilip</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Smart Are the Smart Guys? A Unique View from Hedge Fund Stock Holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, John M.; Xu, Jin
Compared to mutual funds, hedge funds prefer smaller, opaque value securities, and have higher turnover and more active share bets. Decomposing returns into three components, we find that hedge funds are better than mutual funds at stock picking by only 1.32% per year on a value-weighted basis, and this result is insignificant on an equal-weighted basis or with price-to-sales benchmarks. Hedge funds exhibit no ability to time sectors or pick better stock styles. Surprisingly, we find only weak evidence of differential ability between hedge funds. Overall, our study raises serious questions about the perceived superior skill of hedge fund managers. (JEL G11, G23)</description><author>Griffin, John M.; Xu, Jin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are "Market Neutral" Hedge Funds Really Market Neutral?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Patton, Andrew J.
Using a variety of different definitions of "neutrality," this study presents significant evidence against the neutrality to market risk of hedge funds in a range of style categories. I generalize standard definitions of " market neutrality," and propose five different neutrality concepts. I suggest statistical tests for each neutrality concept, and apply these tests to a database of monthly returns on 1423 hedge funds from five style categories. For the " market neutral" style, approximately one-quarter of the funds exhibit significant exposure to market risk; this proportion is statistically significantly different from zero, but less than the proportion of significant exposures for other hedge fund styles. (JEL G11, G23)</description><author>Patton, Andrew J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the Market for Mortgage-Backed Securities a Market for Lemons?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Downing, Chris; Jaffee, Dwight; Wallace, Nancy
This paper models and provides empirical evidence for the quality of assets that are securitized through bankruptcy remote special purpose vehicles (SPVs). The model predicts that assets sold to SPVs will be of lower quality ("lemons") compared to assets that are not sold to SPVs. We find strong empirical support for this prediction using a comprehensive data set of sales of mortgage-backed securities (Freddie Mac Participation Certificates, or PCs) to SPVs over the period 1991 through 2002. Valuation estimates based on a structural two-factor model indicate that PCs sold to SPVs are on average valued $0.39 lower per $100 of face value relative to PCs not so sold. For the four largest coupon groups in our full sample of Freddie Mac PCs, we find a "lemons spread" of 4-6 basis points in terms of yield-to-maturity, and this spread accounts for 13-45% of the overall prepayment spread of these securities. (JEL D82, G13, G14, G21)</description><author>Downing, Chris; Jaffee, Dwight; Wallace, Nancy</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects and Unintended Consequences of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act on the Supply and Demand for Directors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Linck, James S.; Netter, Jeffry M.; Yang, Tina
Using eight thousand public companies, we study the impact of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) of 2002 and other contemporary reforms on directors and boards, guided by their impact on the supply and demand for directors. SOX increased directors' workload and risk (reducing the supply), and increased demand by mandating that firms have more outside directors. We find both broad-based changes and cross-sectional changes (by firm size). Board committees meet more often post-SOX and Director and Officer (D&amp;O) insurance premiums have doubled. Directors post-SOX are more likely to be lawyers/consultants, financial experts, and retired executives, and less likely to be current executives. Post-SOX boards are larger and more independent. Finally, we find significant increases in director pay and overall director costs, particularly among smaller firms.</description><author>Linck, James S.; Netter, Jeffry M.; Yang, Tina</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Foreigners Invest Less in Poorly Governed Firms?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leuz, Christian; Lins, Karl V.; Warnock, Francis E.
As domestic sources of outside finance are limited in many countries around the world, it is important to understand factors that influence whether foreign investors provide capital to a country's firms. We study 4,409 firms from twenty-nine countries to assess whether and why concerns about corporate governance result in fewer foreign holdings. We find that foreigners invest less in firms that reside in countries with poor outsider protection and disclosure and have ownership structures that are conducive to governance problems. This effect is particularly pronounced when earnings are opaque, indicating that information asymmetry and monitoring costs faced by foreign investors likely drive the results.</description><author>Leuz, Christian; Lins, Karl V.; Warnock, Francis E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are there permanent valuation gains to overseas listing ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sarkissian, Sergei; Schill, Michael J.
This paper tests whether foreign equity listings are associated with permanent valuation gains and examines how market and firm characteristics influence any valuation effects. Using a global sample of 1,676 listings placed in 25 countries, we find that much of the valuation gains to overseas listings are not permanent. The transitory nature of valuation gains holds for both average US listings and average first-time firm listings. We find little evidence of a permanent effect on returns for firms that list abroad, even for firms' listings in markets that are more liquid, provide better legal protection, or have a larger shareholder base.</description><author>Sarkissian, Sergei; Schill, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Differences of Opinion of Public Information and Speculative Trading in Stocks and Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, H. Henry; Ou-Yang, Hui
We analyze the effects of differences of opinion on the dynamics of trading volume in stocks and options. We find that disagreements about the mean of the current- and next-period public information lead to trading in stocks in the current period but have no effect on options trading. Without options, we find that disagreements about the precision of all past and current public information affect trading in stocks in the current period. With options, only disagreements about the precisions of the next- and current-period information affect stocks and options trading in the current period. Our results suggest that options trading is concentrated around information events that are likely to cause disagreements among investors, whereas trading in stocks may be diffusive over many periods.</description><author>Cao, H. Henry; Ou-Yang, Hui</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Flight-to-Quality or Flight-to-Liquidity? Evidence from the Euro-Area Bond Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Beber, Alessandro; Brandt, Michael W.; Kavajecz, Kenneth A.
Do bond investors demand credit quality or liquidity? The answer is both, but at different times and for different reasons. Using data on the Euro-area government bond market, which features a unique negative correlation between credit quality and liquidity across countries, we show that the bulk of sovereign yield spreads is explained by differences in credit quality, though liquidity plays a nontrivial role, especially for low credit risk countries and during times of heightened market uncertainty. In contrast, the destination of large flows into the bond market is determined almost exclusively by liquidity. We conclude that credit quality matters for bond valuation but that, in times of market stress, investors chase liquidity, not credit quality.</description><author>Beber, Alessandro; Brandt, Michael W.; Kavajecz, Kenneth A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nondiversification Traps in Catastrophe Insurance Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ibragimov, Rustam; Jaffee, Dwight; Walden, Johan
We develop a model for markets for catastrophic risk. The model explains why insurance providers may choose not to offer insurance for catastrophic risks and not to participate in reinsurance markets, even though there is a large enough market capacity to reach full risk sharing through diversification in a reinsurance market. This is a "nondiversification trap." We show that nondiversification traps may arise when risk distributions have heavy left tails and insurance providers have limited liability. When they are present, there may be a coordination role for a centralized agency to ensure that risk sharing takes place.</description><author>Ibragimov, Rustam; Jaffee, Dwight; Walden, Johan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Liquidity-Based Theory of Closed-End Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cherkes, Martin; Sagi, Jacob; Stanton, Richard
This paper develops a rational, liquidity-based model of closed-end funds (CEFs) that provides an economic motivation for the existence of this organizational form: They offer a means for investors to buy illiquid securities, without facing the potential costs associated with direct trading and without the externalities imposed by an open-end fund structure. Our theory predicts the patterns observed in CEF initial public offerings (IPOs) and the observed behavior of the CEF discount, which results from a trade-off between the liquidity benefits of investing in the CEF and the fees charged by the fund's managers. In particular, the model explains why IPOs occur in waves in certain sectors at a time, why funds are issued at a premium to net asset value (NAV), and why they later usually trade at a discount. We also conduct an empirical investigation, which, overall, provides more support for a liquidity-based model than for an alternative sentiment-based explanation.</description><author>Cherkes, Martin; Sagi, Jacob; Stanton, Richard</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing Bank Liquidity Risk: How Deposit-Loan Synergies Vary with Market Conditions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gatev, Evan; Schuermann, Til; Strahan, Philip E.
Liquidity risk in banking has been attributed to transactions deposits and their potential to spark runs or panics. We show instead that transactions deposits help banks hedge liquidity risk from unused loan commitments. Bank stock-return volatility increases with unused commitments, but only for banks with low levels of transactions deposits. This deposit-lending hedge becomes more powerful during periods of tight liquidity, when nervous investors move funds into their banks. Our results reverse the standard notion of liquidity risk at banks, where runs from depositors had been seen as the cause of trouble.</description><author>Gatev, Evan; Schuermann, Til; Strahan, Philip E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Y2K Options and the Liquidity Premium in Treasury Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sundaresan, Suresh; Wang, Zhenyu
Financial institutions around the world expected the millennium date change (Y2K) to cause an aggregate liquidity shortage. Responding to the concern, the Federal Reserve Bank of New York auctioned Y2K options to primary dealers. The options gave the dealers the right to borrow from the Fed at a predetermined interest rate. Using the implied volatilities of Y2K options and the on/off-the-run spread, we demonstrate that the Fed's action eased the fears of bond dealers, contributing to a drop in the liquidity premium of Treasury securities. Our analysis shows the link between the microstructure of government debt markets and the central bank's provision of liquidity. We argue that Y2K options and their effects on liquidity premium broadly conform to the economic theory on public provision of private liquidity.</description><author>Sundaresan, Suresh; Wang, Zhenyu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Lines of Credit in Corporate Finance: An Empirical Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sufi, Amir
I empirically examine the factors that determine whether firms use bank lines of credit or cash in corporate liquidity management. I find that bank lines of credit, also known as revolving credit facilities, are a viable liquidity substitute only for firms that maintain high cash flow. In contrast, firms with low cash flow are less likely to obtain a line of credit, and they rely more heavily on cash in their corporate liquidity management. An important channel for this correlation is the use of cash flow-based financial covenants by banks that supply credit lines. I find that firms must maintain high cash flow to remain compliant with covenants, and banks restrict firm access to credit facilities in response to covenant violations. Using the cash-flow sensitivity of cash as a measure of financial constraints, I provide evidence that lack of access to a line of credit is a more statistically powerful measure of financial constraints than traditional measures used in the literature.</description><author>Sufi, Amir</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Motivating Entrepreneurial Activity in a Firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernardo, Antonio E.; Cai, Hongbin; Luo, Jiang
We examine the problem of motivating privately informed managers to engage in entrepreneurial activity to improve the quality of the firm's investment opportunities. The firm's investment and compensation policy must balance the manager's incentives to provide entrepreneurial effort and to report private information truthfully. The optimal policy is to underinvest (compared to first-best) and provide weak incentive pay in low-quality projects and overinvest (compared to first-best) and provide strong incentive pay in high-quality projects.</description><author>Bernardo, Antonio E.; Cai, Hongbin; Luo, Jiang</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade-offs in Staying Close: Corporate Decision Making and Geographic Dispersion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Landier, Augustin; Nair, Vinay B.; Wulf, Julie
We investigate whether the geographic dispersion of a firm affects corporate decision making. Our findings suggest that social factors work alongside informational considerations to make geography important to corporate decisions. We show that (i) geographically dispersed firms are less employee friendly; (ii) dismissals of divisional employees are less common in divisions located closer to corporate headquarters; and (iii) firms appear to adopt a pecking order and divest out-of-state entities before those in-state. To explain these findings, we consider both information and social factors. We find that firms are more likely to protect proximate employees in soft information industries (i.e., when information is difficult to transfer over long distances). However, employee protection holds only when the headquarters is located in a less populated county, suggesting a role for social factors. Additionally, stock markets respond favorably to divestitures of in-state divisions.</description><author>Landier, Augustin; Nair, Vinay B.; Wulf, Julie</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Idiosyncratic Return Volatility, Cash Flows, and Product Market Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Irvine, Paul J.; Pontiff, Jeffrey
Over the past 40 years, the volatility of the average stock return has drastically outpaced total market volatility. Thus, idiosyncratic return volatility has dramatically increased. We estimate this increase to be 6% per year. Consistent with an efficient market, this result is mirrored by an increase in the idiosyncratic volatility of fundamental cash flows. We argue that these findings are attributable to the more intense economy-wide competition. Various cross-sectional and time-series tests support this idea. Economic competitiveness facilitates reinterpretation of the results from the cross-country R(2) literature, as well as the US idiosyncratic risk literature.</description><author>Irvine, Paul J.; Pontiff, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Mergers Create Value ? A Comparison of Taxes, Market Power, and Efficiency Improvements as Explanations for Synergies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Devos, Erik; Kadapakkam, Palani-Rajan; Krishnamurthy, Srinivasan
There is little evidence in the literature on the relative importance of the underlying sources of merger gains. Prior literature suggests that synergies could arise due to taxes, market power, or efficiency improvements. Based on Value Line forecasts, we estimate the average synergy gains in a broad sample of 264 large mergers to be 10.03% of the combined equity value of the merging firms. The detailed data in Value Line projections allow for the decomposition of these gains into underlying operating and financial synergies. We estimate that tax savings contribute only 1.64% in additional value, while operating synergies account for the remaining 8.38%. Operating synergies are higher in focused mergers, while tax savings constitute a large fraction of the gains in diversifying mergers. The operating synergies are generated primarily by cutbacks in investment expenditures rather than by increased operating profits. Overall, the evidence suggests that mergers generate gains by improving resource allocation rather than by reducing tax payments or increasing the market power of the combined firm.</description><author>Devos, Erik; Kadapakkam, Palani-Rajan; Krishnamurthy, Srinivasan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loyalty-Based Portfolio Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Lauren
I evaluate the effect of loyalty on individuals' portfolio choice using a unique dataset of retirement contributions. I exploit the statutory difference that, in 401(k) plans, stand-alone employees can invest directly in their division, while conglomerate employees must invest in the entire firm, including all unrelated divisions. Consistent with loyalty, employees of stand-alone firms invest 10 percentage points (75%) more in company stock than conglomerate employees. Support is also found using variation in loyalty between different groups of employees, across and within firms. The cost to employees of loyalty is large, amounting to nearly a 20% loss in retirement income.</description><author>Cohen, Lauren</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mispricing of S&amp;P 500 Index Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Constantinides, George M.; Jackwerth, Jens Carsten; Perrakis, Stylianos
Widespread violations of stochastic dominance by 1-month S&amp;P 500 index call options over 1986-2006 imply that a trader can improve expected utility by engaging in a zero-net-cost trade net of transaction costs and bid-ask spread. Although precrash option prices conform to the Black-Scholes-Merton model reasonably well, they are incorrectly priced if the distribution of the index return is estimated from time-series data. Substantial violations by postcrash OTM calls contradict the notion that the problem lies primarily with the left-hand tail of the index return distribution and that the smile is too steep. The decrease in violations over the postcrash period of 1988-1995 is followed by a substantial increase over 1997-2006, which may be due to the lower quality of the data but, in any case, does not provide evidence that the options market is becoming more rational over time.</description><author>Constantinides, George M.; Jackwerth, Jens Carsten; Perrakis, Stylianos</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual Fund Fees Around the World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khorana, Ajay; Servaes, Henri; Tufano, Peter
Using a new database, we study fees charged by 46,580 mutual fund classes offered for sale in 18 countries, which account for about 86% of the world fund industry in 2002. We examine management fees, total expense ratios, and total shareholder costs (including load charges). Fees vary substantially across funds and from country to country. To explain these differences, we consider fund, sponsor, and national characteristics. Fees differ by investment objectives: larger funds and fund complexes charge lower fees; fees are higher for funds distributed in more countries and funds domiciled in certain offshore locations (especially when selling into countries levying higher taxes). Substantial cross-country differences persist even after controlling for these variables. These remaining differences can be explained by a variety of factors, the most robust of which is that fund fees are lower in countries with stronger investor protection.</description><author>Khorana, Ajay; Servaes, Henri; Tufano, Peter</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Variance Risk Premiums</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carr, Peter; Wu, Liuren
We propose a direct and robust method for quantifying the variance risk premium on financial assets. We show that the risk-neutral expected value of return variance, also known as the variance swap rate, is well approximated by the value of a particular portfolio of options. We propose to use the difference between the realized variance and this synthetic variance swap rate to quantify the variance risk premium. Using a large options data set, we synthesize variance swap rates and investigate the historical behavior of variance risk premiums on five stock indexes and 35 individual stocks.</description><author>Carr, Peter; Wu, Liuren</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cointegration and Consumption Risks in Asset Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bansal, Ravi; Dittmar, Robert; Kiku, Dana
We argue that the cointegrating relation between dividends and consumption, a measure of long-run consumption risks, is a key determinant of risk premia at all investment horizons. As the investment horizon increases, transitory risks disappear, and the asset's beta is dominated by long-run consumption risks. We show that the return betas, derived from the cointegration-based VAR (EC-VAR) model, successfully account for the cross-sectional variation in equity returns at both short and long horizons; however, this is not the case when the cointegrating restriction is ignored. Our evidence highlights the importance of cointegration-based long-run consumption risks for financial markets.</description><author>Bansal, Ravi; Dittmar, Robert; Kiku, Dana</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Leasing, Ability to Repossess, and Debt Capacity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eisfeldt, Andrea L.; Rampini, Adriano A.
This paper studies the financing role of leasing and secured lending. We argue that the benefit of leasing is that repossession of a leased asset is easier than foreclosure on the collateral of a secured loan, which implies that leasing has higher debt capacity than secured lending. However, leasing involves agency costs due to the separation of ownership and control. More financially constrained firms value the additional debt capacity more and hence lease more of their capital than less constrained firms. We provide empirical evidence consistent with this prediction. Our theory is consistent with the explanation of leasing by practitioners, namely that leasing "preserves capital," which the academic literature considers a fallacy.</description><author>Eisfeldt, Andrea L.; Rampini, Adriano A.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real Effects of Debt Certification: Evidence from the Introduction of Bank Loan Ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sufi, Amir
I examine the introduction of syndicated bank loan ratings by Moody's and Standard &amp; Poor's in 1995 to evaluate whether third-party rating agencies affect firm financial and investment policy. The introduction of bank loan ratings leads to an increase in the use of debt by firms that obtain a rating, and also increases in firms' asset growth, cash acquisitions, and investment in working capital. Consistent with a causal effect of the ratings, the increase in debt usage and investment is concentrated in the set of borrowers who are of lower credit quality and do not have an issuer credit rating before 1995. A loan-level analysis demonstrates that previously unrated borrowers who obtain a loan rating gain increased access to the capital of less-informed investors. The results suggest that third-party debt certification has real effects on firm investment policy.</description><author>Sufi, Amir</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Nature and Persistence of Buyback Anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peyer, Urs; Vermaelen, Theo
Using recent data, we reject the hypothesis that the buyback anomalies first reported by Lakonishok and Vermaelen (1990, Journal of Finance 45:455-77) and Ikenberry, Lakonishok, and Vermaelen (1995, Journal of Financial Economics 39:181-208) have disappeared over time. We find evidence consistent with the hypothesis that open market repurchases are a response to a market overreaction to bad news: significant analyst downgrades, combined with overly pessimistic forecasts of long-term earnings. Stock prices after tender offers are set as if all investors tender their shares, but empirically they do not. Thus, the arbitrage opportunity persists because the market sets prices as if the average, not the marginal investor, determines the stock price.</description><author>Peyer, Urs; Vermaelen, Theo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Performance of Private Equity Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phalippou, Ludovic; Gottschalg, Oliver
The performance of private equity funds as reported by industry associations and previous research is overstated. A large part of performance is driven by inflated accounting valuation of ongoing investments and we find a bias toward better performing funds in the data. We find an average net-of-fees fund performance of 3% per year below that of the S&amp;P 500. Adjusting for risk brings the underperformance to 6% per year. We estimate fees to be 6% per year. We discuss several misleading aspects of performance reporting and some side benefits as a first step toward an explanation.</description><author>Phalippou, Ludovic; Gottschalg, Oliver</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Controlling for Fixed-Income Exposure in Portfolio Evaluation: Evidence from Hybrid Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Comer, George; Larrymore, Norris; Rodriguez, Javier
We examine whether explicitly controlling for the fixed-income exposure of mutual funds affects conclusions drawn in performance assessment. We focus on daily return data from two hybrid mutual fund samples. Comparing abnormal performance estimates from the Carhart (1997) model to extensions designed to correct for bond holdings, we find that the estimates within one of our samples change from positive to significantly negative. Additional evidence indicates that cash flows to the funds are more closely correlated with the traditional Carhart measure, clearly indicating that the absence of bond indices misleads investors who use a fund's risk-adjusted performance as the basis for investment decisions.</description><author>Comer, George; Larrymore, Norris; Rodriguez, Javier</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading Restrictions and Stock Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenwood, Robin
I examine a series of stock splits in Japan in which firms restrict the ability of their investors to sell their shares for a period of approximately 2 months. By removing potential sellers from the market, the restrictions have the effect of increasing the impact of trading on prices. The greater the desire of investors to trade, and the greater the restrictions, the larger the impact of the restrictions. In the data, particularly severe restrictions are associated with returns of over 30% around the ex-date, most of which are reversed when investors are allowed to sell again. Firms are more likely to issue equity or redeem convertible debt during the restricted period, suggesting strong incentives for manipulation.</description><author>Greenwood, Robin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge Funds as Investors of Last Resort ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brophy, David J.; Ouimet, Paige P.; Sialm, Clemens
Hedge funds have become important investors in public companies raising equity privately. Hedge funds tend to finance companies that have poor fundamentals and pronounced information asymmetries. To compensate for these shortcomings, hedge funds protect themselves by requiring substantial discounts, negotiating repricing rights, and entering into short positions of the underlying stocks. We find that companies that obtain financing from hedge funds significantly underperform companies that obtain financing from other investors during the following two years. We argue that hedge funds are investors of last resort and provide funding for companies that are otherwise constrained from raising equity capital.</description><author>Brophy, David J.; Ouimet, Paige P.; Sialm, Clemens</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Harming Depositors and Helping Borrowers: The Disparate Impact of Bank Consolidation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Park, Kwangwoo; Pennacchi, George
A model of multimarket spatial competition is developed where small, single-market banks compete with large, multimarket banks (LMBs) for retail loans and deposits. Consistent with empirical evidence, LMBs are assumed to set retail interest rates uniformly across markets, have different operating costs, and have access to wholesale funding. If LMBs have significant funding advantages that offset potential loan operating cost disadvantages, then market-extension mergers by LMBs promote loan competition, especially in concentrated markets. However, such mergers reduce retail deposit competition, especially in less concentrated markets. Prior empirical research and our own analysis of retail deposit rates support the model's predictions.</description><author>Park, Kwangwoo; Pennacchi, George</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Debt and Corporate Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ivashina, Victoria; Nair, Vinay B.; Saunders, Anthony; Massoud, Nadia; Stover, Roger
In this paper, we investigate the disciplining role of banks and bank debt in the market for corporate control. We find that relationship bank lending intensity and bank client network have positive effects on the probability of a borrowing firm becoming a target. This effect is enhanced in cases where the target and acquirer have a relationship with the same bank. Moreover, we utilize an experiment to show that the effects of relationship bank lending intensity on takeover probability are not driven by endogeneity. Finally, we also investigate reasons motivating a bank's informational role in the market for corporate control.</description><author>Ivashina, Victoria; Nair, Vinay B.; Saunders, Anthony; Massoud, Nadia; Stover, Roger</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disappearing Dividends, Catering, and Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoberg, Gerard; Prabhala, Nagpurnanand R.
Fama and French (2001a) show that the propensity to pay dividends declines significantly between 1978 and 1999. We examine this "disappearing dividends" puzzle through the lens of risk and report two main findings: (i) Risk is a significant determinant of the propensity to pay dividends, and it explains roughly 40% of disappearing dividends; (ii) We find little support for the view that disappearing dividends reflects firms' catering to transient fads for dividends. Absent risk controls, proxies for fads matter, but these proxies are insignificant once we control for risk. Our results are robust to an extensive battery of robustness tests that vary samples, time periods, proxies for fads, the types of empirical tests, and the nature of payout decisions made by firms.</description><author>Hoberg, Gerard; Prabhala, Nagpurnanand R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Contracting with Optimistic Entrepreneurs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Landier, Augustin; Thesmar, David
Optimistic beliefs are a source of nonpecuniary benefits for entrepreneurs that can explain the "Private Equity Puzzle." This paper looks at the effects of entrepreneurial optimism on financial contracting. When the contract space is restricted to debt, we show the existence of a separating equilibrium in which optimists self-select into short-term debt and realists into long-term debt. Long-term debt is optimal for a realist entrepreneur as it smooths payoffs across states of nature. Short-term debt is optimal for optimists for two reasons: (i) "bridging the gap in beliefs" by letting the entrepreneur take a bet on his project's success, and (ii) letting the investor impose adaptation decisions in bad states. We test our theory on a large data set of French entrepreneurs. First, in agreement with the psychology literature, we find that biases in beliefs may be (partly) explained by individual characteristics and tend to persist over time. Second, as predicted by our model, we find that short-term debt is robustly correlated with "optimistic" expectation errors, even controlling for firm risk and other potential determinants of short-term leverage.</description><author>Landier, Augustin; Thesmar, David</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Retail Trades Move Markets ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barber, Brad M.; Odean, Terrance; Zhu, Ning
We study the trading of individual investors using transaction data and identifying buyer- or seller-initiated trades. We document four results: (1) Small trade order imbalance correlates well with order imbalance based on trades from retail brokers. (2) Individual investors herd. (3) When measured annually, small trade order imbalance forecasts future returns; stocks heavily bought underperform stocks heavily sold by 4.4 percentage points the following year. (4) Over a weekly horizon, small trade order imbalance reliably predicts returns, but in the opposite direction; stocks heavily bought one week earn strong returns the subsequent week, while stocks heavily sold earn poor returns.</description><author>Barber, Brad M.; Odean, Terrance; Zhu, Ning</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Stock Market and Corporate Investment: A Test of Catering Theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Polk, Christopher; Sapienza, Paola
We test a catering theory describing how stock market mispricing might influence individual firms' investment decisions. We use discretionary accruals as our proxy for mispricing. We find a positive relation between abnormal investment and discretionary accruals; that abnormal investment is more sensitive to discretionary accruals for firms with higher R&amp;D intensity (opaque firms) or share turnover (firms with shorter shareholder horizons); that firms with high abnormal investment subsequently have low stock returns; and that the larger the relative price premium, the stronger the abnormal return predictability. We show that patterns in abnormal returns are stronger for firms with higher R&amp;D intensity or share turnover.</description><author>Polk, Christopher; Sapienza, Paola</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Promotion Tournaments and Capital Rationing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Bing; Hirshleifer, David; Persons, John C.
We analyze capital allocation in a conglomerate where divisional managers with uncertain abilities compete for promotion to CEO. A manager can sometimes gain by unobservably adding variance to divisional performance. Capital rationing can limit this distortion, increase productive efficiency, and allow the owner to make more accurate promotion decisions. Firms for which CEO talent is more important for firm performance are more likely to ration capital. A rationed manager is more likely to be promoted even though all managers are identical ex ante. When the tournament payoff is relatively small, offering an incentive wage can be more efficient than rationing capital; however, when tournament incentives are paramount, rationing is more efficient.</description><author>Han, Bing; Hirshleifer, David; Persons, John C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-Sale Strategies and Return Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Diether, Karl B.; Lee, Kuan-Hui; Werner, Ingrid M.
We examine short selling in US stocks based on new SEC-mandated data for 2005. There is a tremendous amount of short selling in our sample: short sales represent 24% of NYSE and 31% of Nasdaq share volume. Short sellers increase their trading following positive returns and they correctly predict future negative abnormal returns. These patterns are robust to controlling for voluntary liquidity provision and for opportunistic risk-bearing by short sellers. The results are consistent with short sellers trading on short-term overreaction of stock prices. A trading strategy based on daily short-selling activity generates significant positive returns during the sample period.</description><author>Diether, Karl B.; Lee, Kuan-Hui; Werner, Ingrid M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Just How Much Do Individual Investors Lose by Trading ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barber, Brad M.; Lee, Yi-Tsung; Liu, Yu-Jane; Odean, Terrance
Individual investor trading results in systematic and economically large losses. Using a complete trading history of all investors in Taiwan, we document that the aggregate portfolio of individuals suffers an annual performance penalty of 3.8 percentage points. Individual investor losses are equivalent to 2.2% of Taiwan's gross domestic product or 2.8% of the total personal income. Virtually all individual trading losses can be traced to their aggressive orders. In contrast, institutions enjoy an annual performance boost of 1.5 percentage points, and both the aggressive and passive trades of institutions are profitable. Foreign institutions garner nearly half of institutional profits.</description><author>Barber, Brad M.; Lee, Yi-Tsung; Liu, Yu-Jane; Odean, Terrance</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market Valuation and Acquisition Quality: Empirical Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bouwman, Christa H. S.; Fuller, Kathleen; Nain, Amrita S.
Existing research shows that significantly more acquisitions occur when stock markets are booming than when markets are depressed. Rhodes-Kropf and Viswanathan (2004) hypothesize that firm-specific and market-wide valuations lead to an excess of mergers, and these will be value destroying. This article investigates whether acquisitions occurring during booming markets are fundamentally different from those occurring during depressed markets. We find that acquirers buying during high-valuation markets have significantly higher announcement returns but lower long-run abnormal stock and operating performance than those buying during low-valuation markets. We investigate possible explanations for the long-run underperformance and conclude it is consistent with managerial herding.</description><author>Bouwman, Christa H. S.; Fuller, Kathleen; Nain, Amrita S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equity and Cash in Intercorporate Asset Sales: Theory and Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hege, Ulrich; Lovo, Stefano; Slovin, Myron B.; Sushka, Marie E.
We develop a two-sided asymmetric information model of asset sales that incorporates the key differences from mergers and allows the information held by each party to be impounded in the transaction. The buyer's information is conveyed through a first-stage competitive auction. A seller with unfavorable information about the asset accepts the cash offer of the highest bidder. A seller with favorable information proposes a take-it-or-leave-it counteroffer that entails buyer equity. Thus, the cash-equity decision reflects the seller's but not the buyer's information in contrast to the theoretical and empirical findings for mergers. The central prediction of our model is that there are large gains in wealth for both buyers and sellers in equity-based asset sales, whereas cash sales generate significantly smaller gains that typically accrue only to sellers. Our empirical results are consistent with the predictions of our theoretical model.</description><author>Hege, Ulrich; Lovo, Stefano; Slovin, Myron B.; Sushka, Marie E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consensus in Diverse Corporate Boards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baranchuk, Nina; Dybvig, Philip H.
Many directors are not simply insiders or outsiders. For example, an officer of a supplier is neither independent nor captive of management. We use a spatial model of board decision-making to analyze bargaining among multiple types of directors. Board decisions are modeled using a new solution concept called consensus. We use consensus to show that the information a new director brings is more important than the new director's impact on bargaining when the board is large and not too diverse. Our model suggests broadening the regulatory definition of independence and requiring a supermajority of outsiders. It also cautions that strong penalties, such as those imposed by Sarbanes-Oxley erode incentives when board performance is difficult to measure.</description><author>Baranchuk, Nina; Dybvig, Philip H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Design and Renegotiation of Debt Covenants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garleanu, Nicolae; Zwiebel, Jeffrey
We analyze the design and renegotiation of covenants in debt contracts as a specific example of the contractual assignment of property rights under asymmetric information. Specifically, we consider a setting where managers are better informed than lenders regarding potential transfers from debt to equity associated with future investments. This simple adverse-selection problem leads to the allocation of greater ex ante decision rights to the creditor (the uninformed party), i.e., tighter covenants, than would follow under symmetric information. This corresponds well to empirical evidence indicating that covenants are very tight upon inception and are frequently waived (and never tightened) upon renegotiation.</description><author>Garleanu, Nicolae; Zwiebel, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Matters in Corporate Governance?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bebchuk, Lucian; Cohen, Alma; Ferrell, Allen
We investigate the relative importance of the twenty-four provisions followed by the Investor Responsibility Research Center (IRRC) and included in the Gompers, Ishii, and Metrick governance index (Gompers, Ishii, and Metrick 2003). We put forward an entrenchment index based on six provisions: staggered boards, limits to shareholder bylaw amendments, poison pills, golden parachutes, and supermajority requirements for mergers and charter amendments. We find that increases in the index level are monotonically associated with economically significant reductions in firm valuation as well as large negative abnormal returns during the 1990-2003 period. The other eighteen IRRC provisions not in our entrenchment index were uncorrelated with either reduced firm valuation or negative abnormal returns. (JEL G30, G34, K22)</description><author>Bebchuk, Lucian; Cohen, Alma; Ferrell, Allen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance Transfer and Synergistic Gains from Mergers and Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Cong; Xie, Fei
We present evidence on the benefits of changes in control from mergers and acquisitions. We find that the stronger the acquirer's shareholder rights relative to the target's, the higher the synergy created by an acquisition. This result supports the hypothesis that acquisitions of firms with poor corporate governance by firms with good corporate governance generate higher total gains. We also find that the synergy effect of corporate governance is shared by target shareholders and acquiring shareholders, in that both target returns and acquirer returns increase with the shareholder-rights difference between the acquirer and the target.</description><author>Wang, Cong; Xie, Fei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Executive Compensation when Firm Size Follows Geometric Brownian Motion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Zhiguo
This paper studies a continuous-time agency model in which the agent controls the drift of the geometric Brownian motion firm size. The changing firm size generates partial incentives, analogous to awarding the agent equity shares according to her continuation payoff. When the agent is as patient as investors, performance-based stock grants implement the optimal contract. Our model generates a leverage effect on the equity returns, and implies that the agency problem is more severe for smaller firms. That the empirical evidence shows that grants compensation are largely based on the CEO's historical performance-025EFrather than current performance-025EFlends support to our model.</description><author>He, Zhiguo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional Investors and Equity Returns: Are Short-term Institutions Better Informed ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yan, Xuemin; Zhang, Zhe
We show that the positive relation between institutional ownership and future stock returns documented in Gompers and Metrick (2001) is driven by short-term institutions. Furthermore, short-term institutions trading forecasts future stock returns. This predictability does not reverse in the long run and is stronger for small and growth stocks. Short-term institutions trading is also positively related to future earnings surprises. By contrast, long-term institutions trading does not forecast future returns, nor is it related to future earnings news. Our results are consistent with the view that short-term institutions are better informed and they trade actively to exploit their informational advantage.</description><author>Yan, Xuemin; Zhang, Zhe</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Salability and Debt Maturity: Evidence from Nineteenth-Century American Railroads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benmelech, Efraim
I investigate the effect of assets' liquidation values on capital structure by exploiting the diversity of track gauges in nineteenth-century American railroads. The abundance of track gauges limited the redeployability of rolling stock and tracks to potential users with similar track gauge. Moreover, potential demand for both rolling stock and tracks was further diminished when many railroads went under equity receiverships. I find that the potential demand for a railroad's rolling stock and tracks were significant determinants of debt maturity and the amount of debt that was issued by railroads. The results are consistent with liquidation values models of financial contracting and capital structure.</description><author>Benmelech, Efraim</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and Manipulation of Executive Compensation Schemes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Axelson, Ulf; Baliga, Sandeep
Compensation contracts have been criticized for encouraging managers to manipulate information. This includes bonus schemes that encourage earnings smoothing, and option packages that allow managers to cash out early when the firm is overvalued. We show that the intransparency induced by these contract features is critical for giving long-term incentives. Lack of transparency makes it harder for the owner to engage in ex post optimal but ex ante inefficient liquidity provision to the manager. For the same reason, it is often optimal to "pay for luck" (i.e., tie long-term compensation to variables that the manager has no influence over, but may have private information about, such as future profitability of the whole industry).</description><author>Axelson, Ulf; Baliga, Sandeep</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Demand-Based Option Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garleanu, Nicolae; Pedersen, Lasse Heje; Poteshman, Allen M.
We model demand-pressure effects on option prices. The model shows that demand pressure in one option contract increases its price by an amount proportional to the variance of the unhedgeable part of the option. Similarly, the demand pressure increases the price of any other option by an amount proportional to the covariance of the unhedgeable parts of the two options. Empirically, we identify aggregate positions of dealers and end-users using a unique dataset, and show that demand-pressure effects make a contribution to well-known option-pricing puzzles. Indeed, time-series tests show that demand helps explain the overall expensiveness and skew patterns of index options, and cross-sectional tests show that demand impacts the expensiveness of single-stock options as well.</description><author>Garleanu, Nicolae; Pedersen, Lasse Heje; Poteshman, Allen M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring Abnormal Bond Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Kahle, Kathleen M.; Maxwell, William F.; Xu, Danielle
We analyze the empirical power and specification of test statistics designed to detect abnormal bond returns in corporate event studies, using monthly and daily data. We find that test statistics based on frequently used methods of calculating abnormal monthly bond returns are biased. Most methods implemented in monthly data also lack power to detect abnormal returns. We also consider unique issues arising when using the newly available daily bond data, and formulate and test methods to calculate daily abnormal bond returns. Using daily bond data significantly increases the power of the tests, relative to the monthly data. Weighting individual trades by size while eliminating noninstitutional trades from the TRACE data also increases the power of the tests to detect abnormal performance, relative to using all trades or the last price of the day. Further, value-weighted portfolio-matching approaches are better specified and more powerful than equal-weighted approaches. Finally, we examine abnormal bond returns to acquirers around mergers and acquisitions to demonstrate how the abnormal return model and use of daily versus monthly data can affect inferences.</description><author>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Kahle, Kathleen M.; Maxwell, William F.; Xu, Danielle</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conflicts of Interest and Stock Recommendations: The Effects of the Global Settlement and Related Regulations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kadan, Ohad; Madureira, Leonardo; Wang, Rong; Zach, Tzachi
We study the effect of the Global Analyst Research Settlement and related regulations on sell-side research. These regulations attempted to mitigate the interdependence between research and investment banking. We document that following the regulations many brokerage houses have migrated from the traditional five-tier rating system to a three-tier system. Optimistic recommendations have become less frequent and more informative, whereas neutral and pessimistic recommendations have become more frequent and less informative. Importantly, the overall informativeness of recommendations has declined. The likelihood of issuing optimistic recommendations no longer depends on affiliation with the covered firm, although affiliated analysts are still reluctant to issue pessimistic recommendations.</description><author>Kadan, Ohad; Madureira, Leonardo; Wang, Rong; Zach, Tzachi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ambiguity Aversion and the Term Structure of Interest Rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gagliardini, Patrick; Porchia, Paolo; Trojani, Fabio
This paper studies the term structure implications of a simple structural model in which the representative agent displays ambiguity aversion, modeled by Multiple Priors Recursive Utility. Bond excess returns reflect a premium for ambiguity, which is observationally distinct from the risk premium of affine yield curve models. The ambiguity premium can be large even in the simplest log-utility setting and is also nonzero for stochastic factors that have a zero risk premium. A calibrated low-dimensional two-factor model with ambiguity is able to reproduce the deviations from the expectations hypothesis documented in the literature, without modifying in a substantial way the nonlinear mean-reversion dynamics of the short interest rate. Moreover, the model does not imply any apparent trade-off between fitting the first and second moments of the yield curve.</description><author>Gagliardini, Patrick; Porchia, Paolo; Trojani, Fabio</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing the Costs and Benefits of Brokers in the Mutual Fund Industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bergstresser, Daniel; Chalmers, John M. R.; Tufano, Peter
Many investors purchase mutual funds through intermediated channels, paying brokers or financial advisors for fund selection and advice. This article attempts to quantify the benefits that investors enjoy in exchange for the costs of these services. We study broker-sold and direct-sold funds from 1996 to 2004, and fail to find that brokers deliver substantial tangible benefits. Relative to direct-sold funds, broker-sold funds deliver lower risk-adjusted returns, even before subtracting distribution costs. These results hold across fund objectives, with the exception of foreign equity funds. Further, broker-sold funds exhibit no more skill at aggregate-level asset allocation than do funds sold through the direct channel. Our results are consistent with two hypotheses: that brokers deliver substantial intangible benefits that we do not observe and that there are material conflicts of interest between brokers and their clients.</description><author>Bergstresser, Daniel; Chalmers, John M. R.; Tufano, Peter</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pension Reform, Ownership Structure, and Corporate Governance: Evidence from a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Laeven, Luc
Sweden offers a unique natural experiment to analyze the effects of institutionalized saving on the ownership structure, corporate governance, and firm performance. The Swedish pension reform increased the stock market participation of pension funds, causing a significant reshuffling in the ownership of pension funds. We show that the effects of institutional investment on firm performance depend on the industry structure of pension funds. Firm valuation improves if public pension funds and large independent private pension funds increase their shareholdings. Additionally, controlling shareholders appear reluctant to relinquish control and the control premium increases if public pension funds acquire shares.</description><author>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Laeven, Luc</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the Effect of Hierarchies on Information Use</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liberti, Jose M.; Mian, Atif R.
Theory suggests that greater hierarchical distance between a subordinate and his boss makes it more difficult to share abstract and subjective information in decision making. A novel dataset put together from credit dossiers of large corporate loan applicants enables us to observe the information collected by loan officers, and how it is used by the ultimate loan approving officer. We find that greater hierarchical/geographical distance between the information collecting agent and the loan approving officer leads to less reliance on subjective information and more on objective information. By exploiting nonlinearities in the "assignment rules" that determine an applicant's hierarchical distance, and using information collecting agent fixed effects, we show that our result cannot be driven by endogenous assignment of applicants. We also find that higher frequency of interactions between the information collecting agent and loan approving officer, both over time and through geographical proximity, helps mitigate the effects of hierarchical distance on information use. Our results show that hierarchical distance influences information use, and highlights the importance of "human touch" in communication.</description><author>Liberti, Jose M.; Mian, Atif R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership: Evolution and Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Franks, Julian; Mayer, Colin; Rossi, Stefano
This article is the first study of long-run evolution of investor protection and corporate ownership in the United Kingdom over the twentieth century. Formal investor protection emerged only in the second half of the century. We assess the influence of investor protection on ownership by comparing cross-sections of firms at different times in the century and the evolution of firms incorporating at different stages of the century. Investor protection had little impact on dispersion of ownership: even in the absence of investor protection, rates of dispersion of ownership were high, associated primarily with mergers. Preliminary evidence suggests that ownership dispersion in the United Kingdom relied more on informal relations of trust than on formal investor protection.</description><author>Franks, Julian; Mayer, Colin; Rossi, Stefano</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Scaling the Hierarchy: How and Why Investment Banks Compete for Syndicate Co-management Appointments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ljungqvist, Alexander; Marston, Felicia; Wilhelm, William J.
We show that relatively optimistic research and even the mere provision of research coverage for the issuer (regardless of its direction) attract co-management appointments for securities offerings. Co-management appointments are valuable because they help banks establish relationships with issuers. These relationships, in turn, substantially increase the banks' chances of winning more lucrative lead-management mandates in the future. This is true even in the presence of historically exclusive banking relationships.</description><author>Ljungqvist, Alexander; Marston, Felicia; Wilhelm, William J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Large Shareholders and Corporate Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cronqvist, Henrik; Fahlenbrach, Ruediger
We analyze the effects of heterogeneity across large shareholders, using a new blockholder-firm panel dataset in which we can track all unique blockholders among large public firms in the United States. We find statistically significant and economically important blockholder fixed effects in investment, financial, and executive compensation policies. We also find blockholder fixed effects in firm performance measures, and differences in corporate policies are systematically related to differences in firm performance. We study potential sources of the heterogeneity and find that blockholders with a larger block size, board membership, direct management involvement, or with a single decision maker are associated with larger effects on corporate policies and firm performance.</description><author>Cronqvist, Henrik; Fahlenbrach, Ruediger</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Disagreement and Learning in a Dynamic Contracting Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adrian, Tobias; Westerfield, Mark M.
We present a dynamic contracting model in which the principal and agent disagree about the resolution of uncertainty, and we illustrate the contract design in an application with Bayesian learning. The disagreement creates gains from trade that the principal realizes by transferring payment to states that the agent considers relatively more likely, changing incentives. The interaction between incentive provision and learning creates an intertemporal source of "disagreement risk" that alters optimal risk sharing. There is an endogenous regime shift between economies with small and large belief differences, and an early shock to beliefs can lead to large persistent differences in variable pay even after beliefs have converged. Under risk-neutrality, "selling the firm" to the agent does not implement the first-best because it precludes state-contingent trades.</description><author>Adrian, Tobias; Westerfield, Mark M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Limitations of Industry Concentration Measures Constructed with Compustat Data: Implications for Finance Research</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ali, Ashiq; Klasa, Sandy; Yeung, Eric
Industry concentration measures calculated with Compustat data, which cover only the public firms in an industry, are poor proxies for actual industry concentration. These measures have correlations of only 13% with the corresponding U.S. Census measures, which are based on all public and private firms in an industry. Also, only when U.S. Census measures are used is there evidence consistent with theoretical predictions that more-concentrated industries, which should be more oligopolistic, are populated by larger and fewer firms with higher price-cost margins. Further, the significant relations of Compustat-based industry concentration measures with the dependent variables of several important prior studies are not obtained when U.S. Census measures are used. One of the reasons for this occurrence is that Compustat-based measures proxy for industry decline. Overall, our results indicate that product markets research that uses Compustat-based industry concentration measures may lead to incorrect conclusions.</description><author>Ali, Ashiq; Klasa, Sandy; Yeung, Eric</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option Backdating and Board Interlocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bizjak, John; Lemmon, Michael; Whitby, Ryan
We examine the role of board connections in explaining how the controversial practice of backdating employee stock options spread to a large number of firms across a wide range of industries. The increase in the likelihood that a firm begins to backdate stock options that can be explained by having a board member who is interlocked to a previously identified backdating firm is approximately one-third of the unconditional probability of backdating in our sample. Our analysis provides new insight into how boards function and the role that they play in providing managerial oversight and determining corporate strategy. (JEL G30, G32, G38, J33)</description><author>Bizjak, John; Lemmon, Michael; Whitby, Ryan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Sale of Multiple Assets with Private Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Zhiguo
By generalizing the Leland and Pyle (1977) model to the case of multiple correlated assets, this paper studies the signaling and hedging behavior of an intermediary who sells multiple assets in financial markets. Based on information asymmetry, this paper demonstrates the intrinsic interdependence of risk management and asset selling for intermediaries, and obtains several testable empirical implications. For instance, an intermediary with a more diversified underlying portfolio will face greater liquidity (a smaller price impact) when selling assets to the market. Several applications are discussed, including bank loan sales and selling mechanisms. (JEL D40, D82, G20)</description><author>He, Zhiguo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Reexamination of Corporate Governance and Equity Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, Shane A.; Moorman, Theodore C.; Sorescu, Sorin
We reexamine long-term abnormal returns for portfolios sorted on governance characteristics. Firms with strong shareholder rights and firms with weak shareholder rights differ from the population of firms and from each other in how they cluster across industries. Using well-specified tests under this industry clustering, we find statistically zero long-term abnormal returns for portfolios sorted on governance. Our results have important implications for interpreting studies that link governance to firm value and stock returns, demonstrate the importance of the coarseness of industry definitions in financial research, and shed light on addressing statistical problems created by industry clustering in samples. (JEL C1, C52, G11, G12, G14, G34)</description><author>Johnson, Shane A.; Moorman, Theodore C.; Sorescu, Sorin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the Growth Effect of Stock Market Liberalizations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gupta, Nandini; Yuan, Kathy
We investigate the effect of a stock market liberalization on industry growth in emerging markets. Consistent with the view that liberalization reduces financing constraints, we find that industries that are more externally dependent and face better growth opportunities grew faster following liberalization. However, this growth increase appears to come from an expansion in the size of existing firms rather than through the entry of financially constrained new firms. We show that following liberalization, new firm growth occurs in countries and industries with lower entry barriers. Hence, liberalization has a more uniform growth impact if accompanied by competition-enhancing reforms. (JEL E32, F30, F36, F43, G15, G18, G28)</description><author>Gupta, Nandini; Yuan, Kathy</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentive Contracts in Delegated Portfolio Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, C. Wei; Tiwari, Ashish
This article analyzes optimal nonlinear portfolio management contracts. We consider a setting in which the investor faces moral hazard with respect to the effort and risk choices of the portfolio manager. The employment contract promises the manager: (i) a fixed payment, (ii) a proportional asset-based fee, (iii) a benchmark-linked fulcrum fee, and (iv) a benchmark-linked option-type "bonus" incentive fee. We show that the option-type incentive helps overcome the effort-underinvestment problem that undermines linear contracts. More generally, we find that for the set of contracts we consider, with the appropriate choice of benchmark it is always optimal to include a bonus incentive fee in the contract. We derive the conditions that such a benchmark must satisfy. Our results suggest that current regulatory restrictions on asymmetric performance-based fees in mutual fund advisory contracts may be costly. (JEL G11, G12, D82, D86)</description><author>Li, C. Wei; Tiwari, Ashish</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Size and Focus of a Venture Capitalist's Portfolio</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fulghieri, Paolo; Sevilir, Merih
We take a portfolio approach to analyze the investment strategy of a venture capitalist (VC) and show that portfolio size and scope affect both the entrepreneurs' and the VC's incentives to exert effort. A small portfolio improves entrepreneurial incentives because it allows the VC to concentrate the limited human capital on a smaller number of startups, adding more value. A large and focused portfolio is beneficial because it allows the VC to reallocate the limited resources and human capital in the case of startup failure and allows the VC to extract greater rents from the entrepreneurs. We show that the VC finds it optimal to limit portfolio size when startups have higher payoff potential-that is, when providing strong entrepreneurial incentives is most valuable. The VC expands portfolio size only when startup fundamentals are more moderate and when he can form a sufficiently focused portfolio. Finally, we show that the VC may find it optimal to engage in portfolio management by divesting some of the startups early since this strategy allows him to extract a greater surplus. (JEL G24)</description><author>Fulghieri, Paolo; Sevilir, Merih</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Dynamic Model of the Limit Order Book</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rosu, Ioanid
This paper presents a model of an order-driven market where fully strategic, symmetrically informed liquidity traders dynamically choose between limit and market orders, trading off execution price and waiting costs. In equilibrium, the bid and ask prices depend only on the numbers of buy and sell orders in the book. The model has a number of empirical predictions: (i) higher trading activity and higher trading competition cause smaller spreads and lower price impact; (ii) market orders lead to a temporary price impact larger than the permanent price impact, therefore to price overshooting; (iii) buy and sell orders can cluster away from the bid-ask spread, generating a hump-shaped order book; (iv) bid and ask prices display a comovement effect: after, e.g., a sell market order moves the bid price down, the ask price also falls, by a smaller amount, so the bid-ask spread widens; (v) when the order book is full, traders may submit quick, or fleeting, limit orders. (JEL C7, D4, G1)</description><author>Rosu, Ioanid</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Benchmarking Money Manager Performance: Issues and Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chan, Louis K. C.; Dimmock, Stephen G.; Lakonishok, Josef
Academic and practitioner research evaluates portfolio performance using size and value/growth attributes or factors. We assess the merits of popular evaluation procedures based on matched-characteristic benchmark portfolios or time-series return regressions by applying them to a sample of active money managers and passive indexes. Estimated abnormal returns display large variation across approaches. The benchmarks typically used in academic research-attribute-matched portfolios from independent sorts, the three-factor time-series model, and cross-sectional regressions of returns on stock characteristics-track returns poorly. Some simple alterations improve the performance of these methods. (JEL G11, G12, G14, G23)</description><author>Chan, Louis K. C.; Dimmock, Stephen G.; Lakonishok, Josef</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Open-Loop Equilibria and Perfect Competition in Option Exercise Games</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Back, Kerry; Paulsen, Dirk
The investment boundaries defined by Grenadier (2002) for an oligopoly investment game determine equilibria in open-loop strategies. As closed-loop strategies, they are not equilibria, because any firm by investing sooner can preempt the investments of other firms and expropriate the growth options. The perfectly competitive outcome is produced by closed-loop strategies that are mutually best responses. In this equilibrium, the option to delay investment has zero value, and the simple NPV rule is followed by all firms. (JEL C73, D43, D92, G31, L13)</description><author>Back, Kerry; Paulsen, Dirk</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding Index Option Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Broadie, Mark; Chernov, Mikhail; Johannes, Michael
Previous research concludes that options are mispriced based on the high average returns, CAPM alphas, and Sharpe ratios of various put selling strategies. One criticism of these conclusions is that these benchmarks are ill suited to handle the extreme statistical nature of option returns generated by nonlinear payoffs. We propose an alternative way to evaluate the statistical significance of option returns by comparing historical statistics to those generated by option pricing models. The most puzzling finding in the existing literature, the large returns to writing out-of-the-money puts, is not inconsistent (i.e., is statistically insignificant) relative to the Black-Scholes model or the Heston stochastic volatility model due to the extreme sampling uncertainty associated with put returns. This sampling problem can largely be alleviated by analyzing market-neutral portfolios such as straddles or delta-hedged returns. The returns on these portfolios can be explained by jump risk premiums and estimation risk. (JEL C12, G13)</description><author>Broadie, Mark; Chernov, Mikhail; Johannes, Michael</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected Stock Returns and Variance Risk Premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollerslev, Tim; Tauchen, George; Zhou, Hao
Motivated by the implications from a stylized self-contained general equilibrium model incorporating the effects of time-varying economic uncertainty, we show that the difference between implied and realized variation, or the variance risk premium, is able to explain a nontrivial fraction of the time-series variation in post-1990 aggregate stock market returns, with high (low) premia predicting high (low) future returns. Our empirical results depend crucially on the use of "model-free," as opposed to Black-Scholes, options implied volatilities, along with accurate realized variation measures constructed from high-frequency intraday as opposed to daily data. The magnitude of the predictability is particularly strong at the intermediate quarterly return horizon, where it dominates that afforded by other popular predictor variables, such as the P/E ratio, the default spread, and the consumption-wealth ratio. (JEL C22, C51, C52, G12, G13, G14)</description><author>Bollerslev, Tim; Tauchen, George; Zhou, Hao</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unspanned Stochastic Volatility and the Pricing of Commodity Derivatives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Trolle, Anders B.; Schwartz, Eduardo S.
Commodity derivatives are becoming an increasingly important part of the global derivatives market. Here we develop a tractable stochastic volatility model for pricing commodity derivatives. The model features unspanned stochastic volatility, quasi-analytical prices of options on futures contracts, and dynamics of the futures curve in terms of a low-dimensional affine state vector. We estimate the model on NYMEX crude oil derivatives using an extensive panel data set of 45,517 futures prices and 233,104 option prices, spanning 4082 business days. We find strong evidence for two predominantly unspanned volatility factors. (JEL G13)</description><author>Trolle, Anders B.; Schwartz, Eduardo S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Good Times or Bad Times? Investors' Uncertainty and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ozoguz, Arzu
This paper investigates empirically the dynamics of investors' beliefs and Bayesian uncertainty about the state of the economy as state variables that describe the time-variation in investment opportunities. Using measures of uncertainty constructed from the state probabilities estimated from two-state regime-switching models of aggregate market return and of aggregate output, I find a negative relationship between the level of uncertainty and asset valuations. This relationship shows substantial cross-sectional variation across portfolios sorted on size, book-to-market, and past returns, especially conditional on the state of the economy. I show that a conditional model with investors' beliefs and an uncertainty risk factor is remarkably successful in explaining a large part of the cross-sectional variation in average portfolio returns. The uncertainty risk factor retains its incremental explanatory power when compared to other conditional models such as the conditional CAPM. (JEL G12, G14 and D80)</description><author>Ozoguz, Arzu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonparametric Estimation of State-Price Densities Implicit in Interest Rate Cap Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Haitao; Zhao, Feng
Based on a multivariate extension of the constrained locally polynomial estimator of Ait-Sahalia and Duarte (2003), we provide one of the first nonparametric estimates of probability densities of LIBOR rates under forward martingale measures and state-price densities (SPDs) implicit in interest rate cap prices. The forward densities and SPDs depend significantly on the slope and volatility of LIBOR rates, and mortgage markets activities have strong impacts on the shape of the forward densities. The SPDs exhibit a pronounced U-shape as a function of future LIBOR rates, suggesting that the state prices are high at both extremely low and high interest rates, which tend to be associated with recessions and periods of high inflation, respectively. Our results provide nonparametric evidence of unspanned stochastic volatility and suggest that the unspanned factors could be partly driven by activities in the mortgage markets. (JEL G12, G13)</description><author>Li, Haitao; Zhao, Feng</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Erica X. N.; Livdan, Dmitry; Zhang, Lu
We take a simple g-theory model and ask how well it can explain external financing anomalies, both qualitatively and quantitatively. Our central insight is that optimal investment is an important driving force of these anomalies. The model simultaneously reproduces procyclical equity issuance waves, the negative relation between investment and average returns, long-term underperformance following equity issues, positive long-term drift following cash distributions, the mean-reverting operating performance of issuing and cash-distributing firms, and the failure of the CAPM in explaining the long-term stock-price drifts. However, the model cannot fully capture the magnitude of the positive drift following cash distributions observed in the data. (JEG D21, D92, E22, E44, G12, G14, G31, G32, G35)</description><author>Li, Erica X. N.; Livdan, Dmitry; Zhang, Lu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected Returns and the Business Cycle: Heterogeneous Goods and Time-Varying Risk Aversion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lochstoer, Lars A.
This paper proposes a representative agent habit-formation model where preferences are defined for both luxury goods and basic goods. The model matches the equity risk premium, risk-free rate, and volatilities. From the intratemporal first-order condition, one can substitute out basic good consumption and the habit level, yielding a stochastic discount factor driven by two observable risk factors: luxury good consumption and the relative price of the two goods. I estimate these processes and find them to be heteroskedastic, implying time variation in the conditional volatility of the stochastic discount factor. These dynamics occur both at the business cycle frequency and at a lower, "generational" frequency. The findings reveal that the time variation in aggregate stock market and Treasury bond risk premiums are consistent with the predictions of the model.</description><author>Lochstoer, Lars A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Return Decomposition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Long; Zhao, Xinlei
A crucial issue in asset pricing is to understand the relative importance of discount rate (DR) news and cash flow (CF) news in driving the time-series and cross-sectional variations of stock returns. Many studies directly estimate the DR news but back out the CF news as the residual. We argue that this approach has a serious limitation because the DR news cannot be accurately measured due to the small predictive power, and the CF news, as the residual, inherits the large misspecification error of the DR news. We apply this residual-based decomposition approach to Treasury bonds and equities and find results that are either counterintuitive or unrobust. Potential solutions, including modeling both DR news and CF news directly, the Bayesian model averaging approach, and the principal component analysis, are explored.</description><author>Chen, Long; Zhao, Xinlei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Brokerage Commissions and Institutional Trading Patterns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldstein, Michael A.; Irvine, Paul; Kandel, Eugene; Wiener, Zvi
The institutional brokerage industry faces an ever-increasing pressure to lower trading costs, which has already driven down average commissions and shifted volume toward low-cost execution venues. However, traditional full-service brokers that bundle execution with services remain a force and their commissions are still considerably higher than the marginal cost of trade execution. We hypothesize that commissions constitute a convenient way of charging a prearranged fixed fee for long-term access to a broker's premium services. We derive testable predictions based on this hypothesis and test them on a large sample of institutional trades from 1999 to 2003. We find that institutions negotiate commissions infrequently, and thus commissions vary little with trade characteristics. Institutions also concentrate their order flow with a relatively small set of brokers, with smaller institutions concentrating their trading more than large institutions and paying higher per-share commissions. These results are stable over time, are consistent with our predictions, and cannot be explained by cost-minimization alone. Finally, we discuss the evolution of the institutional brokerage market within the proposed framework and make informal predictions about future developments in the industry.</description><author>Goldstein, Michael A.; Irvine, Paul; Kandel, Eugene; Wiener, Zvi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Basis Assets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahn, Dong-Hyun; Conrad, Jennifer; Dittmar, Robert F.
This paper proposes a new method of forming basis assets. We use return correlations to sort securities into portfolios and compare the inferences drawn from this set of basis assets with those drawn from other benchmark portfolios. The proposed set of portfolios appears capable of generating measures of risk-return trade-off that are estimated with a lower error. In tests of asset pricing models, we find that the returns of these portfolios are significantly and positively related to both CAPM and Consumption CAPM risk measures, and there are significant components of these returns that are not captured by the three-factor model.</description><author>Ahn, Dong-Hyun; Conrad, Jennifer; Dittmar, Robert F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining Credit Default Swap Spreads with the Equity Volatility and Jump Risks of Individual Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhang, Benjamin Yibin; Zhou, Hao; Zhu, Haibin
This paper attempts to explain the credit default swap (CDS) premium, using a novel approach to identify the volatility and jump risks of individual firms from high-frequency equity prices. Our empirical results suggest that the volatility risk alone predicts 48% of the variation in CDS spread levels, whereas the jump risk alone forecasts 19%. After controlling for credit ratings, macroeconomic conditions, and firms' balance sheet information, we can explain 73% of the total variation. We calibrate a Merton-type structural model with stochastic volatility and jumps, which can help to match credit spreads after controlling for the historical default rates. Simulation evidence suggests that the high-frequency-based volatility measures can help to explain the credit spreads, above and beyond what is already captured by the true leverage ratio.</description><author>Zhang, Benjamin Yibin; Zhou, Hao; Zhu, Haibin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empirical Analysis of Corporate Credit Lines</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jimenez, Gabriel; Lopez, Jose A.; Saurina, Jesus
Since bank credit lines are a major source of corporate funding, we examine the determinants of their usage with a comprehensive database of Spanish corporate credit lines. A line's default status is a key factor driving its usage, which increases as firm financial conditions worsen. Firms with prior defaults access their credit lines less, suggesting that bank monitoring influences firms' usage decisions. Line usage has an aging effect that causes it to decrease by roughly 10% per year of its life. Lender characteristics, such as the length of a firm's banking relationships, as well as macroeconomic conditions, affect usage decisions.</description><author>Jimenez, Gabriel; Lopez, Jose A.; Saurina, Jesus</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macro Factors in Bond Risk Premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ludvigson, Sydney C.; Ng, Serena
Are there important cyclical fluctuations in bond market premiums and, if so, with what macroeconomic aggregates do these premiums vary? We use the methodology of dynamic factor analysis for large datasets to investigate possible empirical linkages between forecastable variation in excess bond returns and macroeconomic fundamentals. We find that "real" and "inflation" factors have important forecasting power for future excess returns on U.S. government bonds, above and beyond the predictive power contained in forward rates and yield spreads. This behavior is ruled out by commonly employed affine term structure models where the forecastability of bond returns and bond yields is completely summarized by the cross-section of yields or forward rates. An important implication of these findings is that the cyclical behavior of estimated risk premia in both returns and long-term yields depends importantly on whether the information in macroeconomic factors is included in forecasts of excess bond returns. Without the macro factors, risk premia appear virtually acyclical, whereas with the estimated factors risk premia have a marked countercyclical component, consistent with theories that imply investors must be compensated for risks associated with macroeconomic activity.</description><author>Ludvigson, Sydney C.; Ng, Serena</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment Banks as Insiders and the Market for Corporate Control</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bodnaruk, Andriy; Massa, Massimo; Simonov, Andrei
We study holdings in merger and acquisition (M&amp;A) targets by financial conglomerates in which affiliated investment banks advise the bidders. We show that advisors take positions in the targets before M&amp;A announcements. These stakes are positively related to the probability of observing the bid and to the target premium. We argue that this can be explained in terms of advisors who are privy to important information about the deal, investing in the target in the expectation of its price increasing. We document the high profits of this strategy. The advisory stake is positively related to the likelihood of deal completion and to the termination fees. However, these deals are not wealth creating: there is a negative relation between the advisory stake and the viability of the deal.</description><author>Bodnaruk, Andriy; Massa, Massimo; Simonov, Andrei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcy Codes and Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Subramanian, Krishnamurthy V.
We argue that when bankruptcy code is creditor friendly, excessive liquidations cause levered firms to shun innovation, whereas by promoting continuation upon failure, a debtor-friendly code induces greater innovation. We provide empirical support for this claim by employing patents as a proxy for innovation. Using time-series changes within a country and cross-country variation in creditor rights, we confirm that a creditor-friendly code leads to a lower absolute level of innovation by firms, as well as relatively lower innovation by firms in technologically innovative industries. When creditor rights are stronger, technologically innovative industries employ relatively less leverage and grow disproportionately slower.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Subramanian, Krishnamurthy V.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Empire-Building or Bridge-Building ? Evidence from New CEOs' Internal Capital Allocation Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xuan, Yuhai
This article investigates how the job histories of CEOs influence their capital allocation decisions when they preside over multidivisional firms. I find that, after CEO turnover, divisions not previously affiliated with the new CEO receive significantly more capital expenditures than divisions through which the new CEO has advanced. The pattern of reverse-favoritism in capital allocation is more pronounced if the new CEO has less authority or if the unaffiliated divisions have more bargaining power. I find evidence that having a specialist CEO negatively affects segment investment efficiency. The results suggest that new specialist CEOs use the capital budget as a bridge-building tool to elicit cooperation from powerful divisional managers in previously unaffiliated divisions.</description><author>Xuan, Yuhai</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Multiplicative Model of Optimal CEO Incentives in Market Equilibrium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex; Gabaix, Xavier; Landier, Augustin
This paper presents a unified theory of both the level and sensitivity of pay in competitive market equilibrium, by embedding a moral hazard problem into a talent assignment model. By considering multiplicative specifications for the CEO's utility and production functions, we generate a number of different results from traditional additive models. First, both the CEO's low fractional ownership (the Jensen-Murphy incentives measure) and its negative relationship with firm size can be quantitatively reconciled with optimal contracting, and thus need not reflect rent extraction. Second, the dollar change in wealth for a percentage change in firm value, divided by annual pay, is independent of firm size, and therefore a desirable empirical measure of incentives. Third, incentive pay is effective at solving agency problems with multiplicative impacts on firm value, such as strategy choice. However, additive issues such as perk consumption are best addressed through direct monitoring.</description><author>Edmans, Alex; Gabaix, Xavier; Landier, Augustin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tunnel-Proofing the Executive Suite: Transparency, Temptation, and the Design of Executive Compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Noe, Thomas H.
This paper considers optimal compensation for a CEO who is entrusted with administering corporate assets honestly. Optimal compensation designs maximize integrity at minimum cost. These designs are very "low powered," i.e., while specifying a lower bound for performance and increasing pay with performance, they increase compensation at a rapidly decreasing rate. Thus, integrity considerations engender optimal compensation packages that closely resemble the very pervasive 80/120 bonus plans, exactly the sort of compensation that Jensen (2003) argues should compromise integrity. Under optimal designs, expected compensation increases linearly with firm size, and increases in the market/book ratio. Moreover, given optimal compensation, CEO asset diversion is limited to high market-to-book firms that have received negative productivity shocks.</description><author>Noe, Thomas H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Disclosure and Stock Returns: Theory and Evidence from US Cross-Listing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goto, Shingo; Watanabe, Masahiro; Xu, Yan
When a firm exercises discretion to disclose or withhold information (strategic disclosure), risk-averse investors command higher expected returns when expected cash flows decrease, producing a negative correlation between these expectations. Moreover, stock returns exhibit stronger reversal than they do when full disclosure is enforced. We propose a model that makes these predictions and provide consistent evidence using a panel of foreign firms that list American Depositary Receipts (ADRs). We find significant shifts in the time-series properties of stock returns for firms that undergo large changes in disclosure environments, such as those cross-listing on the NYSE/AMEX/NASDAQ and those from less-developed/emerging markets and code-law countries.</description><author>Goto, Shingo; Watanabe, Masahiro; Xu, Yan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does capital account liberalization lead to growth ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Quinn, Dennis P.; Toyoda, A. Maria
We test whether capital account liberalization led to higher economic growth using de jure measures of capital account and financial current account openness for 94 nations, from 1950 (or independence) onward. We argue that measurement error, differing time periods used, and collinearity among independent variables account for conflicting results in prior scholarship. We use pooled time-series, cross-sectional OLS and system GMM estimators to examine economic growth rates, 1955-2004. Capital account liberalization had a positive association with growth in both developed and emerging market nations. We confirm that equity market liberalization has an independent effect on economic growth.</description><author>Quinn, Dennis P.; Toyoda, A. Maria</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimation risk, information, and the conditional CAPM: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Praveen; Sorescu, Sorin M.; Boehme, Rodney D.; Danielsen, Bartley R.
We theoretically and empirically investigate the role of information on the cross section of stock returns and firms' cost of capital when investors face estimation risk and learn from noisy signals of uncertain quality. The resultant equilibrium is an information-dependent conditional CAPM. We find strong empirical support for the model. Innovations in market volatility, oil prices, exchange rates, and dispersion of analysts' forecasts not only help explain the cross section of stock returns, but their influence depends on the stock's systematic estimation risk. Moreover, dividend and share repurchase initiations have significant downward announcement effects on estimated betas and their standard errors.</description><author>Kumar, Praveen; Sorescu, Sorin M.; Boehme, Rodney D.; Danielsen, Bartley R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust stochastic discount factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyle, Phelim; Feng, Shui; Tian, Weidong; Wang, Tan
When the market is incomplete, a new non-redundant derivative security cannot be priced by no-arbitrage arguments alone. Moreover, there will be a multiplicity of stochastic discount factors and each of them may give a different price for the new derivative security. This paper develops an approach to the selection of a stochastic discount factor for pricing a new derivative security. The approach is based on the idea that the price of a derivative security should not vary too much when the payoff of the primitive security is slightly perturbed, i.e., the price of the derivative should be robust to model misspecification. The paper develops two metrics of robustness. The first is based on robustness in expectation. The second is based on robustness in probability and draws on tools from the theory of large deviations. We show that in a stochastic volatility model, the two metrics yield analytically tractable bounds for the derivative price, as the underlying stochastic volatility model is perturbed. The bounds can be readily used for numerical examination of the sensitivity of the price of the derivative to model misspecification.</description><author>Boyle, Phelim; Feng, Shui; Tian, Weidong; Wang, Tan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Small trades and the cross-section of stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hvidkjaer, Soeren
This paper uses volume arising from small trades to analyze the relationship between retail investor trading behavior and the cross-section of future stock returns. The central finding is that stocks with intense sell-initiated small-trade volume, measured over the past several months, outperform stocks with intense buy-initiated small-trade volume. This return difference accrues from the first month after the portfolio formation up to two years later. Among small- and medium-sized firms, the return difference continues in the third year. The results suggest that stocks favored by retail investors subsequently experience prolonged underperformance relative to stocks out of favor with retail investors.</description><author>Hvidkjaer, Soeren</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Excess comovement of stock returns: Evidence from cross-sectional variation in Nikkei 225 weights</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenwood, Robin
Relative to their weights in a value-weighted index, a number of stocks in Japans Nikkei 225 stock index are overweighted by a factor of 10 or more. I document a strong positive relation between overweighting and the comovement of a stock with other stocks in the Nikkei index, and a negative relationship between index overweighting and comovement with stocks outside of the index. The cross-sectional approach resolves endogeneity problems associated with event study demonstrations of excess comovement. A trading strategy that bets on the reversion of stock prices of overweighted stocks generates economic profits, confirming that the observed comovement patterns are excessive, and providing further evidence that comovement of stock returns can be a consequence of commonality in trading behavior.</description><author>Greenwood, Robin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The spline-GARCH model for low-frequency volatility and its global macroeconomic causes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engle, Robert F.; Rangel, Jose Gonzalo
Twenty-five years of volatility research has left the macroeconomic environment playing a minor role. This paper proposes modeling equity volatilities as a combination of macro- economic effects and time series dynamics. High-frequency return volatility is specified to be the product of a slow-moving component, represented by an exponential spline, and a unit GARCH. This slow-moving component is the low-frequency volatility, which in this model coincides with the unconditional volatility. This component is estimated for nearly 50 countries over various sample periods of daily data. Low-frequency volatility is then modeled as a function of macroeconomic and financial variables in an unbalanced panel with a variety of dependence structures. It is found to vary over time and across countries. The low-frequency component of volatility is greater when the macroeconomic factors of GDP, inflation, and short-term interest rates are more volatile or when inflation is high and output growth is low. Volatility is higher not only for emerging markets and markets with small numbers of listed companies and market capitalization relative to GDP, but also for large economies. The model allows long horizon forecasts of volatility to depend on macroeconomic developments, and delivers estimates of the volatility to be anticipated in a newly opened market.</description><author>Engle, Robert F.; Rangel, Jose Gonzalo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A GARCH option pricing model with filtered historical simulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barone-Adesi, Giovanni; Engle, Robert F.; Mancini, Loriano
We propose a new method for pricing options based on GARCH models with filtered historical innovations. In an incomplete market framework, we allow for different distributions of historical and pricing return dynamics, which enhances the model's flexibility to fit market option prices. An extensive empirical analysis based on S&amp;P 500 index options shows that our model outperforms other competing GARCH pricing models and ad hoc Black-Scholes models. We show that the flexible change of measure, the asymmetric GARCH volatility, and the nonparametric innovation distribution induce the accurate pricing performance of our model. Using a nonparametric approach, we obtain decreasing state-price densities per unit probability as suggested by economic theory and corroborating our GARCH pricing model. Implied volatility smiles appear to be explained by asymmetric volatility and negative skewness of filtered historical innovations.</description><author>Barone-Adesi, Giovanni; Engle, Robert F.; Mancini, Loriano</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Average idiosyncratic volatility in G7 countries</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, Hui; Savickas, Robert
We argue that changes in average idiosyncratic volatility provide a proxy for changes in the investment opportunity set and that this proxy is closely related to the book-to-market factor. We test this idea in two ways using G7 countries' data. First, we show that idiosyncratic volatility has statistically significant predictive power for aggregate stock market returns over time. Second, we show that idiosyncratic volatility performs just as well as the book-to-market factor in explaining the cross section of stock returns. Our results suggest that the hedge against changes in investment opportunities is an important determinant of asset prices.</description><author>Guo, Hui; Savickas, Robert</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected returns, yield spreads, and asset pricing tests</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campello, Murillo; Chen, Long; Zhang, Lu
We construct firm-specific measures of expected equity returns using corporate bond yields, and replace standard ex post average returns with our expected-return measures in asset pricing tests. We find that the market beta is significantly priced in the cross section of expected returns. The expected size and value premiums are positive and countercyclical, but there is no evidence of positive expected momentum profits.</description><author>Campello, Murillo; Chen, Long; Zhang, Lu</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting default with the Merton distance to default model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bharath, Sreedhar T.; Shumway, Tyler
We examine the accuracy and contribution of the Merton distance to default (DD) model, which is based on Merton's (1974) bond pricing model. We compare the model to a "naive" alternative, which uses the functional form suggested by the Merton model but does not solve the model for an implied probability of default. We find that the naive predictor performs slightly better in hazard models and in out-of-sample forecasts than both the Merton DD model and a reduced-form model that uses the same inputs. Several other forecasting variables are also important predictors, and fitted values from an expanded hazard model outperform Merton DD default probabilities out of sample. Implied default probabilities from credit default swaps and corporate bond yield spreads are only weakly correlated with Merton DD probabilities after adjusting for agency ratings and bond characteristics. We conclude that while the Merton DD model does not produce a sufficient statistic for the probability of default, its functional form is useful for forecasting defaults.</description><author>Bharath, Sreedhar T.; Shumway, Tyler</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who monitors the monitor? The effect of board independence on executive compensation and firm value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Praveen; Sivaramakrishnan, K.
Recent corporate governance reforms focus on the board's independence and encourage equity ownership by directors. We analyze the efficacy of these reforms in a model in which both adverse selection and moral hazard exist at the level of the firm's management. Delegating governance to the board improves monitoring but creates another agency problem because directors themselves avoid effort and are dependent on the CEO. We show that as directors become less dependent on the CEO, their monitoring efficiency may decrease even as they improve the incentive efficiency of executive compensation contracts. Therefore, a board composed of directors that are more independent may actually perform worse. Moreover, higher equity incentives for the board may increase equity-based compensation awards to management.</description><author>Kumar, Praveen; Sivaramakrishnan, K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Choosing to cofinance: Analysis of project-specific alliances in the movie industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Palia, Darius; Ravid, S. Abraham; Reisel, Natalia
We use a movie industry project-by-project dataset to analyze the choice of financing a project internally versus financing it through outside alliances. The results indicate that project risk is positively correlated with alliance formation. Movie studios produce a variety of films and tend to develop their safest projects internally. Our findings are consistent with internal capital market explanations. We find mixed evidence regarding resource pooling, i.e., sharing the cost of large projects. Finally, the evidence shows that projects developed internally perform similarly to projects developed through outside alliances.</description><author>Palia, Darius; Ravid, S. Abraham; Reisel, Natalia</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Building relationships early: Banks in venture capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hellmann, Thomas; Lindsey, Laura; Puri, Manju
This paper examines bank behavior in venture capital. It considers the relation between a bank's venture capital investments and its subsequent lending, which can be thought of as intertemporal cross-selling. Theory suggests that unlike independent venture capital firms, banks may be strategic investors who seek complementarities between venture capital and lending activities. We find evidence that banks use venture capital investments to build lending relationships. Having a prior relationship with a company in the venture capital market increases a bank's chance of subsequently granting a loan to that company. Companies can benefit from these relationships through more favorable loan pricing.</description><author>Hellmann, Thomas; Lindsey, Laura; Puri, Manju</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Production in entrepreneurial firms: The effects of financial constraints on labor and capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garmaise, Mark J.
I model the contrasting capital-labor decisions of financially constrained and unconstrained firms. I show that financially restricted firms use relatively more labor than physical capital because informed employees provide more efficient financing than uninformed capital suppliers. I demonstrate that constrained firms cannot easily attract new employees to replace existing staff. Their greater employee retention aligns owner-worker incentives and encourages workers to make firm-specific investments. Constrained firms, however, gradually suffer from their inability to replace low-quality workers, such that their relative labor productivity decreases over time. Empirical tests utilizing instrumental variables confirm several implications of the theory.</description><author>Garmaise, Mark J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Complex ownership structures and corporate valuations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Laeven, Luc; Levine, Ross
The bulk of corporate governance theory examines the agency problems that arise from two extreme ownership structures: 100% small shareholders or one large, controlling owner combined with small shareholders. In this paper, we question the empirical validity of this dichotomy. In fact, one-third of publicly listed firms in Europe have multiple large owners, and the market value of firms with multiple blockholders differs from firms with a single large owner and from widely held firms. Moreover, the relationship between corporate valuations and the distribution of cash-flow rights across multiple large owners is consistent with the predictions of recent theoretical models.</description><author>Laeven, Luc; Levine, Ross</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The value of investor protection: Firm evidence from cross-border mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bris, Arturo; Cabolis, Christos
International law prescribes that in a cross-border acquisition of 100% of the target shares, the target firm becomes a national of the country of the acquiror, and consequently subject to its corporate governance system. Therefore, cross-border mergers provide a natural experiment to analyze the effects of changes in corporate governance on firm value. We construct measures of the change in investor protection in a sample of 506 acquisitions from 39 countries. We find that the better the shareholder protection and accounting standards in the acquiror's country, the higher the merger premium in cross-border mergers relative to matching domestic acquisitions.</description><author>Bris, Arturo; Cabolis, Christos</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic alliances and the boundaries of the firm</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Robinson, David T.
Strategic alliances are long-term contracts between legally distinct organizations that provide for sharing the costs and benefits of a mutually beneficial activity. In this paper, I develop and test a model that helps explain why firms sometimes prefer alliances over internally organized projects. I introduce managerial effort into a model of internal capital markets and show how strategic alliances help overcome incentive problems that arise when headquarters cannot pre-commit to particular capital allocations. The model generates a number of implications, which I test using a large sample of alliance transactions in conjunction with Compustat data.</description><author>Robinson, David T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analytic pricing of employee stock options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cvitanic, Jaksa; Wiener, Zvi; Zapatero, Fernando
We introduce a model that captures the main properties that characterize employee stock options (ESO). We discuss the likelihood of early voluntary ESO exercise, and the obligation to exercise immediately if the employee leaves the firm, except if this happens before options are vested, in which case the options are forfeited. We derive an analytic formula for the price of the ESO and in a case study compare it to alternative methods.</description><author>Cvitanic, Jaksa; Wiener, Zvi; Zapatero, Fernando</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Where is the market? Evidence from cross-listings in the United States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Halling, Michael; Pagano, Marco; Randl, Otto; Zechner, Josef
We analyze the location of stock trading for firms with a US cross-listing. The fraction of trading that occurs in the United States tends to be larger for companies from countries that are geographically close to the United States and feature low financial development and poor insider trading protection. For companies based in developed countries, trading volume in the United States is larger if the company is small, volatile, and technology-oriented, while this does not apply to emerging country firms. The domestic turnover rate increases in the cross-listing year and remains higher for firms based in developed markets, but not for emerging market firms. Domestic trading volume actually declines for companies from countries with poor enforcement of insider trading regulation.</description><author>Halling, Michael; Pagano, Marco; Randl, Otto; Zechner, Josef</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distance still matters: Evidence from municipal bond underwriting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Butler, Alexander W.
Using a sample of municipal bond offerings, I find that "local" investment banks have substantial comparative and absolute advantages over nonlocal counterparts--locals charge lower fees and sell bonds at lower yields. Local investment banks' strongest comparative advantage is at underwriting bonds with higher credit risk and bonds not rated by rating agencies. These findings suggest that high-risk bonds and nonrated bonds are more difficult to evaluate and market, and that investment banks with a local presence are better able to assess "soft" information and place difficult bond issues.</description><author>Butler, Alexander W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>All that glitters: The effect of attention and news on the buying behavior of individual and institutional investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barber, Brad M.; Odean, Terrance
We test and confirm the hypothesis that individual investors are net buyers of attention-grabbing stocks, e.g., stocks in the news, stocks experiencing high abnormal trading volume, and stocks with extreme one-day returns. Attention-driven buying results from the difficulty that investors have searching the thousands of stocks they can potentially buy. Individual investors do not face the same search problem when selling because they tend to sell only stocks they already own. We hypothesize that many investors consider purchasing only stocks that have first caught their attention. Thus, preferences determine choices after attention has determined the choice set.</description><author>Barber, Brad M.; Odean, Terrance</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identifying term structure volatility from the LIBOR-swap curve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thompson, Samuel
This paper proposes a new family of specification tests and applies them to affine term structure models of the London Interbank Offered Rate (LIBOR)-swap curve. Contrary to Dai and Singleton (2000), the tests show that when standard estimation techniques are used, affine models do a poor job of forecasting volatility at the short end of the term structure. Improving the volatility forecast does not require different models; rather, it requires a different estimation technique. The paper distinguishes between two econometric procedures for identifying volatility. The cross-sectional approach backs out volatility from a cross section of bond yields, and the time-series approach imputes volatility from time-series variation in yields. For an affine model, the volatility implied by the time-series procedure passes the specification tests, while the cross-sectionally identified volatility does not. This is surprising, since under correct specification, the cross-sectional approach is maximum likelihood. One explanation is that affine models are slightly misspecified; another is that bond yields do not span volatility, as in Collin-Dufresne and Goldstein (2002).</description><author>Thompson, Samuel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International asset allocation under regime switching, skew, and kurtosis preferences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guidolin, Massimo; Timmermann, Allan
This paper investigates the international asset allocation effects of time-variations in higher-order moments of stock returns such as skewness and kurtosis. In the context of a four-moment International Capital Asset Pricing Model (ICAPM) specification that relates stock returns in five regions to returns on a global market portfolio and allows for time-varying prices of covariance, co-skewness, and co-kurtosis risk, we find evidence of distinct bull and bear regimes. Ignoring such regimes, an unhedged US investor's optimal portfolio is strongly diversified internationally. The presence of regimes in the return distribution leads to a substantial increase in the investor's optimal holdings of US stocks, as does the introduction of skewness and kurtosis preferences.</description><author>Guidolin, Massimo; Timmermann, Allan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Endogenous events and long-run returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Viswanathan, S.; Wei, Bin
We analyze event abnormal returns when returns predict events. In fixed samples, we show that the expected abnormal return is negative and becomes more negative as the holding period increases. Asymptotically, abnormal returns converge to zero provided that the process of the number of events is stationary. Nonstationarity in the process of the number of events is needed to generate a large negative bias. We present theory and simulations for the specific case of a lognormal model to characterize the magnitude of the small-sample bias. We illustrate the theory by analyzing long-term returns after initial public offerings (IPOs) and seasoned equity offerings (SEOs).</description><author>Viswanathan, S.; Wei, Bin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional portfolio flows and international investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Froot, Kenneth A.; Ramadorai, Tarun
Using a new technique, and weekly data for 25 countries from 1994 to 1998, we analyze the relationship between institutional cross-border portfolio flows, and domestic and foreign equity returns. In emerging markets, institutional flows forecast statistically indistinguishable movements in country closed-end fund NAV returns and price returns. In contrast, closed-end fund flows forecast price returns, but not NAV returns. Furthermore, institutional flows display trend-following (trend-reversing) behavior in response to symmetric (asymmetric) movements in NAV and price returns. The results suggest that institutional cross-border flows are linked to fundamentals, while closed-end fund flows are a source of price pressure in the short run.</description><author>Froot, Kenneth A.; Ramadorai, Tarun</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>State dependence can explain the risk aversion puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chabi-Yo, Fousseni; Garcia, Rene; Renault, Eric
Risk aversion functions extracted from observed stock and option prices can be negative, as shown by Ait-Sahalia and Lo (2000), Journal of Econometrics 94: 9-51; and Jackwerth (2000), The Review of Financial Studies 13(2), 433-51. We rationalize this puzzle by a lack of conditioning on latent state variables. Once properly conditioned, risk aversion functions and pricing kernels are consistent with economic theory. To differentiate between the various theoretical explanations in terms of heterogeneity of beliefs or preferences, market sentiment, state-dependent utility, or regimes in fundamentals, we calibrate several consumption-based asset pricing models to match the empirical pricing kernel and risk aversion functions at different dates and over several years.</description><author>Chabi-Yo, Fousseni; Garcia, Rene; Renault, Eric</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bubbles: Some perspectives (and loose talk) from history</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O'Hara, Maureen
Bubbles are a topic of great importance and great controversy. This paper discusses alternative perspectives on the economic meaning and origin of bubbles. Drawing on historical approaches to bubbles, this article sets out a taxonomy of approaches used to explain the nature of bubbles. The paper also considers issues connected with the scientific thinking surrounding bubbles.</description><author>O'Hara, Maureen</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note from the editor</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spiegel, Matthew
nan</description><author>Spiegel, Matthew</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The causes and consequences of recent financial market bubbles: An introduction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Yu, Xiaoyun
On August 12-13, 2005, the department of finance at the Kelley School of Business, Indiana University, collaborated with the Review of Financial Studies to host a conference titled "The Causes and Consequences of Recent Financial Market Bubbles." This article begins with our overview of the themes and findings of the conference, and it ends with the questions that the literature has yet to answer.</description><author>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Yu, Xiaoyun</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relative wealth concerns and financial bubbles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeMarzo, Peter M.; Kaniel, Ron; Kremer, Ilan
We present a rational general equilibrium model that highlights the fact that relative wealth concerns can play a role in explaining financial bubbles. We consider a finite-horizon overlapping generations model in which agents care only about their consumption. Though the horizon is finite, competition over future investment opportunities makes agents utilities dependent on the wealth of their cohort and induces relative wealth concerns. Agents herd into risky securities and drive down their expected return. Even though the bubble is likely to burst and lead to a substantial loss, agents relative wealth concerns make them afraid to trade against the crowd.</description><author>DeMarzo, Peter M.; Kaniel, Ron; Kremer, Ilan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tournaments in mutual-fund families</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kempf, Alexander; Ruenzi, Stefan
We examine intrafirm competition in the mutual-fund industry. We test the hypothesis that fund managers within mutual-fund families compete with each other in a tournament. Our empirical study of the US equity mutual-fund market shows that they adjust the risk they take depending on the relative position within their fund family. The direction of the adjustment depends on the competitive situation in that family. Risk adjustments are particularly pronounced among managers of funds with high expense ratios, which are managed by a single manager and which belong to large families.</description><author>Kempf, Alexander; Ruenzi, Stefan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual funds and bubbles: The surprising role of contractual incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dass, Nishant; Massa, Massimo; Patgiri, Rajdeep
This article studies one of the potential causes of the financial market bubble of the late 1990s: the herding behavior of mutual funds. We show that the incentives contained in the mutual funds advisory contracts induce managers to overcome their tendency to herd. We argue that investing in bubble stocks amounts to herding and contracts with high incentives induce managers to diverge from the herd, thus reducing their holding of bubble stocks. The differential exposure to bubble stocks significantly impacted the funds performance both in the period prior to March 2000, as well as afterwards.</description><author>Dass, Nishant; Massa, Massimo; Patgiri, Rajdeep</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyst behavior following IPOs: The "Bubble Period" evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bradley, Daniel J.; Jordan, Bradford D.; Ritter, Jay R.
We examine over 7400 analyst recommendations made in the year after going public for IPOs from 1999 to 2000. Initiations of coverage at the end of the quiet period come almost exclusively from affiliated analysts, whereas initiations afterward are predominantly from unaffiliated analysts. Contrary to previous findings, we find no evidence that the market discounts recommendations from affiliated analysts once we control for recommendation characteristics and timing. Moreover, analyst coverage in the first year is not affected by underpricing, and after the flurry of initiations at the end of the quiet period, the number of analysts covering a firm during the following 11 months is unrelated to the number of managing underwriters. (JEL G12, G14, G24).</description><author>Bradley, Daniel J.; Jordan, Bradford D.; Ritter, Jay R.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Money illusion and housing frenzies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brunnermeier, Markus K.; Julliard, Christian
A reduction in inflation can fuel run-ups in housing prices if people suffer from money illusion. For example, investors who decide whether to rent or buy a house by simply comparing monthly rent and mortgage payments do not take into account the fact that inflation lowers future real mortgage costs. We decompose the price-rent ratio into a rational component-meant to capture the proxy effect and risk premia-and an implied mispricing. We find that inflation and nominal interest rates explain a large share of the time series variation of the mispricing, and that the tilt effect is very unlikely to rationalize this finding.</description><author>Brunnermeier, Markus K.; Julliard, Christian</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditioning information and variance bounds on pricing kernels with higher-order moments: Theory and evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chabi-Yo, Fousseni
We develop a strategy for utilizing higher moments, variance risk premia, and conditioning information efficiently, and hence improve on the variance bounds computed by Hansen and Jagannathan (1991); Gallant, Hansen, and Tauchen (1990); and Bekaert and Liu (2004). Our bounds reach existing bounds when nonlinearities in returns are not priced. We also use higher moments, variance risk premia, and conditioning information to provide distance measures that improve on the Hansen and Jagannathan (1997) distance measure. Empirical results indicate that when accounting for the impact of higher moments and variance risk premia, the existing pricing kernels have difficulty in explaining returns on the assets and derivatives.</description><author>Chabi-Yo, Fousseni</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the dynamics of mutual fund alphas and betas</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mamaysky, Harry; Spiegel, Matthew; Zhang, Hong
This article develops a Kalman filter model to track dynamic mutual fund factor loadings. It then uses the estimates to analyze whether managers with market-timing ability can be identified ex ante. The primary findings are as follows: (i) Ordinary least squares (OLS) timing models produce false positives (nonzero alphas) at too high a rate with either daily or monthly data. In contrast, the Kalman filter model produces them at approximately the correct rate with monthly data; (ii) In monthly data, though the OLS models fail to detect any timing among fund managers, the Kalman filter does; (iii) The alpha and beta forecasts from the Kalman model are more accurate than those from the OLS timing models; (iv) The Kalman filter model tracks most fund alphas and betas better than OLS models that employ macroeconomic variables in addition to fund returns.</description><author>Mamaysky, Harry; Spiegel, Matthew; Zhang, Hong</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A dynamic model for the forward curve</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chua, Choong Tze; Foster, Dean; Ramaswamy, Krishna; Stine, Robert
This article develops and estimates a dynamic arbitrage-free model of the current forward curve as the sum of (i) an unconditional component, (ii) a maturity-specific component and (iii) a date-specific component. The model combines features of the Preferred Habitat model, the Expectations Hypothesis (ET) and affine yield curve models; it permits a class of low-parameter, multiple state variable dynamic models for the forward curve. We show how to construct alternative parametric examples of the three components from a sum of exponential functions, verify that the resulting forward curves satisfy the Heath-Jarrow-Morton (HJM) conditions, and derive the risk-neutral dynamics for the purpose of pricing interest rate derivatives. We select a model from alternative affine examples that are fitted to the Fama-Bliss Treasury data over an initial training period and use it to generate out-of-sample forecasts for forward rates and yields. For forecast horizons of 6 months or longer, the forecasts of this model significantly outperform those from common benchmark models.</description><author>Chua, Choong Tze; Foster, Dean; Ramaswamy, Krishna; Stine, Robert</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is nonlinear drift implied by the short end of the term structure?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Takamizawa, Hideyuki
Nonlinear drift models of the short rate are estimated using data on the short end of the term structure, where the cross-sectional relation is obtained by an analytical approximation. The findings reveal that (i) nonlinear physical drift is not implied unless it is strongly affected by cross-sectional dimensions of the data; (ii) nonlinear risk-neutral drift that allows for fast mean reversion for high rates is desirable to explain and predict observed patterns of yield spreads; and (iii) for higher frequency data from which transitory shocks are removed, (ii) still remains valid although the nonlinearity is somewhat reduced.</description><author>Takamizawa, Hideyuki</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Two trees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cochrane, John H.; Longstaff, Francis A.; Santa-Clara, Pedro
We solve a model with two i.i.d. Lucas trees. Although the corresponding one-tree model produces a constant price-dividend ratio and i.i.d. returns, the two-tree model produces interesting asset-pricing dynamics. Investors want to rebalance their portfolios after any change in value. Because the size of the trees is fixed, prices must adjust to offset this desire. As a result, expected returns, excess returns, and return volatility all vary through time. Returns display serial correlation and are predictable from price-dividend ratios. Return volatility differs from cash-flow volatility, and return shocks can occur without news about cash flows.</description><author>Cochrane, John H.; Longstaff, Francis A.; Santa-Clara, Pedro</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor sentiment and option prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Bing
This paper examines whether investor sentiment about the stock market affects prices of the S&amp;P 500 options. The findings reveal that the index option volatility smile is steeper (flatter) and the risk-neutral skewness of monthly index return is more (less) negative when market sentiment becomes more bearish (bullish). These significant relations are robust and become stronger when there are more impediments to arbitrage in index options. They cannot be explained by rational perfect-market-based option pricing models. Changes in investor sentiment help explain time variation in the slope of index option smile and risk-neutral skewness beyond factors suggested by the current models.</description><author>Han, Bing</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing with limited risk sharing and heterogeneous agents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gomes, Francisco; Michaelides, Alexander
We develop a model with incomplete markets and heterogeneous agents that generates a large equity premium, while simultaneously matching stock market participation and individual asset holdings. The high risk-premium is driven by incomplete risk sharing among stockholders, which results from the combination of aggregate uncertainty, borrowing constraints, and a (realistically) calibrated life-cycle earnings profile subject to idiosyncratic shocks. We show that it is challenging to simultaneously match asset pricing moments and individual portfolio decisions, while limited participation has a negligible impact on the risk-premium, contrary to the results of models where it is imposed exogenously.</description><author>Gomes, Francisco; Michaelides, Alexander</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stocks or options? Moral hazard, firm viability, and the design of compensation contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kadan, Ohad; Swinkels, Jeroen M.
We consider the choice between stocks and options to provide effort incentives to a risk-averse manager. We show that stocks can dominate options as a means of motivation only if nonviability risk is substantial, as in financially distressed firms or start-ups. Options dominate stocks for other firms. These results hold regardless of the existing portfolio of the manager. We provide empirical evidence that higher bankruptcy risk is indeed correlated with more use of stock.</description><author>Kadan, Ohad; Swinkels, Jeroen M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inflation Uncertainty, Asset Valuations, and the Credit Spreads Puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>David, Alexander
Investors' learning of the state of future real fundamentals from current inflation leads to macroeconomic state dependence of asset valuations and solvency ratios of firms within given rating categories. Since credit spreads are convex functions of solvency ratios, average spreads are higher than spreads at average solvency ratios. Macroeconomic shocks carry risk premiums so that expected default losses are more sensitive to changes in the price of risk than are credit spreads. By incorporating state dependence and increasing the price of risk, the econometrician obtains high credit spreads while maintaining average default losses at historical levels-the credit spreads puzzle.</description><author>David, Alexander</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unobserved Actions of Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kacperczyk, Marcin; Sialm, Clemens; Zheng, Lu
Despite extensive disclosure requirements, mutual fund investors do not observe all actions of fund managers. We estimate the impact of unobserved actions on fund returns using the return gap-the difference between the reported fund return and the return on a portfolio that invests in the previously disclosed fund holdings. We document that unobserved actions of some funds persistently create value, while such actions of other funds destroy value. Our main result shows that the return gap predicts fund performance.</description><author>Kacperczyk, Marcin; Sialm, Clemens; Zheng, Lu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum Profits, Factor Pricing, and Macroeconomic Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Laura Xiaolei; Zhang, Lu
Recent winners have temporarily higher loadings than recent losers on the growth rate of industrial production. The loading spread derives mostly from the positive loadings of winners. The growth rate of industrial production is a priced risk factor in standard asset pricing tests. In many specifications, this macroeconomic risk factor explains more than half of momentum profits. We conclude that risk plays an important role in driving momentum profits.</description><author>Liu, Laura Xiaolei; Zhang, Lu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>