<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>RFS6</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:27:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Time-Varying Liquidity Risk and the Cross Section of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Watanabe, Akiko; Watanabe, Masahiro
This paper studies whether stock returns' sensitivities to aggregate liquidity fluctuations and the pricing of liquidity risk vary over time. We find that liquidity betas vary across two distinct states: one with high liquidity betas and the other with low betas. The high liquidity-beta state is short lived and characterized by heavy trade, high volatility, and a wide cross-sectional dispersion in liquidity betas. It also delivers a disproportionately large liquidity risk premium, amounting to more than twice the value premium. Our results are consistent with a model of liquidity risk in which investors face uncertainty about their trading counterparties' preferences.</description><author>Watanabe, Akiko; Watanabe, Masahiro</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jumps in Financial Markets: A New Nonparametric Test and Jump Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Suzanne S.; Mykland, Per A.
This article introduces a new nonparametric test to detect jump arrival times and realized jump sizes in asset prices up to the intra-day level. We demonstrate that the likelihood of misclassification of jumps becomes negligible when we use high-frequency returns. Using our test, we examine jump dynamics and their distributions in the U. S. equity markets. The results show that individual stock jumps are associated with prescheduled earnings announcements and other company-specific news events. Additionally, S&amp;P 500 Index jumps are associated with general market news announcements. This suggests different pricing models for individual equity options versus index options.</description><author>Lee, Suzanne S.; Mykland, Per A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning and Asset Prices Under Ambiguous Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leippold, Markus; Trojani, Fabio; Vanini, Paolo
In a Lucas exchange economy with standard power utility, we study asset prices under learning and ambiguous information. In contrast with models featuring only learning or ambiguity, our model is successful in matching the equity premium, the interest rate, and the volatility of stock returns under empirically reasonable parameters. Our closed-form formulas also show that a severe downward bias arises in the empirical relation between stock returns and return volatility. We quantify this bias in simulations and show that our model can explain why such a relation is difficult to detect in the data.</description><author>Leippold, Markus; Trojani, Fabio; Vanini, Paolo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Growth Options Explain the Trend in Idiosyncratic Risk?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, Charles; Simin, Timothy; Zhao, Jing
While recent studies document increasing idiosyncratic volatility over the past four decades, an explanation for this trend remains elusive. We establish a theoretical link between growth options available to managers and the idiosyncratic risk of equity. Empirically both the level and variance of corporate growth options are significantly related to idiosyncratic volatility. Accounting for growth options eliminates or reverses the trend in aggregate firm-specific risk. These results are robust for different measures of idiosyncratic volatility, different growth option proxies, across exchanges, and through time. Finally, our results suggest that growth options explain the trend in idiosyncratic volatility beyond alternative explanations.</description><author>Cao, Charles; Simin, Timothy; Zhao, Jing</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Quality and Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vanden, Joel M.
Microstructure researchers have long understood that information quality has an effect on price formation in the underlying asset market. However, option researchers have largely ignored the fact that information quality might also impact the options market. This article characterizes the nature of the impact by showing how option prices and implied volatility levels are related to the forward looking information quality path. This result follows from a noisy rational expectations model that abandons the normal distribution in favor of the gamma distribution, but maintains the standard assumption of exponential utility. Thus the new model bridges the gap between the microstructure literature that relies so heavily on the normal-exponential framework, and the options literature that relies exclusively on models that are consistent with the limited liability of stock prices. The model's tractability allows for a robustness check against the standard framework and provides a viable setting for analyzing the empirical implications of information quality for the options market.</description><author>Vanden, Joel M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monopoly and Information Advantage in the Residential Mortgage Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gan, Jie; Riddiough, Timothy J.
Information advantage and entry deterrence incentives are investigated as they affect lending outcomes and competitive structure of the U. S. residential mortgage market. In the model, when assessing a loan applicant, the incumbent monopoly lender employs a proprietary screening technology to produce a privately observed estimate of loan credit quality. When faced with potential competitive entry, the incumbent signals poor credit quality by charging high prices to higher-quality borrowers. Market structure and loan pricing strategy are derived endogenously, where the incumbent deters entry first by segmenting consumers into prime and sub-prime loan markets and second by charging prime market borrowers a uniform rate that is higher than the risk-based monopoly rate. Empirical implications of the model are identified, and evidence is presented that is consistent with predictions.</description><author>Gan, Jie; Riddiough, Timothy J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash-in-the-Market Pricing and Optimal Resolution of Bank Failures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Yorulmazer, Tanju
As the number of bank failures increases, the set of assets available for acquisition by surviving banks enlarges but the total liquidity available with surviving banks falls. This results in "cash-in-the-market" pricing for liquidation of banking assets. At a sufficiently large number of bank failures, and in turn, at a sufficiently low level of asset prices, there are too many banks to liquidate and inefficient users of assets who are liquidity-endowed may end up owning the liquidated assets. In order to avoid this allocation inefficiency, it may be ex-post optimal for the regulator to bail out some failed banks. We show, however, that there exists a policy that involves granting liquidity to surviving banks in the purchase of failed banks, which is equivalent to the bailout policy from an ex-post standpoint. Crucially, this liquidity provision policy gives banks incentives to differentiate, rather than to herd, makes aggregate banking crises less likely, and thereby dominates the bailout policy from an ex-ante standpoint.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Yorulmazer, Tanju</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Default Risk, Shareholder Advantage, and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garlappi, Lorenzo; Shu, Tao; Yan, Hong
This paper examines the relationship between default probability and stock returns. Using the Expected Default Frequency (EDF) of Moody's KMV, we document that higher default probabilities are not associated with higher expected stock returns. Within a model of bargaining between equity holders and debt holders in default, we show that the relationship between default probability and equity return is (i) upward sloping for firms where shareholders can extract little benefit from renegotiation (low "shareholder advantage") and (ii) humped and downward sloping for firms with high shareholder advantage. This dichotomy implies that distressed firms with stronger shareholder advantage should exhibit lower expected returns in the cross section. Our empirical evidence, based on several proxies for shareholder advantage, is consistent with the model's predictions.</description><author>Garlappi, Lorenzo; Shu, Tao; Yan, Hong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder Diversification and the Decision to Go Public</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bodnaruk, Andriy; Kandel, Eugene; Massa, Massimo; Simonov, Andrei
We study the effects of the controlling shareholders' portfolio diversification on the initial public offering (IPO) process. Less diversified shareholders have more to gain from taking their firm public, and are more willing to accept a lower price for shares. We test these hypotheses using the data on all IPOs in Sweden between 1995 and 2001. Using detailed information on the portfolio composition of shareholders in private and public firms, we construct several proxies of their portfolio diversification and relate them to the probability of the IPO and the underpricing. We show that the less diversified individual shareholders, especially those with lower wealth, sell more of their shares at the IPO. Firms held by less diversified controlling shareholders are more likely to go public, and exhibit higher underpricing. These effects are economically and statistically significant, while the diversification of noncontrolling shareholders has no effect. Our findings suggest that diversification of controlling shareholders plays a prominent role in the IPO process.</description><author>Bodnaruk, Andriy; Kandel, Eugene; Massa, Massimo; Simonov, Andrei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The New Issues Puzzle: Testing the Investment-Based Explanation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lyandres, Evgeny; Sun, Le; Zhang, Lu
An investment factor, long in low-investment stocks and short in high-investment stocks, helps explain the new issues puzzle. Adding the investment factor into standard factor regressions reduces the SEO underperformance by about 75%, the IPO underperformance by 80%, the underperformance following convertible debt offerings by 50%, and Daniel and Titman's (2006) composite issuance effect by 40%. The reason is that issuers invest more than nonissuers, and the investment factor earns a significantly positive average return of 0.57% per month.</description><author>Lyandres, Evgeny; Sun, Le; Zhang, Lu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Constraints and Growth: Multinational and Local Firm Responses to Currency Depreciations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desai, Mihir A.; Foley, C. Fritz; Forbes, Kristin J.
This article examines how financial constraints and product market exposures determine the response of multinational and local firms to sharp depreciations. U. S. multinational affiliates increase sales, assets, and investment significantly more than local firms during, and subsequent to, depreciations. Differing product market exposures do not explain these differences in performance. Instead, a differential ability to circumvent financial constraints is a significant determinant of the observed differences in investment responses. Multinational affiliates also access parent equity when local firms are most constrained. These results indicate another role for foreign direct investment in emerging markets-multinational affiliates expand economic activity during currency crises when local firms are most constrained.</description><author>Desai, Mihir A.; Foley, C. Fritz; Forbes, Kristin J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How well do institutional theories explain firms perceptions of property rights?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ayyagari, Meghana; Demirguec-Kunt, Asli; Maksimovic, Vojislav
We examine how well several institutional- and firm-level factors explain firms' perceptions of property rights protection. The institutional theories we investigate account for approximately 50% of the country-level variation, indicating that current research addresses first-order factors. Firm-level characteristics, such as legal organization and ownership structure, are comparable with institutional factors in explaining variations in property rights protection. A country's legal origin predicts property rights variation better than its religion, ethnic fractionalization, or natural endowments. However, these results are driven by the inclusion of former Socialist economies in the sample. When we exclude the former Socialist economies, legal origin explains considerably less than ethnic fractionalization does.</description><author>Ayyagari, Meghana; Demirguec-Kunt, Asli; Maksimovic, Vojislav</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market discipline and internal governance in the mutual fund industry</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dangl, Thomas; Wu, Youchang; Zechner, Josef
We develop a continuous-time model in which a portfolio manager is hired by a management company. On the basis of observed portfolio returns, all agents update their beliefs about the managers skills. In response, investors can move capital into or out of the mutual fund, and the management company can fire the manager. Introducing firing rationalizes several empirically documented findings, such as the positive relation between manager tenure and fund size or the increase of portfolio risk before a manager replacement and the following risk decrease. The analysis predicts that the critical performance threshold that triggers firing increases significantly over a managers tenure and that management replacements are accompanied by capital inflows when a young manager is replaced but may be accompanied by capital outflows when a manager with a long tenure is fired. Our model yields much lower valuation levels for management companies than simple applications of discounted cash flow (DCF) methods and is thus more consistent with empirical observations.</description><author>Dangl, Thomas; Wu, Youchang; Zechner, Josef</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dating game: Do managers designate option grant dates to increase their compensation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Narayanan, M. P.; Seyhun, H. Nejat
We provide evidence of two variants of a dating game that entails picking a grant date ex post, that is, after the boards compensation decision is made: back-dating (picking a date before the board decision date), and forward-dating (waiting after the board decision date to observe the stock price behavior). Consistent with back-dating, we find stock return behavior around the grant date to be positively related to reporting lag. In the promptly reported sample, we find stock return behavior and the pattern of reporting lags consistent with forward-dating. Our calculations show that managers can obtain economically significant benefits by playing the dating game.</description><author>Narayanan, M. P.; Seyhun, H. Nejat</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contracts and exits in venture capital finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cumming, Douglas
nan</description><author>Cumming, Douglas</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do sovereign bonds benefit corporate bonds in emerging markets ?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dittmar, Robert F.; Yuan, Kathy
We analyze the impact of emerging-market sovereign bonds on emerging-market corporate bonds by examining their spanning enhancement, price discovery, and issuance effects. We find that the effect of spanning enhancement is positive and large; over one-fifth of the information in corporate yield spreads is traced to innovations in sovereign bonds; and most of these effects are due to discovery and spanning of systematic risks. Further, issuance of sovereign bonds, controlling for endogeneity of market-timing decisions, lowers corporate yield and bid-ask spreads. Our results indicate that sovereign securities act as benchmarks and suggest they promote a vibrant corporate bond market.</description><author>Dittmar, Robert F.; Yuan, Kathy</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Intragroup propping: Evidence from the stock-price effects of earnings announcements by Korean business groups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bae, Gil S.; Cheon, Youngsoon S.; Kang, Jun-Koo
Using earnings announcement events made by firms belonging to Korean chaebols, we examine propping within a chaebol. Consistent with the market's ex ante valuation of intragroup propping, we find that the announcement of increased (decreased) earnings by a chaebol-affiliated firm has a positive (negative) effect on the market value of other nonannouncing affiliates. The sensitivity of the change in the market value of nonannouncing affiliates to abnormal returns for the announcing firms is higher if the cash flow right of the announcing firm's controlling shareholder is higher. The sensitivity is also higher if the announcing firm is larger, performs well, and has a higher debt guarantee ratio.</description><author>Bae, Gil S.; Cheon, Youngsoon S.; Kang, Jun-Koo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do retail incentives work in privatizations?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keloharju, Matti; Knuepfer, Samuli; Torstila, Sami
Twenty countries around the world have used 27 billion in incentives such as bonus shares and discounts to attract retail investors to participate in privatizations and to discourage them from flipping their shares. Our results show that incentives have performed well, increasing retail investor participation much more cost effectively than underpricing. Flipping is not only much reduced in the short term but remains cumulatively at least 15% lower after 1000 trading days. The expiration of bonus share plans is associated with a 6-day abnormal return of 1.0% and a long-term increase in trading volume.</description><author>Keloharju, Matti; Knuepfer, Samuli; Torstila, Sami</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The returns on human capital: Good news on wall street is bad news on main street</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lustig, Hanno; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn
We use a standard single-agent model to conduct a simple consumption growth accounting exercise. Consumption growth is driven by news about current and expected future returns on the market portfolio. We impute the residual of consumption growth innovations that cannot be attributed to either news about financial asset returns or future labor income growth to news about expected future returns on human wealth, and we back out the implied human wealth and market return process. Innovations in current and future human wealth returns are negatively correlated with innovations in current and future financial asset returns, regardless of the elasticity of intertemporal substitution.</description><author>Lustig, Hanno; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Habit formation, incomplete markets, and the significance of regional risk for expected returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korniotis, George M.
This paper introduces a consumption-based capital asset pricing model (CCAPM) that combines undiversifiable income shocks and external habit formation. Using US state-level data, the paper provides realistic estimates for preference parameters when the external habit of the state investors is based on the consumption of the four Census regions. The model also implies four asset pricing factors: the cross-sectional means of consumption growth and habit growth (capturing national systematic risk) and the cross-sectional variances of consumption growth and habit growth (capturing regional systematic risk). This four-factor model has greater power in explaining expected returns than the CCAPM described in Breeden (1979).</description><author>Korniotis, George M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Taxable and tax-deferred investing: A tax-arbitrage approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Jennifer
We analyze an intertemporal portfolio problem with both taxable and tax-deferred retirement accounts. Using a tax-arbitrage argument, we identify conditions under which the optimal location decision (where to place an asset) is separable from the allocation decision (how much to allocate to each asset). Investors place highly taxed assets in the tax-deferred account to maximize the tax benefit and adjust their taxable portfolios to achieve the optimal risk exposure. We show that the two-account problem can be reduced to a taxable-account-only problem. The results are robust to capital gains tax deferrals, consumption and contribution decisions, and stochastic tax rates.</description><author>Huang, Jennifer</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining the level of credit spreads: Option-implied jump risk premia in a firm value model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Driessen, Joost; Maenhout, Pascal
We study whether option-implied jump risk premia can explain the high observed level of credit spreads. We use a structural jump-diffusion firm value model to assess the level of credit spreads generated by option-implied jump risk premia. Prices and returns of equity index and individual options are used to estimate the jump parameters. We further calibrate the model to historical information on default risk and the equity premium. The results show that incorporating option-implied jump risk premia brings predicted credit spread levels much closer to observed levels. The introduction of jumps also helps to improve the fit of the volatility of credit spreads and equity returns.</description><author>Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Driessen, Joost; Maenhout, Pascal</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Biases in decomposing holding-period portfolio returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Weimin; Strong, Norman
A growing number of studies in finance decompose multiperiod portfolio returns into a series of single-period returns, using these to test asset pricing models or market efficiency or to evaluate the returns to investment strategies such as those based on momentum, size, and value-growth. We provide a formal analysis of the decomposition method. Crucially, we argue and present empirical evidence that some methods researchers use involve portfolios that nobody would seriously consider ex ante, that transactions costs associated with such portfolios make them poor investment vehicles, and that they can lead to spurious statistical inferences.</description><author>Liu, Weimin; Strong, Norman</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strong-form efficiency with monopolistic insiders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chau, Minh; Vayanos, Dimitri
We study market efficiency in an infinite-horizon model with a monopolistic insider. The insider can trade with competitive market makers and noise traders, and observes privately the expected growth rate of asset dividends. In the absence of the insider, this information would be reflected in prices only after a long series of dividend observations. Thus, the insiders information is long-lived. Surprisingly, however, the monopolistic insider chooses to reveal her information very quickly, within a time converging to zero as the market approaches continuous trading. Although the market converges to strong-form efficiency, the insiders profits do not converge to zero.</description><author>Chau, Minh; Vayanos, Dimitri</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Bayesian analysis of return dynamics with Levy jumps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Haitao; Wells, Martin T.; Yu, Cindy L.
We have developed Bayesian Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) methods for inferences of continuous-time models with stochastic volatility and infinite-activity Levy jumps using discretely sampled data. Simulation studies show that (i) our methods provide accurate joint identification of diffusion, stochastic volatility, and Levy jumps, and (ii) the affine jump-diffusion (AJD) models fail to adequately approximate the behavior of infinite-activity jumps. In particular, the AJD models fail to capture the "infinitely many" small Levy jumps, which are too big for Brownian motion to model and too small for compound Poisson process to capture. Empirical studies show that infinite-activity Levy jumps are essential for modeling the S&amp;P 500 index returns.</description><author>Li, Haitao; Wells, Martin T.; Yu, Cindy L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting the equity premium: Where we stand today</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spiegel, Matthew
The Review of Financial Studies has among its missions the facilitation and promotion of a vigorous academic debate across unsettled questions in finance. This issue represents a cross section of views regarding one such debate: Can ourempirical models accurately forecast the equity premium any better than the historical mean ? Or, is the forecast our empirical models give us any more accurate than what we would get by simply using the historical mean ?</description><author>Spiegel, Matthew</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A comprehensive look at the empirical performance of equity premium prediction</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Welch, Ivo; Goyal, Amit
Our article comprehensively reexamines the performance of variables that have been suggested by the academic literature to be good predictors of the equity premium. We find that by and large, these models have predicted poorly both in-sample (IS) and out-of-sample (OOS) for 30 years now; these models seem unstable, as diagnosed by their out-of-sample predictions and other statistics; and these models would not have helped an investor with access only to available information to profitably time the market. (JEL G12, G14).</description><author>Welch, Ivo; Goyal, Amit</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predicting excess stock returns out of sample: Can anything beat the historical average?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, John Y.; Thompson, Samuel B.
Goyal and Welch (2007) argue that the historical average excess stock return forecasts future excess stock returns better than regressions of excess returns on predictor variables. In this article, we show that many predictive regressions beat the historical average return, once weak restrictions are imposed on the signs of coefficients and return forecasts. The out-of-sample explanatory power is small, but nonetheless is economically meaningful for mean-variance investors. Even better results can be obtained by imposing the restrictions of steady-state valuation models, thereby removing the need to estimate the average from a short sample of volatile stock returns.</description><author>Campbell, John Y.; Thompson, Samuel B.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The dog that did not bark: A defense of return predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cochrane, John H.
If returns are not predictable, dividend growth must be predictable, to generate the observed variation in divided yields. I find that the absence of dividend growth predictability gives stronger evidence than does the presence of return predictability. Long-horizon return forecasts give the same strong evidence. These tests exploit the negative correlation of return forecasts with dividend-yield autocorrelation across samples, together with sensible upper bounds on dividend-yield autocorrelation, to deliver more powerful statistics. I reconcile my findings with the literature that finds poor power in long-horizon return forecasts, and with the literature that notes the poor out-of-sample R-2 of return- forecasting regressions.</description><author>Cochrane, John H.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The myth of long-horizon predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boudoukh, Jacob; Richardson, Matthew; Whitelaw, Robert F.
The prevailing view in finance is that the evidence for long-horizon stock return predictability is significantly stronger than that for short horizons. We show that for persistent regressors, a characteristic of most of the predictive variables used in the literature, the estimators are almost perfectly correlated across horizons under the null hypothesis of no predictability. For the persistence levels of dividend yields, the analytical correlation is 99% between the 1- and 2-year horizon estimators and 94% between the 1- and 5- ear horizons. Common sampling error across equations leads to ordinary least squares coefficient estimates and R(2)s that are roughly proportional to the horizon under the null hypothesis. This is the precise pattern found in the data. We perform joint tests across horizons for a variety of explanatory variables and provide an alternative view of the existing evidence.</description><author>Boudoukh, Jacob; Richardson, Matthew; Whitelaw, Robert F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reconciling the return predictability evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lettau, Martin; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn
Evidence of stock-return predictability by financial ratios is still controversial, as documented by inconsistent results for in-sample and out-of-sample regressions and by substantial parameter instability. This article shows that these seemingly incompatible results can be reconciled if the assumption of a fixed steady state mean of the economy is relaxed. We find strong empirical evidence in support of shifts in the steady state and propose simple methods to adjust financial ratios for such shifts. The in-sample forecasting relationship of adjusted price ratios and future returns is statistically significant and stable over time. In real time, however, changes in the steady state make the in-sample return forecastability hard to exploit out-of-sample. The uncertainty of estimating the size of steady-state shifts rather than the estimation of their dates is responsible for the difficulty of forecasting stock returns in real time. Our conclusions hold for a variety of financial ratios and are robust to changes in the econometric technique used to estimate shifts in the steady state.</description><author>Lettau, Martin; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The declining equity premium: What role does macroeconomic risk play?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lettau, Martin; Ludvigson, Sydney C.; Wachter, Jessica A.
Aggregate stock prices, relative to virtually any indicator of fundamental value, soared to unprecedented levels in the 1990s. Even today, after the market declines since 2000, they remain well above historical norms. Why? We consider one particular explanation: a fall in macroeconomic risk, or the volatility of the aggregate economy. Empirically, we find a strong correlation between low-frequency movements in macroeconomic volatility and low-frequency movements in the stock market. To model this phenomenon, we estimate a two-state regime switching model for the volatility and mean of consumption growth, and find evidence of a shift to substantially lower consumption volatility at the beginning of the 1990s. We then use these estimates from postwar data to calibrate a rational asset pricing model with regime switches in both the mean and standard deviation of consumption growth. Plausible parameterizations of the model are found to account for a significant portion of the run- up in asset valuation ratios observed in the late 1990s.</description><author>Lettau, Martin; Ludvigson, Sydney C.; Wachter, Jessica A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The causal effect of mortgage refinancing on interest rate volatility: Empirical evidence and theoretical implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duarte, Jefferson
This article investigates the effects of mortgage-backed security (MBS) hedging activity on interest rate volatility and proposes a model that takes these effects into account. An empirical examination suggests that the inclusion of information about MBSs considerably improves model performance in pricing interest rate options and in forecasting future interest rate volatility. The empirical results are consistent with the hypothesis that MBS hedging affects the interest rate volatility implied by both options and the actual interest rate volatility. The results also indicate that the inclusion of information about the MBS universe may result in models that better describe the price of fixed-income securities.</description><author>Duarte, Jefferson</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why leverage affects pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pichler, Pegaret; Stomper, Alex; Zulehner, Christine
We explain and provide evidence for effects of leverage on pricing. Our model identifies two effects that either counteract or reinforce each other, depending on the debt maturity structure: (i) firms set higher prices (underinvest in market share) if they have more debt, and (ii) firms engage in dynamic risk-shifting by setting lower (higher) prices if the current debt obligation will be higher (lower) in the next period than in the present period. Using a unique dataset of owner-managed hotels in Austrian ski resorts, we provide empirical evidence of both effects.</description><author>Pichler, Pegaret; Stomper, Alex; Zulehner, Christine</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interpreting the value effect through the Q-theory: An empirical investigation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xing, Yuhang
This article interprets the well-known value effect through the implications of standard Q-theory. An investment growth factor, defined as the difference in returns between low-investment stocks and high-investment stocks, contains information similar to the Fama and French (1993) value factor (HML), and can explain the value effect about as well as HML. In the cross-section, portfolios of firms with low investment growth rates (IGRs) or low investment-to-capital ratios have significantly higher average returns than those with high IGRs or high investment-to-capital ratios. The value effect largely disappears after controlling for investment, and the investment effect is robust against controls for the marginal product of capital. These results are consistent with the predictions of a standard Q-theory model with a stochastic discount factor.</description><author>Xing, Yuhang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of board control and size</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harris, Milton; Raviv, Artur
This article presents a model of optimal control of corporate boards of directors. We determine when one would expect inside versus outside directors to control the board, when the controlling party will delegate decision-making to the other party, the extent of communication between the parties, and the number of outside directors. We show that shareholders can sometimes be better off with an insider-controlled board. We derive endogenous relationships among profits, board control, and the number of outside directors that call into question the usual interpretation of some documented empirical regularities.</description><author>Harris, Milton; Raviv, Artur</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Good IPOs draw in bad: Inelastic banking capacity and hot markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khanna, Naveen; Noe, Thomas H.; Sonti, Ramana
We posit that screening IPOs requires specialized labor which is in fixed supply. A sudden increase in demand for IPO financing increases the compensation of IPO screening labor. This results in reduced screening, encouraging sub-marginal firms to enter the IPO market, further fueling the demand for screening labor. The model's conclusions are consistent with empirical findings of increased underpricing during hot markets, positive correlation between issue volume and underpricing, and with tipping points between hot and cold markets. Finally, the model makes sharp predictions relating the IPO market to fundamental values of firms and to investment banking returns.</description><author>Khanna, Naveen; Noe, Thomas H.; Sonti, Ramana</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spin-offs, divestitures, and conglomerate investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colak, Gonul; Whited, Toni M.
We examine whether spin-offs or divestitures cause improvements in conglomerate investment efficiency. At issue are endogeneity of these restructuring decisions and correct measurement of investment efficiency. Endogeneity is a problem because the factors that induce firms to spin off or divest divisions may also improve investment efficiency; measurement error is a problem because efficiency measures employ Tobin's q as a noisy proxy for investment opportunities. We find important differences between firms that divest or spin off and a control sample. After accounting for these differences and for measurement error in q, we find no evidence of improvements in investment efficiency.</description><author>Colak, Gonul; Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transactions accounts and loan monitoring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mester, Loretta J.; Nakamura, Leonard I.; Renault, Micheline
We show that transactions accounts, by providing ongoing data on borrowers' activities, help financial intermediaries monitor borrowers. This information is most readily available to commercial banks, which offer these accounts and lending together. We find that (1) monthly changes in accounts receivable are reflected in transactions accounts; (2) borrowings in excess of collateral predict credit downgrades and loan write-downs; and (3) the lender intensifies monitoring in response. This is evidence on a key issue in financial intermediation-there is an advantage to providing deposit-taking and lending jointly. But this advantage may have fallen as the cost of communication has declined.</description><author>Mester, Loretta J.; Nakamura, Leonard I.; Renault, Micheline</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tipping</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Irvine, Paul; Lipson, Marc; Puckett, Andy
We investigate the trading of institutions immediately before the release of analysts' initial buy recommendations. We document abnormally high institutional trading volume and buying beginning five days before recommendations are publicly released. Abnormal buying is related to initiation characteristics that would require knowledge of the content of the report-such as the identity of the analyst and brokerage firm, and whether the recommendation is a strong buy. We confirm that institutions buying before the recommendation release earn abnormal profits. Our results are consistent with institutional traders receiving tips regarding the contents of forthcoming analysts' reports.</description><author>Irvine, Paul; Lipson, Marc; Puckett, Andy</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The effect of private-debt-underwriting reputation on bank public-debt underwriting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Narayanan, Rajesh P.; Rangan, Kasturi P.; Rangan, Nanda K.
We provide evidence that commercial banks extend their reputation in underwriting syndicated loans and private placements (private debt) to their bond-underwriting activities. In the absence of bond market reputation, private-debt-market reputation enables commercial banks to win underwriting mandates from their loan clients. Furthermore, it allows them to credibly commit to investors against opportunistically using lending information and thereby deliver superior certification benefits in the form of higher issue prices relative to investment-bank underwriters. This pricing benefit is not offset by higher underwriting fees and thus results in lower total issuance costs for borrowers.</description><author>Narayanan, Rajesh P.; Rangan, Kasturi P.; Rangan, Nanda K.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Price informativeness and investment sensitivity to stock price</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Qi; Goldstein, Itay; Jiang, Wei
The article shows that two measures of the amount of private information in stock price-price nonsynchronicity and probability of informed trading (PIN)-have a strong positive effect on the sensitivity of corporate investment to stock price. Moreover, the effect is robust to the inclusion of controls for managerial information and for other information-related variables. The results suggest that firm managers learn from the private information in stock price about their own firms' fundamentals and incorporate this information in the corporate investment decisions. We relate our findings to an alternative explanation for the investment-to-price sensitivity, namely that it is generated by capital constraints, and show that both the learning channel and the alternative channel contribute to this sensitivity.</description><author>Chen, Qi; Goldstein, Itay; Jiang, Wei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock return predictability: Is it there?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Andrew; Bekaert, Geert
We examine the predictive power of the di backslash vidend yields for forecasting excess returns, cash flows, and interest rates. Dividend yields predict excess returns only at short horizons together with the short rate and do not have any long-horizon predictive power. At short horizons, the short rate strongly negatively predicts returns. These results are robust in international data and are not due to lack of power. A present value model that matches the data shows that discount rate and short rate movements play a large role in explaining the variation in dividend yields. Finally, we find that earnings yields significantly predict future cash flows.</description><author>Ang, Andrew; Bekaert, Geert</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk and return in fixed-income arbitrage: Nickels in front of a steamroller?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duarte, Jefferson; Longstaff, Francis A.; Yu, Fan
We conduct an analysis of the risk and return characteristics of a number of widely used fixed-income arbitrage strategies. We find that the strategies requiring more "intellectual capital" to implement tend to produce significant alphas after controlling for bond and equity market risk factors. These positive alphas remain significant even after taking into account typical hedge fund fees. In contrast with other hedge fund strategies, many of the fixed-income arbitrage strategies produce positively skewed returns. These results suggest that there may be more economic substance to fixed-income arbitrage than simply "picking up nickels in front of a steamroller."</description><author>Duarte, Jefferson; Longstaff, Francis A.; Yu, Fan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The cross-section of expected trading activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, Tarun; Huh, Sahn-Wook; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
This article studies cross-sectional variations in trading activity for a comprehensive sample of NYSE/AMEX and Nasdaq stocks over a period of about 40 years. We test whether trading activity depends upon the degree of liquidity trading, the mass of informed traders, and the extent of uncertainty and dispersion of opinion about fundamental values. We hypothesize that liquidity (or noise) trading depends both on a stock's visibility and on portfolio rebalancing needs triggered by past price performance. We use firm size, age, price, and the book-to-market ratio as proxies for a firm's visibility. The mass of informed agents is proxied by the number of analysts whereas forecast dispersion and firm leverage proxy for differences of opinion. Earning volatility and absolute earning surprises proxy for uncertainty about fundamental values. Overall, the results provide support for theories of trading based on stock visibility, portfolio rebalancing needs, differences of opinion, and uncertainty about fundamental values.</description><author>Chordia, Tarun; Huh, Sahn-Wook; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information diffusion effects in individual investors' common stock purchases: Covet thy neighbors' investment choices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ivkovic, Zoran; Weisbenner, Scott
We study the relation between households' stock purchases and stock purchases made by their neighbors. A ten percentage point increase in neighbors' purchases of stocks from an industry is associated with a two percentage point increase in households' own purchases of stocks from that industry. The effect is considerably larger for local stocks and among households in more social states. Controlling for area sociability, households' and neighbors' investment style preferences, and the industry composition of local firms, we attribute approximately one-quarter to one-half of the correlation between households' stock purchases and stock purchases made by their neighbors to word-of-mouth communication.</description><author>Ivkovic, Zoran; Weisbenner, Scott</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International evidence on cash holdings and expected managerial agency problems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kalcheva, Ivalina; Lins, Karl V.
This article uses managerial control rights data for over 5000 firms from 31 countries to examine the net costs and benefits of cash holdings. We find that when external country-level shareholder protection is weak, firm values are lower when controlling managers hold more cash. Further, when external shareholder protection is weak we find that firm values are higher when controlling managers pay dividends. Only when external shareholder protection is strong do we find that cash held by controlling managers is unrelated to firm value, consistent with generally prevailing U.S. and international evidence.</description><author>Kalcheva, Ivalina; Lins, Karl V.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal equity stakes and corporate control</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mathews, Richmond D.
I show that firms may optimally sell blocks of their own equity to other firms in anticipation of future corporate control activity. In the model, a target and one potential acquirer, who may also be an alliance partner, can negotiate before synergy values are learned. I find that equity implements an optimal mechanism, allowing the partners to extract surplus from outside bidders who may arrive later. The stake is limited by the outsiders' willingness to investigate. The results imply that corporate control may motivate an equity sale even when no takeover activity is apparent at the time or occurs ex post.</description><author>Mathews, Richmond D.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why does implied risk aversion smile?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ziegler, Alexandre
Implied risk aversion estimates reported in the literature are strongly U-shaped. This article explores different potential explanations for these "smile" patterns: (i) preference aggregation, both with and without stochastic volatility and jumps in returns, (ii) misestimation of investors' beliefs caused by stochastic volatility, jumps, or a Peso problem, and (iii) heterogeneous beliefs. The results reveal that preference aggregation and misestimation of investors' beliefs caused by stochastic volatility and jumps are unlikely to be the explanation for the smile. Although a Peso problem can account for the smile, the required probability of a market crash is unrealistically large. Heterogeneous beliefs cause sizable distortions in implied risk aversion, but the degree of heterogeneity required to explain the smile is implausibly large.</description><author>Ziegler, Alexandre</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry information diffusion and the lead-lag effect in stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hou, Kewei
I argue that the slow diffusion of industry information is a leading cause of the lead-lag effect in stock returns. I find that the lead-lag effect between big firms and small firms is predominantly an intra-industry phenomenon. Moreover, this effect is driven by sluggish adjustment to negative information, and is robust to alternative determinants of the lead-lag effect. Small, less competitive and neglected industries experience a more pronounced lead-lag effect. The lead-lag effect is related to the post-announcement drift of small firms following the earnings releases of big firms within the industry.</description><author>Hou, Kewei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset prices and exchange rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pavlova, Anna; Rigobon, Roberto
We study the implications of introducing demand shocks and trade in goods into an otherwise standard international asset pricing model. Trade in goods gives rise to an additional channel of international propagation-through the terms of trade-absent in traditional single-good models. The inclusion of demand shocks helps overturn many unrealistic implications of existing international finance models in which productivity shocks are the sole source of uncertainty. Our model generates a rich set of implications on how stock, bond, and foreign exchange markets co-move. We solve the model in closed-form, which yields a system of equations that can be readily estimated empirically. Our estimation validates the main predictions of the theory.</description><author>Pavlova, Anna; Rigobon, Roberto</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Walrasian tatonnement auctions on the Tokyo Grain Exchange</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eaves, James; Williams, Jeffrey
The Tokyo Grain Exchange (TGE)'s itayose mechanism provides the opportunity to analyze functioning Walrasian tatonnement auctions (WTA). In 15,677 auctions conducted over 1997-1998 for corn and redbean futures contracts, price formation is unexpectedly similar to that observed in continuous double auctions. Provisional prices and pledges are informative. In contrast to behavior observed in experiments, few pledges are deceptive, because the traders participate repeatedly and because the auctioneer has flexibility when changing the provisional price and ending the auction. Both the risk of the auction ending and the more equitable dispersion of information increase depth and the speed at which information is embodied in price.</description><author>Eaves, James; Williams, Jeffrey</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Booms, busts, and fraud</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Povel, Paul; Singh, Rajdeep; Winton, Andrew
Firms sometimes commit fraud by altering publicly reported information to be more favorable, and investors can monitor firms to obtain more accurate information. We study equilibrium fraud and monitoring decisions. Fraud is most likely to occur in relatively good times, and the link between fraud and good times becomes stronger as monitoring costs decrease. Nevertheless, improving business conditions may sometimes diminish fraud. We provide an explanation for why fraud peaks towards the end of a boom and is then revealed in the ensuing bust. We also show that fraud can increase if firms make more information available to the public.</description><author>Povel, Paul; Singh, Rajdeep; Winton, Andrew</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium underdiversification and the preference for skewness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mitton, Todd; Vorkink, Keith
We develop a one-period model of investor asset holdings where investors have heterogeneous preference for skewness. Introducing heterogeneous preference for skewness allows the model's investors, in equilibrium, to underdiversify. We find support for our model's three key implications using a dataset of 60,000 individual investor accounts. First, we document that the portfolio returns of underdiversified investors are substantially more positively skewed than those of diversified investors. Second, we show that the apparent mean-variance inefficiency of underdiversified investors can be largely explained by the fact that investors sacrifice mean-variance efficiency for higher skewness exposure. Furthermore, we show that idiosyncratic skewness, and not just coskewness, can impact equilibrium prices. Third, the underdiversification of investors does not appear to be coincidentally related to skewness. Stocks most often selected by underdiversified investors have substantially higher average skewness-especially idiosyncratic skewness-than stocks most often selected by diversified investors.</description><author>Mitton, Todd; Vorkink, Keith</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing a portfolio of projects</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Inderst, Roman; Mueller, Holger M.; Munnich, Felix
This article shows that investors financing a portfolio of projects may use the depth of their financial pockets to overcome entrepreneurial incentive problems. Competition for scarce informed capital at the refinancing stage strengthens investors' bargaining positions. And yet, entrepreneurs' incentives may be improved, because projects funded by investors with "shallow pockets" must have not only a positive net present value at the refinancing stage, but one that is higher than that of competing portfolio projects. Our article may help understand provisions used in venture capital finance that limit a fund's initial capital and make it difficult to add more capital once the initial venture capital fund is raised.</description><author>Inderst, Roman; Mueller, Holger M.; Munnich, Felix</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option market activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lakonishok, Josef; Lee, Inmoo; Pearson, Neil D.; Poteshman, Allen M.
This article uses a unique option data set to provide detailed descriptive statistics on the purchased and written open interest and open buy and sell volume of several classes of investors. We also show that volatility trading through straddles and strangles accounts for a small fraction of option trading volume and presents evidence that a large percentage of call writing is part of covered call positions. Finally, we find that during the stock market bubble of the late 1990s and early 2000 the least sophisticated investors in the data set substantially increased their purchases of calls on growth but not value stocks.</description><author>Lakonishok, Josef; Lee, Inmoo; Pearson, Neil D.; Poteshman, Allen M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do investors trade more when stocks have performed well? Evidence from</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, John M.; Nardari, Federico; Stulz, Rene M.
This article investigates the dynamic relation between market-wide trading activity and returns in 46 markets. Many stock markets exhibit a strong positive relation between turnover and past returns. These findings stand up in the face of various controls for volatility, alternative definitions of turnover, differing sample periods, and are present at both the weekly and daily frequency. The relation is more statistically and economically significant in countries with high levels of corruption, with short-sale restrictions, and in which market volatility is high.</description><author>Griffin, John M.; Nardari, Federico; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transparency and liquidity: A controlled experiment on corporate bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldstein, Michael A.; Hotchkiss, Edith S.; Sirri, Erik R.
This article reports the results of an experiment designed to assess the impact of last-sale trade reporting on the liquidity of BBB corporate bonds. Overall, adding transparency has either a neutral or a positive effect on liquidity. Increased transparency is not associated with greater trading volume. Except for very large trades, spreads on newly transparent bonds decline relative to bonds that experience no transparency change. However, we find no effect on spreads for very infrequently traded bonds. The observed decrease in transaction costs is consistent with investors' ability to negotiate better terms of trade once they have access to broader bond-pricing data.</description><author>Goldstein, Michael A.; Hotchkiss, Edith S.; Sirri, Erik R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial intermediation and the costs of trading in an opaque market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Green, Richard C.; Hollifield, Burton; Schuerhoff, Norman
Municipal bonds trade in opaque, decentralized broker-dealer markets in which price information is costly to gather. We analyze a database of trades between broker-dealers and customers in municipal bonds. These data were only released to the public with a lag; the market was opaque. Dealers earn lower average markups on larger trades, even though dealers bear a higher risk of losses with larger trades. We estimate a bargaining model and compute measures of dealer's bargaining power. Dealers exercise substantial market power. Our measures of market power decrease in trade size and increase in the complexity of the trade for the dealer.</description><author>Green, Richard C.; Hollifield, Burton; Schuerhoff, Norman</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public disclosure and private decisions: Equity market execution quality and order routing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Jennings, Robert; Wei, Li
In 2001, the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) required market centers to publish monthly execution-quality reports in an effort to spur competition for order flow between markets. Using samples of stocks trading on several markets, we investigate whether past execution quality affects order-routing decisions and whether the new disclosure requirements influence this relationship. We find that routing decisions are associated with execution quality; markets reporting low execution costs and fast fills subsequently receive more orders. Moreover, the reports themselves appear to provide information that was 2unavailable previously. Our results are consistent with active competition for order flow that can be influenced by public disclosure.</description><author>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Jennings, Robert; Wei, Li</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Options and bubbles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heston, Steven L.; Loewenstein, Mark; Willard, Gregory A.
The Black-Scholes-Merton option valuation method involves deriving and solving a partial differential equation (PDE). But this method can generate multiple values for an option. We provide new solutions for the Cox-Ingersoll-Ross (CIR) term structure model, the constant elasticity of variance (CEV) model, and the Heston stochastic volatility model. Multiple solutions reflect asset pricing bubbles, dominated investments, and (possibly infeasible) arbitrages. We provide conditions to rule out bubbles on underlying prices. If they are not satisfied, put-call parity might not hold, American calls have no optimal exercise policy, and lookback calls have infinite value. We clarify a longstanding conjecture of Cox, Ingersoll, and Ross.</description><author>Heston, Steven L.; Loewenstein, Mark; Willard, Gregory A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Imperfect competition, information heterogeneity, and financial contagion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pasquariello, Paolo
This study examines how heterogeneity of private information may induce financial contagion. Using a model of multi-asset trading in which the three main channels of contagion through financial linkages in the literature (correlated information, correlated liquidity, and portfolio rebalancing) are ruled out by construction, I show that financial contagion can still be an equilibrium outcome when speculators receive heterogeneous fundamental information. Risk-neutral speculators trade strategically across many assets to mask their information advantage about one asset. Asymmetric sharing of information among them prevents rational market makers from learning about their individual signals and trades with sufficient accuracy. Incorrect cross-inference about terminal payoffs and contagion ensue. When used to analyze the transmission of shocks across countries, my model suggests that the process of generation and disclosure of information in emerging markets may explain their vulnerability to financial contagion (JEL D82, G14, G15).</description><author>Pasquariello, Paolo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Approximation and calibration of short-term implied volatilities under jump-diffusion stochastic volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Medvedev, Alexey; Scaillet, Olivier
We derive an asymptotic expansion formula for option implied volatility under a two-factor jump-diffusion stochastic volatility model when time-to-maturity is small. We further propose a simple calibration procedure of an arbitrary parametric model to short-term near-the-money implied volatilities. An important advantage of our approximation is that it is free of the unobserved spot volatility. Therefore, the model can be calibrated on option data pooled across different calendar dates to extract information from the dynamics of the implied volatility smile. An example of calibration to a sample of S&amp;P 500 option prices is provided.</description><author>Medvedev, Alexey; Scaillet, Olivier</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do termination provisions truncate the takeover bidding process?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boone, Audra L.; Mulherin, J. Harold
We provide new evidence on termination provisions and the takeover bidding process. Our central contribution is a novel database from Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) documents that accurately measures the incidence of termination provisions and the depth of competition in takeover deals. We show that biased data in prior research produced incorrect conclusions on the relation between termination provisions and judicial decisions, bidder toeholds, and deal size. Our comprehensive data also show that termination provisions are positively related to takeover competition. Our evidence is consistent with the information/commitment hypothesis in which termination provisions do not truncate bidding but instead culminate the takeover process.</description><author>Boone, Audra L.; Mulherin, J. Harold</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade credit: Suppliers as debt collectors and insurance providers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cunat, Vicente
This article examines how in a context of limited enforceability of contracts suppliers may have a comparative advantage over banks in lending to customers because they are able to stop the supply of intermediate goods. Suppliers may act also as liquidity providers, insuring against liquidity shocks that could endanger the survival of their customer relationships. The relatively high implicit interest rates of trade credit are the result of insurance and default premiums that are amplified whenever suppliers face a relatively high cost of funds. I explore these effects empirically for a panel of UK firms.</description><author>Cunat, Vicente</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio selection in stochastic environments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Jun
In this article, I explicitly solve dynamic portfolio choice problems, up to the solution of an ordinary differential equation (ODE), when the asset returns are quadratic and the agent has a constant relative risk aversion (CRRA) coefficient. My solution includes as special cases many existing explicit solutions of dynamic portfolio choice problems. I also present three applications that are not in the literature. Application 1 is the bond portfolio selection problem when bond returns are described by "quadratic term structure models." Application 2 is the stock portfolio selection problem when stock return volatility is stochastic as in Heston model. Application 3 is a bond and stock portfolio selection problem when the interest rate is stochastic and stock returns display stochastic volatility. (JEL G11)</description><author>Liu, Jun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio selection with parameter and model uncertainty: A multi-prior approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garlappi, Lorenzo; Uppal, Raman; Wang, Tan
We develop a model for an investor with multiple priors and aversion to ambiguity. We characterize the multiple priors by a "confidence interval" around the estimated expected returns and we model ambiguity aversion via a minimization over the priors. Our model has several attractive features: (1) it has a solid axiomatic foundation; (2) it is flexible enough to allow for different degrees of uncertainty about expected returns for various subsets of assets and also about the return-generating model; and (3) it delivers closed-form expressions for the optimal portfolio. Our empirical analysis suggests that, compared with portfolios from classical and Bayesian models, ambiguity-averse portfolios are more stable over time and deliver a higher out-of sample Sharpe ratio. (JEL G11)</description><author>Garlappi, Lorenzo; Uppal, Raman; Wang, Tan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Life-cycle portfolio choice with additive habit formation preferences and uninsurable labor income risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Polkovnichenko, Valery
This article explores the implications of additive and endogenous habit formation preferences in the context of a life-cycle model of an investor who has stochastic uninsurable labor income. To solve the model, I analytically derive the habit-wealth feasibility constraints and show that they depend on the worst possible path of future labor income and on the habit strength, but not on the probability of the worst income. When there is only a slim chance of a severe income shock, the model implies much more conservative portfolios. The model also predicts that for some low to moderately wealthy households, the portfolio share allocated to stocks increases with wealth. Because of this feature, the model can generate more conservative portfolios for younger than for middle-aged households. The effects of habits on portfolio choice are robust to income smoothing through borrowing or flexible labor supply. One controversial finding is that for high values of the habit strength parameter, usually required for the resolution of asset pricing puzzles in general equilibrium, the life-cycle model predicts counterfactually high wealth accumulation. (JEL: G11, G12)</description><author>Polkovnichenko, Valery</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A theory of IPO waves</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Ping
In the IPO market, investors coordinate on acceptable IPO price based on the performance of past IPOs, and this generates an incentive for investment banks to produce information about IPO firms. In hot periods, the information produced by investment banks improves the quality of IPO firms, and this allows ex ante low quality firms to go public and increases the secondary market price, thus synchronizing high IPO volumes and high first day returns. When investment banks behave asymmetrically in information production, the "reputations" of investment banks are interpreted as a form of market segmentation to economize on the social cost of information production.</description><author>He, Ping</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does motivation matter when assessing trade performance? An analysis of mutual funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alexander, Gordon J.; Cici, Gjergji; Gibson, Scott
We relate the performance of mutual fund trades to their motivation. A fund manager who buys stocks when there are heavy investor outflows is likely to be motivated by the belief that the stocks are significantly undervalued. In contrast, when there are heavy inflows, the manager is likely to be motivated to work off excess liquidity by buying stocks. Our analysis reveals that managers making purely valuation-motivated purchases substantially beat the market but are unable to do so when compelled to invest excess cash from investor inflows. A similar, but weaker, pattern is found for stocks that are sold. (JEL G11, G29)</description><author>Alexander, Gordon J.; Cici, Gjergji; Gibson, Scott</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Good stewards, cheap talkers, or family men? The impact of mutual fund closures on fund managers, flows, fees, and performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bris, Arturo; Gulen, Huseyin; Kadiyala, Padma; Rau, P. Raghavendra
We examine a sample of 125 equity mutual funds that closed to new investment between 1993 and 2004. We find that funds close following a period of superior performance and abnormal fund inflows. Fund managers raise their fees when they close to compensate managers for losses in income due to the restrictions in size imposed by the fund closure decision. Managers reopen when fund size declines. However, they do not earn superior returns after reopening, suggesting that the fund closure decision does not provide information about superior fund managers.</description><author>Bris, Arturo; Gulen, Huseyin; Kadiyala, Padma; Rau, P. Raghavendra</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyst hype in IPOs: Explaining the popularity of bookbuilding</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Degeorge, Francois; Derrien, Francois; Womack, Kent L.
The bookbuilding IPO procedure has captured significant market share from auction alternatives recently, despite the significantly lower costs related to the auction mechanism. In France, where both mechanisms were used in the 1990s, the ostensible advantages of bookbuilding were advertising-related benefits. Book-built issues were more likely to be followed and positively recommended by lead underwriters. Even nonunderwriters' analysts promote book-built issues more in order to curry favor with the IPO underwriter for allocations of future deals. Yet we do not observe valuation or post-IPO return differentials that suggest these types of promotion have any value to the issuing firm.</description><author>Degeorge, Francois; Derrien, Francois; Womack, Kent L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public disclosure and private decisions - Equity merket execution quality and order routing (vol 20, pg 315, 2007)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boehmer, E.
nan</description><author>Boehmer, E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Turning over turnover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Mei, Jianping
This article applies the methodology of Bai and Ng (2002, 2004) for decomposing panel data into systematic and idiosyncratic components to both stock returns and turnover panels. This approach works well for both returns and turnover, despite the presence of severe heteroscedasticity and nonstationarity of individual stocks turnover. We test the mutual fund separation model of Lo and Wang (2000). Trading due to systematic risk in returns can account for 66% of systematic turnover. Thus, portfolio rebalancing due to systematic risk is a very important motive for stock trading. Finally, several common turnover measures may understate the impact of stock trading.</description><author>Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Mei, Jianping</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and expected returns: Lessons from emerging markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekaert, Geert; Harvey, Campbell R.; Lundblad, Christian
Given the cross-sectional and temporal variation in their liquidity, emerging equity markets provide an ideal setting to examine the impact of liquidity on expected returns. Our main liquidity measure is a transformation of the proportion of zero daily firm returns, averaged over the month. We find that it significantly predicts future returns, whereas alternative measures such as turnover do not. Consistent with liquidity being a priced factor, unexpected liquidity shocks are positively correlated with contemporaneous return shocks and negatively correlated with shocks to the dividend yield. We consider a simple asset-pricing model with liquidity and the market portfolio as risk factors and transaction costs that are proportional to liquidity. The model differentiates between integrated and segmented countries and time periods. Our results suggest that local market liquidity is an important driver of expected returns in emerging markets, and that the liberalization process has not fully eliminated its impact.</description><author>Bekaert, Geert; Harvey, Campbell R.; Lundblad, Christian</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Insider trades and private information: The special case of delayed-disclosure trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheng, Shijun; Nagar, Venky; Rajan, Madhav V.
In certain circumstances, insider trades such as private transactions between executives and their firms could be disclosed after the end of the firms fiscal year, on a Form-5 filing. We find that insider sales disclosed in such a delayed manner for large firms are predictive of negative future returns (6 to 8 percent), as well as lower future annual earnings relative to analyst forecasts. These results stand in contrast to existing findings on the uninformativeness of quickly disclosed open-market insider sales. The Sarbanes-Oxley Act curtailed the use of Form 5 under the presumption that managers used this vehicle opportunistically. Our systematic evidence supports this presumption.</description><author>Cheng, Shijun; Nagar, Venky; Rajan, Madhav V.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does anonymity matter in electronic limit order markets?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foucault, Thierry; Moinas, Sophie; Theissen, Erik
We develop a model in which limit order traders possess volatility information. We show that in this case the size of the bid-ask spread is informative about future volatility. Moreover, if volatility information is in part private, we establish that (i) the size of the bid-ask spread and (ii) its informativeness about future volatility should change in the same direction when limit order traders' identifiers stop being disclosed. We test these predictions using data from the Paris Bourse. As expected, we find that the average quoted spread and its informativeness are significantly smaller when limit order traders' identifiers are concealed. These findings suggest that the limit order book is a channel for volatility information.</description><author>Foucault, Thierry; Moinas, Sophie; Theissen, Erik</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The role of knowhow acquisition in the formation and duration of joint ventures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Habib, Michel A.; Mella-Barral, Pierre
We analyze the role of knowhow acquisition in the formation and duration of joint ventures. Two parties become partners in a joint venture to benefit from each other's knowhow. Joint operations provide each party with the opportunity to acquire part of its partner's knowhow. A party's increased knowhow provides the impetus for the dissolution of the joint venture. We characterize the conditions under which dissolution takes place, identify the party that buys out its partner, determine the time to dissolution, establish its comparative statics, and examine the implications of knowledge acquisition for the desirability of joint venture formation. (JEL code: G34)</description><author>Habib, Michel A.; Mella-Barral, Pierre</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation in over-the-counter markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duffie, Darrell; Garleanu, Nicolae; Pedersen, Lasse Heje
We provide the impact on asset prices of search-and-bargaining frictions in over-the-counter markets. Under certain conditions, illiquidity discounts are higher when counterparties are harder to find, when sellers have less bargaining power, when the fraction of qualified owners is smaller, or when risk aversion, volatility, or hedging demand is larger. Supply shocks cause prices to jump, and then recover over time, with a time signature that is exaggerated by search frictions: The price jump is larger and the recovery is slower in less liquid markets. We discuss a variety of empirical implications.</description><author>Duffie, Darrell; Garleanu, Nicolae; Pedersen, Lasse Heje</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic cost of diversification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lyandres, Evgeny
This article proposes a new explanation for the large cross-sectional variation in the excess values of diversified firms. The model applies the idea of shareholders limited liability affecting firms output market strategies to the analysis of financial and operating choices of conglomerates. The inability of conglomerates to commit to unconstrained optimal operating strategies, following from the lack of flexibility in choosing their divisions capital structures, reduces their value. Thus, the model highlights a new type of inefficiency of the conglomerate organizational structure, which is suboptimal financing. The predictions of the model are generally supported by the data.</description><author>Lyandres, Evgeny</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The real effects of asset market bubbles: Loan- and firm-level evidence of a lending channel</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gan, Jie
This article studies how a shock to the financial health of banks, caused by a decline in the asset markets, affects the real economy. The land market collapse in Japan provides an ideal testing field in separating the impact of a loan supply shock from demand shocks. I find that banks with greater real estate exposure have to reduce lending. Firms investment and market valuation are negatively associated with their top lenders real estate exposure. The lending channel is economically important: it accounts for one-third of lending contraction, one-fifth of the decline in investment, and a quarter of value loss.</description><author>Gan, Jie</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed and strategic order flow in the bond markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pasquariello, Paolo; Vega, Clara
We study the role played by private and public information in the process of price formation in the U.S. Treasury bond market. To guide our analysis, we develop a parsimonious model of speculative trading in the presence of two realistic market frictions - information heterogeneity and imperfect competition among informed traders - and a public signal. We test its equilibrium implications by analyzing the response of two-year, five-year, and ten-year U.S. bond yields to order flow and real-time U.S. macroeconomic news. We find strong evidence of informational effects in the U.S. Treasury bond market: unanticipated order flow has a significant and permanent impact on daily bond yield changes during both announcement and nonannouncement days. Our analysis further shows that, consistent with our stylized model, the contemporaneous correlation between order flow and yield changes is higher when the dispersion of beliefs among market participants is high and public announcements are noisy.</description><author>Pasquariello, Paolo; Vega, Clara</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Governance mechanisms and bond prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Nair, Vinay B.; Wei, Chenyang
We investigate the effects of shareholder governance mechanisms on bondholders and document two new findings. First, the impact of shareholder control (proxied by large institutional blockholders) on credit risk depends on takeover vulnerability. Shareholder control is associated with higher (lower) yields if the firm is exposed to (protected from) takeovers. In the presence of shareholder control, the difference in bond yields due to differences in takeover vulnerability can be as high as 66 basis points. Second, event risk covenants reduce the credit risk associated with strong shareholder governance. Therefore, without bond covenants, shareholder governance, and bondholder interests diverge.</description><author>Cremers, K. J. Martijn; Nair, Vinay B.; Wei, Chenyang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can the trade-off theory explain debt structure?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hackbarth, Dirk; Hennessy, Christopher A.; Leland, Hayne E.
We examine the optimal mixture and priority structure of bank and market debt using a trade-off model in which banks have the unique ability to renegotiate outside formal bankruptcy. Flexible bank debt offers a superior trade-off between tax shields and bankruptcy costs. Ease of renegotiation limits bank debt capacity, however. Optimal debt structure hinges upon which party has bargaining power in private workouts. Weak firms have high bank debt capacity and utilize bank debt exclusively. Strong firms lever up to their (lower) bank debt capacity, augment with market debt, and place the bank senior. Therefore, the trade-off theory offers an explanation for: (i) why young/small firms use bank debt exclusively; (ii) why large/mature firms employ mixed debt financing; and (iii) why bank debt is senior. The trade-off theory also generates predictions consistent with international evidence. In countries in which the bankruptcy regime entails soft (tough) enforcement of contractual priority, bank debt capacity is low (high), implying greater (less) reliance on market debt.</description><author>Hackbarth, Dirk; Hennessy, Christopher A.; Leland, Hayne E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial constraints, asset tangibility, and corporate investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Almeida, Heitor; Campello, Murillo
Pledgeable assets support more borrowing, which allows for further investment in pledgeable assets. We use this credit multiplier to identify the impact of financing frictions on corporate investment. The multiplier suggests that investment-cash flow sensitivities should be increasing in the tangibility of firms' assets (a proxy for pledgeability), but only if firms are financially constrained. Our empirical results confirm this theoretical prediction. Our approach is not subject to the Kaplan and Zingales (1997) critique, and sidesteps problems stemming from unobservable variation in investment opportunities. Thus, our results strongly suggest that financing frictions affect investment decisions.</description><author>Almeida, Heitor; Campello, Murillo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An equilibrium model of investment under uncertainty</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Novy-Marx, Robert
We analyze the optimal investment decisions of heterogeneous firms in a competitive, uncertain environment, characterizing firms' investment strategies explicitly and deriving closed-form solutions for firm value. Real option premia remain significant, and are even unmitigated relative to the standard partial-equilibrium model when both are calibrated to observables. Firms consequently delay investment, choosing not to undertake some positive NPV projects. We compare competitive behavior to that of a strategic monopolist, and quantify the welfare loss associated with monopoly. Finally, the model predicts business cycle dependence on firm returns, with returns negatively skewed during industry expansions but positively skewed in industry recessions.</description><author>Novy-Marx, Robert</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio performance manipulation and manipulation-proof performance measures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ingersoll, Jonathan; Spiegel, Matthew; Goetzmann, William; Welch, Ivo
Numerous measures have been proposed to gauge the performance of active management. Unfortunately, these measures can be gamed. Our article shows that gaming can have a substantial impact on popular measures even in the presence of high transactions costs. Our article shows there are conditions under which a manipulation-proof measure exists and fully characterizes it. This measure looks like the average of a power utility function, calculated over the return history. The case for using our alternative ranking metric is particularly compelling for hedge funds whose use of derivatives is unconstrained and whose managers' compensation itself induces a nonlinear payoff.</description><author>Ingersoll, Jonathan; Spiegel, Matthew; Goetzmann, William; Welch, Ivo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetries in stock returns: Statistical tests and economic evaluation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Yongmiao; Tu, Jun; Zhou, Guofu
We provide a model-free test for asymmetric correlations in which stocks move more often with the market when the market goes down than when it goes up, and also provide such tests for asymmetric betas and covariances. When stocks are sorted by size, book-to-market, and momentum, we find strong evidence of asymmetries for both size and momentum portfolios, but no evidence for book-to-market portfolios. Moreover, we evaluate the economic significance of incorporating asymmetries into investment decisions, and find that they can be of substantial economic importance for an investor with a disappointment aversion (DA) preference as described by Ang, Bekaert, and Liu (2005).</description><author>Hong, Yongmiao; Tu, Jun; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal asset allocation and risk shifting in money management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basak, Suleyman; Pavlova, Anna; Shapiro, Alexander
This article investigates a fund manager's risk-taking incentives induced by an increasing and convex relationship of fund flows to relative performance. In a dynamic portfolio choice framework, we show that the ensuing convexities in the manager's objective give rise to a finite risk-shifting range over which she gambles to finish ahead of her benchmark. Such gambling entails either an increase or a decrease in the volatility of the manager's portfolio, depending on her risk tolerance. In the latter case, the manager reduces her holdings of the risky asset despite its positive risk premium. Our empirical analysis lends support to the novel predictions of the model.</description><author>Basak, Suleyman; Pavlova, Anna; Shapiro, Alexander</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The forgone gains of incomplete portfolios</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Paiella, Monica
This article proposes a test for the cost-based explanation of nonparticipation, by estimating a lower bound to the forgone gains of incomplete portfolios; these are in turn a lower bound to the costs that could rationalize nonparticipation in financial markets: high bounds would imply implausibly high costs. Assuming isoelastic utility and a relative risk aversion of three or less, for the stock market I estimate an average lower bound of between 0.7 and 3.3 percent of consumption. Since total annual (observable plus unobservable) participation costs are likely to exceed these bounds, the cost-based explanation is not rejected by this test.</description><author>Paiella, Monica</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When does extra risk strictly increase an option's value?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rasmusen, Eric
It is well known that risk increases the value of options. This article makes that precise in a new way. The conventional theorem says that the value of an option does not fall if the underlying asset becomes riskier in the conventional sense of the mean-preserving spread. This article uses two new definitions of "riskier" to show that the value of an option strictly increases (i) if the underlying asset becomes "pointwise riskier," and (ii) only if the underlying asset becomes "extremum riskier."</description><author>Rasmusen, Eric</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regime shifts in a dynamic term structure model of US Treasury bond yields</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dai, Qiang; Singleton, Kenneth J.; Yang, Wei
This article develops and empirically implements an arbitrage-free, dynamic term structure model with "priced" factor and regime-shift risks. The risk factors are assumed to follow a discrete-time Gaussian process, and regime shifts are governed by a discrete-time Markov process with state-dependent transition probabilities. This model gives closed-form solutions for zero-coupon bond prices, an analytic representation of the likelihood function for bond yields, and a natural decomposition of expected excess returns to components corresponding to regime-shift and factor risks. Using monthly data on U.S. Treasury zero-coupon bond yields, we show a critical role of priced, state-dependent regime-shift risks in capturing the time variations in expected excess returns, and document notable differences in the behaviors of the factor risk component of the expected returns across high and low volatility regimes. Additionally, the state dependence of the regime-switching probabilities is shown to capture an interesting asymmetry in the cyclical behavior of interest rates. The shapes of the term structure of volatility of bond yield changes are also very different across regimes, with the well-known hump being largely a low-volatility regime phenomenon.</description><author>Dai, Qiang; Singleton, Kenneth J.; Yang, Wei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Underpricing in the corporate bond market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cai, Nianyun Kelly; Helwege, Jean; Warga, Arthur
This article examines underpricing of initial public offerings (IPOs) and seasoned offerings in the corporate bond market. We investigate whether underpricing represents a solution to an information problem or a liquidity problem. We find that underpricing occurs with both IPOs and seasoned offerings and is highest among riskier, unknown firms. Our evidence suggests that information problems drive underpricing, with support for both the bookbuilding view of underpricing and the asymmetric information theory. We do not find evidence in favor of the Rock model of underpricing or any evidence that illiquidity causes underpricing.</description><author>Cai, Nianyun Kelly; Helwege, Jean; Warga, Arthur</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How do diversity of opinion and information asymmetry affect acquirer returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Moeller, Sara B.; Schlingemann, Frederik P.; Stulz, Rene M.
We examine the theoretical predictions that link acquirer returns to diversity of opinion and information asymmetry. Theory suggests that acquirer abnormal returns should be negatively related to information asymmetry and diversity-of-opinion proxies for equity offers but not cash offers. We find that this is the case and that, more strikingly, there is no difference in abnormal returns between cash offers for public firms, equity offers for public firms, and equity offers for private firms after controlling for one of these proxies, idiosyncratic volatility.</description><author>Moeller, Sara B.; Schlingemann, Frederik P.; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal long-term financial contracting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeMarzo, Peter M.; Fishman, Michael J.
We develop an agency model of financial contracting. We derive long-term debt, a line of credit, and equity as optimal securities, capturing the debt coupon and maturity; the interest rate and limits on the credit line; inside versus outside equity; dividend policy; and capital structure dynamics. The optimal debt-equity ratio is history dependent, but debt and credit line terms are independent of the amount financed and, in some cases, the severity of the agency problem. In our model, the agent can divert cash flows; we also consider settings in which the agent undertakes hidden effort, or can control cash flow risk.</description><author>DeMarzo, Peter M.; Fishman, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relationship banking, fragility, and the asset-liability matching problem</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Song, Fenghua; Thakor, Anjan V.
We address a fundamental question in relationship banking: why do banks that make relationship loans finance themselves primarily with core deposits and when would it be optimal to finance such loans with purchased money? We show that not only are relationship loans informationally opaque and illiquid, but they also require the relationship between the bank and the borrower to endure in order for the bank to add value. However, the informational opacity of relationship loans gives rise to endogenous withdrawal risk that makes the bank fragile. Core deposits are an attractive funding source for such loans because the bank provides liquidity services to core depositors and this diminishes the likelihood of premature deposit withdrawal, thereby facilitating the continuity of relationship loans. That is, we show that banks will wish to match the highest value-added liabilities with the highest value-added loans and that doing so simultaneously minimizes the banks fragility owing to withdrawal risk and maximizes the value the bank adds in relationship lending. We also examine the impact of interbank competition on the banks asset-liability matching and extract numerous testable predictions.</description><author>Song, Fenghua; Thakor, Anjan V.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency and optimal investment dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeMarzo, Peter M.; Fishman, Michael J.
Agency problems limit firms' access to capital markets, curbing investment. Firms and investors seek contractual ways to mitigate these problems. What are the implications for investment? We present a theory of a firm's investment dynamics in the presence of agency problems and optimal long-term financial contracts. We derive results relating firms' investment decisions, current and past cash flows, firm size, capital structure, and dividends. Among the results, optimal investment is increasing in current and past cash flow; and optimal investment is positively serially correlated over time (after controlling for investment opportunities). These results hold for a range of agency problems. (JEL G30, G31, G32, G35, D82, D86, D92)</description><author>DeMarzo, Peter M.; Fishman, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumer confidence and asset prices: Some empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lemmon, Michael; Portniaguina, Evgenia
We explore the time-series relationship between investor sentiment and the small-stock premium using consumer confidence as a measure of investor optimism. We estimate the components of consumer confidence related to economic fundamentals and investor sentiment. After controlling for the time variation of beta, we study the time-series variation of the pricing error with sentiment. Over the last 25 years, investor sentiment measured using consumer confidence forecasts the returns of small stocks and stocks with low institutional ownership in a manner consistent with the predictions of models based on noise-trader sentiment. Sentiment does not appear to forecast time-series variation in the value and momentum premiums.</description><author>Lemmon, Michael; Portniaguina, Evgenia</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate diversification and credit constraints: Real effects across the business cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dimitrov, Valentin; Tice, Sheri
We study whether differences in access to credit cause focused firms to perform differently from diversified firms in the product market. Prior work has identified binding credit constraints for bank-dependent firms during recessions. We assess whether corporate diversification alleviates these constraints. We find that during recessions sales growth rates drop more for bank-dependent focused firms than for rival segments of bank-dependent diversified firms. We also find that during recessions inventory growth rates drop more for bank-dependent focused firms than for bank-dependent diversified firms even after we control for contemporaneous sales growth. Consistent with a credit constraint explanation, we find no difference in the sensitivities to recessions of bank-independent focused and bank-independent diversified firms.</description><author>Dimitrov, Valentin; Tice, Sheri</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital controls, liberalizations, and foreign direct investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Desai, Mihir A.; Foley, C. Fritz; Hines, James R.
This article evaluates the impact of capital controls and their liberalization on the activities of US multinational firms. These firms attempt to circumvent capital controls by reducing reported local profitability and increasing the frequency of dividend repatriations. As a result, the reported profit impact of local capital controls is comparable with the effect of 27% higher corporate tax rates, and affiliates located in countries imposing capital controls are 9.8% more likely than other affiliates to remit dividends to parent companies. Multinational affiliates located in countries with capital controls face 5.25% higher interest rates on local borrowing than do affiliates of the same parent borrowing locally in countries without capital controls. Capital control liberalizations are associated with significant increases in multinational activity-property, plant, and equipment grow at 6.9% faster annual rates following liberalizations. The combination of the costliness of avoidance and higher interest rates discourages investment in countries with capital controls, and this effect is reversed upon liberalization of controls.</description><author>Desai, Mihir A.; Foley, C. Fritz; Hines, James R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Takeover contests with asymmetric bidders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Povel, Paul; Singh, Rajdeep
Target firms often face bidders that are not equally well informed, which reduces competition, because bidders with less information fear the winner's curse more. We analyze how targets should be sold in this situation. We show that a sequential procedure can extract the highest possible transaction price. The target first offers an exclusive deal to a better-informed bidder, without considering a less well-informed bidder. If rejected, the target offers either an exclusive deal to the less well-informed bidder, or a modified first-price auction. Deal protection devices can be used to enhance a target's commitment to the procedure.</description><author>Povel, Paul; Singh, Rajdeep</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Theory and evidence on the resolution of financial distress</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, David T.; Ciochetti, Brian A.; Riddiough, Timothy J.
We analyze a financially distressed owner-managed project. The main results of the model are: (1) borrower default is an endogenous response to the anticipated restructuring-foreclosure outcome; (2) the lender's restructuring-foreclosure decision depends critically on the interaction between project value and industry liquidity; and (3) the lender waits for the industry to recapitalize before selling assets obtained through foreclosure. Empirical analysis of a large sample of defaulted commercial real estate loans supports many of the model predictions, including restructuring-foreclosure outcomes that are consistent with endogenous borrower default and firesale discounts that vary depending on industry market conditions at the time of foreclosure.</description><author>Brown, David T.; Ciochetti, Brian A.; Riddiough, Timothy J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing implications of firms' financing constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gomes, Joao F.; Yaron, Amir; Zhang, Lu
We use a production-based asset pricing model to investigate whether financing constraints are quantitatively important for the cross-section of returns. Specifically, we use GMM to explore the stochastic Euler equation imposed on returns by optimal investment. Our methods can identify the impact of financial frictions on the stochastic discount factor with cyclical variations in cost of external funds. We find that financing frictions provide a common factor that improves the pricing of cross-sectional returns. Moreover, the shadow cost of external funds exhibits strong procyclical variation, so that financial frictions are more important in relatively good economic conditions.</description><author>Gomes, Joao F.; Yaron, Amir; Zhang, Lu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option coskewness and capital asset pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vanden, Joel M.
This article shows how the market coskewness model of Rubinstein (1973) and Kraus and Litzenberger (1976) is altered when a nonredundant call option is optimally traded. Owing to the option's nonredundancy, the economy's stochastic discount factor (SDF) depends not only on the market return and the square of the market return but also on the option return, the square of the option return, and the product of the market and option returns. This leads to an asset pricing model in which the expected return on any risky asset depends explicitly on the asset's coskewness with option returns. The empirical results show that the option coskewness model outperforms several competing benchmark models. Furthermore, option coskewness captures some of the same risks as the Fama-French factors small minus big (SMB) and high minus low (HML). These results suggest that the factors that drive the pricing of nonredundant options are also important for pricing risky equities.</description><author>Vanden, Joel M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of trades on daily volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avramov, Doron; Chordia, Tarun; Goyal, Amit
This article proposes a trading-based explanation for the asymmetric effect in daily volatility of individual stock returns. Previous studies propose two major hypotheses for this phenomenon: leverage effect and time-varying expected returns. However, leverage has no impact on asymmetric volatility at the daily frequency and, moreover, we observe asymmetric volatility for stocks with no leverage. Also, expected returns may vary with the business cycle, that is, at a lower than daily frequency. Trading activity of contrarian and herding investors has a robust effect on the relationship between daily volatility and lagged return. Consistent with the predictions of the rational expectation models, the non-informational liquidity-driven (herding) trades increase volatility following stock price declines, and the informed (contrarian) trades reduce volatility following stock price increases. The results are robust to different measures of volatility and trading activity.</description><author>Avramov, Doron; Chordia, Tarun; Goyal, Amit</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Downside risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Andrew; Chen, Joseph; Xing, Yuhang
Economists have long recognized that investors care differently about downside losses versus upside gains. Agents who place greater weight on downside risk demand additional compensation for holding stocks with high sensitivities to downside market movements. We show that the cross section of stock returns reflects a downside risk premium of approximately 6% per annum. Stocks that covary strongly with the market during market declines have high average returns. The reward for beasring downside risk is not simply compensation for regular market beta, nor is it explained by coskewness or liquidity risk, or by size, value, and momentum characteristics.</description><author>Ang, Andrew; Chen, Joseph; Xing, Yuhang</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Transmission of information across international equity markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wongswan, Jon
This article provides evidence of information transmission from the United States and Japan to Korean and Thai equity markets. Information is defined as important macroeconomic announcements in the United States, Japan, Korea, and Thailand. Using high-frequency intraday data, I find a large and significant association between developed-economy macroeconomic announcements and emerging-economy equity volatility and trading volume at short time horizons. Previous studies' findings of at most weak evidence of transmission from developed to emerging economies may be due to their use of lower frequency data and their focus on developed-economy financial market innovations as a proxy for information.</description><author>Wongswan, Jon</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic portfolio choice with parameter uncertainty and the economic value of analysts' recommendations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cvitanic, Jaksa; Lazrak, Ali; Martellini, Lionel; Zapatero, Fernando
We derive a closed-form solution for the optimal portfolio of a nonmyopic utility maximizer who has incomplete information about the alphas or abnormal returns of risky securities. We show that the hedging component induced by learning about the expected return can be a substantial part of the demand. Using our methodology, we perform an "ex ante" empirical exercise, which shows that the utility gains resulting from optimal allocation are substantial in general, especially for long horizons, and an "ex post" empirical exercise, which shows that analysts' recommendations are not very useful.</description><author>Cvitanic, Jaksa; Lazrak, Ali; Martellini, Lionel; Zapatero, Fernando</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor income and predictable stock returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Santos, T.; Veronesi, P.
We propose a novel economic mechanism that generates stock return predictability in both the time series and the cross-section. Investors' income has two sources, wages and dividends that grow stochastically over time. As a consequence the fraction of total income produced by wages fluctuates depending on economic conditions. We show that the risk premium that investors require to hold stocks varies with these fluctuations. A regression of stock returns on lagged values of the labor income to consumption ratio produces statistically significant coefficients and large adjusted R(2)s. Tests of the model's cross-sectional predictions on the set of 25 Fama-French portfolios sorted on size and book-to-market are also met with considerable support.</description><author>Santos, T.; Veronesi, P.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the source of capital affect capital structure?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faulkender, M.; Petersen, M. A.
Prior work on leverage implicitly assumes capital availability depends solely on firm characteristics. However, market frictions that make capital structure relevant may also be associated with a firm's source of capital. Examining this intuition, we find firms that have access to the public bond markets, as measured by having a debt rating, have significantly more leverage. Although firms with a rating are fundamentally different, these differences do not explain our findings. Even after controlling for firm characteristics that determine observed capital structure, and instrumenting for the possible endogeneity of having a rating, firms with access have 35% more debt.</description><author>Faulkender, M.; Petersen, M. A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit ratings as coordination mechanisms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boot, A. W. A.; Milbourn, T. T.; Schmeits, A.
In this article, we provide a novel rationale for credit ratings. The rationale that we propose is that credit ratings serve as a coordinating mechanism in situations where multiple equilibria can obtain. We show that credit ratings provide a "focal point" for firms and their investors, and explore the vital, but previously overlooked implicit contractual relationship between a credit rating agency (CRA) and a firm through its credit watch procedures. Credit ratings can help fix the desired equilibrium and as such play an economically meaningful role. Our model provides several empirical predictions and insights regarding the expected price impact of rating changes.</description><author>Boot, A. W. A.; Milbourn, T. T.; Schmeits, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit ratings and stock liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Odders-White, E. R.; Ready, M. J.
We analyze contemporaneous and predictive relations between credit ratings and measures of equity market liquidity and find that common measures of adverse selection, which reflect a portion of the uncertainty about future firm value, are larger when credit ratings are poorer. We also show that future rating changes can be predicted using current levels of adverse selection. Collectively, our results validate widely used microstructure measures of adverse selection and offer new insights into the value of credit ratings and the specific nature of the information they contain.</description><author>Odders-White, E. R.; Ready, M. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Explaining returns with cash-flow proxies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hecht, P.; Vuolteenaho, T.
Stock returns are correlated with contemporaneous earnings growth, dividend growth, future real activity, and other cash-flow proxies. The correlation between cash-flow proxies and stock returns may arise from association of cash-flow proxies with one-period expected returns, cash-flow news, and/or expected-return news. We use Campbell's (1991) return decomposition to measure the relative importance of these three effects in regressions of returns on cash-flow proxies. In some of the popular specifications, variables that are motivated as proxies for cash-flow news also track a nontrivial proportion of one-period expected returns and expected-return news. As a result, the R-2 from a regression of returns on cash-flow proxies may overstate or understate the importance of cash-flow news as a source of return variance.</description><author>Hecht, P.; Vuolteenaho, T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition and cooperation in divisible good auctions: An experimental examination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sade, O.; Schnitzlein, C.; Zender, J. F.
An experimental approach is used to examine the performance of three different multiunit auction designs: discriminatory, uniform-price with fixed supply, and uniform-price with endogenous supply. We find the actual strategies to be inconsistent with theoretically identified equilibrium strategies. The discriminatory auction is found to be more susceptible to collusion than either uniform-price auction and so, contrary to theoretical predictions and previous experimental results, it generates the lowest average revenue. Consistent with theoretical predictions, the actual bid schedules are more elastic with reducible supply or discriminatory pricing than in the uniform-price auction with fixed supply.</description><author>Sade, O.; Schnitzlein, C.; Zender, J. F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset allocation with a high dimensional latent factor stochastic volatility model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Y. F.
We investigate the implications of time-varying expected return and volatility on asset allocation in a high dimensional setting. We propose a dynamic factor multivariate stochastic volatility (DFMSV) model that allows the first two moments of returns to vary over time for a large number of assets. We then evaluate the economic significance of the DFMSV model by examining the performance of various dynamic portfolio strategies chosen by mean-variance investors in a universe of 36 stocks. We find that the DFMSV dynamic strategies significantly outperform various benchmark strategies out of sample. This outperformance is robust to different performance measures, investor's objective functions, time periods, and assets.</description><author>Han, Y. F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exchange rates, equity prices, and capital flows</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hau, H.; Rey, H.
We develop an equilibrium model in which exchange rates, stock prices, and capital flows are jointly determined under incomplete foreign exchange (forex) risk trading. Incomplete hedging of forex risk, documented for U.S. global mutual funds, induces the following price and capital flow dynamics: Higher returns in the home equity market relative to the foreign equity market are associated with a home currency depreciation. Net equity flows into the foreign market are positively correlated with a foreign currency appreciation. The model predictions are strongly supported at daily, monthly, and quarterly frequencies for 17 OECD countries vis-a-vis the United States. Correlations are strongest after 1990 and for countries with higher equity market capitalization relative to GDP, suggesting that the observed exchange rate dynamics is indeed related to equity market development.</description><author>Hau, H.; Rey, H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analysts' weighting of private and public information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Q.; Jiang, W.
Using both a linear regression method and a probability-based method, we find that on average, analysts place larger than efficient weights on (i.e., they overweight) their private information when they forecast corporate earnings. We also find that analysts overweight more when issuing forecasts more favorable than the consensus, and overweight less, and may even underweight, private information when issuing forecasts less favorable than the consensus. Further, the deviation from efficient weighting increases when the benefits from doing so are high or when the costs of doing so are low. These results suggest that analysts' incentives play a larger role in misweighting than their behavioral biases.</description><author>Chen, Q.; Jiang, W.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor overconfidence and trading volume</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Statman, Meir; Thorley, Steven; Vorkink, Keith
The proposition that investors are overconfident about their valuation and trading skills can explain high observed trading volume. With biased self-attribution, the level of investor overconfidence and thus trading volume varies with past returns. We test the trading volume predictions of formal overconfidence models and find that share turnover is positively related to lagged returns for many months. The relationship holds for both market-wide and individual security turnover, which we interpret as evidence of investor overconfidence and the disposition effect, respectively. Security volume is more responsive to market return shocks than to security return shocks, and both relationships are more pronounced in small-cap stocks and in earlier periods where individual investors hold a greater proportion of shares.</description><author>Statman, Meir; Thorley, Steven; Vorkink, Keith</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The behavior of interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fama, E. F.
The evidence in Fama and Bliss (1987) that forward interest rates forecast future spot interest rates for horizons beyond a year repeats in the out-of-sample 1986-2004 period. But the inference that this forecast power is due to mean reversion of the spot rate toward a constant expected value no longer seems valid. Instead, the predictability of the spot rate captured by forward rates seems to be due to mean reversion toward a time-varying expected value that is subject to a sequence of apparently permanent shocks that are on balance positive to mid-1981 and on balance negative thereafter.</description><author>Fama, E. F.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating government bond fund performance with stochastic discount factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferson, W.; Henry, T. R.; Kisgen, D. J.
This article shows how to evaluate the performance of managed portfolios using stochastic discount factors (SDFs) from continuous-time term structure models. These models imply empirical factors that include time averages of the underlying state variables. The approach addresses a performance measurement bias, described by Goetzmann, Ingersoll, and Ivkovic (2000) and Ferson and Khang (2002), arising because fund managers may trade within the return measurement interval or hold positions in replicable options. The empirical factors contribute explanatory power in factor model regressions and reduce model pricing errors. We illustrate the approach on US government bond funds during 1986-2000.</description><author>Ferson, W.; Henry, T. R.; Kisgen, D. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A trade-based analysis of momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hvidkjaer, S.
This article uses transactions data for all NYSE/AMEX stocks in the period 1983-2002 to study how investors trade in Jegadeesh and Titman's (1993) momentum portfolios. Among small trades, there is an extremely sluggish reaction to the past returns. For instance, an initial small-trade buying pressure exists for loser stocks, and it gradually converts into an intense selling pressure over the following year. The results are consistent with initial underreaction followed by delayed reaction among small traders. Moreover, small-trade imbalances during the formation period significantly affect momentum returns, suggesting that underreaction among small traders contributes to the momentum effect. Large traders, by contrast, show no evidence of underreaction, and large-trade imbalances have little impact on subsequent returns. Overall, the results suggest that momentum could partly be driven by the behavior of small traders.</description><author>Hvidkjaer, S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loan sales and the cost of corporate borrowing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guner, A. B.
When a loan is sold, it goes to a lower-cost financing source than its originator. Yet, lending markets are less than perfectly competitive. Despite the lower funding cost, therefore, the loan price is not necessarily more favorable to the borrower. However, corporate borrowers are averse to the participation of their loans to other lenders because of the complexity of dealing with multiple banks and the potential information costs of the sale announcement. Consequently, I conjecture that the borrower extracts a price concession in exchange for allowing the bank to sell participations in the loan. Using a hand-matched dataset of loans, borrowers, and lenders, I find that the average yield spread on loans originated by active loan sellers is about 20 basis points lower than the average spread on loans originated by moderate loan sellers.</description><author>Guner, A. B.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedging, familiarity and portfolio choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, M.; Simonov, A.
We exploit the restrictions of intertemporal portfolio choice in the presence of nonfinancial income risk to test hedging using the information contained in the actual portfolio of the investor. We use a unique data set of Swedish investors with information broken down at the investor level and into various components of investor wealth, income, and demographic characteristics. Portfolio holdings are identified at the stock level. We show that investors do not hedge but invest in stocks closely related to their nonfinancial income. We explain this with familiarity, that is, the tendency to concentrate holdings in stocks to which the investor is geographically or professionally close or that he has held for a long period. We show that familiarity is not a behavioral bias, but is information driven. Familiarity-based investment allows investors to earn higher returns than they would have otherwise earned if they had hedged.</description><author>Massa, M.; Simonov, A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital structure, compensation and incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Douglas, A. V. S.
This article illustrates an incentive-aligning role of debt in the presence of optimal compensation contracts. Owing to information asymmetry, value-maximizing compensation contracts allow managerial rents following high investment outcomes. The manager has an incentive to increase these rents by choosing investments that generate greater information asymmetry. An aptly chosen debt level mitigates this incentive, because investments that generate greater information asymmetry have more volatile outcomes. The greater volatility would make the debt risky, causing the shareholders to focus on high outcomes and therefore compensation contracts that reduce managerial rents. At the optimum, the manager avoids opportunistic investments, and the shareholders offer value-maximizing compensation contracts. Empirically, the analysis predicts a negative relationship between leverage and market-to-book that is reversed at extreme market-to-book ratios, a negative relationship between leverage and profitability, a negative relationship between leverage and pay-for-performance, and a positive relationship between pay-for-performance and investment opportunities.</description><author>Douglas, A. V. S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>If at first you don't succeed: The effect of the option to resolicit on corporate takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gillette, A. B.; Noe, T. H.
This article models, and experimentally simulates, the free-rider problem in a takeover when the raider has the option to "resolicit," that is, to make a new offer after an offer has been rejected. In theory, the option to resolicit, by lowering offer credibility, increases the dissipative losses associated with free riding. The outcomes of our experiment support this prediction and produce losses from free riding even higher than theoretically predicted. These dissipation losses reduce raider gains to less than 3% of synergy value of the acquisition.</description><author>Gillette, A. B.; Noe, T. H.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial constraints risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Whited, T. M.; Wu, G. J.
We construct an index of firms' external finance constraints via generalized method of moments (GMM) estimation of an investment Euler equation. Unlike the commonly used KZ index, ours is consistent with firm characteristics associated with external finance constraints. Constrained firms' returns move together, suggesting the existence of a financial constraints factor. This factor earns a positive but insignificant average return. Much of the variation in this factor cannot be explained by the Fama-French and momentum factors. Cross-sectional regressions of returns on our index and other firm characteristics show that constrained firms earn higher returns and that the financial-constraints effect dominates the size effect.</description><author>Whited, T. M.; Wu, G. J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing options in an extended Black Scholes economy with illiquidity: Theory and empirical evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cetin, U.; Jarrow, R.; Protter, P.; Warachka, M.
This article studies the pricing of options in an extended Black Scholes economy in which the underlying asset is not perfectly liquid. The resulting liquidity risk is modeled as a stochastic supply curve, with the transaction price being a function of the trade size. Consistent with the market microstructure literature, the supply curve is upward sloping with purchases executed at higher prices and sales at lower prices. Optimal discrete time hedging strategies are then derived. Empirical evidence reveals a significant liquidity cost intrinsic to every option.</description><author>Cetin, U.; Jarrow, R.; Protter, P.; Warachka, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO underpricing and after-market liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellul, A.; Pagano, M.
The underpricing of initial public offerings (IPOs) is generally explained with asymmetric information and risk. We complement these traditional explanations with a new theory where investors worry also about the after-market illiquidity that may result from asymmetric information after the IPO. The less liquid the aftermarket is expected to be, and the less predictable its liquidity, the larger will be the IPO underpricing. Our model blends such liquidity concerns with adverse selection and risk as motives for underpricing. The model's predictions are supported by evidence for 337 British IPOs effected between 1998 and 2000. Using various measures of liquidity, we find that expected after-market liquidity and liquidity risk are important determinants of IPO underpricing.</description><author>Ellul, A.; Pagano, M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Innovation, differentiation, and the choice of an underwriter: Evidence from equity-linked securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schroth, Enrique
Investment banks imitate other bank's innovative corporate securities and compete with the innovator to underwrite new issues. This article uses data of all the corporate offerings of equity-linked and derivative securities in the Securities Data Company (SDC) to estimate the issuer's demand of underwriting services provided by investment banks across different varieties of securities. It finds that the demand for the innovator's variety is larger than the imitators'. This demand advantage decreases with time and faster for securities that appear later in a sequence of innovations. Imitation becomes less attractive later in the sequence as information from earlier deals spills-over to all banks.</description><author>Schroth, Enrique</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate finance and the monetary transmission mechanism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Patrick; Freixas, Xavier
We analyze the transmission effects of monetary policy in a general equilibrium model of the financial sector, with bank lending and securities markets. Bank lending is constrained by capital adequacy requirements, and asymmetric information adds a cost to outside bank equity capital. In our model, monetary policy does not affect bank lending through changes in bank liquidity; rather, it operates through changes in the spread of bank loans over corporate bonds, which induce changes in the aggregate composition of financing by firms, and in banks' equity-capital base. The model produces multiple equilibria, one of which displays all the features of a "credit crunch."</description><author>Bolton, Patrick; Freixas, Xavier</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The impact of legal and political institutions on equity trading costs: A cross-country analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eleswarapu, Venkat R.; Venkataraman, Kumar
We conjecture that macro-level institutions affect equity trading costs through their impact on information risk and investor participation. In a study of trading costs for 412 NYSE-listed American Depository Receipts (ADRs) from 44 countries, we find that, after controlling for firm-level determinants of trading costs, effective spreads and price impact of trades are significantly lower for stocks from countries with better ratings for judicial efficiency, accounting standards, and political stability. Trading costs are significantly higher for stocks from French civil law countries than from common law countries. Overall, we conclude that improvements in legal and political institutions will lower the cost of liquidity in financial markets.</description><author>Eleswarapu, Venkat R.; Venkataraman, Kumar</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset pricing models and financial market anomalies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avramov, Doron; Chordia, Tarun
This article develops a framework that applies to single securities to test whether asset pricing models can explain the size, value, and momentum anomalies. Stock level beta is allowed to vary with firm-level size and book-to-market as well as with macroeconomic variables. With constant beta, none of the models examined capture any of the market anomalies. When beta is allowed to vary, the size and value effects are often explained, but the explanatory power of past return remains robust. The past return effect is captured by model mispricing that varies with macroeconomic variables.</description><author>Avramov, Doron; Chordia, Tarun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition and strategic information acquisition in credit markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hauswald, Robert; Marquez, Robert
We investigate the interaction between banks' use of information acquisition as a strategic tool and their role in promoting the efficiency of credit markets when a bank's ability to gather information varies with its distance to the borrower. We show that banks acquire proprietary information both to soften lending competition and to extend their market share. As competition increases, investments in information acquisition fall, leading to lower interest rates but also to less efficient lending decisions. Consistent with the recent wave of bank acquisitions, we also find that merging for informational reasons with a competitor is an optimal response to industry consolidation.</description><author>Hauswald, Robert; Marquez, Robert</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Maximum likelihood estimation of latent affine processes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bates, David S.
This article develops a direct filtration-based maximum likelihood methodology for estimating the parameters and realizations of latent affine processes. Filtration is conducted in the transform space of characteristic functions, using a version of Bayes' rule for recursively updating the joint characteristic function of latent variables and the data conditional upon past data. An application to daily stock market returns over 1953-1996 reveals substantial divergences from estimates based on the Efficient Methods of Moments (EMM) methodology; in particular, more substantial and time-varying jump risk. The implications for pricing stock index options are examined.</description><author>Bates, David S.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The information in option volume for future stock prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pan, Jun; Poteshman, Allen M.
We present strong evidence that option trading volume contains information about future stock prices. Taking advantage of a unique data set, we construct put-call ratios from option volume initiated by buyers to open new positions. Stocks with low put-call ratios outperform stocks with high put-call ratios by more than 40 basis points on the next day and more than 1% over the next week. Partitioning our option signals into components that are publicly and nonpublicly observable, we find that the economic source of this predictability is nonpublic information possessed by option traders rather than market inefficiency. We also find greater predictability for stocks with higher concentrations of informed traders and from option contracts with greater leverage.</description><author>Pan, Jun; Poteshman, Allen M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International capital markets and foreign exchange risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brennan, Michael J.; Xia, Yihong
Relations between foreign exchange risk premia, exchange rate volatility, and the volatilities of the pricing kernels for the underlying currencies, are derived under the assumption of integrated capital markets. As predicted, the volatility of exchange rates is significantly associated with the estimated volatility of the relevant pricing kernels, and foreign exchange risk premia are significantly related to both the estimated volatility of the pricing kernels and the volatility of exchange rates. The estimated foreign exchange risk premia mostly satisfy Fama's (1984) necessary conditions for explaining the forward premium puzzle, but the puzzle remains in several cases even after taking account of the pricing kernel volatilities.</description><author>Brennan, Michael J.; Xia, Yihong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Beauty contests and iterated expectations in asset markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Franklin; Morris, Stephen; Shin, Hyun Song
In a financial market where traders are risk averse and short lived and prices are noisy, asset prices today depend on the average expectation today of tomorrow's price. Thus (iterating this relationship) the date 1 price equals the date I average expectation of the date 2 average expectation of the date 3 price. This will not, in general, equal the date I average expectation of the date 3 price. We show how this failure of the law of iterated expectations for average belief can help understand the role of higher-order beliefs in a fully rational asset pricing model.</description><author>Allen, Franklin; Morris, Stephen; Shin, Hyun Song</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A note from the Editor</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>O'Hara, Maureen
nan</description><author>O'Hara, Maureen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pairs trading: Performance of a relative-value arbitrage rule</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gatev, Evan; Goetzmann, William N.; Rouwenhorst, K. Geert
We test a Wall Street investment strategy, "pairs trading," with daily data over 1962-2002. Stocks are matched into pairs with minimum distance between normalized historical prices. A simple trading rule yields average annualized excess returns of up to 11% for self-financing portfolios of pairs. The profits typically exceed conservative transaction-cost estimates. Bootstrap results suggest that the "pairs" effect differs from previously documented reversal profits. Robustness of the excess returns indicates that pairs trading profits from temporary mispricing of close substitutes. We link the profitability to the presence of a common factor in the returns, different from conventional risk measures.</description><author>Gatev, Evan; Goetzmann, William N.; Rouwenhorst, K. Geert</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate governance, incentives, and industry consolidations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, K. C.; Dittmar, A.; Servaes, H.
This article studies the determinants of the success of industry consolidations using a unique sample of firms established at the time of their initial public offering: roll-up IPOs. In these transactions, small, private firms merge into a shell company, which goes public at the same time. These firms deliver poor stock returns; their operating performance mimics that of comparable firms but does not justify their high initial valuations. However, if the managers and owners of the firms included in the transaction remain involved in the business as shareholders and directors, operating and stock price performance improve, and future acquisitions are better received by the market. Higher ownership by the sponsor of the transaction leads to a reduction in performance, consistent with the view that the sponsor's compensation is excessive. These findings highlight the impact of corporate governance on performance.</description><author>Brown, K. C.; Dittmar, A.; Servaes, H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPOs with buy- and sell-side information production: The dark side of open sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yung, C.
The proposed model, by incorporating both (1) banker screening of new issues and (2) costly evaluation by investors, is the first to admit endogenous double-sided information production. It demonstrates a nontrivial link between these two sides: the banker wishes to structure a sale conducive to investor research because selling to an uninformed pool would result in his own shirking. One application of this paradigm indicates that, contrary to the findings of most IPO models, larger investor pools are not always better. This result resolves the "participation restriction puzzle" of why bankers do not open sales to all bidders even when doing so would maximize competition and reduce underpricing.</description><author>Yung, C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decision processes, agency problems, and. information: An economic analysis of capital budgeting procedures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marino, A. M.; Matsusaka, J. G.
Corporations use a variety of processes to allocate capital. This article studies the benefits and costs of several common budget procedures from the perspective of a model with agency and information problems. Processes that delegate aspects of the decision to the agent result in too many projects being approved, while processes in which the principal retains the right-to reject projects cause the agent to strategically distort his information about project quality. We show how the choice of a decision process depends on these two costs, and specifically on severity of the agency problem, quality of information, and project risk.</description><author>Marino, A. M.; Matsusaka, J. G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do firms announce open-market repurchase programs?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oded, J.
Empirically, a price increase accompanies the announcement of an open-market stock repurchase program, even though the announcement is not a commitment. In fact, for many announced programs no shares are ever actually repurchased. This article explores this puzzle. In the single-firm-type version of the model, the option that a firm grants itself by announcing a program does not generate announcement returns. In equilibrium, long-run gains from the informed trading that the option creates are offset by short-run costs from the market's accounting for this adverse selection. Based on this trade-off, I construct a signaling (two-type) model that can deliver announcement returns. In the separating equilibrium, good firms do not incur any cost when they announce programs. Their gains from informed trading in the long run offset the cost of announcement incurred in the short run. Mimicry is costly, because a bad firm's long-run gains from informed trading cannot compensate for the short-run cost of announcing.</description><author>Oded, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal consumption and portfolio choices with risky housing and borrowing constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yao, R.; Zhang, H. H.
We examine the optimal dynamic portfolio decisions for investors who acquire housing services from either renting or owning a house. Our results show that when indifferent between owning and renting, investors owning a house hold a lower equity proportion in their net worth (bonds, stocks, and home equity), reflecting the substitution effect, yet hold a higher equity proportion in their liquid portfolios (bonds and stocks), reflecting the diversification effect. Furthermore, following the suboptimal policy of always renting leads investors to overweigh in stocks, while following the suboptimal policy of always owning a house causes investors to underweigh in stocks.</description><author>Yao, R.; Zhang, H. H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is default event risk priced in corporate bonds?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Driessen, J.
This article provides an empirical decomposition of the default, liquidity, and tax factors that determine expected corporate bond returns. In particular, the risk premium associated with a default event is estimated. The intensity-based model is estimated using bond price data for 104 US firms and historical default rates. Significant risk premia on common intensity factors and important tax and liquidity effects are found. These components go a long way towards explaining the level of expected corporate bond returns. Adding a positive default event risk premium helps to explain the remaining error, although this premium cannot be estimated with high statistical precision.</description><author>Driessen, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An equilibrium model of rare-event premia and its implication for option smirks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, J.; Pan, J.; Wang, T.
This article studies the asset pricing implication of imprecise knowledge about rare events. Modeling rare events as jumps in the aggregate endowment, we explicitly solve the equilibrium asset prices in a pure-exchange economy with a representative agent Who is Averse not only to risk but also to model uncertainty with respect to rare events. The equilibrium equity premium has three components: the diffusive- and jump-risk premiums, both driven by risk aversion; and the "rare-event premium," driven exclusively by uncertainty aversion. To disentangle the rare-event premiums from the standard risk-based premiums, we examine the equilibrium prices of options across moneyness or, equivalently, across varying sensitivities to rare events. We find that uncertainty aversion toward rare events plays an important role in explaining the pricing differentials among options across moneyness, particularly the prevalent "smirk" patterns documented in the index options market.</description><author>Liu, J.; Pan, J.; Wang, T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An empirical analysis of stock and bond market liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, T.; Sarkar, A.; Subrahmanyam, A.
This article explores cross-market liquidity dynamics by estimating a vector autoregressive model for liquidity (bid-ask spread and depth, returns, volatility, and order flow in the stock and Treasury bond markets). Innovations to stock and bond market liquidity and volatility are significantly correlated, implying that common factors drive liquidity and volatility in these markets. Volatility shocks are informative in predicting shifts in liquidity. During crisis periods, monetary expansions are associated with increased liquidity. Moreover, money flows to government bond funds forecast bond market liquidity. The results establish a link between "macro" liquidity, or money flows, and "micro" or transactions liquidity.</description><author>Chordia, T.; Sarkar, A.; Subrahmanyam, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonparametric specification testing for continuous-time models with applications to term structure of interest rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Y. M.; Li, H. T.
We develop a nonparametric specification test for continuous-time models using the transition density. Using a data transform and correcting for the boundary bias of kernel estimators, our test is robust to serial dependence in data and provides excellent finite sample performance. Besides univariate diffusion models, our test is applicable to a wide variety of continuous-time and discrete-time dynamic models, including time-inhomogeneous diffusion, GARCH, stochastic volatility, regime-switching, jump-diffusion, and multivariate diffusion models. A class of separate inference procedures is also proposed to help gauge possible sources of model misspecification. We strongly reject a variety of univariate diffusion models for daily Eurodollar spot rates and some popular multivariate affine term structure models for monthly U.S. Treasury yields.</description><author>Hong, Y. M.; Li, H. T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The pooling and tranching of securities: A model of informed intermediation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeMarzo, P. M.
I show that when an issuer has superior information about the value of its assets, it is better off selling assets separately rather than as a pool due to the information destruction effect of Pooling. If, however, the issuer can create a derivative security that is collateralized by the assets, pooling and "tranching" may be optimal. If the residual risk of each asset is not highly correlated, tranching allows the issuer to exploit the risk diversification effect of pooling to create a low-risk and highly liquid security. In contrast, for an uninformed seller, pure pooling reduces underpricing and is preferred to separate asset sales. These results lead to a dynamic model of financial intermediation: originators sell pools of assets, some of which are purchased by informed intermediaries who then further pool and tranche them. Pooling and tranching allow intermediaries to leverage their capital more efficiently, enhancing the returns to their private information.</description><author>DeMarzo, P. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information acquisition under uncertainty in credit markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, P.
This article studies information acquisition through investment in improved risk assessment technology in competitive credit markets. A technology has two attributes: its ability to screen in productive borrowers, and its ability to screen out unproductive borrowers. The two attributes have fundamentally different effects on acquisition incentives and the structure of equilibrium informational externalities between lenders. The article also studies how uncertainty associated with the quality of superior technology affects information acquisition incentives. Uncertainty influences information acquisition even with risk-neutral banks. Increased uncertainty may raise or dampen incentives, depending on whether uncertainty is, respectively, about screening out or screening in quality.</description><author>Banerjee, P.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>IPO market timing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alti, A.
I develop a model of information spillovers in initial public offerings (IPOs). The outcomes of pioneers' IPOs reflect participating investors' private information on common valuation factors. This makes the pricing of subsequent issues relatively easier and attracts more firms to the IPO market. I show that IPO market timing by the followers emerges as an equilibrium clustering pattern. High offer price realizations for pioneers' IPOs better reflect investors' private information and trigger a larger number of subsequent IPOs than low offer price realizations do. This asymmetry in the spillover effect is more pronounced early on in a hot market. The model provides an explanation for recent empirical findings that illustrate the high sensitivity of going public decision to IPO market conditions.</description><author>Alti, A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal contracts under adverse selection and moral hazard: A continuous-time approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sung, J. Y.
This article presents a continuous-time agency model in the presence of adverse selection and moral hazard with a risk-averse agent and a risk-neutral principal. Under the model setup, we show that the optimal controls are constant over time, and thus the optimal menu consists of contracts that are linear in the final outcome. We also show that when a moral hazard problem adds to an adverse selection problem, the monotonicity condition well known in the pure adverse selection literature needs to be modified to ensure the incentive compatibility for information revelation. The model is applied to a few managerial compensation problems involving managerial project selection and capital budgeting decisions. We argue that in the third-best world, the relationship between the volatility of the outcome and the sensitivity of the contract depends on interactions between the managerial cost and the firm's production functions. Contrary to conventional wisdom, sometimes the higher the volatility, the higher the sensitivity of the contract. The firm receiving good news sometimes chooses safer projects or invests less than it does with bad news. We also examine the effects of the observability of the volatility on corporate investment decisions.</description><author>Sung, J. Y.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market frictions, price delay, and the cross-section of expected returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hou, K. W.; Moskowitz, T. J.
We parsimoniously characterize the severity of market frictions affecting a stock using the delay with which its price responds to information. The most delayed firms command a large return premium not explained by size, liquidity, or microstructure effects. Moreover, delay captures part of the size effect, idiosyncratic risk is priced only among the most delayed firms, and earnings drift is monotonically increasing in delay. Frictions associated with investor recognition appear most responsible for the delay effect. The very small segment of delayed firms, comprising only 0.02% of the market, generates substantial variation in average returns, highlighting the importance of frictions.</description><author>Hou, K. W.; Moskowitz, T. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Coordination of expectations in asset pricing experiments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hommes, C.; Sonnemans, J.; Tuinstra, J.; van de Velden, H.
We investigate expectation formation in a controlled experimental environment. Subjects are asked to predict the price in a standard asset pricing model. They do not have knowledge of the underlying market equilibrium equations, but they know all past realized prices and their own predictions. Aggregate demand for the risky asset depends upon the forecasts of the participants. The realized price is then obtained from market equilibrium with feedback from six individual expectations. Realized prices differ significantly from fundamental values and typically exhibit oscillations around, or slow convergence to, this fundamental. In all groups participants coordinate on a common prediction strategy.</description><author>Hommes, C.; Sonnemans, J.; Tuinstra, J.; van de Velden, H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does risk seeking drive stock prices? A stochastic dominance analysis of aggregate investor preferences and beliefs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Post, T.; Levy, H.
We use various stochastic dominance criteria that account for (local) risk seeking to analyze market portfolio efficiency relative to benchmark portfolios formed on market capitalization, book-to-market equity ratio and price momentum. Our results suggest that reverse S-shaped utility functions with risk aversion for losses and risk seeking for gains can explain stock returns. The results are also consistent with a reverse S-shaped pattern of subjective probability transformation. The low average yield on big caps, growth stocks, and past losers may reflect investors' twin desire for downside protection in bear markets and upside potential in bull markets.</description><author>Post, T.; Levy, H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do heterogeneous beliefs matter for asset pricing?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, E. W.; Ghysels, E.; Juergens, J. L.
We study how heterogeneous beliefs affect returns and examine whether they are a priced factor in traditional asset pricing models. To accomplish this task, we suggest new empirical measures based on the disagreement among analysts about expected earnings (short-term and long-term) and show they are good proxies. We first establish that the heterogeneity of beliefs matters for asset pricing and then turn our attention to estimating a structural model in which we use the forecasts of financial analysts to proxy for agents' beliefs. Finally, we investigate whether the amount of heterogeneity in analysts' forecasts can help explain asset pricing puzzles.</description><author>Anderson, E. W.; Ghysels, E.; Juergens, J. L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A simulation approach to dynamic portfolio choice with an application to learning about return predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brandt, M. W.; Goyal, A.; Santa-Clara, P.; Stroud, J. R.
We present a simulation-based method for solving discrete-time portfolio choice problems involving non-standard preferences, a large number of assets with arbitrary return distribution, and, most importantly, a large number of state variables with potentially path-dependent or non-stationary dynamics. The method is flexible enough to accommodate intermediate consumption, portfolio constraints, parameter and model uncertainty, and learning. We first establish the properties of the method for the portfolio choice between a stock index and cash when the stock returns are either iid or predictable by the dividend yield. We then explore the problem of an investor who takes into account the predictability of returns but is uncertain about the parameters of the data generating process. The investor chooses the portfolio anticipating that future data realizations will contain useful information to learn about the true parameter values.</description><author>Brandt, M. W.; Goyal, A.; Santa-Clara, P.; Stroud, J. R.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do domestic investors have an edge? The trading experience of foreign investors in Korea</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choe, H.; Kho, B. C.; Stulz, R. M.
We investigate whether domestic investors have an edge over foreign investors in trading domestic stocks. Using Korean data, we show that foreign money managers pay more than domestic money managers when they buy and receive less when they sell for medium and large trades. The sample average daily trade-weighted disadvantage of foreign money managers is 21 basis points for purchases and 16 basis points for sales. There is also some evidence that domestic individual investors have an edge over foreign investors. The explanation for these results is that prices move more against foreign investors than against domestic investors before trades.</description><author>Choe, H.; Kho, B. C.; Stulz, R. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Island goes dark: Transparency, fragmentation, and regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hendershott, T.; Jones, C. M.
Responding to a September 2002 regulatory enforcement, the Island electronic communications network stopped displaying its limit order book in the three most active exchange-traded funds (ETFs) where it was the dominant venue. Island's share of trading activity and price discovery fell, fragmenting the market. ETF prices adjust more slowly when Island goes dark, and there is substantial price discovery movement from ETFs to the futures market. Trading costs increase on Island and decrease off Island, with higher trading costs overall. When Island later redisplays its orders, market quality improves, with transparency and the reduction in fragmentation both playing important roles.</description><author>Hendershott, T.; Jones, C. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic consumption and portfolio choice with stochastic volatility in incomplete markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chacko, G.; Viceira, L. M.
This paper examines the optimal consumption and portfolio-choice problem of long-horizon investors who have access to a riskless asset with constant return and a risky asset ("stocks") with constant expected return and time-varying precision-the reciprocal of volatility. Markets are incomplete, and investors have recursive preferences defined over intermediate consumption. The paper obtains a solution to this problem which is exact for investors with unit elasticity of intertemporal substitution of consumption and approximate otherwise. The optimal portfolio demand for stocks includes an intertemporal hedging component that is negative when investors have coefficients of relative risk aversion larger than one, and the instantaneous correlation between volatility and stock returns is negative, as typically estimated from stock return data. Our estimates of the joint process for stock returns and precision (or volatility) using U.S. data confirm this finding. But we also find that stock return volatility does not appear to be variable and persistent enough to generate large intertemporal hedging demands.</description><author>Chacko, G.; Viceira, L. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Household portfolio diversification: A case for rank-dependent preferences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Polkovnichenko, V.
The proliferation of novel preference theories in financial economics is hampered by a lack of non-experimental evidence and by the theories' additional complexity which has not been shown to be critical in applications. In this article I present arguments in support of preferences with rank dependency. Using the Survey of Consumer Finances data, I document two widespread patterns inconsistent with expected utility: (i) many households simultaneously invest in well-deversified funds and in poorly-diversified portfolios of stocks; and (ii) some households with substantial savings do not invest anything in equities. I show that portfolio choice models with rank-dependent preferences, plausibly parameterized and under fully rational assumptions, are quantitatively consistent with the observed diversification. These results call for further efforts to integrate the models of rank-dependent preferences in portfolio theory and asset pricing.</description><author>Polkovnichenko, V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How does industry affect firm financial structure?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>MacKay, P.; Phillips, G. M.
We examine the importance of industry to firm-level financial and real decisions. We find that in addition to standard industry fixed effects, financial structure also depends on a firm's position within its industry. In competitive industries, a firm's financial leverage depends on its natural hedge (its proximity to the median industry capital-labor ratio), the actions of other firms in the industry, and its status as entrant, incumbent, or exiting firm. Financial leverage is higher and less dispersed in concentrated industries, where strategic debt interactions are also stronger, but a firm's natural hedge is not significant. Our results show that financial structure, technology, and risk are jointly determined within industries. These findings are consistent with recent industry equilibrium models of financial structure.</description><author>MacKay, P.; Phillips, G. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Powerful CEOs and their impact on corporate performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adams, R. B.; Almeida, H.; Ferreira, D.
Executives can only impact firm outcomes if they have influence over crucial decisions. On the basis of this idea, we develop and test the hypothesis that firms whose CEOs have more decision-making power should experience more variability in performance. Focusing primarily on the power the CEO has over the board and other top executives as a consequence of his formal position and titles, status as a founder, and status as the board's sole insider, we find that stock returns are more variable for firms run by powerful CEOs. Our findings suggest that the interaction between executive characteristics and organizational variables has important consequences for firm performance.</description><author>Adams, R. B.; Almeida, H.; Ferreira, D.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why do larger orders receive discounts on the London Stock Exchange?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernhardt, D.; Dvoracek, V.; Hughson, E.; Werner, I. M.
We argue that competition between dealers in a classic dealer market is intertemporal: A trader identifies a particular dealer and negotiates a final price with only the intertemporal threat to switch dealers imposing pricing discipline on the dealer. In this kind of market structure, we show that dealers will offer greater price improvement to more regular customers, and, in turn, these customers optimally choose to submit larger orders. Hence, price improvement and trade size should be negatively correlated in a dealer market. We confirm our model's predictions using unique data from the London Stock Exchange during 1991.</description><author>Bernhardt, D.; Dvoracek, V.; Hughson, E.; Werner, I. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The model-free implied volatility and its information content</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, G. J.; Tian, Y. S.
Britten-Jones and Neuberger (2000) derived a model-free implied volatility under the diffusion assumption. In this article, we extend their model-free implied volatility to asset price processes with jumps and develop a simple method for implementing it using observed option prices. In addition, we perform a direct test of the informational efficiency of the option market using the model-free implied volatility. Our results from the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 index (SPX) options suggest that the model-free implied volatility subsumes all information contained in the Black-Scholes (B-S) implied volatility and past realized volatility and is a more efficient forecast for future realized volatility.</description><author>Jiang, G. J.; Tian, Y. S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An equilibrium model of asset pricing and moral hazard</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hui, O. Y.
This article develops an integrated model of asset pricing and moral hazard. It is demonstrated that the expected dollar return of a stock is independent of managerial incentives and idiosyncratic risk, but the equilibrium price of the stock depends on them. Thus, the expected rate of return is affected by managerial incentives and idiosyncratic risk. It is shown, however, that managerial incentives and idiosyncratic risk affect the expected rate of return through their influence on systematic risk rather than serve as independent risk factors. It is also shown that the risk aversion of the principal in the model leads to less emphasis on relative performance evaluation than in a model with a risk-neutral principal.</description><author>Hui, O. Y.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Model uncertainty, limited market participation, and asset prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cao, H. H.; Wang, T.; Zhang, H. H.
We demonstrate that limited participation can arise endogenously in the presence of model uncertainty and heterogeneous uncertainty-averse investors. When uncertainty dispersion among investors is small, full participation prevails in equilibrium. Equity premium is related to the average uncertainty among investors and a conglomerate trades at a price equal to the sum of its single-segment components. When uncertainty dispersion is large, investors with high uncertainty choose not to participate in the stock market, resulting in limited market participation. When limited participation occurs, participation rate and equity premium can decrease in uncertainty dispersion and a conglomerate trades at a discount.</description><author>Cao, H. H.; Wang, T.; Zhang, H. H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limit order book as a market for liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foucault, T.; Kadan, O.; Kandel, E.
We develop a dynamic model of a limit order market populated by strategic liquidity traders of varying impatience. In equilibrium, patient traders tend to submit limit orders, whereas impatient traders submit market orders. Two variables are the key determinants of the limit order book dynamics in equilibrium: the proportion of patient traders and the order arrival rate. We offer several testable implications for various market quality measures such as spread, trading frequency, market resiliency, and time to execution for limit orders. Finally, we show the effect of imposing a minimal price variation on these measures.</description><author>Foucault, T.; Kadan, O.; Kandel, E.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fund families as delegated monitors of money managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gervais, S.; Lynch, A. W.; Musto, D. K.
Because a money manager learns more about her skill from her management experience than outsiders can learn from her realized returns, she expects inefficiency in future contracts that condition exclusively on realized returns. A fund family that learns what the manager learns can reduce this inefficiency cost if the family is large enough. The family's incentive is to retain any given manager regardless of her skill but, when the family has enough managers, it adds value by boosting the credibility of its retentions through the firing of others. As the number of managers grows, the efficiency loss goes to zero.</description><author>Gervais, S.; Lynch, A. W.; Musto, D. K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-term persistence in mutual fund performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollen, N. P. B.; Busse, J. A.
We estimate parameters of standard stock selection and market timing models using daily mutual fund returns and quarterly measurement periods. We then rank funds quarterly by abnormal return and measure the performance of each decile the following quarter. The average abnormal return of the top decile in the post-ranking quarter is 39 basis points. The post-ranking abnormal return disappears when funds are evaluated over longer periods. These results suggest that superior performance is a short-lived phenomenon that is observable only when funds are evaluated several times a year.</description><author>Bollen, N. P. B.; Busse, J. A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jackknifing bond option prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phillips, P. C. B.; Yu, J.
Prices of interest rate derivative securities depend crucially on the mean reversion parameters of the underlying diffusions. These parameters are subject to estimation bias when standard methods are used. The estimation bias can be substantial even in very large samples and much more serious than the discretization bias, and it translates into a bias in pricing bond options and other derivative securities that is important in practical work. This article proposes a very general and computationally inexpensive method of bias reduction that is based on Quenouille's (1956; Biometrika, 43, 353-360) jackknife. We show how the method can be applied directly to the options price itself as well as the coefficients in the models. We investigate its performance in a Monte Carlo study. Empirical applications to U.S. dollar swap rates highlight the differences between bond and option prices implied by the jackknife procedure and those implied by the standard approach. These differences are large and suggest that bias reduction in pricing options is important in practical applications.</description><author>Phillips, P. C. B.; Yu, J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A shrinkage approach to model uncertainty and asset allocation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Z. Y.
This article takes a shrinkage approach to examine the empirical implications of aversion to model uncertainty. The shrinkage approach explicitly shows how predictive distributions incorporate data and prior beliefs. It enables us to solve the optimal portfolios for uncertainty-averse investors. Aversion to uncertainty about the capital asset pricing model leads investors to hold a portfolio that is not mean-variance efficient for any predictive distribution. However, mean-variance efficient portfolios corresponding to extremely strong beliefs in the Fama-French model are approximately optimal for uncertainty-averse investors. The empirical Bayes approach does not result in optimal portfolios for investors who are averse to model uncertainty.</description><author>Wang, Z. Y.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identifying control motives in managerial ownership: Evidence from antitakeover legislation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheng, S. J.; Nagar, V.; Rajan, M. V.
This study uses the introduction of second-generation antitakeover legislation as a natural experimental setting to infer the value that managers place on the control rights conferred by stock ownership. We conjecture that managers will reduce their stockholdings in the post-legislation period because they can ensure their prior level of control while holding fewer risky shares. Using a variety of specifications, we find robust evidence consistent with this "revealed preference" hypothesis. Further demonstrating the key role played by control considerations in managers' stockholding decisions, the reductions in ownership are concentrated in management teams with higher levels of initial ownership and in firms without poison pills.</description><author>Cheng, S. J.; Nagar, V.; Rajan, M. V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anonymity, adverse selection, and the sorting of interdealer trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Reiss, P. C.; Werner, I. M.
This article uses unique data from the London Stock Exchange to examine how trader anonymity and market liquidity affect dealers' decisions about where to place interdealer trades. During our sample period, dealers could trade with each other in the direct, nommonymous public market or use one of four anonymous brokered trading systems. Surprisingly, we find that adverse selection is less prevalent in the anonymous brokered markets. We show that this pattern can be explained by the way dealers "price" the adverse selection risk inherent in trading with other dealers. We also relate our findings to recent changes in dealer markets.</description><author>Reiss, P. C.; Werner, I. M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Portfolio choice in the presence of housing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cocco, J. F.
I show that investment in housing plays a crucial role in explaining the patterns of cross-sectional variation in the composition of wealth and the level of stockholdings observed in portfolio composition data. Due to investment in housing, younger and poorer investors have limited financial wealth to invest in stocks, which reduces the benefits of equity market participation. House price risk crowds out stockholdings, and this crowding out effect is larger for low financial net-worth. In the model as in the data leverage is positively correlated with stockholdings.</description><author>Cocco, J. F.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Consumption and portfolio choice over the life cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cocco, J. F.; Gomes, F. J.; Maenhout, P. J.
This article solves a realistically calibrated life cycle model of consumption and portfolio choice with non-tradable labor income and borrowing constraints. Since labor income substitutes for riskless asset holdings, the optimal share invested in equities is roughly decreasing over life. We compute a measure of the importance of human capital for investment behavior. We find that ignoring labor income generates large utility costs, while the cost of ignoring only its risk is an order of magnitude smaller, except when we allow for a disastrous labor income shock. Moreover, we study the implications of introducing endogenous borrowing constraints in this incomplete-markets setting.</description><author>Cocco, J. F.; Gomes, F. J.; Maenhout, P. J.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interbank market integration under asymmetric information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Freixas, X.; Holthausen, C.
Cross-country bank lending appears to be subject to market imperfections leading to persistent interest rate differentials. In a model where banks need to cope with liquidity shocks by borrowing or by liquidating assets, we study the scope for international interbank market integration with unsecured lending when cross-country information is noisy. We find that an equilibrium with integrated markets need not always exist, and that it may coexist with one characterized by segmentation. A repo market reduces interest rate spreads and improves upon the segmentation equilibrium. However, it may destroy the unsecured integrated equilibrium.</description><author>Freixas, X.; Holthausen, C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information leakage and market efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brunnermeier, M. K.
This article analyzes the effects of information leakage on trading behavior and market efficiency. A trader who receives a noisy signal about a forthcoming public announcement can exploit it twice. First, when he receives it, and second, after the public announcement since he knows best the extent to which his information is already reflected in the pre-announcement price. Given his information he expects the price to overshoot and intends to partially revert his trade. While information leakage makes the price process more informative in the short-run, it reduces its informativeness in the long-run. The analysis supports Securities and Exchange Commission's Regulation Fair Disclosure.</description><author>Brunnermeier, M. K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How often to sample a continuous-time process in the presence of market microstructure noise</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ait-Sahalia, Y.; Mykland, P. A.; Zhang, L.
In theory, the sum of squares of log returns sampled at high frequency estimates their variance. When market microstructure noise is present but unaccounted for, however, we show that the optimal sampling frequency is Finite and derives its closed-form expression. But even with optimal sampling, using say 5-min returns when transactions are recorded every second, a vast amount of data is discarded, in contradiction to basic statistical principles. We demonstrate that modeling the noise and using all the data is a better solution, even if one misspecifies the noise distribution. So the answer is: sample as often as possible.</description><author>Ait-Sahalia, Y.; Mykland, P. A.; Zhang, L.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extreme value dependence in financial markets: Diagnostics, models, and financial implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Poon, S. H.; Rockinger, M.; Tawn, J.
This article presents a general framework for identifying and modeling the joint-tail distribution based on multivariate extreme value theories. We argue that the multivariate approach is the most efficient and effective way to study extreme events such as systemic risk and crisis. We show, using returns on five major stock indices, that the use of traditional dependence measures could lead to inaccurate portfolio risk assessment. We explain how the framework proposed here could be exploited in a number of finance applications such as portfolio selection, risk management, Sharpe ratio targeting, hedging, option valuation, and credit risk analysis.</description><author>Poon, S. H.; Rockinger, M.; Tawn, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Multiple unit auctions and short squeezes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nyborg, K. G.; Strebulaev, I. A.
This article develops a theory of multiunit auctions where short squeezes can occur in the secondary market. Both uniform and discriminatory auctions are studied and bidders can submit multiple bids. We show that bidders with short and long preauction positions have different valuations in an otherwise common value setting. Discriminatory auctions lead to more short squeezing and higher revenue than uniform auctions, ceteris paribus. Asymptotically, as the auction size approaches infinity, the two formats lead to equivalent outcomes. Shorts employ more aggressive equilibrium bidding strategies. Most longs strategically choose to be passive. Free riding on a squeeze by small, long players has no impact on these results, but affects revenue in discriminatory auctions.</description><author>Nyborg, K. G.; Strebulaev, I. A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structural models of corporate bond pricing: An empirical analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Eom, Y. H.; Helwege, J.; Huang, J. Z.
This article empirically tests five structural models of corporate bond pricing: those of Merton (1974), Geske (1977), Longstaff and Schwartz (1995), Leland and Toft (1996), and Collin-Dufresne and Goldstein (200 1). We implement the models using a sample of 182 bond prices from firms with simple capital structures during the period 1986-1997. The conventional wisdom is that structural models do not generate spreads as high as those seen in the bond market, and true to expectations, we find that the predicted spreads in our implementation of the Merton model are too low. However, most of the other structural models predict spreads that are too high on average. Nevertheless, accuracy is a problem, as the newer models tend to severely overstate the credit risk of firms with high leverage or volatility and yet suffer from a spread underprediction problem with safer bonds. The Leland and Toft model is an exception in that it overpredicts spreads on most bonds, particularly those with high coupons. More accurate structural models must avoid features that increase the credit risk on the riskier bonds while scarcely affecting the spreads of the safest bonds.</description><author>Eom, Y. H.; Helwege, J.; Huang, J. Z.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On the timing and execution of open market repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cook, D. O.; Krigman, L.; Leach, J. C.
Little is known about the timing and execution of open market repurchases. U.S. firms are under no obligation to disclose when they are trading, and generally report only quarterly changes in shares outstanding. We use 64 firms' supplementally disclosed repurchase trading data to provide the first examination of repurchase timing and execution. Across the days reported in our sample, firms adopted a variety of execution styles ranging from immediate intense repurchasing to delayed and smoothed repurchasing. We find no clear evidence that repurchases are timed to coincide with, precede, or follow, days on which information is released. We benchmark the costs and value of a given repurchase program against naive accumulation strategies achieving the same terminal portfolio. While there is considerable variation across the firms, NYSE firms on average beat their benchmarks, whereas NASDAQ firms do not. Finally, we document the liquidity impact of open market repurchases. We find that repurchasing contributes to market liquidity by narrowing bid-ask spreads and attenuating the price impact of order imbalances on days when repurchase trades are completed.</description><author>Cook, D. O.; Krigman, L.; Leach, J. C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Advertising, breadth of ownership, and liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grullon, G.; Kanatas, G.; Weston, J. P.
We provide empirical evidence that a firm's overall visibility with investors, as measured by its product market advertising, has important consequences for the stock market. Specifically we show that firms with greater advertising expenditures, ceteris paribus, have a larger number of both individual and institutional investors, and better liquidity of their common stock. Our findings are robust to a variety of methodological approaches and to various measures of liquidity. These results suggest that the investors' degree of familiarity with a firm may affect its cost of capital and consequently its value.</description><author>Grullon, G.; Kanatas, G.; Weston, J. P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Confronting information asymmetries: Evidence from real estate markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garmaise, M. J.; Moskowitz, T. J.
There are relatively few direct tests of the economic effects of asymmetric information because of the difficulty in identifying exogenous information measures. We propose a novel exogenous measure of information based on the quality of property tax assessments in different regions and apply this to the U.S. commercial real estate market. We find strong evidence that information considerations are significant. Market participants resolve information asymmetries by purchasing nearby properties, trading properties with long income histories, and avoiding transactions with informed professional brokers. The evidence that the choice of financing is used to address information concerns is mixed and weak.</description><author>Garmaise, M. J.; Moskowitz, T. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating an alternative risk preference in affine term structure models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duarte, J.
Dai and Singleton (2002) and Duffee (2002) show that there is a tension in affine term structure models between matching the mean and the volatility of interest rates. This article examines whether this tension can be solved by an alternative parametrization of the price of risk. The empirical evidence suggests that, first, the examined parametrization is not sufficient to solve the mean-volatility tension. Second, the usual result in the estimation of affine models, indicating that some of the state variables are extremely persistent, may have been caused by the lack of flexibility in the parametrization of the price of risk.</description><author>Duarte, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Conditioning information and variance bounds on pricing kernels</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bekaert, G.; Liu, J.
Gallant, Hansen, and Tauchen (1990) show how to use conditioning information optimally to construct a sharper unconditional variance bound (the GHT bound) on pricing kernels. The literature predominantly resorts to a simple but suboptimal procedure that scales returns with predictive instruments and computes standard bounds using the original and scaled returns. This article provides a formal bridge between the two approaches. We propose an optimally scaled bound that coincides with the GHT bound when the first and second conditional moments are known. When these moments are misspecified, our optimally scaled bound yields a valid lower bound for the standard deviation of pricing kernels, whereas the GHT bound does not. We illustrate the behavior of the bounds using a number of linear and nonlinear models for consumption growth and bond and stock returns. We also illustrate how the optimally scaled bound can be used as a diagnostic for the specification of the first two conditional moments of asset returns.</description><author>Bekaert, G.; Liu, J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic trading, liquidity, and information acquisition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Mendelson, H.; Tunca, T. I.
We study endogenous liquidity trading in a market with long-lived asymmetric information. We distinguish between public information, tractable information that can be acquired, and intractable information that cannot be acquired. Besides information asymmetry and noise, the adverse-selection spread depends on the diffusion of intractable information and on the interest rate. With endogenous liquidity trading, efficiency is lower than that implied by noise-trading models. Liquidity traders benefit from the information released through the insider's trades in spite of their monetary losses. We study factors that affect the insider's information acquisition decision, including the amount of intractable information, observability, and information acquisition costs.</description><author>Mendelson, H.; Tunca, T. I.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Career concerns and resource allocation in conglomerates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goel, A. M.; Nanda, V.; Narayanan, M. P.
We investigate resource allocation decisions in conglomerates when managers are motivated by career concerns. When divisional cash flows are differentially informative about managerial ability, we show that it is in the managers' interest to over-allocate unobservable intangible resources to the more informative divisions. Anticipating this bias, it is optimal for the firm's owners to also over-allocate observable capital to the more informative divisions. The model provides rationale for corporate socialism and corporate hedging. It also highlights a cost of segment reporting and tracking stocks, namely, that they allow managers to distort their perceived ability at the expense of investors.</description><author>Goel, A. M.; Nanda, V.; Narayanan, M. P.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation and return dynamics of new ventures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berk, J. B.; Green, R. C.; Naik, V.
A dynamic model of a multistage investment project that captures many features of research and development (R&amp;D) ventures and start-up companies is developed. An important feature these problems share is that firms learn about the potential profitability of the project throughout its life, but that technical uncertainty about the R&amp;D effort is only resolved through additional investment. Consequently the risks associated with the ultimate cash flows have a systematic component even while the purely technical risks are idiosyncratic. Our model captures these different sources of risk and allows us to study their interaction in determining the value and risk premium of the venture.</description><author>Berk, J. B.; Green, R. C.; Naik, V.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What's in it for me? CEOs whose firms are acquired</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hartzell, J. C.; Ofek, E.; Yermack, D.
We study benefits received by target chief executive officers (CEOs) in completed mergers and acquisitions. Certain target CEOs negotiate large cash payments in the form of special bonuses or increased golden parachutes. These negotiated cash payments are positively associated with the CEO's prior excess compensation and negatively associated with the likelihood that the CEO becomes an executive of the acquiring company. Regression estimates suggest that target shareholders receive lower acquisition premia in transactions involving extraordinary personal treatment of the CEO. Target CEOs experience very high turnover rates both at the time of acquisition and, for those who remain employed, for several years thereafter.</description><author>Hartzell, J. C.; Ofek, E.; Yermack, D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risks and portfolio decisions involving hedge funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, V.; Naik, N. Y.
This article characterizes the systematic risk exposures of hedge funds using buy-and-hold and option-based strategies. Our results show that a large number of equity-oriented hedge fund strategies exhibit payoffs resembling a short position in a put option on the market index and therefore bear significant left-tail risk, risk that is ignored by the commonly used mean-variance framework. Using a mean-conditional value-at-risk framework, we demonstrate the extent to which the mean-variance framework underestimates the tail risk. Finally, working with the systematic risk exposures of hedge funds, we show that their recent performance appears significantly better than their long-run performance.</description><author>Agarwal, V.; Naik, N. Y.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The emergence and persistence of the Anglo-Saxon and German financial systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baliga, S.; Polak, B.
We use a moral hazard model to compare monitored (nontraded) bank loans and traded (nonmonitored) bonds as sources of external funds for industry. We contrast the theoretical conditions that favor each system with the historical conditions prevailing when these financial systems evolved during the British and German industrial revolutions. To study persistence, we consider an entry model where financiers take the industrial structure as given when they lend and firms take the financial system as given when they borrow. We show multiple equilibria can exist, compare equilibria in welfare terms, and discuss their robustness to coordination between lenders and borrowers.</description><author>Baliga, S.; Polak, B.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional herding</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sias, R. W.
Institutional investors' demand for a security this quarter is positively correlated with their demand for the security last quarter. We attribute this to institutional investors following each other into and out of the same securities ("herding") and institutional investors following their own lag trades. Although institutional investors are "momentum" traders, little of their herding results from momentum trading. Moreover, institutional demand is more strongly related to lag institutional demand than lag returns. Results are most consistent with the hypothesis that institutions herd as a result of inferring information from each other's trades.</description><author>Sias, R. W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Options trading and the CAPM</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vanden, J. M.
This article studies equilibrium asset pricing when agents face nonnegative wealth constraints. In the presence of these constraints it is shown that options on the market portfolio are nonredundant securities and the economy's pricing kernel is a function of both the market portfolio and the nonredundant options. This implies that the options should be useful for explaining risky asset returns. To test the theory, a model is derived in which the expected excess return on any risky asset is linearly related (via a collection of betas) to the expected excess return on the market portfolio and to the expected excess returns on the nonredundant options. The empirical results indicate that the returns on traded index options are relevant for explaining the returns on risky asset portfolios.</description><author>Vanden, J. M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why the NPV criterion does not maximize NPV</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berkovitch, E.; Israel, R.
This article presents a theory of capital allocation that shows how the use of net present value (NPV) as an investment criterion leads to inefficient capital budgeting outcomes and how this criterion may be dominated by other capital budgeting criteria, like the internal rate of return and the profitability index. The essence of our theory is rooted in the mainstream paradigm of corporate finance: while firms use NPV to measure the addition to firm value from prospective projects, "classical" informational and agency considerations prevent it from implementing the optimal capital budgeting outcome. Our theory also identifies conditions when alternative criteria should be used. Finally, we characterize when direct monitoring through capital budgeting dominates compensation contracts in alleviating the agency problem.</description><author>Berkovitch, E.; Israel, R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can managerial discretion explain observed leverage ratios?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morellec, E.
This article analyzes the impact of managerial discretion and corporate control mechanisms on leverage and firm value within a contingent claims model where the manager derives perquisites from investment. Optimal capital structure reflects both the tax advantage of debt less bankruptcy costs and the agency costs of managerial discretion. Actual capital structure reflects the trade-off made by the manager between his empire-building desires and the need to ensure sufficient efficiency to prevent control challenges, The model shows that manager-shareholder conflicts can explain the low debt levels observed in practice. It also examines the impact of these conflicts on the cross-sectional variation in capital structures.</description><author>Morellec, E.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Whence GARCH? A preference-based explanation for conditional volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>McQueen, G.; Vorkink, K.
We develop a preference-based equilibrium asset pricing model that explains low-frequency conditional volatility. Similar to Barberis, Huang, and Santos (2001), agents in our model care about wealth changes, experience loss aversion, and keep a mental scorecard that affects their level of risk aversion. A new feature of our model is that when perturbed by unexpected returns, investors become temporarily more sensitive to news. Gradually investors become accustomed to the new level of wealth, restoring prior levels of risk aversion and news sensitivity. The state-dependent sensitivity to news creates the type of volatility clustering found in low-frequency stock returns. We find empirical support for our model's predictions that relate the scorecard to conditional volatility and skewness.</description><author>McQueen, G.; Vorkink, K.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust portfolio rules and asset pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maenhout, P. J.
I present a new approach to the dynamic portfolio and consumption problem of an investor who worries about model uncertainty (in addition to market risk) and seeks robust decisions along the lines of Anderson, Hansen, and Sargent (2002). In accordance with max-min expected utility, a robust investor insures against some endogenous worst case. I first show that robustness dramatically decreases the demand for equities and is observationally equivalent to recursive preferences when removing wealth effects. Unlike standard recursive preferences, however, robustness leads to environment-specific "effective" risk aversion. As an extension, I present a closed-form solution for the portfolio problem of a robust Duffie-Epstein-Zin investor. Finally, robustness increases the equilibrium equity premium and lowers the risk-free rate. Reasonable parameters generate a 4% to 6% equity premium.</description><author>Maenhout, P. J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Public trading and private incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faure-Grimaud, A.; Gromb, D.
This article studies the link between public trading and the activity of a firm's large shareholder who can affect firm value. Public trading results in the formation of a stock price that is informative about the large shareholder's activity. This increases the latter's incentives to engage in value-increasing activities. Indeed, if he has to liquidate part of his stake before the effect of his activity is publicly observed, a more informative price rewards him for his activity. Implications are derived for the decision to go public, capital structure, and security design.</description><author>Faure-Grimaud, A.; Gromb, D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>