<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>RFS0</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Ratings-Based Regulation and Systematic Risk Incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iannotta, Giuliano; Pennacchi, George; Santos, Joao A. C.
Our model shows that when regulation is based on credit ratings, banks with low charter value maximize shareholder value by minimizing capital and selecting identically rated loans and bonds with the highest systematic risk. This regulatory arbitrage is possible if the credit spreads on same-rated loans and bonds are greater when their systematic risk (debt beta) is higher. We empirically confirm this relationship between credit spreads, ratings, and debt betas. We also show that banks with lower capital select syndicated loans with higher debt betas and credit spreads. Banks with lower charter value choose overall assets with higher systematic risk.</description><author>Iannotta, Giuliano; Pennacchi, George; Santos, Joao A. C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cyclical Dispersion in Expected Defaults</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gomes, Joao F.; Grotteria, Marco; Wachter, Jessica A.
A growing literature shows that credit indicators forecast aggregate real outcomes. While researchers have proposed various explanations, the economic mechanism behind these results remains an open question. In this paper, we show that a simple, frictionless model explains empirical findings commonly attributed to credit cycles. Our key assumption is that firms have heterogeneous exposures to underlying economy-wide shocks. This leads to endogenous dispersion in credit quality that varies over time and predicts future excess returns and real outcomes.</description><author>Gomes, Joao F.; Grotteria, Marco; Wachter, Jessica A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm Financing over the Business Cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Begenau, Juliane; Salomao, Juliana
Data from U.S. public firms show that in booms large firms finance with debt and payout equity, whereas small firms issue both equity and debt. Therefore, large firms generally substitute between debt and equity financing over the business cycle, whereas small firms adhere to a procyclical financing policy for debt and equity. We explain these cyclical financing patterns quantitatively using a heterogeneous firm model with endogenous firm dynamics. We find that cross-sectional differences in investment returns and, therefore, funding needs and exposures to financial frictions are essential to understanding how firms' financing policies respond to macroeconomic shocks. Received December 24, 2016; editorial decision April 24, 2018 by Editor Stijn Van Nieuwerburgh. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Begenau, Juliane; Salomao, Juliana</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Valuable Is FinTech Innovation?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Mark A.; Wu, Qinxi; Yang, Baozhong
We provide large-scale evidence on the occurrence and value of FinTech innovation. Using data on patent filings from 2003 to 2017, we apply machine learning to identify and classify innovations by their underlying technologies. We find that most FinTech innovations yield substantial value to innovators, with blockchain being particularly valuable. For the overall financial sector, internet of things (IoT), robo-advising, and blockchain are the most valuable innovation types. Innovations affect financial industries more negatively when they involve disruptive technologies from nonfinancial startups, but market leaders that invest heavily in their own innovation can avoid much of the negative value effect. ReceivedMay 31, 2017; editorial decision September 30, 2018 by Editor Andrew Karolyi.</description><author>Chen, Mark A.; Wu, Qinxi; Yang, Baozhong</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Big Data as a Governance Mechanism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhu, Christina
This study empirically investigates two effects of alternative data availability: stock price informativeness and its disciplining effect on managers' actions. Recent computing advancements have enabled technology companies to collect real-time, granular indicators of fundamentals to sell to investment professionals. These data include consumer transactions and satellite images. The introduction of these data increases price informativeness through decreased information acquisition costs, particularly in firms in which sophisticated investors have higher incentives to uncover information. I document two effects on managers. First, managers reduce their opportunistic trading. Second, investment efficiency increases, consistent with price informativeness improving managers' incentives to invest and divest efficiently. Received June 1, 2017; editorial decision June 1, 2018 by Editor Wei Jiang. The Author has furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Zhu, Christina</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Promises and Pitfalls of Robo-Advising</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>D'Acunto, Francesco; Prabhala, Nagpurnanand; Rossi, Alberto G.
We study the introduction of a wealth-management robo-adviser that constructs portfolios tailored to investors' holdings and preferences. Adopters are similar to non-adopters in terms of demographics and prior interactions with human advisers but tend to be more active and have greater assets under management. Investors adopting robo-advising experience diversification benefits. Ex ante undiversified investors increase stock holdings and hold portfolios with less volatility and better returns. Already well-diversified investors hold fewer stocks, yet see some reduction in volatility, and trade more after adoption. All investors increase attention based on online account logins. We find that adopters exhibit declines in prominent behavioral biases, including the disposition, trend chasing, and rank effect. Our results emphasize the promises and pitfalls of robo-advising tools, which are becoming ubiquitous all over the world. Received May 31, 2017; editorial decision August 21, 2018 by Editor Wei Jiang.</description><author>D'Acunto, Francesco; Prabhala, Nagpurnanand; Rossi, Alberto G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Marketplace Lending: A New Banking Paradigm?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vallee, Boris; Zeng, Yao
Marketplace lending relies on screening and information production by investors, a major deviation from the traditional banking paradigm. Theoretically, the participation of sophisticated investors improves screening outcomes and also creates adverse selection among investors. In maximizing loan volume, the platform trades off these two forces. As the platform develops, it optimally increases platform prescreening intensity but decreases information provision to investors. Using novel investor-level data, we find that sophisticated investors systematically outperform, and this outperformance shrinks when the platform reduces information provision to investors. Our findings shed light on the optimal distribution of information production in this new lending model. Received August 29, 2018; editorial decision July 1, 2018 by Editor Itay Goldstein. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Vallee, Boris; Zeng, Yao</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Peer-to-Peer Lenders Versus Banks: Substitutes or Complements?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tang, Huan
This paper studies whether, in the consumer credit market, peer-to-peer (P2P) lending platforms serve as substitutes for banks or instead as complements. I develop a conceptual framework and derive testable predictions to distinguish between these two possibilities. Using a regulatory change as an exogenous shock to bank credit supply, I find that P2P lending is a substitute for bank lending in terms of serving infra-marginal bank borrowers yet complements bank lending with respect to small loans. These results indicate that the credit expansion resulting from P2P lending likely occurs only among borrowers who already have access to bank credit. Received June 1, 2017; editorial decision September 15, 2018 by Editor Andrew Karolyi. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Tang, Huan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Role of Technology in Mortgage Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fuster, Andreas; Plosser, Matthew; Schnabl, Philipp; Vickery, James
Technology-based (FinTech) lenders increased their market share of U.S. mortgage lending from 2% to 8% from 2010 to 2016. Using loan-level data on mortgage applications and originations, we show that FinTech lenders process mortgage applications 20% faster than other lenders, controlling for observable characteristics. Faster processing does not come at the cost of higher defaults. FinTech lenders adjust supply more elastically than do other lenders in response to exogenous mortgage demand shocks. In areas with more FinTech lending, borrowers refinance more, especially when it is in their interest. We find no evidence that FinTech lenders target borrowers with low access to finance. Received June 1, 2017; editorial decision November 5, 2018 by Editor Wei Jiang. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Fuster, Andreas; Plosser, Matthew; Schnabl, Philipp; Vickery, James</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sex, Drugs, and Bitcoin: How Much Illegal Activity Is Financed through Cryptocurrencies?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foley, Sean; Karlsen, Jonathan R.; Putnins, Talis J.
Cryptocurrencies are among the largest unregulated markets in the world. We find that approximately one-quarter of bitcoin users are involved in illegal activity. We estimate that around 76 billion of illegal activity per year involve bitcoin (46% of bitcoin transactions), which is close to the scale of the U.S. and European markets for illegal drugs. The illegal share of bitcoin activity declines with mainstream interest in bitcoin and with the emergence of more opaque cryptocurrencies. The techniques developed in this paper have applications in cryptocurrency surveillance. Our findings suggest that cryptocurrencies are transforming the black markets by enabling black e-commerce. Received June 1, 2017; editorial decision December 8, 2018 by Editor Andrew Karolyi. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Foley, Sean; Karlsen, Jonathan R.; Putnins, Talis J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Blockchain Disruption and Smart Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cong, Lin William; He, Zhiguo
Blockchain technology provides decentralized consensus and potentially enlarges the contracting space through smart contracts. Meanwhile, generating decentralized consensus entails distributing information that necessarily alters the informational environment. We analyze how decentralization relates to consensus quality and how the quintessential features of blockchain remold the landscape of competition. Smart contracts can mitigate informational asymmetry and improve welfare and consumer surplus through enhanced entry and competition, yet distributing information during consensus generation may encourage greater collusion. In general, blockchains sustain market equilibria with a wider range of economic outcomes. We further discuss the implications for antitrust policies targeted at blockchain applications. Received May 31, 2017; editorial decision May 29, 2018 by Editor Itay Goldstein.</description><author>Cong, Lin William; He, Zhiguo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Blockchain-Based Settlement for Asset Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chiu, Jonathan; Koeppl, Thorsten V.
Can securities be settled on a blockchain, and, if so, what are the gains relative to existing settlement systems? The main benefit of a blockchain is faster and more flexible settlement, whereas settlement fails need to be ruled out where participants fork the chain to cancel trading losses. With a proof-of-work protocol, the blockchain needs to restrict settlement speed through block size and time in order to generate transaction fees, which finance costly mining. Despite mining being a deadweight cost, our estimates for the U.S. corporate debt market yield net gains from a blockchain in the range of 1-4 bps. Received May 31, 2017; editorial decision May 29, 2018 by Editor Itay Goldstein. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Chiu, Jonathan; Koeppl, Thorsten V.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Blockchain Folk Theorem</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Biais, Bruno; Bisiere, Christophe; Bouvard, Matthieu; Casamatta, Catherine
Blockchains are distributed ledgers, operated within peer-to-peer networks. We model the proof-of-work blockchain protocol as a stochastic game and analyze the equilibrium strategies of rational, strategic miners. Mining the longest chain is a Markov perfect equilibrium, without forking, in line with Nakamoto (2008). The blockchain protocol, however, is a coordination game, with multiple equilibria. There exist equilibria with forks, leading to orphaned blocks and persistent divergence between chains. We also show how forks can be generated by information delays and software upgrades. Last we identify negative externalities implying that equilibrium investment in computing capacity is excessive. Received May 31, 2017; editorial decision July 6, 2018 by Editor Itay Goldstein.</description><author>Biais, Bruno; Bisiere, Christophe; Bouvard, Matthieu; Casamatta, Catherine</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>To FinTech and Beyond</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldstein, Itay; Jiang, Wei; Karolyi, G. Andrew
FinTech is about the introduction of new technologies into the financial sector, and it is now revolutionizing the financial industry. In 2017, when the academic finance community was not actively researching FinTech, the editorial team of the Review of Financial Studies launched a competition to develop research proposals focused on this topic. This special issue is the result. In this introductory article, we describe the recent FinTech phenomenon and the novel editorial protocol employed for this special issue following the Registered Reports format. We discuss what we learned from the submitted proposals about the field of FinTech and which ones we selected to be completed and ultimately come out in this special issue. We also provide several observations to help guide future research in the emerging area of FinTech.</description><author>Goldstein, Itay; Jiang, Wei; Karolyi, G. Andrew</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Private Equity and Financial Fragility during the Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernstein, Shai; Lerner, Josh; Mezzanotti, Filippo
Does private equity (PE) contribute to financial fragility during economic crises? The proliferation of poorly structured transactions during booms may increase the vulnerability of the economy to downturns. During the 2008 crisis, PE-backed companies decreased investments less than did their peers and experienced greater equity and debt inflows, higher asset growth, and increased market share. These effects are especially strong among financially constrained companies and those whose PE investors had more resources at the crisis onset. In a survey, PE firms report being active investors during the crisis and spending more time working with their portfolio companies.</description><author>Bernstein, Shai; Lerner, Josh; Mezzanotti, Filippo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Riding the Bubble with Convex Incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sotes-Paladino, Juan; Zapatero, Fernando
We show that benchmark-linked convex incentives can lead risk-averse money managers aware of mispricing to overinvest in overpriced securities. In the model, the managers' risk-seeking behavior varies in response to the interaction of mispricing with convexity and benchmarking concerns. Convexity effects can exacerbate the manager's overinvestment in overvalued nonbenchmark securities. In contrast, they potentially offset the benchmarking effects studied in the literature, leading to underinvestment in overpriced benchmark securities. Under correlated mispricing across assets, our model rationalizes positive positions in nonbenchmark, negative risk premium (i.e., bubble) securities and pairs trading in two overvalued securities. Our findings help explain several empirical puzzles.</description><author>Sotes-Paladino, Juan; Zapatero, Fernando</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Shocks to Personal Wealth Affect Risk-taking in Delegated Portfolios?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pool, Veronika K.; Stoffman, Noah; Yonker, Scott E.; Zhang, Hanjiang
Using exogenous wealth shocks stemming from the collapse of the housing market, we show that managers who experience substantial losses in their home values subsequently reduce risk in their delegated funds. The decline in fund risk comes through reductions in idiosyncratic risk and tracking error, suggesting that the behavior is likely driven by career concerns. Our paper provides evidence that idiosyncratic personal preferences affect mutual fund managers' professional decisions and offers a methodology for testing for manager effects that is not subject to the selection critique of Fee, Hadlock, and Pierce (2013).</description><author>Pool, Veronika K.; Stoffman, Noah; Yonker, Scott E.; Zhang, Hanjiang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inventory Behavior and Financial Constraints: Theory and Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dasgupta, Sudipto; Li, Erica X. N.; Yan, Dong
We model the interaction of financial constraints, capacity constraints, and the response of production and inventory to cost and demand shocks. The model predicts that in response to favorable shocks, financially constrained firms are unable to build inventory as rapidly as are unconstrained firms. However, because the favorable shocks gradually ease the financial constraints, constrained firms continue to build inventory and eventually carry surplus inventory (relative to unconstrained firms) to unfavorable states. This allows them to deplete inventory more aggressively in response to unfavorable shocks. Our empirical evidence provides broad support for the model's predictions. Received September 3, 2016; editorial decision January 11, 2018 by Editor David Denis. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Dasgupta, Sudipto; Li, Erica X. N.; Yan, Dong</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic Risk and Idiosyncratic Risk-taking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Zhiyao; Strebulaev, Ilya A.
We develop and estimate a dynamic model of risk-shifting over the business cycle. First, equity holders with Epstein-Zin preferences increase their taking of idiosyncratic risk substantially more than the standard model in repeated games, because they perceive the arrival probability of bad states to be higher than the actual probability and prefer an early resolution of macroeconomic uncertainty. Second, sudden switches to bad states and large shocks in the bad states induce the countercyclical and synchronized idiosyncratic risk. Third, combined with the high market risk premium in the bad states, clustered risk-taking generates a countercyclical idiosyncratic volatility discount on equity returns. Received July 1, 2017; editorial decision January 22, 2018 by Editor Stijn Van Nieuwerburgh. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Chen, Zhiyao; Strebulaev, Ilya A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Grown-up Business Cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pugsley, Benjamin Wild; Sahin, Aysegul
The entry rate of U.S. employer businesses has declined for more than 30 years. We use a novel dynamic decomposition framework to show that regardless of its causes, the direct effects of the continued decline in the entry rate and its delayed effects on the firm age distribution together play a major role in the slowing of trend employment growth and the emergence of jobless recoveries. We identify changing demographic structure of the population and increased import competition as leading factors behind the decline in startup activity. Received September 1, 2015; editorial decision April 5, 2018 by Editor Francesca Cornelli. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Pugsley, Benjamin Wild; Sahin, Aysegul</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Discrete Price Fragments US Stock Exchanges and Disperses Their Fee Structures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chao, Yong; Yao, Chen; Ye, Mao
Stock exchange operators compete for order flow by setting make fees for limit orders and take fees for market orders. When traders can quote continuous prices, exchange operators compete on total fee, because traders can choose prices that perfectly neutralize any fee division. The 1-cent minimum tick size, however, prevents traders from neutralizing fee division. The nonneutrality of division between make and take fees (1) allows an exchange operator to establish exchanges that differ in fee structure to engage in second-degree price discrimination and (2) destroys the Bertrand equilibrium, leads to frequent fee changes, and encourages entries of new exchanges. Received May 29, 2016; editorial decision April 19, 2018 by Editor Robin Greenwood. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Chao, Yong; Yao, Chen; Ye, Mao</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High-Frequency Market Making to Large Institutional Trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Korajczyk, Robert A.; Murphy, Dermot
We study market-making high-frequency trader (HFT) dynamics around large institutional trades in Canadian equities markets using order-level data with masked trader identification. Following a regulatory change that negatively affected HFT order activity, we find that bid-ask spreads increased and price impact decreased for institutional trades. The decrease in price impact is strongest for informed institutional traders. During institutional trade executions, HFTs submit more same-direction orders and increase their inventory mean reversion rates. Our evidence indicates that high-frequency trading is associated with lower transaction costs for small, uninformed trades and higher transaction costs for large, informed trades. Received May 24, 2016; editorial decision June 21, 2018 by Editor Andrew Karolyi. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Korajczyk, Robert A.; Murphy, Dermot</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information, Trading, and Volatility: Evidence from Firm-Specific News</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boudoukh, Jacob; Feldman, Ronen; Kogan, Shimon; Richardson, Matthew
What moves stock prices? Prior literature concludes that the revelation of private information through trading, and not public news, is the primary driver. We revisit the question by using textual analysis to identify fundamental information in news. We find that this information accounts for 49.6% of overnight idiosyncratic volatility (vs. 12.4% during trading hours), with a considerable fraction due to days with multiple news types. We use our measure of public information arrival to reinvestigate two important contributions in the literature related to individual s of stock returns on aggregate factors. Received February 24, 2016; editorial decision May 19, 2018 by Editor Andrew Karolyi.</description><author>Boudoukh, Jacob; Feldman, Ronen; Kogan, Shimon; Richardson, Matthew</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the Value of Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kadan, Ohad; Manela, Asaf
We derive a general expression for the value of information to a price-taking investor in a dynamic environment and provide a framework for its estimation. We study the value of both private and public information and break it into its instrumental and psychic parts. To illustrate, we estimate and rank the values of leading macroeconomic indicators (GDP, employment, etc.). Using variations in option prices, we find that consumer-investors with conventional preference parameters would pay 3 to 5 bps of their wealth for a one-time private peek into these indicators. Such signals provide substantial instrumental value but a minor psychic value. Received August 29, 2016; editorial decision June 6, 2018 by Editor Itay Goldstein. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Kadan, Ohad; Manela, Asaf</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Strategy, Conformism, and the Stock Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foucault, Thierry; Fresard, Laurent
We show that product differentiation reduces the informativeness of a firm's stock price (or its peers' stock prices) about the value of its growth opportunities. This results in less efficient exercise of a firm's growth options when managers rely on information in stock prices for their decisions. This informational cost of differentiation induces conformity in product market strategies and is larger for private firms. Hence, a firm should differentiate more after going public. We confirm this prediction empirically and show that the post-IPO increase in differentiation is stronger for firms with better informed managers or less informative peers' stock prices. Received January 19, 2016; editorial decision May 8, 2018 by Editor Itay Goldstein. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Foucault, Thierry; Fresard, Laurent</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investing for Impact</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chowdhry, Bhagwan; Davies, Shaun William; Waters, Brian
We study joint financing between profit-motivated and socially motivated (impact) investors and derive conditions under which impact investments improve social outcomes. When project owners cannot commit to social objectives, impact investors hold financial claims to counterbalance owners' tendencies to overemphasize profits. Impact investors' ownership stakes are higher when the value of social output is higher, and pure nonprofit status may be optimal for the highest valued social projects. We provide guidance about the design of contingent social contracts, such as social impact bonds and social impact guarantees. Received May 23, 2016; editorial decision April 28, 2018 by Editor Francesca Cornelli. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Chowdhry, Bhagwan; Davies, Shaun William; Waters, Brian</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing Entrepreneurial Production: Security Design with Flexible Information Acquisition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yang, Ming; Zeng, Yao
We propose a theory of security design in financing entrepreneurial production, positing that the investor can acquire costly information on the entrepreneur's project before making the financing decision. When the entrepreneur has enough bargaining power in security design, the optimal security helps incentivize both efficient information acquisition and efficient financing. Debt is optimal when information is not very valuable for production, whereas the combination of debt and equity is optimal when information is valuable. If, instead, the investor has sufficiently strong bargaining power in security design or can acquire information only after financing, equity is optimal. Received October 12, 2015; editorial decision February 10, 2018 by Editor Itay Goldstein.</description><author>Yang, Ming; Zeng, Yao</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Arbitrage Trading: The Long and the Short of It</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Yong; Da, Zhi; Huang, Dayong
We examine net arbitrage trading (NAT) measured by the difference between quarterly abnormal hedge fund holdings and abnormal short interest. NAT strongly predicts stock returns in the cross-section. Across ten well-known stock anomalies, abnormal returns are realized only among stocks experiencing large NAT. Exploiting Regulation SHO, which facilitated short selling for a random group of stocks, we present causal evidence that NAT has stronger return predictability among stocks facing greater limits to arbitrage. We also find large returns for anomalies that arbitrageurs chose to exploit despite capital constraints during the 2007-09 financial crisis. We confirm our findings using daily data.</description><author>Chen, Yong; Da, Zhi; Huang, Dayong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Protocol for Factor Identification</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pukthuanthong, Kuntara; Roll, Richard; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
We propose a protocol for identifying genuine risk factors. A genuine risk factor must be related to the covariance matrix of returns, must be priced in the cross-section of returns, and should yield a reward-to-risk ratio that is reasonable enough to be consistent with risk pricing. A market factor, a profitability factor, and traded versions of macroeconomic factors pass our protocol, but many characteristic-based factors do not. Several of the underlying characteristics, however, do command premiums in the cross-section.</description><author>Pukthuanthong, Kuntara; Roll, Richard; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exploration Activity, Long-run Decisions, and the Risk Premium in Energy Futures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>David, Alexander
Investment by oil firms positively affects the futures basis and negatively predicts excess returns on crude oil futures. I build an equilibrium model of drilling, exploration, and storage to understand these facts. Firms' capital stock lowers extraction costs as firms drill in increasingly expensive fields. Drilled wells produce the resource at a geometrically declining rate; however, by specifying consumers' habit level equaling production from old wells, the futures basis and risk premium are only related to drilling, investment, and inventory. Investment leads to a more elastic drilling response by firms and dampens oil price increases from demand shocks, thus lowering the risk premium.</description><author>David, Alexander</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limited Stock Market Participation Among Renters and Homeowners</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vestman, Roine
The stock market participation rate among homeowners is twice as high as among renters. This paper builds a life-cycle portfolio choice model with endogenous housing tenure choice. A stylized form of preference heterogeneity generates a substantial difference in participation rates. A majority of households have a large savings motive and choose to be homeowners and participate. A minority of households have a small savings motive and find it less worthwhile to participate. Fewer of these households become homeowners. Difference-in-difference regressions on panel data do not find evidence of a crowding-out effect of homeownership on participation, supporting the message that preference heterogeneity matters.</description><author>Vestman, Roine</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interfund Lending in Mutual Fund Families: Role in Liquidity Management</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Vikas; Zhao, Haibei
The Investment Company Act of 1940 restricts interfund lending and borrowing within a mutual fund family, but families can apply for regulatory exemptions to participate in such transactions. We find that the monitoring mechanisms and investment restrictions influence the family's decision to apply for the interfund lending programs. We document several benefits of such programs for equity funds. First, participating funds reduce cash holdings and increase investments in illiquid assets. Second, fund investors exhibit less run-like behavior. Third, it helps mitigate asset fire sales after extreme investor redemptions. Offsetting these benefits, money market funds in participating families experience investor outflows.</description><author>Agarwal, Vikas; Zhao, Haibei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Markets with Trade on Risk and Return</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Smith, Kevin
In this paper, I develop a model in which risk-averse investors possess private information regarding both a stock's expected payoff and its risk. These investors trade in the stock and a derivative whose payoff is driven by the stock's risk. In equilibrium, the derivative is used to speculate on the stock's risk and to hedge against adverse fluctuations in the stock's risk. I analyze the derivative price and variance risk premium that arise in this equilibrium and their predictive power for stock returns. Finally, I examine the relationship between prices and trading volume in the stock and derivative.</description><author>Smith, Kevin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Returns to Talent and the Finance Wage Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Celerier, Claire; Vallee, Boris
To study the role of talent in finance workers' pay, we exploit a special feature of the French higher education system. Wage returns to talent have been significantly higher and have risen faster since the 1980s in finance than in other sectors. Both wage returns to project size and the elasticity of project size to talent are also higher in this industry. Last, the share of performance pay varies more for talent in finance. These findings are supportive of finance wages reflecting the competitive assignment of talent in an industry that exhibits a high complementarity between talent and scale.</description><author>Celerier, Claire; Vallee, Boris</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Matching in Housing Markets: The Role of Ethnic Social Networks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Sumit; Choi, Hyun-Soo; He, Jia; Sing, Tien Foo
This paper investigates the role of ethnic matching between buyers and sellers in Singapore's public housing market. We find that sellers sell homes in blocks with a high concentration of their own (other) ethnic group(s) at significant premiums (discounts). Chinese sellers earn 1.7% higher premiums when selling homes to Chinese buyers in high Chinese concentrations housing blocks, but Malay sellers accept 1.6% discounts from Malay buyers in the same blocks. We find that the high volume of within-ethnicity transactions with the price discounts is supported by the ethnic social networks, that is, through ethnicity-specialized real estate agents.</description><author>Agarwal, Sumit; Choi, Hyun-Soo; He, Jia; Sing, Tien Foo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Teachers Teaching Teachers: The Role of Workplace Peer Effects in Financial Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Maturana, Gonzalo; Nickerson, Jordan
This paper studies the role of workplace peers in the transmission of information pertinent to an important household financial decision: the mortgage refinancing choice. Exploiting commonalities in teaching schedules of school teachers in Texas to identify peer groups, we find that refinancing activity among teachers' peers increases their likelihood of refinancing by 20.7%. The effect of peers increases with the potential savings realized upon refinancing and is stronger among younger teachers. Peers also affect teachers' choice of lender. Overall, our findings suggest that peer interactions greatly reduce a household's cost of acquiring and processing financial information.</description><author>Maturana, Gonzalo; Nickerson, Jordan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Noncognitive Abilities and Financial Distress: Evidence from a Representative Household Panel</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Parise, Gianpaolo; Peijnenburg, Kim
This paper provides evidence of how noncognitive abilities affect financial distress. In a representative panel of households, we find that people in the bottom quintile of noncognitive abilities are 10 times more likely to experience financial distress than those in the top quintile. We provide evidence that this relation largely arises from worse financial choices and lack of financial insight by low-ability individuals and reflects differential exposure to income shocks only to a lesser degree. We mitigate endogeneity concerns using an IV approach and an extensive set of controls. Implications for policy and finance research are discussed.</description><author>Parise, Gianpaolo; Peijnenburg, Kim</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Persistence of Financial Distress</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Athreya, Kartik; Mustre-del-Rio, Jose; Sanchez, Juan M.
Using proprietary panel data, we show that many U.S. consumers experience financial distress (35% when distress is defined by having debt in severe delinquency, e.g.) at some point in their lives. However, most distress events are concentrated on a much smaller proportion of consumers in persistent trouble: fewer than 10% of borrowers account for half of all distress events. These facts can be largely accounted for in a straightforward extension of a workhorse model of unsecured debt with informal default that accommodates a simple form of heterogeneity in time preference.</description><author>Athreya, Kartik; Mustre-del-Rio, Jose; Sanchez, Juan M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding Mortgage Spreads</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyarchenko, Nina; Fuster, Andreas; Lucca, David O.
Because most mortgages in the United States are securitized in agency mortgage-backed securities (MBS), yield spreads on MBS are a key determinant of homeowners' funding costs. We study variation in MBS spreads in the time series and across securities and document that MBS spreads show a pronounced cross-sectional smile with respect to the securities' coupon rates. We present a new pricing model that uses "stripped" MBS prices to identify the contribution of non-interest-rate prepayment risk to spreads and find that this risk explains the smile, whereas the time-series spread variation is mostly accounted for by nonprepayment risk factors.</description><author>Boyarchenko, Nina; Fuster, Andreas; Lucca, David O.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Supply Side of Household Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foa, Gabriele; Gambacorta, Leonardo; Guiso, Luigi; Mistrulli, Paolo Emilio
Using matched borrower-lender data, we document strong nonprice supplier effects in mortgage contract choice. For given relative price of adjustable and fixed rate mortgages, households borrowing from banks hit by shocks to the cost of long term funding, or to the deposits base or to access to securitization are more likely to choose adjustable rate mortgages. Supply factors have larger effects on less-sophisticated households and at times of price inaction. A model in which banks affect borrowers' choices through prices and distorted advice predicts these findings. We contrast the distorted advice interpretation of the evidence against the potential alternative nonprice channels.</description><author>Foa, Gabriele; Gambacorta, Leonardo; Guiso, Luigi; Mistrulli, Paolo Emilio</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Life below Zero: Bank Lending under Negative Policy Rates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heider, Florian; Saidi, Farzad; Schepens, Glenn
We show that negative policy rates affect the supply of bank credit in a novel way. Banks are reluctant to pass on negative rates to depositors, which increases the funding cost of high-deposit banks, and reduces their net worth, relative to low-deposit banks. As a consequence, the introduction of negative policy rates by the European Central Bank in mid-2014 leads to more risk-taking and less lending by euro-area banks with a greater reliance on deposit funding. Our results suggest that negative rates are less accommodative and could pose a risk to financial stability, if lending is done by high-deposit banks.</description><author>Heider, Florian; Saidi, Farzad; Schepens, Glenn</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Resolution and the Structure of Global Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Patrick; Oehmke, Martin
We study the resolution of global banks by national regulators. Single-point-of-entry (SPOE) resolution, where loss-absorbing capital is shared across jurisdictions, is efficient but faces implementation constraints. First, when expected transfers across jurisdictions are too asymmetric, national regulators fail to set up SPOE resolution ex ante. Second, when required ex post transfers are too large, national regulators ring-fence assets instead of cooperating in SPOE resolution. In this case, a multiple-point-of-entry (MPOE) resolution, where loss-absorbing capital is preassigned, is more robust. Our analysis highlights a fundamental link between efficient bank resolution, the operational structures, risks, and incentives of global banks.</description><author>Bolton, Patrick; Oehmke, Martin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Sector Stress and Risk Sharing: Evidence from the Weather Derivatives Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weagley, Daniel
I examine the effect of financial sector stress on risk sharing in a novel setting: the CME's weather derivatives market. The structure of the market allows me to disentangle price movements due to financial sector stress from price movements due to fundamentals. Contracts, which are typically priced near their actuarially fair value, experience significant price declines during periods of financial sector stress. Contracts with greater margin requirements and total risk are the most affected. The results provide causal evidence of the effect of financial sector stress on the pricing of exchange-traded financial contracts and risk sharing in the economy.</description><author>Weagley, Daniel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Encumbrance, Bank Funding, and Fragility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahnert, Toni; Anand, Kartik; Gai, Prasanna; Chapman, James
We model asset encumbrance by banks subject to rollover risk and study the consequences for fragility, funding costs, and prudential regulation. A bank's privately optimal encumbrance choice balances the benefit of expanding profitable, yet illiquid, investment funded by cheap long-term senior secured debt, against the cost of greater fragility from runs on unsecured debt. We derive testable implications about encumbrance ratios. The introduction of deposit insurance or wholesale funding guarantees induces excessive encumbrance and fragility. Limits on asset encumbrance or Pigovian taxes eliminate such risk-shifting incentives. Our results shed light on prudential policies currently being pursued in several jurisdictions.</description><author>Ahnert, Toni; Anand, Kartik; Gai, Prasanna; Chapman, James</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Social Risk, Fiscal Risk, and the Portfolio of Government Programs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanson, Samuel G.; Scharfstein, David S.; Sunderam, Adi
We develop a model of government portfolio choice in which the government chooses the scale of risky projects in the presence of market failures and tax distortions. These frictions motivate the government to manage social risk and fiscal risk. Social risk management favors programs that ameliorate market failures in bad times. Fiscal risk management makes unattractive programs involving large government outlays when other government programs also require large outlays. These two risk management motives often conflict. Using the model, we explore how the attractiveness of different financial stability programs varies with the government's fiscal burden and characteristics of the economy. (JEL G11, G28, G32)</description><author>Hanson, Samuel G.; Scharfstein, David S.; Sunderam, Adi</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contingent Convertibles with Stock Price Triggers: The Case of Perpetuities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pennacchi, George; Tchistyi, Alexei
Initial proposals for contingent convertibles (CoCos) envisioned that these bonds would convert to equity when the issuing bank's stock price declined to a prespecified trigger. Subsequent research has claimed that doing so causes the stock price to have multiple equilibria or no equilibrium. We show that when CoCos are perpetuities, which characterizes most actual CoCos, a unique stock price equilibrium exists, except under unrealistic conditions. Unique equilibria occur when conversion favors or disfavors CoCo investors, when CoCos convert to equity or are written down, and when CoCos are callable. We also analyze a bank's risk choices before and after conversion.</description><author>Pennacchi, George; Tchistyi, Alexei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional Investors and Information Acquisition: Implications for Asset Prices and Informational Efficiency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breugem, Matthijs; Buss, Adrian
We study the joint portfolio and information choice problem of institutional investors who are concerned about their performance relative to a benchmark. Benchmarking influences information choices through two distinct economic mechanisms. First, benchmarking reduces the number of shares in investors' portfolios that are sensitive to information. Hence, the value of private information declines. Second, benchmarking limits investors' willingness to speculate. This not only reduces the value of private information but also adversely affects information aggregation. In equilibrium, investors acquire less information and informational efficiency declines. As a result, return volatility increases, and less-benchmarked institutional investors outperform more-benchmarked ones.</description><author>Breugem, Matthijs; Buss, Adrian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Silence Golden? Real Effects of Mandatory Disclosure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jayaraman, Sudarshan; Wu, Joanna Shuang
Mandatory disclosure provides benefits, but it also entails costs. One cost concerns managerial learning: by discouraging informed trading, disclosure could reduce managers' ability to glean decision-relevant information from prices. Using mandatory segment reporting in the United States, we uncover a reduction in investment-q sensitivity, indicating lower investment efficiency after regulation. Consistent with learning, lower sensitivity is concentrated in firms with more informed trading and lower financing constraints. Constrained firms exhibit no change in investment-q sensitivity, suggesting that they enjoy countervailing benefits via greater financing and stronger governance. Overall, we document a novel link between mandatory disclosure and real effects.</description><author>Jayaraman, Sudarshan; Wu, Joanna Shuang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Analyst Career Concerns, Effort Allocation, and Firms' Information Environment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harford, Jarrad; Jiang, Feng; Wang, Rong; Xie, Fei
Analysts strategically allocate more effort to portfolio firms that are relatively more important to their careers. Thus, the other firms the analysts cover indirectly affect a firm's information environment. Controlling for analyst and firm characteristics, we find that an analyst makes more accurate, frequent, and informative earnings forecasts and recommendations for firms ranked higher within her portfolio based on proxies for importance to institutions. A firm's relative rank widely varies across analysts, but its information environment improves when a larger proportion of analysts consider it to be relatively important. Analysts experience more favorable career outcomes when strategically allocating their efforts.</description><author>Harford, Jarrad; Jiang, Feng; Wang, Rong; Xie, Fei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unleashing Animal Spirits: Self-Control and Overpricing in Experimental Asset Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kocher, Martin G.; Lucks, Konstantin E.; Schindler, David
One explanation for overpricing on asset markets is a lack of traders' self-control. We implement the first experiment to address the causal relationship between self-control and systematic overpricing on financial markets. Our setup detects some of the channels through which low individual self-control could transmit into irrational exuberance in markets. Our data indicate a large direct effect of reduced self-control on market overpricing. Low self-control traders report stronger emotions after the market.</description><author>Kocher, Martin G.; Lucks, Konstantin E.; Schindler, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Low Interest Rates and Risk-Taking: Evidence from Individual Investment Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lian, Chen; Ma, Yueran; Wang, Carmen
How do low interest rates affect investor behavior? We demonstrate that individuals reach for yield, that is, have a greater appetite for risk-taking when interest rates are low. Using randomized investment experiments holding fixed risk premiums and risks, we show low interest rates lead to significantly higher allocations to risky assets among diverse populations. The behavior is not easily explained by conventional portfolio choice theory or institutional frictions. We then propose and provide evidence of mechanisms related to investor psychology, including reference dependence and salience. We also present results using observational data on household investment decisions.</description><author>Lian, Chen; Ma, Yueran; Wang, Carmen</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading Regularity and Fund Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Busse, Jeffrey A.; Tong, Lin; Tong, Qing; Zhang, Zhe
We construct a new measure of trading regularity, capturing the extent to which investors trade on a regular basis. Institutional investors that regularly trade outperform those that trade less regularly. The performance of funds that regularly trade persists for at least a year. Among those who trade most regularly, larger funds perform relatively worse, because they incur higher transaction costs associated with their larger trades. Institutions that regularly trade generate superior performance, in part, by behaving as contrarians and by trading more aggressively on information. By contrast, we find no relation between trading regularity and performance among index funds. Received November 21, 2016; editorial decision March 28, 2018 by Editor Andrew Karolyi. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Busse, Jeffrey A.; Tong, Lin; Tong, Qing; Zhang, Zhe</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Revealing Downturns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schmalz, Martin C.; Zhuk, Sergey
When Bayesian risk-averse investors are uncertain about their assets' cash flows' exposure to systematic risk, stock prices react to news more in downturns than in upturns, implying higher volatility in downturns and negatively skewed returns. In good times, less desirable assets with low average cash flows and high market risk perform similar to more desirable assets with high average cash flows and low market risk, rendering them difficult to distinguish. However, their performance diverges in downturns, enabling better inference. Consistent with these predictions, stocks' reaction to earnings news is up to 70% stronger in downturns than in upturns. Received July 7, 2014; editorial decision March 20, 2018 by Editor Laura Starks. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Schmalz, Martin C.; Zhuk, Sergey</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heterogeneity in Target Date Funds: Strategic Risk-taking or Risk Matching?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Balduzzi, Pierluigi; Reuter, Jonathan
The use of target date funds (TDFs) as default options in 401(k) plans increased sharply following the Pension Protection Act of 2006. We document large differences in the realized returns and ex ante risk profiles of TDFs with similar target retirement dates. Analyzing fund-level data, we find evidence that this heterogeneity reflects strategic risk-taking by families with low market share, especially those entering the TDF market after 2006. Analyzing plan-level data, we find little evidence that 401(k) plan sponsors consider, to any economically meaningful degree, the risk profiles of their firms when choosing among TDFs. Received June 13, 2013; editorial decision March 20, 2018 by Editor Laura Starks. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Balduzzi, Pierluigi; Reuter, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks Response to Higher Capital Requirements: Evidence from a Quasi-Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gropp, Reint; Mosk, Thomas; Ongena, Steven; Wix, Carlo
We study the impact of higher capital requirements on banks' balance sheets and their transmission to the real economy. The 2011 EBA capital exercise is an almost ideal quasi-natural experiment to identify this impact with a difference-in-differences matching estimator. We find that treated banks increase their capital ratios by reducing their risk-weighted assets, not by raising their levels of equity, consistent with debt overhang. Banks reduce lending to corporate and retail customers, resulting in lower asset, investment, and sales growth for firms obtaining a larger share of their bank credit from the treated banks. Received November 28, 2016; editorial decision March 9, 2018 by Editor Philip Strahan. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which are available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Gropp, Reint; Mosk, Thomas; Ongena, Steven; Wix, Carlo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Demand for Crash Insurance, Intermediary Constraints, and Risk Premia in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hui; Joslin, Scott; Ni, Sophie Xiaoyan
We propose a new measure of financial intermediary constraints based on how intermediaries manage their tail risk exposures. Using data for the trading activities in the market of deep out-of-the-money index put options, we identify periods when the variations in the net amount of trading between financial intermediaries and public investors are likely to be mainly driven by shocks to intermediary constraints. We then infer tightness of intermediary constraints from the quantities of option trading. A tightening of intermediary constraints according to our measure is associated with increasing option expensiveness, higher risk premia, deteriorating funding liquidity, and broker-dealer deleveraging. Received December 1, 2014; editorial decision May 19, 2017 by Editor Geert Bekaert. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Chen, Hui; Joslin, Scott; Ni, Sophie Xiaoyan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The VIX Premium</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheng, Ing-Haw
Ex ante estimates of the volatility premium embedded in VIX futures, known as the VIX premium, fall or stay flat when ex ante measures of risk rise. This is not an artifact of mismeasurement: (i) ex ante premiums reliably predict ex post returns to VIX futures with a coefficient near one, and (ii) falling ex ante premiums predict increasing ex post market and investment risk, creating profitable trading opportunities. Falling hedging demand helps explain this behavior, as premiums and trader exposures tend to fall together when risk rises. These facts provide a puzzle for theories of why investors hedge volatility. Received January 13, 2017; editorial decision April 26, 2018 by Editor Stijn Van Nieuwerburgh. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Cheng, Ing-Haw</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade-Time Measures of Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barardehi, Yashar H.; Bernhardt, Dan; Davies, Ryan J.
Dramatic microstructure changes in equity markets have made standard liquidity measures less accurate proxies for trading costs. We develop trade-time liquidity measures that reflect per-dollar price impacts of fixed-dollar volumes. Our measures better capture institutional trading costs and better explain the cross-section of returns than do standard measures, especially in recent years. Despite improvements in measures of market quality, expected trading costs have explanatory power for the cross-section of expected returns: we obtain monthly liquidity premium estimates of 5.3 bp for expected returns and 2.4 bp for risk-adjusted returns. Estimated premiums rise after the financial crisis and remain high thereafter. Received April 15, 2016; editorial decision December 24, 2017 by Editor Andrew Karolyi.</description><author>Barardehi, Yashar H.; Bernhardt, Dan; Davies, Ryan J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Characteristic-Based Benchmark Returns and Corporate Events</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Cooper, Michael J.; Zhang, Feng
We propose that fitted values from market-wide regressions of firm returns on lagged firm characteristics provide useful benchmarks for assessing whether average returns to certain stocks are abnormal. To illustrate, we study eight documented events with abnormal returns, including credit rating and analyst recommendation downgrades, initial and seasoned public equity offerings, mergers and acquisitions, dividend initiations, share repurchases, and stock splits. We show that the apparently abnormal returns in the months after these events are substantially reduced or eliminated when compared to characteristic-based benchmarks. Characteristic-based benchmarks perform better in explaining post-event returns than do recent four- and five-factor models. Received September 19, 2016; editorial decision February 16, 2018 by Editor Andrew Karolyi. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web Site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Cooper, Michael J.; Zhang, Feng</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Relevance of Credit Ratings in Transparent Bond Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Badoer, Dominique C.; Demiroglu, Cem
Mandated public dissemination of over-the-counter transactions in corporate debt securities via the TRACE system dramatically reduces the average short-term market reaction to rating downgrades by both issuer-paid and investor-paid rating agencies. Ratings become relatively more accurate predictors of default and more sensitive to innovations in credit spreads after the introduction of dissemination. However, in transparent markets, they provide no significant information about future defaults beyond that provided by credit spreads. Dissemination increases the efficiency of information aggregation and transmission in bond markets, thereby reducing the incremental information content of ratings and the price impact of rating revisions. Received June 8, 2017; editorial decision January 24, 2018 by Editor Philip Strahan. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Badoer, Dominique C.; Demiroglu, Cem</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Cost of Immediacy for Corporate Bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dick-Nielsen, Jens; Rossi, Marco
Liquidity provision for corporate bonds has become significantly more expensive after the 2008 crisis. Using index exclusions as a natural experiment during which uninformed index trackers request immediacy, we find that the cost of immediacy has more than doubled. In addition, the supply of immediacy has become more elastic with respect to its price. Consistent with a stringent regulatory environment incentivizing smaller dealer inventories, we also find that dealers revert deviations from their target inventory more quickly after the crisis. Finally, we investigate the pricing impact of information, changes in ownership structure, and differences between bank and nonbank dealers. Received February 22, 2017; editorial decision May 29, 2018 by Editor Itay Goldstein. Authors have furnished an Internet Appendix, which is available on the Oxford University Press Web site next to the link to the final published paper online.</description><author>Dick-Nielsen, Jens; Rossi, Marco</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hostile Resistance to Hedge Fund Activism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boyson, Nicole M.; Pichler, Pegaret
When facing hedge fund activists, target firms often fight back. Targets with agency problems and those confronting the threat of investor coordination frequently engage in hostile resistance by implementing governance changes associated with managerial entrenchment. The market negatively responds to hostile resistance, and unless hedge funds counterresist, these campaigns have worse operating performance, faster activist exit, and fewer mergers than do campaigns without hostile target resistance. By contrast, when hedge funds counterresist with proxy fights, lawsuits, or unsolicited tender offers, the impact of hostile target resistance is reversed, and these campaigns have similar outcomes to campaigns without hostile target resistance.</description><author>Boyson, Nicole M.; Pichler, Pegaret</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>International Corporate Governance Spillovers: Evidence from Cross-Border Mergers and Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albuquerque, Rui; Brandao-Marques, Luis; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro
We test the hypothesis that foreign direct investment promotes corporate governance spillovers in the host country. Using firm-level data from 64 countries during the period 2005-2014, we find that cross-border M&amp;A activity is associated with subsequent improvements in the governance of nontarget firms when the acquirer country has stronger investor protection than the target country. The effect is more pronounced when the target industry is more competitive. Cross-border M&amp;As are also associated with increases in investment and valuation of nontarget firms. Alternative explanations, such as access to global financial markets and cultural similarities, do not appear to explain our findings.</description><author>Albuquerque, Rui; Brandao-Marques, Luis; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Comparables Pricing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Murfin, Justin; Pratt, Ryan
Finance professionals commonly set prices based on the analysis of recently closed, comparable transactions. Using data on syndicated loans, we exploit the lag between loans' closing dates and their inclusion in a widely used comparables database to identify the effect of past transactions on new transaction pricing. Comparables pricing is an important determinant of individual loan spreads, but a failure to account for overlap in information across loans leads to pricing mistakes. Comparables used repeatedly are overweighted as they develop redundant channels of influence on later transactions. Market conditions prevailing at the time a comparable was priced also unduly influence subsequent loans.</description><author>Murfin, Justin; Pratt, Ryan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Option Pricing of Earnings Announcement Risks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dubinsky, Andrew; Johannes, Michael; Kaeck, Andreas; Seeger, Norman J.
This paper uses option prices to learn about the equity price uncertainty surrounding information released on earnings announcement dates. To do this, we introduce reduced-form models and estimators to separate price uncertainty about earnings announcements from normal day-to-day volatility. Empirically, we find strong support for the importance of earnings announcements. We find that the anticipated price uncertainty is quantitatively large, varies across time, and is informative about the future return volatility. Finally, we quantify the impact of earnings announcements on formal option pricing models.</description><author>Dubinsky, Andrew; Johannes, Michael; Kaeck, Andreas; Seeger, Norman J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informed Trading by Advisor Banks: Evidence from Options Holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lowry, Michelle; Rossi, Marco; Zhu, Zhongyan
Strong conflicts of interest exist within investment banks: the investment banking division possesses substantial private information, and the asset management division seeks such information. This raises the question of whether the asset management division benefits from an information advantage on client firms. While prior examinations of advisor bank trading in client firms have focused on stocks and found mixed results, we argue that the options market represents a more attractive venue for such trading. We find significant evidence of advisor banks trading in client firm options ahead of merger announcements, but no evidence of similar trading in client firm stock.</description><author>Lowry, Michelle; Rossi, Marco; Zhu, Zhongyan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Organizational Hierarchy Affects Information Production</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Skrastins, Janis; Vig, Vikrant
We exploit a variation in organizational hierarchy induced by a reorganization plan implemented in roughly 2,000 bank branches in India. We do so to investigate how organizational hierarchy affects the allocation of credit. We find that increased hierarchization of a branch induces credit rationing, reduces loan performance, and generates standardization in loan contracts. Additionally, we find that hierarchical structures perform better in environments characterized by a high degree of corruption, highlighting the benefits of hierarchies in restraining rent-seeking activities. Overall, our results are consistent with the view that valuable information may be lost in hierarchical structures.</description><author>Skrastins, Janis; Vig, Vikrant</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Birds of a Feather: The Impact of Homophily on the Propensity to Follow Financial Advice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stolper, Oscar; Walter, Andreas
Homophilyindividuals' affinity for others like themis a powerful principle that governs whose opinions people attend to. Using nearly 2,400 advisory meetings, we find that homophily has a significant positive impact on the likelihood of following financial advice. The increased likelihood of following stems from homophily on gender and age for male clients and from sameness on marital and parental status for female advisees. Moreover, the homophily effect is mitigated by reduced information asymmetry between client and advisor and a long-term relationship with the bank. Our results suggest that client-advisor matching increases individuals' propensity to follow financial advice.</description><author>Stolper, Oscar; Walter, Andreas</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Payday Loans Affect Borrowers? Evidence from the UK Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gathergood, John; Guttman-Kenney, Benedict; Hunt, Stefan
Payday loans are controversial high-cost, short-term lending products, banned in many U.S. states. But debates surrounding their benefits to consumers continue. We analyze the effects of payday loans on consumers by using a unique data set including 99% of loans approved in the United Kingdom over a two-year period matched to credit files. Using a regression discontinuity research design, our results show that payday loans provide short-lived liquidity gains and encourage consumers to take on additional credit. However, in the following months, payday loans cause persistent increases in defaults and cause consumers to exceed their bank overdraft limits.</description><author>Gathergood, John; Guttman-Kenney, Benedict; Hunt, Stefan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What's the Catch? Suspicion of Bank Motives and Sluggish Refinancing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Johnson, Eric J.; Meier, Stephan; Toubia, Olivier
Failing to refinance a mortgage can cost a borrower thousands of dollars. Based on administrative data from a large financial institution, we show that around 50% of borrowers leave thousands of dollars on the table by not refinancing. Survey data indicate that, among all the behavioral factors examined, only suspicion of banks' motives is consistently related to the probability of accepting a refinancing offer. Finally, we report the results of three field experiments showing that enticing offers made by banks fail to increase participation and may even deepen suspicion. Our findings highlight the important role of trust in financial decisions.</description><author>Johnson, Eric J.; Meier, Stephan; Toubia, Olivier</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Supply and the Rise in College Tuition: Evidence from the Expansion in Federal Student Aid Programs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lucca, David O.; Nadauld, Taylor; Shen, Karen
We study the link between the student credit expansion of the past 15 years and the contemporaneous rise in college tuition. To disentangle simultaneity issues, we analyze the effects of increases in federal student loan caps using detailed student-level financial data. We find a pass-through effect on tuition of changes in subsidized loan maximums of about 60 cents on the dollar and of about 20 cents on the dollar for unsubsidized federal loans. The effect is most pronounced for more expensive degrees and degrees offered by for-profit and 2-year institutions.</description><author>Lucca, David O.; Nadauld, Taylor; Shen, Karen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Mutual Fund Managers Paid for Investment Skill? (vol 31, pg 715, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ibert, Markus; Kaniel, Ron; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn; Vestman, Roine
nan</description><author>Ibert, Markus; Kaniel, Ron; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn; Vestman, Roine</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating and Testing Dynamic Corporate Finance Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bazdresch, Santiago; Kahn, R. Jay; Whited, Toni M.
We assess the finite sample performance of simulation estimators that are used to estimate the parameters of dynamic corporate finance models. We formulate an external validity specification test and propose a new set of statistical benchmarks that can be used to estimate and evaluate these models. These benchmarks are based on model policy functions. Our Monte Carlo simulations show that the estimators are largely unbiased with low root mean squared errors. When computed with an optimal weight matrix, the specification tests associated with the estimators are close to correctly sized. These tests have excellent power to detect misspecification.</description><author>Bazdresch, Santiago; Kahn, R. Jay; Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Global Relation between Financial Distress and Equity Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Pengjie; Parsons, Christopher A.; Shen, Jianfeng
This study explores the distress risk anomaly-the tendency for stocks with high credit risk to perform poorly-among 38 countries over two decades. We find a strongly negative relationship between default probabilities and equity returns concentrated among low-capitalization stocks in developed countries in North America and Europe. Although risk-based explanations provide a poor account of these patterns, several pieces of evidence point to a behavioral interpretation, suggesting that stocks of firms in financial distress are temporarily overpriced.</description><author>Gao, Pengjie; Parsons, Christopher A.; Shen, Jianfeng</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Foreign Direct Investment, Trade Credit, and Transmission of Global Liquidity Shocks: Evidence from Chinese Manufacturing Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Shu; Ye, Haichun
We empirically explore a trade credit channel through which foreign direct investment (FDI) firms can propagate global liquidity shocks to the host country despite its tight controls on portfolio flows. In a large sample of Chinese manufacturing firms, we find robust evidence that FDI firms provide more trade credit than local firms during tight domestic credit periods and that a favorable global liquidity shock amplifies FDI firms' advantage in trade credit provision. Moreover, the differential responses of FDI and local firms are stronger in financially more dependent industries or in Chinese provinces with less financial depth.</description><author>Lin, Shu; Ye, Haichun</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does a CEO's Cultural Heritage Affect Performance under Competitive Pressure?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nguyen, Duc Duy; Hagendorff, Jens; Eshraghi, Arman
We exploit variation in the cultural heritage across U.S. CEOs who are the children or grandchildren of immigrants to demonstrate that the cultural origins of CEOs matter for corporate outcomes. Following shocks to industry competition, firms led by CEOs who are second-or third-generation immigrants are associated with a 6.2% higher profitability compared with the average firm. This effect weakens over successive immigrant generations and cannot be detected for top executives apart from the CEO. Additional analysis attributes this effect to various cultural values that prevail in a CEO's ancestral country of origin.</description><author>Nguyen, Duc Duy; Hagendorff, Jens; Eshraghi, Arman</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Drives Racial and Ethnic Differences in High-Cost Mortgages? The Role of High-Risk Lenders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bayer, Patrick; Ferreira, Fernando; Ross, Stephen L.
This paper examines racial and ethnic differences in high-cost mortgage lending in seven diverse metropolitan areas from 2004 to 2007. Controlling for credit score and other risk factors, AfricanAmerican and Hispanic borrowers are 103% and 78% more likely to receive high-cost mortgages for home purchases. Alarge part of the increase is attributable to sorting across lenders (55%-65%), and this, in turn, can be largely accounted for by the lender's ex post foreclosure risk. The remaining within-lender differences are also concentrated in high-risk lenders, revealing the central role of these institutions in explaining market-wide racial and ethnic differences.</description><author>Bayer, Patrick; Ferreira, Fernando; Ross, Stephen L.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decomposing Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gerakos, Joseph; Linnainmaa, Juhani T.
Firms move between growth and value because of changes in either size or book value of equity. The value premium is specific to variation in book-to-market that emanates from size changes. A factor based on this variation earns the entire value premium; one based on the remaining variation earns no premium. Hence, not all high book-to-market firms earn the value premium, and some low book-to-market firms earn value-like returns. Many models price portfolios sorted by size and book-to-market. None distinguish firms that earn the value premium from those that have a high book-to-market but do not earn the premium.</description><author>Gerakos, Joseph; Linnainmaa, Juhani T.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Who Captures the Power of the Pen?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>You, Jiaxing; Zhang, Bohui; Zhang, Le
We study how government control affects the roles of the media as an information intermediary and a corporate monitor. Comparing a large sample of news articles written by state-controlled and market-oriented Chinese media, we find that articles by the market-oriented media are more critical, more accurate, more comprehensive, and timelier than those by the state-controlled media. Moreover, only articles by the market-oriented media have a significant corporate governance impact. Subsample analyses, interviews with journalists, and a survey of university students suggest that the market-oriented media's superior effects are explained by their operating efficiency and independence.</description><author>You, Jiaxing; Zhang, Bohui; Zhang, Le</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Winning by Losing: Evidence on the Long-run Effects of Mergers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malmendier, Ulrike; Moretti, Enrico; Peters, Florian S.
We propose a novel approach for measuring returns to mergers. In a new data set of close bidding contests, we use losers' post-merger performance to construct the counterfactual performance of winners had they not won the contest. Stock returns of winners and losers closely track each other over the 36 months before the merger, corroborating our identification approach. Bidders are also very similar in terms of Tobins q, profitability, and other accounting measures. Over the 3 years after the merger, however, losers outperform winners by 24%. Commonly used methodologies, such as announcement returns, fail to identify acquirer underperformance.</description><author>Malmendier, Ulrike; Moretti, Enrico; Peters, Florian S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Vote Avoidance and Shareholder Voting in Mergers and Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Li, Kai; Liu, Tingting; Wu, Juan
We examine whether, how, and why acquirer shareholder voting matters. We show that acquirers with low institutional ownership, high deal risk, and high agency costs are more likely to bypass shareholder voting. Such acquirers have lower announcement returns and make higher offers than those who do not. To avoid a shareholder vote, acquirers increase equity issuance and cut payouts to raise the portion of cash in mixed-payment deals. Employing a regression discontinuity design, we show a positive effect on acquirer announcement returns concentrated in acquirers with higher institutional ownership. We conclude that shareholder voting mitigates agency problems in corporate acquisitions.</description><author>Li, Kai; Liu, Tingting; Wu, Juan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Deleveraging and Financial Flexibility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeAngelo, Harry; Goncalves, Andrei S.; Stulz, Rene M.
Most firms deleverage from their historical peak market-leverage (ML) ratios to near-zero ML, while also markedly increasing cash balances to high levels. Among 4,476 nonfinancial firms with five or more years of post-peak data, median ML is 0.543 at the peak and 0.026 at the later trough, with a six-year median time from peak to trough and with debt repayment and earnings retention accounting for 93.7% of the median peak-to-trough decline in ML. The findings support theories in which firms deleverage to restore ample financial flexibility and are difficult to reconcile with most firms having materially positive leverage targets.</description><author>DeAngelo, Harry; Goncalves, Andrei S.; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder-Creditor Conflict and Payout Policy: Evidence from Mergers between Lenders and Shareholders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chu, Yongqiang
This paper studies how the conflict of interest between shareholders and creditors affects corporate payout policy. Using mergers between lenders and equity holders of the same firm as shocks to the shareholder-creditor conflict, I find that firms pay out less when there is less conflict between shareholders and creditors, suggesting that the shareholder-creditor conflict induces firms to pay out more at the expense of creditors. The effect is stronger for firms in financial distress.</description><author>Chu, Yongqiang</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Kicking Maturity Down the Road: Early Refinancing and Maturity Management in the Corporate Bond Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Xu, Qiping
This paper examines debt maturity management through early refinancing, where firms retire their outstanding bonds before the due date and simultaneously issue new ones as replacements. Speculative-grade firms frequently refinance their corporate bonds early to extend maturity, particularly under accommodating credit supply conditions, leading to a procyclical maturity structure. In contrast, investment-grade firms do not manage their maturity in the same manner. I exploit the protection period of callable bonds to show that the maturity extension is not driven by unobservable confounding factors. The evidence is consistent with speculative-grade firms dynamically managing maturity to mitigate refinancing risk.</description><author>Xu, Qiping</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lending Standards over the Credit Cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rodano, Giacomo; Serrano-Velarde, Nicolas; Tarantino, Emanuele
We analyze howfirms' segmentation into credit classes affects the lending standards applied by banks to small and medium enterprises over the cycle. We exploit an institutional feature of the Italian credit market that generates a discontinuity in the allocation of comparable firms into the performing and substandard classes of credit risk. In the boom period, segmentation results in a positive interest rate spread between substandard and performing firms. In the bust period, the increase in banks' cost of wholesale funds implies that substandard firms are excluded from credit. These firms then report lower values of production and capital investments.</description><author>Rodano, Giacomo; Serrano-Velarde, Nicolas; Tarantino, Emanuele</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real Effects of the Sovereign Debt Crisis in Europe: Evidence from Syndicated Loans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Eisert, Tim; Eufinger, Christian; Hirsch, Christian
We explore the causes of the credit crunch during the European sovereign debt crisis and its impact on the corporate policies of European firms. Our results show that value impairment in banks' exposures to sovereign debt and the risk-shifting behavior of weakly capitalized banks reduced the probability of firms being granted new syndicated loans by up to 53%. This lending contraction depressed investment, employment, and sales growth of firms affiliated with affected banks. Our estimates based on firm-level data suggest that the credit crunch explains between 44% and 66% of the overall negative real effects suffered by European firms.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Eisert, Tim; Eufinger, Christian; Hirsch, Christian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Notes on Bonds: Illiquidity Feedback During the Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Musto, David; Nini, Greg; Schwarz, Krista
We trace the evolution of extreme illiquidity discounts among Treasury securities during the financial crisis, when bond prices fell more than 6% below more liquid but otherwise identical notes. Using high-resolution data on market quality and trader identities and characteristics, we find that the discounts amplify through feedback loops, where cheaper, less-liquid securities flowto longer-horizon investors, thereby increasing their illiquidity and thus their appeal to these investors. The effect of the widened liquidity gap on transactions costs is further amplified by a surge in the price liquidity providers charge for access to their balance sheets in the crisis.</description><author>Musto, David; Nini, Greg; Schwarz, Krista</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Causal Effect of Stop-Loss and Take-Gain Orders on the Disposition Effect (vol 30, pg 2110, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fischbacher, Urs; Hoffmann, Gerson; Schudy, Simeon
nan</description><author>Fischbacher, Urs; Hoffmann, Gerson; Schudy, Simeon</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monetary Policy Implementation and Financial Vulnerability: Evidence from the Overnight Reverse Repurchase Facility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Alyssa G.; Kandrac, John
In this paper, we examine the Federal Reserve's newest policy tool, known as the overnight reverse repo (ONRRP) facility, to understand its effects on the repo market. Using exogenous variation in the parameters of the ONRRP, we show that private repo activity is crowded out when money funds invest in the ONRRP. Additionally, we find that the ONRRP increases lenders' bargaining power, thereby raising borrower funding costs. Lastly, we show that repo borrowers reallocate to repo backed by riskier collateral and borrow more from ONRRP-ineligible asset managers, both of which could increase financial vulnerability due to instability in dealer funding.</description><author>Anderson, Alyssa G.; Kandrac, John</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Spillovers from Costly Credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Melzer, Brian T.
Low-income households with proximate access to payday loans exhibit greater economic distress, higher take-up of food assistance benefits, and greater delinquency on child support payments than peers without proximate loan access. These findings suggest that borrowing can exacerbate distress, leading borrowers to use transfer programs and to prioritize payday loan payments over other liabilities like child support. In that way, payday lending produces negative externalities-costs imposed on taxpayers that fund transfer programs and nonresident family members that fail to receive child support.</description><author>Melzer, Brian T.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Short-Termism, Turnover Policy, and the Dynamics of Incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Varas, Felipe
I study managerial short-termism in a dynamic model of project development with hidden effort and imperfect observability of quality. The manager can complete the project faster by reducing quality. To preempt this behavior, the principal makes payments contingent on long-term outcomes. I analyze the dynamics of the optimal contract and its implications for the level of managerial turnover. I show that optimal contracts might be stationary and entail no termination. In general, I show that the principal reduces the manager's temptation to behave myopically by reducing the likelihood of termination and deferring compensation. The model predicts a negative relation between the rate of managerial turnover and the use of deferred compensation that is consistent with evidence of managerial compensation contracts.</description><author>Varas, Felipe</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Price Dynamics in Partially Segmented Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenwood, Robin; Hanson, Samuel G.; Liao, Gordon Y.
We develop a model in which capital moves quickly within an asset class but slowly between asset classes. While most investors specialize in a single asset class, a handful of generalists gradually reallocate capital across markets. Upon the arrival of a large supply shock, prices of risk in the directly affected asset class become disconnected from those in others. Over the long run, capital flows cause prices of risk to become more closely aligned. While prices in the directly affected market initially overreact, prices in related markets may underreact. We use the model to reassess event-study evidence on quantitative easing.</description><author>Greenwood, Robin; Hanson, Samuel G.; Liao, Gordon Y.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short-Rate Expectations and Unexpected Returns in Treasury Bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cieslak, Anna
I document large and persistent errors in investors' expectations about the short-term interest rate over the business cycle. The largest errors arise in economic downturns and during Fed easings when investors overestimate future short rates and, thus, underestimate future bond returns. At a one-year horizon, errors about the path of the real rate (as opposed to inflation) account for 80% of short-rate forecast error variance, with more than half of that number attributed to the Fed easing more aggressively than the public expected. Short-rate forecast errors induce ex post predictability of excess returns on Treasury bonds that is not due to time-varying risk premium.</description><author>Cieslak, Anna</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mortgage Loan Flow Networks and Financial Norms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stanton, Richard; Walden, Johan; Wallace, Nancy
We develop a theoretical model of a network of intermediaries whose optimal behavior is jointly determined, leading to heterogeneous financial norms and systemic vulnerabilities. We apply the model to the network of U.S. mortgage intermediaries from 2005 to 2007, using a data set containing all private-label, fixed-rate mortgages, with loan flows defining links. Default risk was closely related to network position, evolving predictably among linked nodes, and loan quality estimated from the model was related to independent quality measures, altogether pointing to the vital importance of network effects in this market.</description><author>Stanton, Richard; Walden, Johan; Wallace, Nancy</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Screening on Loan Terms: Evidence from Maturity Choice in Consumer Credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hertzberg, Andrew; Liberman, Andres; Paravisini, Daniel
We exploit a natural experiment in the largest online consumer lending platform to provide the first evidence that loan terms, in particular maturity choice, can be used to screen borrowers based on their private information. We compare two groups of observationally equivalent borrowers who took identical unsecured 36-month loans; for only one of the groups, a 60-month loan was also available. When a long-maturity option is available, fewer borrowers take the short-term loan, and those who do default less. Additional findings suggest borrowers self-select on private information about their future ability to repay.</description><author>Hertzberg, Andrew; Liberman, Andres; Paravisini, Daniel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Myth of the Credit Spread Puzzle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feldhutter, Peter; Schaefer, Stephen M.
Are standard structural models able to explain credit spreads on corporate bonds? In contrast to much of the literature, we find that the Black-Cox model matches the level of investmentgrade spreads well. Model spreads for speculative-grade debt are too low, and we find that bond illiquidity contributes to this underpricing. Our analysis makes use of a new approach for calibrating the model to historical default rates that leads to more precise estimates of investment-grade default probabilities.</description><author>Feldhutter, Peter; Schaefer, Stephen M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interest Rate Risk Management in Uncertain Times</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bretscher, Lorenzo; Schmid, Lukas; Vedolin, Andrea
We revisit evidence of real effects of uncertainty shocks in the context of interest rate uncertainty. We document that adverse movements in interest rate uncertainty predict significant slowdowns in real activity, both at the aggregate and at the firm levels. To understand how firms cope with interest rate uncertainty, we develop a dynamic model of corporate investment, financing, and risk management and test it using a rich data set on corporate swap usage. We find that interest rate uncertainty depresses financially constrained firms' investments in spite of hedging opportunities, because risk management by means of swaps is effectively risky.</description><author>Bretscher, Lorenzo; Schmid, Lukas; Vedolin, Andrea</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks' Incentives and Inconsistent Risk Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Plosser, Matthew C.; Santos, Joao A. C.
This paper investigates banks' incentive to bias the risk estimates they report to regulators. Within loan syndicates, we find that banks with less capital report lower risk estimates. Consistent with an effort to mitigate capital requirements, the sensitivity to capital is robust to bank fixed effects and greater for large, risky, and opaque credits. Also, low-capital banks' risk estimates have less explanatory power than those of high-capital banks with regard to loan prices, indicating that their estimates incorporate less information. Our results suggest banks underreport risk in response to capital constraints and highlight the perils of regulation premised on self-reporting.</description><author>Plosser, Matthew C.; Santos, Joao A. C.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>De Facto Seniority, Credit Risk, and Corporate Bond Prices (vol 30, pg 4038, 2018)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bao, Jack; Hou, Kewei
nan</description><author>Bao, Jack; Hou, Kewei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unsecured Credit Supply, Credit Cycles, and Regulation (vol 31, pg 1184, 2018)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Song; Keys, Benjamin J.; Li, Geng
nan</description><author>Han, Song; Keys, Benjamin J.; Li, Geng</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economic Effects of a Borrower Bailout: Evidence from an Emerging Market (vol 31, pg 1752, 2018)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gine, Xavier; Kanz, Martin
nan</description><author>Gine, Xavier; Kanz, Martin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Transparency Improves, Must Prices Reflect Fundamentals Better?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Snehal; Davis, Jesse; Gondhi, Naveen
No. In the presence of speculative opportunities, investors can learn about both asset fundamentals and the beliefs of other traders. We show that this learning exhibits complementarity: learning more along one dimension increases the value of learning about the other. As a result, regulatory changes may be counterproductive. First, increasing transparency (i.e., making fundamental information cheaper to acquire) can make prices less informative when investors respond by learning relatively more about others. Second, public disclosures discourage private learning about fundamentals, while encouraging information acquisition about others. Accordingly, disclosing more fundamental information can decrease overall informational efficiency by decreasing price informativeness.</description><author>Banerjee, Snehal; Davis, Jesse; Gondhi, Naveen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High-Frequency Measures of Informed Trading and Corporate Announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brennan, Michael J.; Huh, Sahn-Wook; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar
We explore the dynamics of informed trading around corporate announcements of merger bids, dividend initiations, SEOs, and quarterly earnings by calculating daily posterior probabilities of informed buying and selling. We find evidence of informed trading before the announcements and a significant part of the news in announcements is impounded in stock prices before the announcements by pre-event informed trading. We also find evidence of informed trading after the announcements. Most strikingly, the probability of informed trading after merger bids predicts the probability of the bid being withdrawn or met with a competing bid. For other announcements, post-announcement informed-trading probabilities predict subsequent returns.</description><author>Brennan, Michael J.; Huh, Sahn-Wook; Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identifying Information Asymmetry in Securities Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Back, Kerry; Crotty, Kevin; Li, Tao
We propose and estimate a model of endogenous informed trading that is a hybrid of the PIN and Kyle models. When an informed trader trades optimally, both returns and order flows are needed to identify information asymmetry parameters. Empirical relationships between parameter estimates and price impacts and between parameter estimates and stochastic volatility are consistent with theory. We illustrate how the estimates can be used to detect information events in the time series and to characterize the information content of prices in the cross-section. We also compare the estimates to those from other models on various criteria.</description><author>Back, Kerry; Crotty, Kevin; Li, Tao</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Competitive Landscape of High-Frequency Trading Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Li, Dan; Saar, Gideon
We examine product differentiation in the high-frequency trading (HFT) industry, where the "products" are secretive proprietary trading strategies. We demonstrate how principal component analysis can be used to detect underlying strategies common to multiple HFT firms and show that there are three product categories with distinct attributes. We study how HFT competition in each product category affects the market environment and present evidence that indicates how it influences the short-horizon volatility of stocks as well as the viability of trading venues.</description><author>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Li, Dan; Saar, Gideon</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Ratings and the Cost of Municipal Financing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornaggia, Jess; Cornaggia, Kimberly J.; Israelsen, Ryan D.
A common belief held among researchers and policy makers is that regulatory reliance has inflated market demand for credit ratings, despite their decreasing informational value. Advances in information technology, coupled with reputation losses following the subprime crisis, renew the question of whether investors still rely on ratings to assess credit risk. Using Moody's 2010 scale recalibration, which was unrelated to changing issuer fundamentals, we find that ratings still matter to investors and to issuers-apart from any regulatory implications. Our results commend improved disclosure to mitigate mechanistic reliance on ratings and inefficiencies due to rating standards that vary across asset classes.</description><author>Cornaggia, Jess; Cornaggia, Kimberly J.; Israelsen, Ryan D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Labor Market Effects of Credit Market Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bos, Marieke; Breza, Emily; Liberman, Andres
We exploit a natural experiment to provide one of the first measurements of the causal effect of negative credit information on employment and earnings. We estimate that one additional year of negative credit information reduces employment by 3 percentage points and wage earnings by $1,000. In comparison, the decrease in credit is only one-fourth as large. Negative credit information also causes an increase in self-employment and a decrease in mobility. Further evidence suggests this cost of default is inefficiently borne by those most creditworthy among previous defaulters.</description><author>Bos, Marieke; Breza, Emily; Liberman, Andres</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Algorithmic Trading Reduce Information Acquisition?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Weller, Brian M.
I demonstrate an important tension between acquiring information and incorporating it into asset prices. As a salient case, I analyze algorithmic trading (AT), which is typically associated with improved price efficiency. Using a new measure of the information content of prices and a comprehensive panel of 54,879 stock-quarters of Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) market data, I establish instead that the amount of information in prices decreases by 9% to 13% per standard deviation of AT activity and up to a month before scheduled disclosures. AT thus may reduce price informativeness despite its importance for translating available information into prices.</description><author>Weller, Brian M.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Trading Speed Matters: A Tale of Queue Rationing under Price Controls</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Yao, Chen; Ye, Mao
We show that queue rationing under price controls is one driver of high-frequency trading. Uniform tick sizes constrain price competition and create rents for liquidity provision, particularly for securities with lower prices. The time priority rule allocates rents to high-frequency traders (HFTs) because of their speed advantage. An increase in relative tick size, defined as uniform tick sizes divided by security prices, increases the fraction of liquidity provided by HFTs but harms liquidity. We find that the message-to-trade ratio is a poor cross-sectional proxy for HFTs' liquidity provision: stocks with more liquidity provided by HFTs have lower message-to-trade ratios.</description><author>Yao, Chen; Ye, Mao</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Banks, Firms, and Jobs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berton, Fabio; Mocetti, Sauro; Presbitero, Andrea F.; Richiardi, Matteo
We analyze the heterogeneous employment effects of financial shocks using a rich data set of job contracts, matched with the universe of firms and their lending banks in one Italian region. To isolate the effect of the financial shock, we construct a firm-specific time-varying measure of credit supply. The preferred estimate indicates that the average elasticity of employment to a credit supply shock is 0.36. Adjustment affects both the extensive and the intensive margins and is concentrated among workers with temporary contracts. We also examine the heterogeneous effects of the credit crunch by education, age, gender and nationality.</description><author>Berton, Fabio; Mocetti, Sauro; Presbitero, Andrea F.; Richiardi, Matteo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Financial Constraints Priced? Evidence from Textual Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buehlmaier, Matthias M. M.; Whited, Toni M.
We construct novel measures of financial constraints using textual analysis of firms' annual reports and investigate their impact on stock returns. Our three measures capture access to equity markets, debt markets, and external financial markets in general. In all cases, constrained firms earn higher returns, which move together and cannot be explained by the Fama and French (2015) factor model. A trading strategy based on financial constraints is most profitable for large, liquid stocks. Our results are strongest when we consider debt constraints. A portfolio based on this measure earns an annualized risk-adjusted excess return of 6.5%.</description><author>Buehlmaier, Matthias M. M.; Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Housing Price Booms and Crowding-Out Effects in Bank Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chakraborty, Indraneel; Goldstein, Itay; MacKinlay, Andrew
Analyzing the period 1988-2006, we document that banks that are active in strong housing markets increase mortgage lending and decrease commercial lending. Firms that borrow from these banks have significantly lower investment. This is especially pronounced for firms that are more capital constrained or borrow from more-constrained banks. Various extensions and robustness analyses are consistent with the interpretation that commercial loans were crowded out by banks responding to profitable opportunities in mortgage lending, rather than with a demand-based interpretation. The results suggest that housing prices appreciations have negative spillovers to the real economy, which were overlooked thus far.</description><author>Chakraborty, Indraneel; Goldstein, Itay; MacKinlay, Andrew</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Everywhere: Modeling and Managing Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollerslev, Tim; Hood, Benjamin; Huss, John; Pedersen, Lasse Heje
Based on high-frequency data for more than fifty commodities, currencies, equity indices, and fixed-income instruments spanning more than two decades, we document strong similarities in realized volatility patterns within and across asset classes. Exploiting these similarities through panel-based estimation of new realized volatility models results in superior out-of-sample risk forecasts, compared to forecasts from existing models and conventional procedures that do not incorporate the similarities in volatilities. We develop a utility-based framework for evaluating risk models that shows significant economic gains from our new risk model. Lastly, we evaluate the effects of transaction costs and trading speed in implementing different risk models.</description><author>Bollerslev, Tim; Hood, Benjamin; Huss, John; Pedersen, Lasse Heje</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Hedge Funds Exploit Rare Disaster Concerns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, George P.; Gao, Pengjie; Song, Zhaogang
We find hedge funds that have higher return covariation with a disaster concern index, which we develop through out-of-the-money puts on various economic sector indices, earn significantly higher returns in the cross-section. We provide evidence that these funds' managers are more skilled at exploiting the market's ex ante rare disaster concerns (SEDs), which may not be associated with disaster risk. In particular, high-SED funds, on average, outperform low-SED funds by 0.96% per month, but have less exposure to disaster risk. They continue to deliver superior future performance when SEDs are estimated using the disaster concern index purged of disaster risk premiums and have leverage-managing and extreme market-timing abilities.</description><author>Gao, George P.; Gao, Pengjie; Song, Zhaogang</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The History of the Cross-Section of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Linnainmaa, Juhani T.; Roberts, Michael R.
Using data spanning the twentieth century, we show that the majority of accounting-based return anomalies, including investment, are most likely an artifact of data snooping. When examined out-of-sample by moving either backward or forward in time, the average returns and Sharpe ratios of most anomalies decrease, whereas their volatilities and correlations with other anomalies increase. The few anomalies that do persist out-of-sample correlate with the shift from investment in physical capital to intangible capital and the increasing reliance on debt financing over the twentieth century.</description><author>Linnainmaa, Juhani T.; Roberts, Michael R.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Innovative Originality, Profitability, and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, David; Hsu, Po-Hsuan; Li, Dongmei
We propose that innovative originality is a valuable organizational resource and that owing to limited investor attention and skepticism of complexity, greater innovative originality may be undervalued. We find that firms' innovative originality strongly predicts higher, more persistent, and less volatile profitability and higher abnormal stock returns, findings that are robust to extensive controls. The return predictive power of innovative originality is stronger for firms with higher valuation uncertainty, lower investor attention, and greater sensitivity of future profitability to innovative originality. This evidence suggests that innovative originality acts as a "competitive moat" and is undervalued by the market.</description><author>Hirshleifer, David; Hsu, Po-Hsuan; Li, Dongmei</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Detecting Repeatable Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Harvey, Campbell R.; Liu, Yan
Past fund performance does a poor job of predicting future outcomes. The reason is noise. Using a random effects framework, we reduce the noise by pooling information from the cross-sectional alpha distribution to make density forecasts for each individual fund's alpha. In simulations, we show that our method generates parameter estimates that outperform alternative methods, both at the population and at the individual fund level. An out-of-sample forecasting exercise also shows that our method generates improved alpha forecasts.</description><author>Harvey, Campbell R.; Liu, Yan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Information Content of Realized Losses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kelly, Peter
Examining the trades of company insiders, I find that a sale of stock at a loss is a much more negative signal about future returns than is a sale of stock at a gain. I consider a range of explanations for my results and find that the evidence is most consistent with the idea that investors derive direct disutility from selling a stock at a loss. Since selling a stock at a loss is painful, an investor who sells at a loss must have particularly negative information. This result offers a novel measurement of the strength of the disposition effect.</description><author>Kelly, Peter</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>News Shocks and the Production-Based Term Structure of Equity Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ai, Hengjie; Croce, Mariano Max; Diercks, Anthony M.; Li, Kai
We propose a production-based general equilibrium model to study the link between timing of cash flows and expected returns, both in the cross-section of stocks and along the aggregate equity term structure. Our model incorporates long-run growth news with time-varying volatility and slow learning about the exposure that firms have with respect to these shocks. Our framework provides a unified explanation of the stylized features of the slope of the term structure of equity returns, its variations over the business cycle, and the negative relationship between cash-flow duration and expected returns in the cross-section of book-to-market-sorted portfolios.</description><author>Ai, Hengjie; Croce, Mariano Max; Diercks, Anthony M.; Li, Kai</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning from History: Volatility and Financial Crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Danielsson, Jon; Valenzuela, Marcela; Zer, Ilknur
We study the effects of stock market volatility on risk-taking and financial crises by constructing a cross-country database spanning up to 211 years and across 60 countries. Prolonged periods of low volatility have strong in-sample and out-of-sample predictive power over the incidence of banking crises and can be used as a reliable crisis indicator, whereas volatility itself does not predict crises. Low volatility leads to excessive credit buildups and balance sheet leverage in the financial system, indicating that agents take more risk in periods of low risk, supporting the dictum that "stability is destabilizing."</description><author>Danielsson, Jon; Valenzuela, Marcela; Zer, Ilknur</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Management Risk Affects Corporate Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pan, Yihui; Wang, Tracy Yue; Weisbach, Michael S.
We evaluate whether management risk, which arises from investors' uncertainty about management's added value, affects firms' default risks and debt pricing. We find that, regardless of the reason for the turnover, CDS, loan, and bond yield spreads increase at the time of management turnover, when management risk is highest, and decline over the first three years of the new CEO's tenure. The effects increase with prior investor uncertainty about the new management. These results are consistent with the view that management risk affects firms' default risk. An understanding of management risk yields a number of implications for corporate finance.</description><author>Pan, Yihui; Wang, Tracy Yue; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Capital Structure and Investment with Real Options and Endogenous Debt Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Praveen; Yerramilli, Vijay
We examine the joint optimization of financial leverage and irreversible capacity investment in a real options framework with risky debt and endogenous interest costs. Higher capacity, ceteris paribus, increases operating leverage and default probability, but lowers ex post adjustment costs and generates larger tax shields. A key insight is that financial leverage and capacity are substitutes in the debt market equilibrium. We develop novel predictions about the effects of capital adjustment costs, operating costs, and uncertainty on optimal financial leverage and capacity that may potentially help explain ambiguous empirical results in the literature regarding the determinants of capital structure and investment.</description><author>Kumar, Praveen; Yerramilli, Vijay</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government Intervention and Arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pasquariello, Paolo
Direct government intervention in a market may induce violations of the law of one price in other, arbitrage-related markets. I show that a government pursuing a nonpublic, partially informative price target in a model of strategic market-order trading and segmented dealership generates equilibrium price differentials among fundamentally identical assets by clouding dealers' inference about the targeted asset's payoff from its order flow, to an extent complexly dependent on existing price formation. I find supportive evidence using a sample of American Depositary Receipts and other cross-listings traded in the major U.S. exchanges, along with currency interventions by developed and emerging countries between 1980 and 2009.</description><author>Pasquariello, Paolo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Inflows, Sovereign Debt and Bank Lending: Micro-Evidence from an Emerging Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Williams, Tomas
This paper uses a natural experiment to show that government access to foreign credit increases private access to credit. I identify a sudden, and unanticipated increase in capital inflows to the sovereign debt market in Colombia, due to a rebalancing in a government bond index by J.P. Morgan. I find that market makers banks in the treasury market reduced their sovereign debt by 7.8 percentage points of assets and increased their credit availability by 4.2 percentage points of assets. Using industry level data, I show that a higher exposure to market makers led to a higher growth in economic activity.</description><author>Williams, Tomas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Got Rejected? Real Effects of Not Getting a Loan</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berg, Tobias
Using a lender cutoff rule that generates plausibly exogenous variation in credit supply, I investigate a new channel through which funding shocks are transmitted to the real economy. Based on a sample of more than 15,000 loan applications from small-and medium-sized enterprises, I find that precautionary savings motives can aggravate real effects: low-liquidity firms whose loan applications were rejected increase cash holdings and cut noncash assets in excess of the requested loan amount. These results point to the amplifying effect of precautionary savings motives in the transmission of credit supply shocks.</description><author>Berg, Tobias</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mortgage Supply and Housing Rents</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gete, Pedro; Reher, Michael
We show that a contraction of mortgage supply after the Great Recession has increased housing rents. Our empirical strategy exploits heterogeneity in MSAs' exposure to regulatory shocks experienced by lenders over the 2010-2014 period. Tighter lending standards have increased demand for rental housing, leading to higher rents, depressed homeownership rates and an increase in rental supply. Absent the credit supply contraction, annual rent growth would have been 2.1 percentage points lower over 2010-2014 in MSAs in which lending standards rose from their 2008 levels.</description><author>Gete, Pedro; Reher, Michael</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long Forward Probabilities, Recovery, and the Term Structure of Bond Risk Premiums</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Qin, Likuan; Linetsky, Vadim; Nie, Yutian
This paper examines the assumption of transition independence of the stochastic discount factor (SDF) in the bond market. This assumption underlies the recovery result of Ross 2015. Following the methodology of Alvarez and Jermann 2005 and Hansen and Scheinkman 2009, we estimate the martingale component in the long-term factorization of the SDF using U.S. Treasury data. The empirically estimated martingale component is highly volatile and produces a downward-sloping term structure of bond Sharpe ratios. In contrast, the transition independence assumption implies a degenerate martingale component and an upward-sloping term structure of bond Sharpe ratios. Thus, transition independence is inconsistent with our empirical results.</description><author>Qin, Likuan; Linetsky, Vadim; Nie, Yutian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can People Learn about 'Black Swans'? Experimental Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Payzan-LeNestour, Elise
How do people cope with tail risk? In a lab experiment that removed informational and incentive confounds, subjects overwhelmingly behaved like Bayesian learners. The results of simulations further revealed that if one is to survive under tail risk, one needs to follow the Bayesian approach, as all boundedly rational alternatives fail. These findings support the Bayesian assumption commonly made in prior studies on tail risk and model uncertainty, and they also demonstrate the importance of optimal learning under tail risk.</description><author>Payzan-LeNestour, Elise</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk, Unemployment, and the Stock Market: A Rare-Event-Based Explanation of Labor Market Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kilic, Mete; Wachter, Jessica A.
What is the driving force behind the cyclical behavior of unemployment and vacancies? What is the relation between firms' job-creation incentives and stock market valuations? We answer these questions in a model with time-varying risk, modeled as a small and variable probability of an economic disaster. A high probability implies greater risk and lower future growth, lowering the incentives of firms to invest in hiring. During periods of high risk, stock market valuations are low and unemployment rises. The model thus explains volatility in equity and labor markets, and the relation between the two.</description><author>Kilic, Mete; Wachter, Jessica A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Skewness Consequences of Seeking Alpha</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Back, Kerry; Crane, Alan D.; Crotty, Kevin
Mutual funds seek alpha, but coskewness is also an important performance attribute. Coskewness of fund returns is associated with market timing, liquidity management, and derivative use. Measures of active management associated with positive alphas are also associated with undesirable coskewness. When controlling for other characteristics, coskewness is positively associated with activity measures related to market timing and negatively associated with activity measures related to stock picking. In the cross-section of funds, the latter effect dominates, so funds generate undesirable coskewness in the pursuit of alpha. Money flows to funds with desirable coskewness.</description><author>Back, Kerry; Crane, Alan D.; Crotty, Kevin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Active Fundamental Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Hao; Zheng, Lu
We propose a new measure, active fundamental performance (AFP), to identify skilled mutual fund managers. AFP evaluates fund investment skills conditioned on the release of firms' fundamental information. For each fund, we examine the covariance between deviations of its portfolio weights from a benchmark portfolio and the underlying stock performance on days when firms publicize fundamental information. Because asset prices on these information days better reflect firm fundamentals, AFPcan more effectively identify investment skills. From 1984 to 2014, funds in the top decile of high AFP subsequently outperformed those in the bottom decile by 2% to 3% per year.</description><author>Jiang, Hao; Zheng, Lu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rent Seeking by Low-Latency Traders: Evidence from Trading on Macroeconomic Announcements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chordia, Tarun; Green, T. Clifton; Kottimukkalur, Badrinath
Prices of the highly liquid S&amp;P 500 exchange-traded fund (SPY) and the E-mini future (ES) respond to macroeconomic announcement surprises within five milliseconds, with trading intensity increasing over 100-fold following the news release. However, profits from trading quickly are relatively small, roughly $19,000 ($50,000) per event forSPY(ES). Although the speed of information incorporation has increased in recent years, profits have not. Order flow has become less informative, consistent with prices responding directly to news rather than indirectly through trading. Our evidence indicates that low-latency liquidity demanders do not benefit materially from short-term monopolistic access to information.</description><author>Chordia, Tarun; Green, T. Clifton; Kottimukkalur, Badrinath</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does It Pay to Pay Attention?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gargano, Antonio; Rossi, Alberto G.
We employ a novel brokerage account data set to investigate which individual investors are the most attentive, how investors allocate their attention, and the relation between investor attention and performance. Attention is positively related to investment performance, at both the portfolio return level and the individual trades level. We provide evidence that the superior performance of high-attention investors arises because they purchase attentiongrabbing stocks whose positive performance persists for up to six months. Finally, we show that paying attention is particularly profitable when trading stocks with high uncertainty, but for which a lot of public information is available.</description><author>Gargano, Antonio; Rossi, Alberto G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Market and Regional Segmentation and Risk Premia in the First Era of Financial Globalization</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chambers, David; Sarkissian, Sergei; Schill, Michael J.
We study market segmentation effects using data on U.S. railroads that list their bonds in New York and London between 1873 and 1913. This sample provides a unique setting for such analysis because of the precision offered by bond yields in cost of capital estimation, the geography-specific nature of railroad assets, and ongoing substantial technological change. We document a significant reduction in market segmentation over time. While New York bond yields exceeded those in London in the 1870s, this premium disappeared by the early 1900s. However, the segmentation premium persisted in the more remote regions of the United States.</description><author>Chambers, David; Sarkissian, Sergei; Schill, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Implications of Incomplete Markets for International Economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, Gurdip; Cerrato, Mario; Crosby, John
We develop a restriction that precludes implausibly high reward-for-risk in incomplete international economies to consider a theoretical problem that characterizes a lower bound on the covariance between stochastic discount factors (SDFs) subject to correct pricing. The problem is analytically solvable and synthesizes domestic and foreign SDFs into spanned and unspanned components. Our novelty is that exchange rate growth need not equal the ratio of SDFs and that the SDF correlations are plausibly lowered. Exploiting the realities of cross-country correlations of macroeconomic quantities, namely, consumption, wealth, dividend growths, and asset returns, our empirical investigation refutes the specification of complete markets.</description><author>Bakshi, Gurdip; Cerrato, Mario; Crosby, John</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What's behind Smooth Dividends? Evidence from Structural Estimation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wu, Yufeng
I study the driving forces behind dividend smoothing by developing a dynamic agency model in which dividends signal the earnings persistence of firms. In equilibrium, managers treat dividends and earnings as informational substitutes. They smooth dividends relative to earnings to smooth negative news releases and lower their turnover risk. Empirical estimates of the model parameters imply that 39% of observed dividend smoothness among U.S. firms is driven by managers' own career concerns, not shareholders' preferences. Managers cut investments and adjust external financing policies to accommodate this career-concern-based dividend smoothing. These effects lead to a 2% decline in firm value.</description><author>Wu, Yufeng</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Investment Value of Fund Managers' Experience outside the Financial Sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cici, Gjergji; Gehde-Trapp, Monika; Goericke, Marc-Andre; Kempf, Alexander
Human capital acquired while working in other industries before joining fund management provides fund managers with an information advantage. Fund managers exploit this advantage by overweighting their experience industries and by picking outperforming stocks from these industries. These managers' superior information is impounded into stock prices slowly, suggesting that their information is unique and takes a while to be discovered by the markets. Families exploit their manager's industry-specific human capital by broadly employing their investment ideas in other funds. The investment value of industry experience is unaffected by whether or not the manager with such experience is in a team.</description><author>Cici, Gjergji; Gehde-Trapp, Monika; Goericke, Marc-Andre; Kempf, Alexander</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Destabilizing Financial Advice: Evidence from Pension Fund Reallocations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Da, Zhi; Larrain, Borja; Sialm, Clemens; Tessada, Jose
We document a novel channel through which coordinated trading exerts externalities on financial markets. We study the impact of a financial advisory firm that recommends frequent reallocations between equity and bond funds to Chilean pension investors. The recommendations generate large and coordinated fund flows that are exacerbated by the strategic complementarity arising from fund trading restrictions. The recommendations generate significant price pressure and increased volatility in the stock market. In response to these large trade flows, pension funds shift their allocations to more liquid securities. Our findings suggest that giving retirement savers unconstrained reallocation opportunities can destabilize financial markets.</description><author>Da, Zhi; Larrain, Borja; Sialm, Clemens; Tessada, Jose</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantifying Sentiment with News Media across Local Housing Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Soo, Cindy K.
This paper develops first measures of housing sentiment for 34 cities across the United States by quantifying the qualitative tone of local housing news. Housing media sentiment has significant predictive power for future house prices, leading prices by nearly two years. Consistent with theories of investor sentiment, the media sentiment index has a greater effect in markets in which speculative investors are more prevalent and demand appears less informed. Directly examining the content across news articles finds that results are not driven by news stories of unobserved fundamentals.</description><author>Soo, Cindy K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Timing and Method of Payment in Mergers when Acquirers Are Financially Constrained</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gorbenko, Alexander S.; Malenko, Andrey
Although acquisitions are a popular form of investment, the link between firms' financial constraints and acquisition policies is not well understood. We develop a model in which financially constrained bidders approach targets, decide how much to bid and whether to bid in cash or in stock. In equilibrium, financial constraints do not affect the identity of the winning bidder, but they lower bidders' incentives to approach the target. Auctions are initiated by bidders with low constraints or high synergies. The use of cash is positively related to synergies and the acquirer's gains from the deal and negatively to financial constraints.</description><author>Gorbenko, Alexander S.; Malenko, Andrey</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Frictions and the Stock Price Reaction to Monetary Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ozdagli, Ali K.
I show that the stock prices of firms subject to greater information frictions have a weaker reaction to monetary policy. The claim is robust to a broad set of proxies for financial constraints and information frictions. Moreover, I use the Enron accounting scandal and Arthur Andersen's demise as a large exogenous shock, temporarily raising other Andersen clients' information frictions and, thereby, their financial constraints. The scandal's disclosure lowered Andersen's clients' stock price sensitivity to monetary policy to about half that of other firms.</description><author>Ozdagli, Ali K.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decentralized Privatization and Change of Control Rights in China</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gan, Jie; Guo, Yan; Xu, Chenggang
The design and implementation of privatization in China is unique in that both are decentralized and administered by the local governments. Based on a proprietary survey data set containing 3,000 firms in over 200 cities, this paper studies privatization choices and outcomes, as well as the mechanism behind the outcomes. We find that less political opposition to labor downsizing and greater fiscal capacity prompt cities to choose direct sales to insiders (MBOs). This method transfers control rights to private owners, retains limited government supports, imposes hardened budget constraints, allows for restructuring, and achieves performance improvement.</description><author>Gan, Jie; Guo, Yan; Xu, Chenggang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Family Descent as a Signal of Managerial Quality: Evidence from Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chuprinin, Oleg; Sosyura, Denis
Using data from individual Census records on the wealth of managers' parents, we find that mutual fund managers from poor families outperform managers from rich families. We argue that managers born poor face higher entry barriers into asset management. Consistent with this view, managers born poor are promoted only if they outperform, while those born rich are more likely to be promoted for reasons unrelated to performance. Overall, we establish a first link between fund managers' family descent and their ability to create value.</description><author>Chuprinin, Oleg; Sosyura, Denis</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Liquid Hand-to-Mouth: Evidence from Personal Finance Management Software</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Olafsson, Arna; Pagel, Michaela
We use a very accurate panel of all individual spending, income, balances, and credit limits from a personal finance software to document spending responses to the arrival of both regular and irregular income. These payday responses are robust and homogeneous for all income and spending categories throughout the income distribution. Moreover, we find that few people hold little or no liquidity. We then analyze whether people hold liquidity cushions to cope with future liquidity constraints. However, we find that peoples' responses are consistent with standard models without illiquid savings, in which neither present nor future liquidity constraints are frequently binding.</description><author>Olafsson, Arna; Pagel, Michaela</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Evolution of Corporate Cash</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, John R.; Leary, Mark T.
We study time-series and cross-firm variation in corporate cash holdings from 1920 to 2014. The recent increase in cash is not unique in magnitude. However, the recent divergence between average and aggregate cash is new and entirely driven by a shift in cash policies of newly public firms, whereas within-firm changes have been negative or flat since the 1940s. Cross-sectional relations between cash holdings and firm characteristics are stable throughout the century, though characteristics explain little of the trends in aggregate cash. Macroeconomic conditions, corporate profitability and investment, and (since 2000) repatriation taxes explain aggregate cash over the last century.</description><author>Graham, John R.; Leary, Mark T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Government Intervention and Arbitrage (vol 31, pg 3344, 2018)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pasquariello, Paolo
nan</description><author>Pasquariello, Paolo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contagious Effects of a Political Intervention in Debt Contracts: Evidence Using Loan-Level Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tantri, Prasanna L.
Using an unexpected government regulation that restricted the ability of microfinance institutions to recover loans in one Indian state, I examine whether this intervention affected bank loan performance. The bank loan delinquency rate significantly increased as a result. In response, the ex post bank credit supply declined by more than half. For identification, I compare loans from branches located in regions subject to this intervention with loans from nearby branches of the same bank located in regions not subject to the intervention. I conclude that political interventions in credit markets could have significant spillover effects.</description><author>Tantri, Prasanna L.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt Priority Structure, Market Discipline, and Bank Conduct</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Danisewicz, Piotr; McGowan, Danny; Onali, Enrico; Schaeck, Klaus
We examine how debt priority structure affects bank funding costs and soundness. Leveraging an unexplored natural experiment that changes the priority of claims on banks' assets, we document asymmetric effects that are consistent with changes in monitoring intensity by various creditors depending on whether creditors move up or down the priority ladder. The enactment of depositor preference laws that confer priority on depositors reduces deposit rates but increases nondeposit rates. Importantly, subordinating nondepositor claims reduces bank risk-taking, consistent with market discipline. This insight highlights a role for debt priority structure in the regulatory framework.</description><author>Danisewicz, Piotr; McGowan, Danny; Onali, Enrico; Schaeck, Klaus</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Advice and Bank Profits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoechle, Daniel; Ruenzi, Stefan; Schaub, Nic; Schmid, Markus
We use a unique data set from a large retail bank containing internal managerial accounting data on revenues and costs per client to analyze how banks and their financial advisors generate profits with customers. We find that advised transactions are associated with higher profits than independently executed trades of the same client. The bank's own mutual funds and structured products are most profitable for the bank, and profits increase with trade size. We show that advisors recommend exactly those transactions. Furthermore, we find that advised clients achieve a worse performance than independent clients, suggesting that advisors put their employer's interest first.</description><author>Hoechle, Daniel; Ruenzi, Stefan; Schaub, Nic; Schmid, Markus</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Extrapolation Bias and the Predictability of Stock Returns by Price-Scaled Variables</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cassella, Stefano; Gulen, Huseyin
Using survey data on expectations of stock returns, we recursively estimate the degree of extrapolative weighting in investors' beliefs (DOX). In an extrapolation framework, DOX determines the relative weight investors place on recent-versus-distant returns. DOX varies considerably over time. The ability of price-scaled variables to predict the year-ahead equity premium is contingent on DOX. High price-scaled variables are followed by lower returns only when DOX is high. Our findings support extrapolation-based theories of the stock market and the interpretation of price-scaled variables as mispricing proxies. Our results help answer a critical question: when will an overvalued asset experience a correction?</description><author>Cassella, Stefano; Gulen, Huseyin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency Conflicts around the World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Morellec, Erwan; Nikolov, Boris; Schurhoff, Norman
We construct firm-level indexes for agency conflicts between controlling shareholders and outside investors by estimating a dynamic model of financing decisions. Our estimates for 12,652 firms from 14 countries show that agency conflicts are large and highly variable across firms and countries. Differences in agency conflicts are largely due to differences in firm-level governance, ownership concentration, and other firm characteristics. The origin of law is more relevant for curtailing governance excesses than for guarding the typical firm. Agency costs split about equally between wealth transfers and value losses from policy distortions. Recent governance reforms in Europe have significantly reduced agency costs.</description><author>Morellec, Erwan; Nikolov, Boris; Schurhoff, Norman</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Product Market Competition Shocks, Firm Performance, and Forced CEO Turnover</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dasgupta, Sudipto; Li, Xi; Wang, Albert Y.
We examine the effect of competition shocks induced by major industry-level tariff cuts on forced CEO turnover. Both the likelihood of forced CEO turnover and its sensitivity to performance increase. These effects are stronger for firms exposed to greater predation risk and with products more similar to those of other firms. CEOs are more likely to be forced out in weak governance firms; however, in good governance firms, CEOs are offered higher incentive pay. New outside CEOs receive higher incentive pay and come from firms with lower cost structures and higher asset sales. Performance and productivity improve after forced turnover.</description><author>Dasgupta, Sudipto; Li, Xi; Wang, Albert Y.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Retention Effects of Unvested Equity: Evidence from Accelerated Option Vesting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jochem, Torsten; Ladika, Tomislav; Sautner, Zacharias
We document that firms can effectively retain executives by granting deferred equity pay. We show this by analyzing a unique regulatory change (FAS 123-R) that prompted 723 firms to suddenly eliminate stock option vesting periods. This allowed CEOs to keep 33% more options when departing the firm, and we find that voluntary CEO departure rates subsequently rose from 5% to 21%. Our identification strategy exploits FAS 123-R's almost-random timing, which was staggered by firms' fiscal year-ends. Firms that experienced departures suffered negative stock price reactions, and responded by increasing compensation for remaining and newly hired executives.</description><author>Jochem, Torsten; Ladika, Tomislav; Sautner, Zacharias</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic News Releases in Equity Vesting Months</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex; Goncalves-Pinto, Luis; Groen-Xu, Moqi; Wang, Yanbo
We find that CEOs release 20% more discretionary news items in months in which they are expected to sell equity, predicted using scheduled vesting months. These vesting months are determined by equity grants made several years prior and thus unlikely to be driven by the current information environment. The increase arises for positive news, but not neutral or negative news, nor nondiscretionary news. News releases fall in the month before and month after the vesting month. News in vesting months generates a temporary increase in stock prices and market liquidity, which the CEO exploits by cashing out shortly afterwards.</description><author>Edmans, Alex; Goncalves-Pinto, Luis; Groen-Xu, Moqi; Wang, Yanbo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Power of the Street: Evidence from Egypt's Arab Spring</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acemoglu, Daron; Hassan, Tarek A.; Tahoun, Ahmed
Unprecedented street protests brought down Mubarak's government and ushered in an era of competition between three rival political groups in Egypt. Using daily variation in the number of protesters, we document that more intense protests are associated with lower stock market valuations for firms connected to the group currently in power relative to non-connected firms, but have no impact on the relative valuations of firms connected to rival groups. These results suggest that street protests serve as a partial check on political rent-seeking. General discontent expressed on Twitter predicts protests but has no direct effect on valuations.</description><author>Acemoglu, Daron; Hassan, Tarek A.; Tahoun, Ahmed</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-Subsidization in Institutional Asset Management Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaudhuri, Ranadeb; Ivkovic, Zoran; Trzcinka, Charles
We study cross-subsidization among U.S. equity products managed by institutional asset management firms. We find returns-based evidence consistent with both cross-subsidization receipt by strong recent performers that are relatively small in their firms and provision by products that are relatively large in their firms. Tax-exempt investors and taxable investors do not have a clear ranking by expertise, but tax-exempt investors' agency issues are more complex. Accordingly, taxable clients have more flow-performance nonlinearity and receive more (and provide less) cross-subsidization. Taxable investor flows appear more discerning, but only under the circumstances conducive to cross-subsidization, suggesting that "more discerning" likely means "more cross-subsidized."</description><author>Chaudhuri, Ranadeb; Ivkovic, Zoran; Trzcinka, Charles</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Open-End Organizational Structures and Limits to Arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Kahraman, Bige
We provide evidence that open-end organizational structures undermine incentives for asset managers to attack long-term mispricing. We compare open-end funds with closed-end funds. Closed-end funds purchase more underpriced stocks than do open-end funds, especially if the stocks involve high arbitrage risk. We then show that hedge funds with high share restrictions having a lower degree of open-endedness also trade against long-term mispricing to a larger extent than do other hedge funds. Our analysis suggests that open-end organizational structures are not conducive to long-term risky arbitrage.</description><author>Giannetti, Mariassunta; Kahraman, Bige</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting through the Rearview Mirror: Data Revisions and Bond Return Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghysels, Eric; Horan, Casidhe; Moench, Emanuel
A previous literature has documented that bond returns are predicted by macroeconomic information not contained in yields contemporaneously. That literature has mostly relied on final revised, rather than real time macroeconomic data. We show that the use of real time data substantially reduces the predictive power of macro variables for future bond returns as well as the implied countercyclicality of term premiums. We discuss potential interpretations of our results.</description><author>Ghysels, Eric; Horan, Casidhe; Moench, Emanuel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Factor Structure in Equity Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Peter; Fournier, Mathieu; Jacobs, Kris
Equity options display a strong factor structure. The first principal components of the equity volatility levels, skews, and term structures explain a substantial fraction of the cross-sectional variation. Furthermore, these principal components are highly correlated with the S&amp;P 500 index option volatility, skew, and term structure, respectively. We develop an equity option valuation model that captures this factor structure. The model predicts that firms with higher market betas have higher implied volatilities, steeper moneyness slopes, and a term structure that covaries more with the market. The model provides a good fit, and the equity option data support the model's cross-sectional implications.</description><author>Christoffersen, Peter; Fournier, Mathieu; Jacobs, Kris</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inflexibility and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gu, Lifeng; Hackbarth, Dirk; Johnson, Tim
Investment-based asset pricing research highlights the role of irreversibility as a determinant of firms' risk and expected return. In a neoclassical model of a firm with costly scale adjustment options, we show that the effect of scale flexibility (i.e., contraction and expansion options) is to determine the relation between risk and operating leverage: risk increases with operating leverage for inflexible firms, but decreases for flexible firms. Guided by theory, we construct easily reproducible proxies for inflexibility and operating leverage. Empirical tests provide support for the predicted interaction of these characteristics in stock returns and risk.</description><author>Gu, Lifeng; Hackbarth, Dirk; Johnson, Tim</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Stocks Riskier over the Long Run? Taking Cues from Economic Theory</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Avramov, Doron; Cederburg, Scott; Lucivjanska, Katarina
We study whether stocks are riskier or safer in the long run from the perspective of Bayesian investors who employ the long-run risk, habit formation, or prospect theory models to form prior beliefs about return dynamics. Economic theory delivers important guidance for long-run investment opportunities. Specifically, incorporating prior information from the habit formation or prospect theory models reinforces beliefs in mean reversion and inferences that stocks are safer over longer horizons. Conversely, investors with long-run risk priors perceive weaker mean reversion and riskier equities. Model-based information is particularly important for inferences about uncertainty in the dividend growth component of returns.</description><author>Avramov, Doron; Cederburg, Scott; Lucivjanska, Katarina</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing Kernel Monotonicity and Conditional Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Linn, Matthew; Shive, Sophie; Shumway, Tyler
A large literature finds evidence that pricing kernels nonparametrically estimated from option prices and historical returns are not monotonically decreasing in market index returns. We argue that existing estimation methods are inconsistent and propose a new nonparametric estimator of the pricing kernel that reflects the information available to investors who set asset prices. In simulations, the estimator outperforms existing techniques. Our empirical estimates using S&amp;P 500 index option data from 1996 to 2014 and FTSE 100 index option data from 2002 to 2014 suggest that the "pricing kernel puzzle" is due to flaws in existing estimators rather than a behavioral or economic phenomenon.</description><author>Linn, Matthew; Shive, Sophie; Shumway, Tyler</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Structural GARCH: The Volatility-Leverage Connection</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engle, Robert F.; Siriwardane, Emil N.
In the aftermath of the financial crisis, institutions have been asked to reduce leverage in order to reduce risk. To address the effectiveness of this measure, we build a model of equity volatility that accounts for leverage. Our approach blends Merton's insights on capital structure with traditional time-series models of volatility. We estimate that precautionary capital needs for the entire financial sector reached $2 trillion during the crisis. We also investigate the long-standing observation that equity volatility asymmetrically responds to positive and negative news. Volatility asymmetry is mostly explained by exposure to the aggregate market, not a mechanical leverage effect.</description><author>Engle, Robert F.; Siriwardane, Emil N.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Mutual Fund Managers Paid for Investment Skill?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ibert, Markus; Kaniel, Ron; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn; Vestman, Roine
Compensation of mutual fund managers is paramount to understanding agency frictions in asset delegation. We collect a unique registry-based dataset on the compensation of Swedish mutual fund managers. We find a concave relationship between pay and revenue, in contrast to how investors compensate the fund company (firm). We also find a surprisingly weak sensitivity of pay to performance, even after accounting for the indirect effects of performance on revenue. Firm-level fixed effects, revenues, and profits add substantial explanatory power for compensation.</description><author>Ibert, Markus; Kaniel, Ron; Van Nieuwerburgh, Stijn; Vestman, Roine</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Recovery that We Can Trust? Deducing and Testing the Restrictions of the Recovery Theorem</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bakshi, Gurdip; Chabi-Yo, Fousseni; Gao, Xiaohui
How reliable is the recovery theorem of Ross (2015)? We explore this question in the context of options on the 30-year Treasury bond futures, allowing us to deduce restrictions that link the physical and risk-neutral return distributions. Our empirical results undermine the implications of the recovery theorem. First, we reject an implicit assumption of the recovery theorem that the martingale component of the stochastic discount factor is identical to unity. Second, we consider the restrictions between the physical and risk-neutral return moments when the recovery theorem holds, and reject them in both forecasting regressions and generalized method of moments estimations.</description><author>Bakshi, Gurdip; Chabi-Yo, Fousseni; Gao, Xiaohui</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust Bond Risk Premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bauer, Michael D.; Hamilton, James D.
A consensus has recently emerged that variables beyond the level, slope, and curvature of the yield curve can help predict bond returns. This paper shows that the statistical tests underlying this evidence are subject to serious small-sample distortions. We propose more robust tests, including a novel bootstrap procedure specifically designed to test the spanning hypothesis. We revisit the analysis in six published studies and find that the evidence against the spanning hypothesis is much weaker than it originally appeared. Our results pose a serious challenge to the prevailing consensus.</description><author>Bauer, Michael D.; Hamilton, James D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Historical Slave Trade and Firm Access to Finance in Africa</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pierce, Lamar; Snyder, Jason A.
Access to finance helps explain the link between the historical African slave trade and current gross domestic product. We first present mistrust, weakened institutions, and ethnic fractionalization as plausible historical channels linking the slave trade to modern finance and development. We then show (i) the slave trade is consistently linked to reduced access to the formal and trade credit needed by modern firms, (ii) this shortage particularly reduces capital investment in smaller firms not in business groups, and (iii) the slave trade cannot explain most other business obstacles, suggesting that long-term societal shocks are exceptionally important for finance.</description><author>Pierce, Lamar; Snyder, Jason A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rolling Mental Accounts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Frydman, Cary; Hartzmark, Samuel M.; Solomon, David H.
When investors sell one asset and quickly buy another ("reinvestment days"), their trades suggest the original mental account is not closed, but is instead rolled into the new asset. Retail investors trading on their own accounts display a rolled disposition effect, selling the new position when its value exceeds the initial investment in the original position. On reinvestment days, these investors display no disposition effect (consistent with no disutility from realizing a loss) and make better selling decisions. Using a laboratory experiment, we show that reinvestment causally reduces the disposition effect and improves trading.</description><author>Frydman, Cary; Hartzmark, Samuel M.; Solomon, David H.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Employment and Wage Insurance within Firms: Worldwide Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ellul, Andrew; Pagano, Marco; Schivardi, Fabiano
Using a firm-level international panel data set, we study if unemployment insurance offered by the government and by firms are substitutes. We exploit cross-country and time-series variation in public unemployment insurance as a shifter of workers' demand for insurance within firms, and family versus nonfamily ownership as a shifter of firms' supply of insurance. Our evidence supports the substitutability hypothesis: employment stability in family firms is greater, and the wage discount larger, in countries and periods with less generous public unemployment insurance, whereas no such substitutability emerges for nonfamily firms.</description><author>Ellul, Andrew; Pagano, Marco; Schivardi, Fabiano</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Does Financial Reporting Regulation Affect Firms' Banking?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breuer, Matthias; Hombach, Katharina; Mueller, Maximilian A.
We examine the effects of financial reporting regulation on firms' banking. Exploiting discontinuous public disclosure and auditing requirements assigned to otherwise similar small and medium-sized private firms, we document that financial reporting regulation reduces firms' reliance on concentrated and local bank relationships and increases banks' reliance on firms' financial reporting, consistent with a shift in firms' banking from relationship toward transactional approaches. Our evidence suggests that financial reporting regulation substitutes for banks' information production role by burdening firms with the disclosure and auditing of their financial statements, consistent with institutional complementarities between reporting and banking systems.</description><author>Breuer, Matthias; Hombach, Katharina; Mueller, Maximilian A.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Director Elections Matter?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fos, Vyacheslav; Li, Kai; Tsoutsoura, Margarita
Using a hand-collected sample of election nominations for more than 30,000 directors over the period 2001-2010, we construct a novel measure of director proximity to elections called Years-to-election. We find that the closer directors of a board are to their next elections, the higher CEO turnover-performance sensitivity is. A series of tests, including one that exploits variation in Years-to-election that comes from other boards, supports a causal interpretation. Further analyses show that other governance mechanisms do not drive the relation between board Years-to-election and CEO turnover-performance sensitivity. We conclude that director elections have important implications for corporate governance.</description><author>Fos, Vyacheslav; Li, Kai; Tsoutsoura, Margarita</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Tax Havens and Transparency</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bennedsen, Morten; Zeume, Stefan
We investigate shareholders' reactions to the increased transparency of corporate tax haven activities in a hand-collected subsidiary data set covering 17,331 publicly listed firms in 52 countries. An increase in transparency through the staggered signing of bilateral tax information exchange agreements (TIEAs) between home countries and tax havens is associated with a 2.5% increase in the value of affected firms. The results are stronger for firms with more complex tax haven structures and weakly governed firms. Furthermore, firms that respond to TIEAs by haven hopping (i.e., they move subsidiaries from affected to nonaffected tax havens) do not experience an increase in firm value. These results are consistent with tax havens being used for expropriation activities that extend beyond pure tax-saving activities.</description><author>Bennedsen, Morten; Zeume, Stefan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual Fund Transparency and Corporate Myopia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Vikas; Vashishtha, Rahul; Venkatachalam, Mohan
Pressure from institutional money managers to generate profits in the short run is often blamed for corporate myopia. Theoretical research suggests that money managers' short-term focus stems from their career concerns and greater fund transparency can amplify these concerns. Using a difference-in-differences design around a regulatory shock that increased the transparency of fund managers' portfolio choices, we examine whether increased transparency encourages myopic corporate investment behavior. We find that corporate innovation declines following the regulatory shock. Moreover, evidence from mutual fund trading behavior corroborates that the increased short-term focus of money managers drives the results.</description><author>Agarwal, Vikas; Vashishtha, Rahul; Venkatachalam, Mohan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reaching for Yield in Corporate Bond Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Jaewon; Kronlund, Mathias
We examine "reaching for yield" in U.S. corporate bond mutual funds. We define reaching for yield as tilting portfolios toward bonds with yields higher than the benchmarks. We find that funds generate higher returns and attract more inflows when they reach for yield, especially in periods of low-interest rates. Returns for high reaching-for-yield funds nevertheless tend to be negative on a risk-adjusted basis. Funds engage in rank-chasing behavior by reaching for yield, although these incentives are moderated by the illiquid nature of corporate bonds. High reaching-for-yield funds hold less cash and less liquid bonds, exacerbating redemption risks.</description><author>Choi, Jaewon; Kronlund, Mathias</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual Fund Competition, Managerial Skill, and Alpha Persistence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoberg, Gerard; Kumar, Nitin; Prabhala, Nagpurnanand
What economic forces limit mutual fund managers from generating consistent outperformance? We propose and test the hypothesis that buy-side competition from other funds matters. We make three contributions. First, we propose new style-based spatial methods to identify the customized rivals of each fund. Second, we construct dynamic, fund-specific measures of competition and generate measures of skill as a fund's outperformance relative to its customized peers. Third, and finally, we show that funds outperforming their customized rivals generate future alpha when they face less competition. These results are economically significant and last for over four quarters.</description><author>Hoberg, Gerard; Kumar, Nitin; Prabhala, Nagpurnanand</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Safe Haven CDS Premiums</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klingler, Sven; Lando, David
Credit default swaps can be used to lower the capital requirements of dealer banks entering into uncollateralized derivatives positions with sovereigns. We show in a model that the regulatory incentive to obtain capital relief makes CDS contracts valuable to dealer banks and empirically that, consistent with the use of CDS for regulatory purposes, there is a disconnect between changes in bond yield spreads and in CDS premiums, especially for safe sovereigns. Additional empirical tests related to the volume of contracts outstanding, effects of regulatory proxies, and the corporate bond and CDS markets support that CDS contracts are used for capital relief.</description><author>Klingler, Sven; Lando, David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economic Effects of a Borrower Bailout: Evidence from an Emerging Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gine, Xavier; Kanz, Martin
We study the credit market impact and real effects of one of the largest borrower bailouts in history, enacted by the government of India against the backdrop of the 2007-2008 financial crisis. We find that the bailout led to a significant reallocation of credit and greater defaults, but had no offsetting positive effect on productivity, wages, or consumption. Post-program loan performance deteriorates faster in districts with greater program exposure, an effect that is not driven by greater risk-taking of banks. Loan defaults become more sensitive to the electoral cycle after debt relief, suggesting strategic default in response to the bailout.</description><author>Gine, Xavier; Kanz, Martin</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Home Bias Abroad: Domestic Industries and Foreign Portfolio Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schumacher, David
In their foreign portfolio allocations, international mutual funds overweight industries that are comparatively large in their domestic stock market. Aggregate excess foreign industry allocations are sizeable, on average amounting to over 100% for the largest domestic industries. While this foreign industry bias partly reflects familiarity-based motives, a large body of evidence on investment and performance patterns is, on the whole, remarkably consistent with a specialized learning motive contributing to the bias. This suggests that differences in industry structures across domestic stock markets proxy for international information asymmetries.</description><author>Schumacher, David</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-Sectional and Time-Series Tests of Return Predictability: What Is the Difference?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goyal, Amit; Jegadeesh, Narasimhan
We compare the performance of time-series (TS) and cross-sectional (CS) strategies based on past returns. While CS strategies are zero-net investment long/short strategies, TS strategies take on a time-varying net long investment in risky assets. For individual stocks, the difference between the performances of TS and CS strategies is largely due to this time-varying net long investment. With multiple international asset classes with heterogeneous return distributions, scaled CS strategies significantly outperform similarly scaled TS strategies.</description><author>Goyal, Amit; Jegadeesh, Narasimhan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Costs of Sovereign Default: Evidence from the Stock Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrade, Sandro C.; Chhaochharia, Vidhi
We use stock market data to test cross-sectional implications of theories of sovereign default and provide a market-based estimate of sovereign default costs. We find that the stock prices of firms vulnerable to financial intermediation disruption, or firms more exposed to the government, are particularly sensitive to changes in sovereign credit spreads. This is consistent with theories in which default is costly because it disrupts financial intermediation and damages government reputation. Estimation of a structural valuation model indicates that the market prices stocks as if sovereign default has large effects on vulnerable stocks, translating to a 12% destruction of the value of their productive assets.</description><author>Andrade, Sandro C.; Chhaochharia, Vidhi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managing the Family Firm: Evidence from CEOs at Work</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bandiera, Oriana; Lemos, Renata; Prat, Andrea; Sadun, Raffaella
We build a comparable and bottom-up measure of CEO labor supply for 1,114 CEOs and investigate whether family and professional CEOs differ along this dimension. Family CEOs work 9% fewer hours relative to professional CEOs. CEO hours worked are positively correlated with firm performance and account for 18% of the performance gap between family and professional CEOs. We study the sources of the differences in labor supply across family and professional CEOs by exploiting firm and industry heterogeneity and variation in meteorological and sports events. Evidence suggests that family CEOs value or can pursue leisure activities more so than professional CEOs.</description><author>Bandiera, Oriana; Lemos, Renata; Prat, Andrea; Sadun, Raffaella</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economic Effects of a Borrower Bailout: Evidence from an Emerging Market (vol 31, pg 1219, 2018)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gine, Xavier; Kanz, Martin
nan</description><author>Gine, Xavier; Kanz, Martin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trust Busting: The Effect of Fraud on Investor Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gurun, Umit G.; Stoffman, Noah; Yonker, Scott E.
We study the importance of trust in the investment advisory industry by exploiting the geographic dispersion of victims of the Madoff Ponzi scheme. Residents of communities that were exposed to the fraud subsequently withdrew assets from investment advisers and increased deposits at banks. Additionally, exposed advisers were more likely to close. Advisers who provided services that can build trust, such as financial planning advice, experienced fewer withdrawals. Our evidence suggests that the trust shock was transmitted through social networks. Taken together, our results show that trust plays a critical role in the financial intermediation industry.</description><author>Gurun, Umit G.; Stoffman, Noah; Yonker, Scott E.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Manipulation in the VIX?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, John M.; Shams, Amin
At the settlement time of the VIX Volatility Index, volume spikes on S&amp;P 500 Index (SPX) options, but only in out-of-the-money options used to calculate the VIX, and more so for options with a higher and discontinuous influence on VIX. We investigate alternative explanations of hedging and coordinated liquidity trading. Tests including those utilizing differences in put and call options, open interest around the settlement, and a similar volatility contract with an entirely different settlement procedure in Europe are inconsistent with these explanations but consistent with market manipulation. Large transient deviations in prices demonstrate the importance of settlement design.</description><author>Griffin, John M.; Shams, Amin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Industry Tournament Incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coles, Jeffrey L.; Li, Zhichuan; Wang, Albert Y.
We empirically assess industry tournament incentives for CEOs, as measured by the compensation gap between a CEO at one firm and the highest-paid CEO among similar (industry, size) firms. We find that firm performance, firm risk, and the riskiness of firm investment and financial policies are positively associated with the external industry pay gap. The industry tournament effects are stronger when industry, firm, and executive characteristics indicate high CEO mobility and a higher probability of the aspirant executive winning.</description><author>Coles, Jeffrey L.; Li, Zhichuan; Wang, Albert Y.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Getting the Incentives Right: Backfilling and Biases in Executive Compensation Data</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gillan, Stuart L.; Hartzell, Jay C.; Koch, Andrew; Starks, Laura T.
We document that backfilling in the ExecuComp database introduces a data-conditioning bias that can affect inferences and make replicating previous work difficult. Although backfilling can be advantageous due to greater data coverage, if not addressed, the oversampling of firms with strong managerial incentives and higher subsequent returns leads to a significant upward bias in abnormal compensation, pay-for-performance sensitivity, and the magnitudes of several previously established relations. The bias also can lead to one misinterpreting the appropriate functional form of a relation and whether the data support one compensation theory over another. We offer methods to address this issue.</description><author>Gillan, Stuart L.; Hartzell, Jay C.; Koch, Andrew; Starks, Laura T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Does Financial Reporting Regulation Affect Firms' Banking? (vol 31, pg 1265, 2018)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Breuer, Matthias; Hombach, Katharina; Muller, Maximilian A.
nan</description><author>Breuer, Matthias; Hombach, Katharina; Muller, Maximilian A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Unsecured Credit Supply, Credit Cycles, and Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Song; Keys, Benjamin J.; Li, Geng
This paper explores the dynamics of unsecured credit supply over the recent credit cycle and around the passage of the CARD Act. We examine a unique data set of over 200,000 credit card mail solicitations to a representative sample of households and introduce credit card offers as a direct, informative measure of supply of such credit. Contrasting personal credit card offer dynamics before and after the passage of the CARD Act with those of personal loans, auto loans, and corporate credit cards, we find that lenders reduced credit supply of personal credit cards to nonprime borrowers in response to the CARD Act. Our analysis highlights the importance of separately examining supply and demand responses to assess the unintended consequences of regulation.</description><author>Han, Song; Keys, Benjamin J.; Li, Geng</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic-Driven Prepayment Risk and the Valuation of Mortgage-Backed Securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernov, Mikhail; Dunn, Brett R.; Longstaff, Francis A.
We develop a three-factor no-arbitrage model for valuing mortgage-backed securities in which we solve for the implied prepayment function from the cross-section of market prices. This model closely fits the cross-section of mortgage-backed security prices without needing to specify an econometric prepayment model. We find that implied prepayments are generally higher than actual prepayments, providing direct evidence of significant macroeconomic-driven prepayment risk premiums in mortgage-backed security prices. We also find evidence that mortgage-backed security prices were significantly affected by Fannie Mae credit risk and the Federal Reserve's quantitative easing programs.</description><author>Chernov, Mikhail; Dunn, Brett R.; Longstaff, Francis A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can't Pay or Won't Pay? Unemployment, Negative Equity, and Strategic Default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gerardi, Kristopher; Herkenhoff, Kyle F.; Ohanian, Lee E.; Willen, Paul S.
This paper uses new data from the PSID to quantify the relative importance of negative equity versus ability to pay, in driving mortgage defaults between 2009 and 2013. These data allow us to construct household budgets sets that provide better measures of ability to pay. Changes in ability to pay have large estimated effects. Job loss has an equivalent effect on the propensity to default as a 35% decline in equity. Strategic motives are also found to be quantitatively important, as we estimate more than 38% of households in default could make their mortgage payments without reducing consumption.</description><author>Gerardi, Kristopher; Herkenhoff, Kyle F.; Ohanian, Lee E.; Willen, Paul S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Does Fast Loan Growth Predict Poor Performance for Banks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fahlenbrach, Rudiger; Prilmeier, Robert; Stulz, Rene M.
From 1973 to 2014, the common stock of U.S. banks with loan growth in the top quartile of banks over a three-year period significantly underperformed the common stock of banks with loan growth in the bottom quartile over the next three years. After the period of high growth, these banks have a lower return on assets and increase their loan loss reserves. The poorer performance of fast-growing banks is not explained by merger activity. The evidence is consistent with banks, analysts, and investors being overoptimistic about the risk of loans extended during bank-level periods of high loan growth.</description><author>Fahlenbrach, Rudiger; Prilmeier, Robert; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does a Larger Menu Increase Appetite? Collateral Eligibility and Credit Supply</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Van Bekkum, Sjoerd; Gabarro, Marc; Irani, Rustom M.
We examine a change in the European Central Bank's collateral framework, which significantly lowered the rating requirement for eligible residential mortgage-backed securities (RMBS), and its impact on bank lending and risk-taking in the Netherlands. Banks most affected by the policy increase loan supply and lower interest rates on new mortgage originations. These lower-interest-rate loans serve as collateral for newly issued RMBS with lower-rated tranches and subsequently experience worse repayment performance. The performance deterioration is pronounced among loans with state guarantees, which suggests that looser collateral requirements may lead to undesired credit risk transfer to the sovereign.</description><author>Van Bekkum, Sjoerd; Gabarro, Marc; Irani, Rustom M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Twilight Zone: OTC Regulatory Regimes and Market Quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brueggemann, Ulf; Kaul, Aditya; Leuz, Christian; Werner, Ingrid M.
Studying a comprehensive sample of stocks from the U.S. OTC market, we show that this market is a large and diverse trading environment with a rich set of regulatory and disclosure regimes, comprising venue rules and state laws beyond SEC regulation. We exploit this institutional richness to show that OTC firms subject to stricter regulatory regimes and disclosure requirements have higher market quality (higher liquidity and lower crash risk). Our analysis points to an important trade-off in regulating the OTC market and protecting investors: lowering regulatory requirements reduces the compliance burden for smaller firms, but it also reduces market quality.</description><author>Brueggemann, Ulf; Kaul, Aditya; Leuz, Christian; Werner, Ingrid M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Quantifying Liquidity and Default Risks of Corporate Bonds over the Business Cycle</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hui; Cui, Rui; He, Zhiguo; Milbradt, Konstantin
We develop a structural credit model to examine how interactions between default and liquidity affect corporate bond pricing. The model features debt rollover and bond-price-dependent holding costs. Over the business cycle and in the cross-section, the model matches average default rates and credit spreads in the data, and captures variations in bid-ask and bond-CDS spreads. A structural decomposition reveals that default-liquidity interactions can account for 10%-24% of the level of credit spreads and 16%-46% of the changes in spreads over the business cycle. Further, liquidity-related corporate bond financing costs amount to 6% of the total issuance amount from 1996 to 2015.</description><author>Chen, Hui; Cui, Rui; He, Zhiguo; Milbradt, Konstantin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Illiquidity Premia in the Equity Options Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Peter; Goyenko, Ruslan; Jacobs, Kris; Karoui, Mehdi
Standard option valuation models leave no room for option illiquidity premia. Yet we find the risk-adjusted return spread for illiquid over liquid equity options is 3.4% per day for at-the-money calls and 2.5% for at-the-money puts. These premia are computed using option illiquidity measures constructed from intraday effective spreads for a large panel of U.S. equities, and they are robust to different empirical implementations. Our findings are consistent with evidence that market makers in the equity options market hold large and risky net long positions, and positive illiquidity premia compensate them for the risks and costs of these positions.</description><author>Christoffersen, Peter; Goyenko, Ruslan; Jacobs, Kris; Karoui, Mehdi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Distributional Implications of Government Guarantees in Mortgage Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gete, Pedro; Zecchetto, Franco
We analyze the removal of the credit-risk guarantees provided by the government-sponsored enterprises (GSEs) in a model with agents heterogeneous in income and house price risk. We find that wealth inequality increases, driven by higher mortgage spreads and housing rents. Housing holdings become more concentrated. Foreclosures fall. The removal benefits high-income households, while hurting low-and mid-income households (renters and highly leveraged mortgagors with conforming loans). GSE reform requires compensating transfers, sufficiently high elasticity of rental supply, or linking GSE reform with the elimination of the mortgage interest deduction.</description><author>Gete, Pedro; Zecchetto, Franco</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcy and the Cost of Organized Labor: Evidence from Union Elections</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campello, Murillo; Gao, Janet; Qiu, Jiaping; Zhang, Yue
Unionized workers are entitled to special treatment in bankruptcy court that can be detrimental to other corporate stakeholders, with unsecured creditors standing to lose the most. Using data on union elections, we employ a regression discontinuity design to identify the effect of worker unionization on bondholders in bankruptcy states. Closely won union elections lead to significant bond value losses, especially when firms approach bankruptcy, have underfunded pension plans, and operate in non-RTW law states. Unionization is associated with longer, more convoluted, and costlier bankruptcy court proceedings. Unions depress bondholders' recovery values as they are assigned seats on creditors' committees.</description><author>Campello, Murillo; Gao, Janet; Qiu, Jiaping; Zhang, Yue</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nonlinear Shrinkage of the Covariance Matrix for Portfolio Selection: Markowitz Meets Goldilocks (vol 30, pg 4349, 2017)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ledoit, Olivier; Wolf, Michael
nan</description><author>Ledoit, Olivier; Wolf, Michael</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effects of Business Accelerators on Venture Performance: Evidence from Start-Up Chile</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gonzalez-Uribe, Juanita; Leatherbee, Michael
Dobusiness accelerators affect new venture performance? We investigate this question in the context of Start-Up Chile, an ecosystem accelerator. We focus on two treatment conditions typically found in business accelerators: basic services of funding and coworking space, and additional entrepreneurship schooling. Using a regression discontinuity design, we show that schooling bundled with basic services can significantly increase new venture performance. In contrast, we find no evidence that basic services affect performance on their own. Our results are most relevant for ecosystem accelerators that attract young and early-stage businesses and suggest that entrepreneurial capital matters in new ventures.</description><author>Gonzalez-Uribe, Juanita; Leatherbee, Michael</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Founder Replacement and Startup Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ewens, Michael; Marx, Matt
We provide causal evidence that venture capitalists (VCs) improve the performance of their portfolio companies by replacing founders. Using a database of venture capital financings augmented with hand-collected founder turnover events, we exploit shocks to the supply of outside executives via 14 states' changes to non-compete laws from 1995 to 2016. Naive regressions of startup performance on replacement suggest a negative correlation that may reflect negative selection. Indeed, instrumented regressions reverse the sign of this effect, suggesting that founder replacement instead improves performance. The evidence points to the replacement of founders as a specific mechanism by which VCs add value.</description><author>Ewens, Michael; Marx, Matt</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>