<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>RFS2</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>Did Dubious Mortgage Origination Practices Distort House Prices?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, John M.; Maturana, Gonzalo
ZIP codes with high concentrations of originators who misreported mortgage information experienced a 75% larger relative increase in house prices from 2003 to 2006 and a 90% larger relative decrease from 2007 to 2012 compared with other ZIP codes. Several causality tests show that high fractions of dubious originators in a ZIP code lead to large price distortions. Originators with high misreporting gave credit to borrowers with high ex ante risk, yet further understated the borrowers' true risk. Overall, excess credit facilitated through dubious origination practices explain much of the regional variation in house prices over a decade. (JEL G21, G23, R30, R31)</description><author>Griffin, John M.; Maturana, Gonzalo</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Ratings and Lending Supply: Evidence from Sovereign Downgrades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adelino, Manuel; Ferreira, Miguel A.
We study the causal effect of bank credit rating downgrades on the supply of bank lending. The identification strategy exploits the asymmetric impact of sovereign downgrades on the ratings of banks at the sovereign bound relative to banks that are not at the bound as a result of rating agencies' sovereign ceiling policies. This asymmetric effect leads to greater reductions in ratings-sensitive funding and lending of banks at the bound relative to other banks. Results for foreign borrowers and within lender-borrower relationships confirm that credit demand does not explain our findings. (JEL E51, G21, G24, G28, H63)</description><author>Adelino, Manuel; Ferreira, Miguel A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interbank Market Freezes and Creditor Runs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Xuewen
We model the interplay between trade in the interbank market and creditor runs on financial institutions. We show that the feedback between them can amplify a small shock into "interbank market freezing" with "liquidity evaporating." Credit crunches of the interbank market drive up the interbank rate. For an individual institution, a higher interbank rate - meaning a higher funding cost - results in more severe coordination problems among creditors in debt rollover decisions. Creditors thus behave more conservatively and run more often. Facing an increased chance of creditor runs, institutions demand more and supply less liquidity, tightening the interbank market. (JEL G01, G21, D83, D53)</description><author>Liu, Xuewen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition and Bank Opacity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Liangliang; Levine, Ross; Lin, Chen
Did regulatory reforms that lowered barriers to competition increase or decrease the quality of information that banks disclose to the public? By integrating the gravity model of investment with the state-specific process of bank deregulation that occurred in the United States from the 1980s through the 1990s, we develop a bank-specific, time-varying measure of deregulation-induced competition. We find that an intensification of competition reduced abnormal accruals of loan loss provisions and the frequency with which banks restate financial statements. The results suggest that competition reduces bank opacity, potentially enhancing the ability of markets to monitor banks. (JEL G21, G28, G34, G38)</description><author>Jiang, Liangliang; Levine, Ross; Lin, Chen</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Human Capital That Matters: Expected Returns and High-Income Households</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, Sean D.; Delikouras, Stefanos; Jiang, Danling; Korniotis, George M.
We propose a novel human capital model that decomposes aggregate income risk into high-and low-income risk. We find that high-income risk is priced, while low-income risk is insignificant. The high-income factor alone explains 77% of the cross-sectional variation in the twenty-five size and book-to-market portfolios, earns a risk premium of about 7% per year, and its pricing power extends to the full cross-section of individual stocks. It is also related to the value factor, suggesting that the value premium might be compensation for income risk. Overall, our evidence indicates that high-income risk is an important macroeconomic risk factor.</description><author>Campbell, Sean D.; Delikouras, Stefanos; Jiang, Danling; Korniotis, George M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Education and the Debt Behavior of the Young</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Meta; Grigsby, John; van der Klaauw, Wilbert; Wen, Jaya; Zafar, Basit
Young Americans are heavily reliant on debt and have clear financial literacy shortcomings. In this paper, we study the effects of exposure to financial training on debt outcomes in early adulthood among a large and representative sample of young Americans. Variation in exposure to financial training comes from statewide changes in high school graduation requirements. Using a flexible event study approach, we find that both mathematics and financial education, by and large, decrease reliance on nonstudent debt and improve repayment behavior. Economics training, on the other hand, increases both the likelihood of holding outstanding debt and the prevalence of repayment difficulties.</description><author>Brown, Meta; Grigsby, John; van der Klaauw, Wilbert; Wen, Jaya; Zafar, Basit</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Posturing and Holdup in Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Khanna, Naveen; Mathews, Richmond D.
We show that the need to "posture" can help solve the holdup problem inherent in many multistage relationships, including those between entrepreneurs and venture capitalists. Posturing arises when an informed party needs to send a strong signal to induce skeptical third parties like employees, suppliers, customers, or competitors to develop/maintain relationships with the firm or take other actions that increase firm value. In the venture capital context, this can be credibly achieved if the VC publicly invests at high prices in later rounds. This tempers holdup by shifting ex-post bargaining power toward the entrepreneur, inducing him to exert greater effort.</description><author>Khanna, Naveen; Mathews, Richmond D.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Experimentation and the Returns to Entrepreneurship</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Manso, Gustavo
Previous studies have argued that entrepreneurs earn less and bear more risk than salaried workers with otherwise similar characteristics. In a simple model of entrepreneurship, I show that estimates of mean and variance of returns to entrepreneurship used by these previous studies are biased, as they fail to account for the option value of experimenting with new ideas. Using longitudinal data, I find patterns that are consistent with entrepreneurship as experimentation and returns to entrepreneurship that are more attractive than established by previous research.</description><author>Manso, Gustavo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing from Family and Friends</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Samuel; Persson, Petra
Most informal finance comes from family and friends. Existing informal finance theories cannot match two characteristics of family finance: family investors may accept below-market or even negative returns, yet borrowers often prefer formal finance. We argue that social preferences make family finance cheap but create shadow costs that nonetheless discourage its use: Committing family funds to risky investment displaces intrafamily insurance and undermines limited liability. The same characteristics that sustain familial insurance thus render family finance a poor source of risk capital. Even when overcoming capital constraints requires social ties, intermediation and semiformalization may therefore be crucial for promoting risk taking.</description><author>Lee, Samuel; Persson, Petra</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wage Rigidity: A Quantitative Solution to Several Asset Pricing Puzzles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Favilukis, Jack; Lin, Xiaoji
In standard production models, wage volatility is far too high, and equity volatility is far too low. A simple modification-sticky wages because of infrequent resetting together with a constant elasticity of substitution (CES) production function leads to both smoother wages and higher equity volatility. Further, the model produces several other hard-to-explain features of financial data: high Sharpe ratios, low and smooth interest rates, time-varying equity volatility and premium, a value premium, and a downward-sloping equity term structure. Procyclical, volatile wages are a hedge for firms in standard models; smoother wages act like operating leverage, making profits and dividends riskier.</description><author>Favilukis, Jack; Lin, Xiaoji</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk and Expected Returns of Private Equity Investments: Evidence Based on Market Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jegadeesh, Narasimhan; Kraeussl, Roman; Pollet, Joshua M.
We estimate the risk and expected return of private equity using market prices of publicly traded funds of funds holding unlisted private equity funds and of publicly traded private equity funds participating directly in private equity transactions. We find that the market expects unlisted private equity funds to earn abnormal returns between -0.5% and 2% per year. In addition, private equity has a market beta close to one and a positive beta on the SMB factor. These listed funds exhibit greater systematic risk than an index based on the self-reported net asset value of unlisted private equity funds.</description><author>Jegadeesh, Narasimhan; Kraeussl, Roman; Pollet, Joshua M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Synthetic or Real? The Equilibrium Effects of Credit Default Swaps on Bond Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Oehmke, Martin; Zawadowski, Adam
We provide a model of nonredundant credit default swaps (CDSs), building on the observation that CDSs have lower trading costs than bonds. CDS introduction involves a trade-off: it crowds out existing demand for the bond, but improves the bond allocation by allowing long-term investors to become levered basis traders and absorb more of the bond supply. We characterize conditions under which CDS introduction raises bond prices. The model predicts a negative CDS-bond basis, as well as turnover and price impact patterns that are consistent with empirical evidence. We also show that a ban on naked CDSs can raise borrowing costs.</description><author>Oehmke, Martin; Zawadowski, Adam</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CEO Assessment and the Structure of Newly Formed Boards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Denis, David J.; Denis, Diane K.; Walker, Mark D.
Following corporate spinoffs, unit boards are formed from scratch. We find that these "de novo" boards are smaller, more independent, include more outside directors with relevant industry expertise, and derive more industry expertise from outsiders than do industry- and size-matched peers. These differences are observed only when the unit CEO was not the CEO or a director of the pre-spinoff parent firm-that is, when there is a greater need to assess the CEO's ability and match with the firm. We conclude that the need for CEO assessment is an important element of the structure of newly formed boards.</description><author>Denis, David J.; Denis, Diane K.; Walker, Mark D.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading Fast and Slow: Colocation and Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brogaard, Jonathan; Hagstromer, Bjorn; Norden, Lars; Riordan, Ryan
We exploit an optional colocation upgrade at NASDAQ OMX Stockholm to assess how speed affects market liquidity. Liquidity improves for the overall market and even for noncolocated trading entities. We find that the upgrade is pursued mainly by participants who engage in market making. Those that upgrade use their enhanced speed to reduce their exposure to adverse selection and to relax their inventory constraints. In particular, the upgraded trading entities remain competitive at the best bid and offer even when their inventories are in their top decile. Our results suggest that increasing the speed of market-making participants benefits market liquidity.</description><author>Brogaard, Jonathan; Hagstromer, Bjorn; Norden, Lars; Riordan, Ryan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Playing the Devil's Advocate: The Causal Effect of Risk Management on Loan Quality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Berg, Tobias
This paper studies the dual role of risk managers and loan officers in a bank's organizational structure. Using 75,000 retail mortgage applications, I analyze the effect of risk-management involvement on loan default rates. The bank requires risk-management approval for loans that are considered risky based on hard information, using a sharp threshold that changes during the sample period. Using a regression discontinuity design and a difference-in-differences estimator, I am able to show that risk-management involvement reduces loan default rates by more than 50%. My findings suggest that a two-agent model can help to facilitate efficient screening decisions.</description><author>Berg, Tobias</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Active Ownership</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dimson, Elroy; Karakas, Oguzhan; Li, Xi
We analyze an extensive proprietary database of corporate social responsibility engagements with U.S. public companies from 1999-2009. Engagements address environmental, social, and governance concerns. Successful (unsuccessful) engagements are followed by positive (zero) abnormal returns. Companies with inferior governance and socially conscious institutional investors are more likely to be engaged. Success in engagements is more probable if the engaged firm has reputational concerns and higher capacity to implement changes. Collaboration among activists is instrumental in increasing the success rate of environmental/social engagements. After successful engagements, particularly on environmental/social issues, companies experience improved accounting performance and governance and increased institutional ownership.</description><author>Dimson, Elroy; Karakas, Oguzhan; Li, Xi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Important Are Foreign Ownership Linkages for International Stock Returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartram, Soehnke M.; Griffin, John M.; Lim, Tae-Hoon; Ng, David T.
We derive a foreign ownership return as the weighted average return of foreign stocks that are connected to a stock through common ownership. The foreign ownership return is of similar economic significance as traditional country and industry factors in explaining international stock returns. It is not related to omitted fundamentals or wealth effects but shifts substantially around ADR and index listings when the investor habitat changes. A decomposition shows that the foreign ownership return is driven by active reallocations of global institutions as opposed to fund flows from end investors. Our findings have important implications for international portfolio diversification.</description><author>Bartram, Soehnke M.; Griffin, John M.; Lim, Tae-Hoon; Ng, David T.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing for Information Asymmetries in Real Estate Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kurlat, Pablo; Stroebel, Johannes
In housing markets, neighborhood characteristics are a key source of information heterogeneity: sellers are usually better informed about neighborhood values than buyers are, but some sellers and buyers are better informed than their peers are. Consistent with predictions from a new framework for analyzing such markets with heterogeneous assets and differentially informed agents, we find that changes in the composition of sellers toward more informed sellers and sellers with a larger supply elasticity predict subsequent house price declines. This effect is larger for houses with more price exposure to neighborhood characteristics, and smaller for houses bought by buyers that are more informed.</description><author>Kurlat, Pablo; Stroebel, Johannes</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding FX Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Karnaukh, Nina; Ranaldo, Angelo; Soederlind, Paul
We provide a comprehensive study of the liquidity of spot foreign exchange (FX) rates over more than two decades and a large cross-section of currencies. First, we show that FX liquidity can be accurately measured with daily and readily available data. Second, we demonstrate that FX liquidity declines with funding constraints and global risk, supporting theoretical models relating funding and market liquidity. In these distressed circumstances, liquidity tends to evaporate more for developed and riskier currencies. Finally, we show stronger comovements of FX liquidities in distressed markets, especially when funding is constrained, volatility is high, and FX speculators incur losses.</description><author>Karnaukh, Nina; Ranaldo, Angelo; Soederlind, Paul</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Home away from Home: Geography of Information and Local Investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bernile, Gennaro; Kumar, Alok; Sulaeman, Johan
We develop a 10-K-based multidimensional measure of firm locations. Using this measure, we show that firm-level information is geographically distributed and institutional investors are able to exploit the resulting information asymmetry. Specifically, institutional investors overweigh firms whose 10-K frequently mentions the investors' state even when those firms are not headquartered locally and earn superior returns on those stocks. These ownership and performance patterns are stronger among hard-to-value firms. Local investor performance increases with the degree of local bias and with the local economic exposure of portfolio firms. Overall, geographical variation in firm-level information generates economically significant location-based information asymmetry.</description><author>Bernile, Gennaro; Kumar, Alok; Sulaeman, Johan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling Credit Contagion via the Updating of Fragile Beliefs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Benzoni, Luca; Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.; Helwege, Jean
We propose an equilibrium model for defaultable bonds that are subject to contagion risk. Contagion arises because agents with "fragile beliefs" are uncertain about the underlying economic state and its probability. Estimation on sovereign European credit default swaps (CDS) data shows that agents require a time-varying risk premium for bearing state uncertainty. The model outperforms affine specifications with the same number of state variables, suggesting that there are important nonlinearities in credit spreads that are captured by our model. Contagion drives most of the variation in CDS spreads, especially before the crisis. However, economic fundamentals account for a significant fraction during the crisis.</description><author>Benzoni, Luca; Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.; Helwege, Jean</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning About Unstable, Publicly Unobservable Payoffs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Payzan-LeNestour, Elise; Bossaerts, Peter
Neoclassical finance assumes that investors are Bayesian. In many realistic situations, Bayesian learning is challenging. Here, we consider investment opportunities that change randomly, while payoffs are observable only when invested. In a stylized version of the task, we wondered whether performance would be affected if one were to follow reinforcement learning principles instead. The answer is a definite yes. When asked to perform our task, participants overwhelmingly learned in a Bayesian way. They stopped being Bayesians, though, when not nudged into paying attention to contingency shifts. This raises an issue for financial markets: who has the incentive to nudge investors?</description><author>Payzan-LeNestour, Elise; Bossaerts, Peter</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Confusion of Confusions: A Test of the Disposition Effect and Momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Birru, Justin
Using investor-level data, I document that the disposition effect is absent following a stock split; inattentive investors may fail to split-adjust their reference point, confusing the winner versus loser status of their holdings. Consistent with the disposition effect impeding the incorporation of news, ex-date returns are significantly higher for split stocks with higher gains. However, the magnitude is small relative to momentum, and momentum remains robustly present among this sample of stocks void of the disposition effect. The results suggest that the disposition effect may slow the incorporation of news, but not to the extent that it alone explains momentum.</description><author>Birru, Justin</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Individual Investors Treat Trading as a Fun and Exciting Gambling Activity? Evidence from Repeated Natural Experiments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gao, Xiaohui; Lin, Tse-Chun
We hypothesize that individual investors treat trading as a fun and exciting gambling activity, implying substitution between this activity and alternative gambling opportunities. To examine this hypothesis, we study the lottery jackpots and the trading of individual investors in Taiwan. When the jackpots exceed 500 million Taiwan dollars, the trading volume decreases between 5.2% and 9.1% among stocks preferred by individual investors and between 6.8% and 8.6% among lottery-like stocks. The decline in individual buy volume is statistically indistinct from the decline in sell volume. Large jackpots are associated with less trading in options with high sensitivity to volatility.</description><author>Gao, Xiaohui; Lin, Tse-Chun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Competition for Order Flow with Fast and Slow Traders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>van Kervel, Vincent
The rise of computerized trading strategies in equity markets has spurred competition between trading venues. This paper shows that cross-venue strategies create highly interlinked markets: trades on one venue are followed by sizeable cancellations of limit orders on competing venues. These cancellations are explained in a simple model of competition between two limit order markets with fast and slow traders. Only the fast traders can access the liquidity of both venues simultaneously. Empirically, we confirm the predictions that the fraction of fast traders (1) reduces the equilibrium liquidity supply and (2) reduces the magnitude of the cancellations following a trade.</description><author>van Kervel, Vincent</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rumor Has It: Sensationalism in Financial Media</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahern, Kenneth R.; Sosyura, Denis
The media has an incentive to publish sensational news. We study how this incentive affects the accuracy of media coverage in the context of merger rumors. Using a novel dataset, we find that accuracy is predicted by a journalist's experience, specialized education, and industry expertise. Conversely, less accurate stories use ambiguous language and feature well-known firms with broad readership appeal. Investors do not fully account for the predictive power of these characteristics, leading to an initial target price overreaction and a subsequent reversal, consistent with limited attention. Overall, we provide novel evidence on the determinants of media accuracy and its effect on asset prices.</description><author>Ahern, Kenneth R.; Sosyura, Denis</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Differences of Opinion, Endogenous Liquidity, and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Osambela, Emilio
This paper studies how investors' differences of opinion affect liquidity and asset prices. In our economy, excessively optimistic investors are subject to an endogenous funding constraint that prevents default due to ex-ante-limited commitment. When the funding constraint binds, optimists use their savings to increase their consumption share, deterring default. This allows them to place speculative trades, increasing market liquidity. Their losses on these trades make them prone to default, leading to a renewed binding of the funding constraint. This feedback between funding illiquidity, disagreement, and market liquidity is consistent with several empirical features of liquidity and financial asset prices.</description><author>Osambela, Emilio</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>House Prices, Home Equity Borrowing, and Entrepreneurship</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corradin, Stefano; Popov, Alexander
This paper shows that housing wealth helps alleviate credit constraints for potential entrepreneurs by enabling home owners to extract equity from their property and invest it in their business. Using a large U.S. individual-level survey dataset for the 1996-2006 period, we find that a 10% increase in home equity raises the share of individuals who transition into self-employment each year from 1% to 1.07%. Our results persist when we use proxies for aggregate housing demand shocks and for the topological elasticity of housing supply to generate variation in home equity that is orthogonal to entrepreneurial choice.</description><author>Corradin, Stefano; Popov, Alexander</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Management in Banking Crises</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shapiro, Joel; Skeie, David
A regulator resolving a bank faces two audiences: depositors, who may run if they believe the regulator will not provide capital, and banks, which may take excess risk if they believe the regulator will provide capital. When the regulator's cost of injecting capital is private information, it manages expectations by using costly signals: (1) a regulator with a low cost of injecting capital may forbear on bad banks to signal toughness and reduce risk taking, and (2) a regulator with a high cost of injecting capital may bail out bad banks to increase confidence and prevent runs.</description><author>Shapiro, Joel; Skeie, David</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What's in a Name? Mutual Fund Flows When Managers Have Foreign-Sounding Names</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kumar, Alok; Niessen-Ruenzi, Alexandra; Spalt, Oliver G.
We show that name-induced stereotypes affect the investment choices of U.S. mutual fund investors. Managers with foreign-sounding names have about 10% lower annual fund flows, and this effect is stronger among funds with investor clienteles more likely to be suspicious of foreigners. Foreign-named managers experience lower appreciation (greater decline) in flows following good (bad) performance. Following 9/11, flows to funds with managers with Middle-Eastern-sounding names declined abnormally. In an experimental setting in which skill differences are absent, individuals allocate 11% less money to an index fund managed by a foreign-named manager. This gap widens following the Boston marathon bombings.</description><author>Kumar, Alok; Niessen-Ruenzi, Alexandra; Spalt, Oliver G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Bright Side of Corporate Diversification: Evidence from Internal Labor Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tate, Geoffrey; Yang, Liu
We document differences in human-capital deployment between diversified and focused firms. We find that diversified firms have higher labor productivity and that they redeploy labor to industries with better prospects in response to changing opportunities. The opportunities and incentives provided in internal labor markets in turn affect the development of workers' human capital. We find that workers more frequently transition to other industries in which their diversified firms operate and with smaller wage losses compared with workers in the open market, even when they leave their original firms. Overall, internal labor markets provide a bright side to corporate diversification.</description><author>Tate, Geoffrey; Yang, Liu</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shareholder Voting and Corporate Governance Around the World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iliev, Peter; Lins, Karl V.; Miller, Darius P.; Roth, Lukas
Using a sample of non-U.S. firms from 43 countries, we investigate whether laws and regulations as well as votes cast by U.S. institutional investors are consistent with an effective shareholder voting process. We find that laws and regulations allow for meaningful votes to be cast, as shareholder voting is both mandatory and binding for important elections. For votes cast, we find there is greater dissent voting when investors fear expropriation. Further, greater dissent voting is associated with higher director turnover and more M&amp;A withdrawals. Our results suggest that shareholder voting is an effective mechanism for exercising governance around the world.</description><author>Iliev, Peter; Lins, Karl V.; Miller, Darius P.; Roth, Lukas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can "High Costs" Justify Weak Demand for the Home Equity Conversion Mortgage?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davidoff, Thomas
Home Equity Conversion Mortgages ("HECMs") implicitly bundle nondefaultable credit lines with put options that let borrowers, or their heirs, sell mortgaged homes for the credit line limit when borrowers move or die. The put option's value, net of closing costs, bounds HECM's value to borrowers below. Older homeowners' weak demand is commonly attributed to HECM's "high costs," and the government prices insurance intending to avoid subsidy. However, simulations indicate put value has often exceeded closing costs, even ignoring other embedded options and using backward-looking expectations near the recent price-cycle peak. These results make weak demand more puzzling.</description><author>Davidoff, Thomas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Territorial Tax System Reform and Corporate Financial Policies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arena, Matteo P.; Kutner, George W.
We examine the effect of a permanent change to a country corporate income repatriation tax system on corporate financial policies. In 2009, Japan and the United Kingdom switched from a worldwide system to a territorial system for the taxation of repatriated foreign earnings, effectively reducing the tax liabilities of most multinational firms when repatriating earnings. We find that after the change firms accumulate less cash, pay out larger amounts through dividends and share repurchases, and invest less abroad. We do not find that the tax system change has significantly affected domestic investments even when controlling for capital constraints.</description><author>Arena, Matteo P.; Kutner, George W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Financing Spur Small Business Productivity? Evidence from a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Krishnan, Karthik; Nandy, Debarshi K.; Puri, Manju
We analyze how increased access to financing affects firm total factor productivity (TFP) by exploiting a natural experiment following interstate banking deregulations that increased access to bank financing. We find that firms' TFP increases after their states implement these deregulations. Using a regression discontinuity approach based on the Small Business Administration's funding eligibility criteria, we show that TFP increases following the deregulations are significantly greater for financially constrained firms. Our results suggest that greater access to financing allows financially constrained firms to invest in productive projects that may otherwise not be taken up.</description><author>Krishnan, Karthik; Nandy, Debarshi K.; Puri, Manju</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real Effects of Short-Selling Constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Grullon, Gustavo; Michenaud, Sebastien; Weston, James P.
We use a regulatory experiment (Regulation SHO) that relaxes short-selling constraints on a random sample of U.S. stocks to test whether capital market frictions have an effect on stock prices and corporate decisions. We find that an increase in short-selling activity causes prices to fall, and that small firms react to these lower prices by reducing equity issues and investment. These results not only provide evidence that short-selling constraints affect asset prices, but also confirm that short-selling activity has a causal impact on financing and investment decisions.</description><author>Grullon, Gustavo; Michenaud, Sebastien; Weston, James P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Invisible Hand of Short Selling: Does Short Selling Discipline Earnings Management?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Massa, Massimo; Zhang, Bohui; Zhang, Hong
We hypothesize that short selling has a disciplining role vis-a-vis firm managers that forces them to reduce earnings management. Using firm-level short-selling data for thirty-three countries collected over a sample period from 2002 to 2009, we document a significantly negative relationship between the threat of short selling and earnings management. Tests based on instrumental variable and exogenous regulatory experiments offer evidence of a causal link between short selling and earnings management. Our findings suggest that short selling functions as an external governance mechanism to discipline managers.</description><author>Massa, Massimo; Zhang, Bohui; Zhang, Hong</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning About CEO Ability and Stock Return Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pan, Yihui; Wang, Tracy Yue; Weisbach, Michael S.
Consistent with predictions from a stylized Bayesian learning model stock return volatility declines with CEO tenure in a convex manner, even for CEOs whose appointments occur for exogenous reasons. The decline is faster when there is higher uncertainty about the CEO's ability when there is more transparency about the firm's prospects, and when CEO ability is more important in value creation. We quantify the importance of uncertainty about CEO ability relative to the firm's fundamental cash flow uncertainty in contributing to stock return volatility, highlighting the importance of management in creating value.</description><author>Pan, Yihui; Wang, Tracy Yue; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Takeover Activity Cause Managerial Discipline? Evidence from International M&amp;A Laws</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lel, Ugur; Miller, Darius P.
This paper exploits the staggered initiation of takeover laws across countries to examine whether the threat of takeover enhances managerial discipline. We show that following the passage of takeover laws, poorly performing firms experience more frequent takeovers; the propensity to replace poorly performing CEOs increases, especially in countries with weak investor protection; and directors of targeted firms are more likely to lose board seats following corporate-control events. Our findings suggest that the threat of takeover causes managerial discipline through the incentives that the market for corporate control provides to boards to monitor managers.</description><author>Lel, Ugur; Miller, Darius P.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing Constraints and the Amplification of Aggregate Downturns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carvalho, Daniel
This paper shows that during industry downturns, firms experience significantly greater valuation losses when their industry peers' long-term debt is maturing at the time of the shocks. Across a range of tests, the analysis addresses the endogenous determination of peer debt-maturity structure. Overall, the evidence suggests that the negative externalities financially constrained firms impose on their industry peers can significantly amplify the effects of industry downturns. The evidence also provides support for the view that these amplification effects are driven by the adverse effect that financially constrained firms have on the balance sheets of their industry peers.</description><author>Carvalho, Daniel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Thinking Outside the Borders: Investors' Underreaction to Foreign Operations Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Xing
I use industry-level returns in foreign markets to examine the hypothesis that value-relevant foreign information slowly diffuses into the stock prices of U.S. multinational firms. A trading strategy that exploits foreign information generates abnormal returns of 0.8% monthly. I find that the market responds more slowly in periods with lower media coverage of foreign news and to information from more linguistically and culturally distant countries. These results suggest that both investors' inattention and lack of understanding of foreign information slow the incorporation of new information into prices. I further separate these two mechanisms by examining market responses to earnings surprises.</description><author>Huang, Xing</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Restraining Overconfident CEOs through Improved Governance: Evidence from the Sarbanes-Oxley Act</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banerjee, Suman; Humphery-Jenner, Mark; Nanda, Vikram
The literature posits that some CEO overconfidence benefits shareholders, though high levels may not. We argue that adequate controls and independent viewpoints provided by an independent board mitigates the costs of CEO overconfidence. We use the concurrent passage of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act and changes to the NYSE/NASDAQ listing rules (collectively, SOX) as natural experiments, to examine whether board independence improves decision making by overconfident CEOs. The results are strongly supportive: after SOX, overconfident CEOs reduce investment and risk exposure, increase dividends, improve postacquisition performance, and have better operating performance and market value. Importantly, these changes are absent for overconfident-CEO firms that were compliant prior to SOX.</description><author>Banerjee, Suman; Humphery-Jenner, Mark; Nanda, Vikram</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board Structure and Monitoring: New Evidence from CEO Turnovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, Lixiong; Masulis, Ronald W.
We use the 2003 NYSE and NASDAQ listing rules for board and committee independence as a quasinatural experiment to examine the causal relations between board structure and CEO monitoring. Noncompliant firms forced to raise board independence or adopt a fully independent nominating committee significantly increased their forced CEO turnover sensitivity to performance relative to compliant firms. Nominating committee independence is important even when firms had an independent board, and the effect is stronger when the CEO is on the committee. We conclude that greater board independence and full independence of nominating committees lead to more rigorous CEO monitoring and discipline.</description><author>Guo, Lixiong; Masulis, Ronald W.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Theory of Income Smoothing When Insiders Know More Than Outsiders</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Lambrecht, Bart M.
We develop a theory of income and payout smoothing by firms when insiders know more about income than outside shareholders, but property rights ensure that outsiders can enforce a fair payout. Insiders set payout to meet outsiders' expectations and underproduce to manage future expectations downward. The observed income and payout process are smooth and adjust partially and over time in response to economic shocks. The smaller the inside ownership, the more severe underproduction is, resulting in an "outside equity Laffer curve."</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Lambrecht, Bart M.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real Effects of Hedge Fund Activism: Productivity, Asset Allocation, and Labor Outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brav, Alon; Jiang, Wei; Kim, Hyunseob
This paper studies the long-term effect of hedge fund activism on firm productivity using plant-level information from the U.S. Census Bureau. A typical target firm improves production efficiency in the 3 years after intervention, with stronger improvements in business strategy-oriented interventions. Plants sold after intervention improve productivity significantly under new ownership, suggesting that capital redeployment is an important channel for value creation. Employees of target firms experience stagnation in work hours and wages despite an increase in labor productivity. Additional tests refute alternative explanations attributing the improvement to mean reversion, management's voluntary reforms, industry consolidation shocks, or activists' stock-picking abilities.</description><author>Brav, Alon; Jiang, Wei; Kim, Hyunseob</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Thin Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rostek, Marzena; Weretka, Marek
Large institutional investors dominate many financial markets. This paper develops a consumption-based model of markets in which all institutional traders recognize their impact on prices. Bilateral (buyer and seller) market power changes efficiency and arbitrage properties of equilibrium. Predictions match temporary and permanent price effects of supply shocks, order breakup, limits to arbitrage, nonneutrality of trading frequency, and real effects of shocks and announcements in periods other than event dates. Maximizing welfare and stabilizing liquidity through disclosure of information about fundamentals presents a trade-off. Equilibrium representation as "trading against price impact" provides a link with the industry's practice.</description><author>Rostek, Marzena; Weretka, Marek</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Exploring Return Dynamics via Corridor Implied Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andersen, Torben G.; Bondarenko, Oleg; Gonzalez-Perez, Maria T.
Some fundamental questions regarding equity-index return dynamics are difficult to address due to the latent character of spot volatility. We exploit tick-by-tick option quotes to compute a novel "Corridor Volatility" index which may serve as an observable proxy for short-term volatility. Exploiting this index, we find that equity-index volatility jumps are common, symmetrically distributed, and cojump with the underlying returns. Moreover, the return-volatility asymmetry is more pronounced than is generally recognized and is in force for both diffusive and jump innovations in volatility. Finally, the index performs admirably during turbulent market conditions, constituting a useful real-time gauge of market stress.</description><author>Andersen, Torben G.; Bondarenko, Oleg; Gonzalez-Perez, Maria T.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected Returns in Treasury Bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cieslak, Anna; Povala, Pavol
We study risk premium in U.S. Treasury bonds. We decompose Treasury yields into inflation expectations and maturity-specific interest-rate cycles, which we define as variation in yields orthogonal to expected inflation. The short-maturity cycle captures the real short-rate dynamics. Jointly with expected inflation, it comprises the expectations hypothesis (EH) term in the yield curve. Controlling for the EH term, we extract a measure of risk-premium variation from yields. The risk-premium factor forecasts excess bond returns in and out of sample and subsumes the common bond return predictor obtained as a linear combination of forward rates.</description><author>Cieslak, Anna; Povala, Pavol</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information, Analysts, and Stock Return Comovement</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hameed, Allaudeen; Morck, Randall; Shen, Jianfeng; Yeung, Bernard
Analysts follow disproportionally firms whose fundamentals correlate more with those of their industry peers. This coverage pattern supports models of profit-maximizing information intermediaries producing preferentially information valuable in pricing more stocks. We designate highly followed firms whose fundamentals best predict those of peer firms as bellwether firms. When analysts revise a bellwether firm's earning forecast, it changes the prices of other firms significantly; however, revisions for firms that are less intensely followed do not change the prices of heavily followed firms. Unidirectional information spillovers explain how the more accurately priced stocks might exhibit more comovement.</description><author>Hameed, Allaudeen; Morck, Randall; Shen, Jianfeng; Yeung, Bernard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Sovereign Wealth Fund Discount: Evidence from Public Equity Investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bortolotti, Bernardo; Fotak, Veljko; Megginson, William L.
We document that announcement-period abnormal returns of sovereign wealth fund (SWF) equity investments in publicly traded firms are positive but lower than those of comparable private investments. Further, SWF investment targets suffer from declining return on assets and sales growth over the following three years. Our results are robust to controls for target and deal characteristics and are not driven by SWF target selection criteria. Larger discounts are associated with SWFs taking seats on boards of directors and with SWFs under strict government control acquiring greater stakes, supporting the hypothesis that political influence negatively affects firm value and performance.</description><author>Bortolotti, Bernardo; Fotak, Veljko; Megginson, William L.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuing Changes in Political Networks: Evidence from Campaign Contributions to Close Congressional Elections</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Akey, Pat
This paper investigates the value of firm political connections using a regression discontinuity design in a sample of close, off-cycle U.S. congressional elections. I compare firms donating to winning candidates and firms donating to losing candidates and find that postelection abnormal equity returns are 3% higher for firms donating to winning candidates. Connections to politicians serving on powerful congressional committees, such as appropriations and taxation, are especially valuable and impact contributing firms sales. Firms' campaign contributions are correlated with other political activities such as lobbying and hiring former government employees, suggesting that firms take coordinated actions to build political networks.</description><author>Akey, Pat</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Structure, Investment, and Fire Sales</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gale, Douglas; Gottardi, Piero
We study a dynamic general equilibrium model in which firms choose their investment level and capital structure, trading off the tax advantages of debt against the risk of costly default. Bankruptcy costs are endogenous, as bankrupt firms are forced to liquidate their assets, resulting in a fire sale if the market is illiquid. When the corporate income tax rate is positive, firms have a unique optimal capital structure. In equilibrium, firms default with positive probability and their assets are liquidated at fire-sale prices. The equilibrium features underinvestment and is constrained inefficient. In particular there is too little debt and default.</description><author>Gale, Douglas; Gottardi, Piero</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuation, Adverse Selection, and Market Collapses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fishman, Michael J.; Parker, Jonathan A.
We study a market for funding real investment where valuation-meaning investors devoting resources to acquiring information about future payoffs-creates an adverse selection problem. Unlike previous models, more valuation is associated with lower market prices and so greater returns to valuation. This strategic complementarity in the capacity to do valuation generates multiple equilibria. With multiple equilibria, the equilibrium without valuation is most efficient despite funding some unprofitable investments. Switches to valuation equilibria, valuation runs, look like credit crunches. A large investor can ensure the efficient equilibrium only if it can precommit to a price and potentially, only if subsidized.</description><author>Fishman, Michael J.; Parker, Jonathan A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>On Bounding Credit-Event Risk Premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bai, Jennie; Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.; Helwege, Jean
Reduced-form models of default that attribute a large fraction of credit spreads to compensation for credit-event risk typically preclude the most plausible economic justification for such risk to be priced, namely, a contemporaneous drop in the market portfolio. When this "contagion" channel is introduced within a general equilibrium framework for an economy comprising a large number of firms, credit-event risk premia have an upper bound of a few basis points, and are dwarfed by the contagion premium. We provide empirical evidence that indicates credit-event risk premia are less than 1 bp, but contagion risk premia are significant.</description><author>Bai, Jennie; Collin-Dufresne, Pierre; Goldstein, Robert S.; Helwege, Jean</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Tax Timing with Asymmetric Long-Term/Short-Term Capital Gains Tax</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dai, Min; Liu, Hong; Yang, Chen; Zhong, Yifei
We develop an optimal tax-timing model that takes into account asymmetric long-term and short-term tax rates for positive capital gains and limited tax deductibility of capital losses. In contrast to the existing literature, this model can help explain why many investors not only defer short-term capital losses to long term but also defer large long-term capital gains and losses. Because the benefit of tax deductibility of capital losses increases with the short-term tax rates, effective tax rates can decrease as short-term capital gains tax rates increase.</description><author>Dai, Min; Liu, Hong; Yang, Chen; Zhong, Yifei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Are University Endowments Large and Risky?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gilbert, Thomas; Hrdlicka, Christopher
We build a model of universities combining their real production decisions with their choice of endowment size and asset allocation. Variation in opportunity cost, that is, the productivity of internal projects, has a first-order effect on these choices. Adding the UPMIFA-mandated 7% payout constraint, the endowment size and asset allocations match those empirically observed. This constraint has little effect on universities that do not value the output of their internal projects but harms those that do: it prevents the endowment's use as an effective buffer stock, thereby increasing the volatility of production, and it slows the growth of the most productive universities.</description><author>Gilbert, Thomas; Hrdlicka, Christopher</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Investment and Industry Risk Dynamics</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bustamante, M. Cecilia
This paper characterizes how firms' strategic interaction in product markets affects the industry dynamics of investment and expected returns. In imperfectly competitive industries, a firm's exposure to systematic risk is affected by both its own investment strategy and the investment strategies of its peers, so that the dynamics of its expected returns depend on the intraindustry value spread. In the model and the data, firms' betas and returns correlate more positively in industries with low value spread, low dispersion in operating markups, and low concentration.</description><author>Bustamante, M. Cecilia</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency Problems of Corporate Philanthropy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Masulis, Ronald W.; Reza, Syed Walid
Evaluating agency theory and optimal contracting theory views of corporate philanthropy, we find that as corporate giving increases, shareholders reduce their valuation of firm cash holdings. Dividend increases following the 2003 Tax Reform Act are associated with reduced corporate giving. Using a natural experiment, we find that corporate giving is positively (negatively) associated with CEO charity preferences (CEO shareholdings and corporate governance quality). Evidence from CEO-affiliated charity donations, market reactions to insider-affiliated donations, its relation to CEO compensation, and firm contributions to director-affiliated charities indicates that corporate donations advance CEO interests and suggests misuses of corporate resources that reduce firm value.</description><author>Masulis, Ronald W.; Reza, Syed Walid</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and Shareholder Activism</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Norli, Oyvind; Ostergaard, Charlotte; Schindele, Ibolya
Blockholders' incentives to intervene in corporate governance are weakened by free-rider problems and high costs of activism. Theory suggests activists may recoup expenses through informed trading of target firms' stock when stocks are liquid. We show that stock liquidity increases the probability of activism but does less so for potentially overvalued firms for which privately informed blockholders may have greater incentives to sell their stake than to intervene. We also document that activists accumulate more stocks in targets when stock is more liquid. We conclude that liquidity helps overcome the free-rider problem and induces activism via preactivism accumulation of target firms' shares.</description><author>Norli, Oyvind; Ostergaard, Charlotte; Schindele, Ibolya</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Investment and Stock Market Listing: A Puzzle?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Asker, John; Farre-Mensa, Joan; Ljungqvist, Alexander
We investigate whether short-termism distorts the investment decisions of stock market-listed firms. To do so, we compare the investment behavior of observably similar public and private firms, using a new data source on private U.S. firms and assuming for identification that closely held private firms are subject to fewer short-termist pressures. Our results show that compared with private firms, public firms invest substantially less and are less responsive to changes in investment opportunities, especially in industries in which stock prices are most sensitive to earnings news. These findings are consistent with the notion that short-termist pressures distort investment decisions.</description><author>Asker, John; Farre-Mensa, Joan; Ljungqvist, Alexander</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Labor Protection and Leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Simintzi, Elena; Vig, Vikrant; Volpin, Paolo
This paper exploits intertemporal variations in employment protection across countries and finds that rigidities in labor markets are an important determinant of firms' capital structure decisions. Over the 1985-2007 period, we find that reforms increasing employment protection are associated with a 187 basis point reduction in leverage. We interpret this finding to suggest that employment protection increases operating leverage, crowding out financial leverage. This result does not appear to be due to pretreatment differences between treated and control firms, omitted variables, unobserved changes in regional economic conditions, and reverse causality. Heterogeneous treatment effects are consistent with our economic intuition.</description><author>Simintzi, Elena; Vig, Vikrant; Volpin, Paolo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ownership Structure, Voting, and Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dhillon, Amrita; Rossetto, Silvia
We analyze the determinants of a firm's ownership structure when decisions over risk are taken by majority vote of risk-averse shareholders. We show that when a fraction of small, diversified shareholders abstains from voting, mid-sized blockholders may emerge to mitigate the conflict of interests between one large shareholder, who prefers less risky investments, and these small, non-voting shareholders. The paper offers a novel explanation for the puzzling observation that many firms have multiple blockholders. The paper develops numerous empirical implications, for example on the link between ownership structure and risk choices and on the relative size of blocks.</description><author>Dhillon, Amrita; Rossetto, Silvia</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Mutual Funds Active Voters?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iliev, Peter; Lowry, Michelle
Mutual funds vary greatly in their reliance on proxy advisory recommendations. Over 25% of funds rely almost entirely on Institutional Shareholder Services (ISS) recommendations, while other funds place little weight on them. Funds with higher benefits and lower costs of researching the items up for vote are less likely to rely on ISS. These actively voting funds are less likely to vote in a "one-size-fits-all" manner, and they earn higher alphas, consistent with benefits from this allocation of resources. For the underlying firms, the presence of actively voting funds mitigates the influence of ISS and helps sway shareholder votes toward value-maximizing outcomes.</description><author>Iliev, Peter; Lowry, Michelle</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Regression Discontinuity and the Price Effects of Stock Market Indexing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Yen-Cheng; Hong, Harrison; Liskovich, Inessa
The Russell 1000 and 2000 stock indexes comprise the first 1000 and next 2000 largest firms ranked by market capitalization. Small changes in the capitalizations of firms ranked near 1000 move them between these indexes. Because the indexes are value-weighted, more money tracks the largest stocks in the Russell 2000 than the smallest in the Russell 1000. Using this discontinuity, we find that additions to the Russell 2000 result in price increases and deletions result in price declines. We then identify time trends in indexing effects and the types of funds that provide liquidity to indexers.</description><author>Chang, Yen-Cheng; Hong, Harrison; Liskovich, Inessa</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Implicit Costs of Trade Credit Borrowing by Large Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Murfin, Justin; Njoroge, Ken
We examine a novel, but economically important, characterization of trade credit relationships in which large investment-grade buyers borrow from their smaller suppliers. Using a matched sample of large retail buyers and their much smaller suppliers, we find that slower payment terms by large retailers are associated with lower investment at the supplier level. The effects are sharpest during periods of tight bank credit and for firms which we might otherwise characterize as financially constrained. The opportunity cost of extending credit to large buyers appears to be positive and sharply increasing in the financial frictions facing a firm.</description><author>Murfin, Justin; Njoroge, Ken</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Weather-Induced Mood, Institutional Investors, and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goetzmann, William N.; Kim, Dasol; Kumar, Alok; Wang, Qin
This study shows that weather-based indicators of mood impact perceptions of mispricing and trading decisions of institutional investors. Using survey and disaggregated trade data, we show that relatively cloudier days increase perceived overpricing in individual stocks and the Dow Jones Industrial Index and increase selling propensities of institutions. We introduce stock-level measures of investor mood; investor optimism positively impacts stock returns among stocks with higher arbitrage costs, and stocks experiencing similar investor mood exhibit return comovement. These findings complement existing studies on how weather impacts stock index returns and identify another channel through which it can manifest.</description><author>Goetzmann, William N.; Kim, Dasol; Kumar, Alok; Wang, Qin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Attention and Stock Market Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andrei, Daniel; Hasler, Michael
We investigate, in a theoretical framework, the joint role played by investors' attention to news and learning uncertainty in determining asset prices. The model provides two main predictions. First, stock return variance and risk premia increase with both attention and uncertainty. Second, this increasing relationship is quadratic. We empirically test these two predictions, and we show that the data lend support to the increasing relationship. The evidence for a quadratic relationship is mixed. Overall, our study shows theoretically and empirically that both attention and uncertainty are key determinants of asset prices.</description><author>Andrei, Daniel; Hasler, Michael</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Sum of All FEARS Investor Sentiment and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Da, Zhi; Engelberg, Joseph; Gao, Pengjie
We use daily Internet search volume from millions of households to reveal market-level sentiment. By aggregating the volume of queries related to household concerns (e.g., "recession," "unemployment," and "bankruptcy"), we construct a Financial and Economic Attitudes Revealed by Search (FEARS) index as a new measure of investor sentiment. Between 2004 and 2011, we find FEARS (i) predict short-term return reversals, (ii) predict temporary increases in volatility, and (iii) predict mutual fund flows out of equity funds and into bond funds. Taken together, the results are broadly consistent with theories of investor sentiment.</description><author>Da, Zhi; Engelberg, Joseph; Gao, Pengjie</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Feedback Trading between Fundamental and Nonfundamental Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guo, Ming; Ou-Yang, Hui
We develop a strategic trading model in which an insider exploits noise traders' overreaction. A feedback effect arises from the insider's trading on fundamental information (the expected growth rate of dividends) and nonfundamental information (insider's inventory or noise supply). We find that the stock price is not fully revealing; a faster mean-reverting noise supply leads to a more volatile price; the price impact can increase with insider's risk-aversion; and a risk-averse insider can trade more aggressively on fundamental information than a risk-neutral one does. Insider's current trade and his previous inventory exhibit simultaneously positive forecasting powers for future stock returns.</description><author>Guo, Ming; Ou-Yang, Hui</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization and the Fixed-Rate Mortgage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fuster, Andreas; Vickery, James
Fixed-rate mortgages (FRMs) dominate the U.S. mortgage market, with important consequences for monetary policy, household risk management, and financial stability. We show that the FRM market share is sharply lower when mortgages are difficult to securitize, exploiting plausibly exogenous variation in access to liquid securitization markets generated by a regulatory cutoff and time variation in private securitization activity. We interpret our findings as evidence that lenders are reluctant to retain the prepayment and interest rate risk embedded in FRMs. The form of securitization (private versus government backed) has little effect on FRM supply during periods in which private securitization markets are well functioning.</description><author>Fuster, Andreas; Vickery, James</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shadow Banking and Bank Capital Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Plantin, Guillaume
Banks are subject to capital requirements because their privately optimal leverage is higher than the socially optimal one. This is in turn because banks fail to internalize all costs that their insolvency creates for agents who use their money-like liabilities to settle transactions. If banks can bypass capital regulation in an opaque shadow banking sector, it may be optimal to relax capital requirements so that liquidity dries up in the shadow banking sector. Tightening capital requirements may spur a surge in shadow banking activity that leads to an overall larger risk on the money-like liabilities of the formal and shadow banking institutions.</description><author>Plantin, Guillaume</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Supply Uncertainty, Cash Holdings, and Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hugonnier, Julien; Malamud, Semyon; Morellec, Erwan
We develop a dynamic model of investment, financing, and cash management decisions in which investment is lumpy and firms face capital supply uncertainty. We characterize optimal policies explicitly, demonstrate that smooth-pasting conditions may not guarantee optimality, and show that firms may not follow standard single barrier policies. In the model, firms with high investment costs differ in their behaviors from firms with low investment costs, financing policy does not follow a strict pecking order, and the optimal payout policy may feature several regions with both incremental and lumpy dividend payments.</description><author>Hugonnier, Julien; Malamud, Semyon; Morellec, Erwan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Sentiment Aligned: A Powerful Predictor of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Dashan; Jiang, Fuwei; Tu, Jun; Zhou, Guofu
We propose a new investor sentiment index that is aligned with the purpose of predicting the aggregate stock market. By eliminating a common noise component in sentiment proxies, the new index has much greater predictive power than existing sentiment indices have both in and out of sample, and the predictability becomes both statistically and economically significant. In addition, it outperforms well-recognized macroeconomic variables and can also predict cross-sectional stock returns sorted by industry, size, value, and momentum. The driving force of the predictive power appears to stem from investors' biased beliefs about future cash flows.</description><author>Huang, Dashan; Jiang, Fuwei; Tu, Jun; Zhou, Guofu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Hedging and Extreme Asset Co-movements</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Elkamhi, Redouane; Stefanova, Denitsa
The paper investigates the portfolio allocation effects of increased asset co-movements during market downturns. We develop a model for the stock price process that allows for increased and asymmetric dependence between extreme return realizations. We isolate the portfolio hedging demands that arise due to extreme co-movements and find a substantial shift of the portfolio holdings toward the risk-free asset. We demonstrate that accounting for dependence between extreme events in portfolio decisions leads to significant economic gains that stem primarily from intertemporal hedging motives. These findings are robust along alternative modeling assumptions of extreme co-movements and conditional correlation.</description><author>Elkamhi, Redouane; Stefanova, Denitsa</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Worst, the Best, Ignoring All the Rest: The Rank Effect and Trading Behavior</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hartzmark, Samuel M.
I document a new stylized fact about how investors trade assets: individuals are more likely to sell the extreme winning and extreme losing positions in their portfolio ("the rank effect"). This effect is not driven by firm-specific information, holding period or the level of returns itself, but is associated with the salience of extreme portfolio positions. The rank effect is exhibited by both retail traders and mutual fund managers. The effect indicates that trades in a given stock depend on how the stock compares to other positions in an investor's portfolio.</description><author>Hartzmark, Samuel M.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Post-Earnings-Announcement Drift in Global Markets: Evidence from an Information Shock</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hung, Mingyi; Li, Xi; Wang, Shiheng
We investigate whether and how an exogenous and unprecedented improvement in non-U.S. firms' financial-reporting quality affects post-earnings-announcement drift (PEAD). We find that PEAD declines after the information shock, and this decrease is more pronounced for firms with fewer concurrent earnings announcements, greater institutional holdings, and lower limits to arbitrage. In addition, the decrease in PEAD is driven by firms with greater changes in financial reporting, an increase in analyst forecast accuracy and institutional ownership, and a decrease in limits to arbitrage. These findings support the mispricing explanation of PEAD, in particular the limited attention hypothesis, in an international setting.</description><author>Hung, Mingyi; Li, Xi; Wang, Shiheng</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Predictable Corporate Distributions and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Zhang, Feng
Corporate managers frequently announce corporate distributions, including stock splits, stock dividends, special dividends, and increases in regular dividends, on the anniversary of a like announcement at the same firm. The market appears to not fully appreciate the implications of current distributions for future distributions and stock returns, as a simple strategy that involves purchasing firms with high predicted probabilities of distribution announcements earns significant abnormal monthly returns. These results are distinct from previously documented return regularities related to regular earnings and dividend announcements and return seasonality.</description><author>Bessembinder, Hendrik; Zhang, Feng</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Traders vs. Relationship Managers: Reputational Conflicts in Full-Service Investment Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Zhaohui; Morrison, Alan D.; Wilhelm, William J.
We present a model that explains why investment bankers struggle to manage conflicts of interest. Banks can build a type reputation for technical competence by performing complex deals that may not serve their clients' interest; on the other hand, banks can sustain a behavioral reputation by refraining from doing so. A behavioral reputation is a luxury reserved for banks that have proven their abilities. The model sheds light on conflicts between the trading and advisory divisions of investment banks, as well as the consequences of technological change for time variation in the relative strength of behavioral- and typereputation concerns.</description><author>Chen, Zhaohui; Morrison, Alan D.; Wilhelm, William J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Geography of Funding Markets and Limits to Arbitrage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buraschi, Andrea; Menguturk, Murat; Sener, Emrah
We use the relative pricing of pairs of emerging market (EM) sovereign bonds issued in both dollars and euros to study capital markets frictions during periods of financial distress. During the 2007-2008 crisis, we find the emergence of large pricing anomalies in EM sovereign bond markets. Neither liquidity nor short-selling constraints can explain these persistent events. We use both cross-sectional and time-series information on these pricing anomalies to learn about specific geographical frictions in funding markets. We find support for explanations based on the interaction of banking capital-structure frictions and the fragility of wholesale funding markets. We document the effects of nonconventional policy interventions on this mispricing.</description><author>Buraschi, Andrea; Menguturk, Murat; Sener, Emrah</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Costs of Closing Failed Banks: A Structural Estimation of Regulatory Incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kang, Ari; Lowery, Richard; Wardlaw, Malcolm
We estimate a dynamic model of the decision to close a troubled bank. Regulators trade off an aversion to closing banks against the risk that allowing a bank to continue will raise the eventual costs to the deposit insurance fund. Using a conditional choice probability approach, we estimate the costs associated with closing banks, both in direct costs to the insurance fund and in other costs perceived by regulators, either social or personal. We find that delayed closures were driven by a desire to defer costs, an aversion to closing the largest and smallest troubled banks, and political influence.</description><author>Kang, Ari; Lowery, Richard; Wardlaw, Malcolm</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Human Capital as an Asset Class Implications from a General Equilibrium Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Palacios, Miguel
This paper derives the value and risk of aggregate human capital in a stochastic equilibrium model with Duffie-Epstein preferences. Athree-factor asset-pricing model is derived, where the factors are the market, the capital share, and investment in human capital. When the model is calibrated to match the historical ratio of wages to consumption in the United States, the weight of human capital in aggregate wealth is estimated to be about 93%, well above most previous estimates, and human capital's riskiness is lower than that of the market portfolio.</description><author>Palacios, Miguel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Money Creation and the Shadow Banking System</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sunderam, Adi
It is widely argued that shadow banking grew rapidly before the recent financial crisis because of rising demand for "money-like" claims. This paper assesses a key premise of this argument: that investors actually treated short-term debt issued by shadow banks as a money-like claim. I present a model where the financial sector and the central bank jointly respond to demand for money-like claims. The model generates predictions about the prices and quantities of Treasury bills, central bank reserves, and shadow bank debt. These predictions are borne out in the data, suggesting investors did treat shadow bank debt as money-like.</description><author>Sunderam, Adi</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Monotonicity of the Stochastic Discount Factor and Expected Option Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chaudhuri, Ranadeb; Schroder, Mark
Evidence shows that the stochastic discount factor (SDF) is not always a downward-sloping function of S&amp;P 500 returns when estimated using options data. In contrast, our results suggest that SDFs as functions of individual stock returns are generally downward sloping. A simple jump-diffusion model can reconcile these empirical findings. The same model also implies a steeper implied-volatility curve for the index than for the typical stock, a well-known empirical fact from the options literature. Both the SDF and volatility-curve results can be explained by a common source of jump risk among stocks, together with diversification of Brownian risk in the index. We also devise novel empirical tests of SDF monotonicity based on average returns of option trading strategies, thus avoiding the estimation of the return density functions.</description><author>Chaudhuri, Ranadeb; Schroder, Mark</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Redefining Financial Constraints: A Text-Based Analysis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hoberg, Gerard; Maksimovic, Vojislav
We score 10-K text to obtain annual measures of financial constraints, with separate measures for firms reporting equity and debt financing issues. Equity market constraints are associated with firms funding growth opportunities, have more severe consequences for the firm following large unexpected negative shocks, and are likely driven by informational asymmetries. A significant population of firms reporting equity market constraints also declare that they possess material undisclosed proprietary information. Constraints in the debt markets are distinct and are linked to covenant violations. Our measures outperform others used in the literature in predicting investment cuts following negative shocks.</description><author>Hoberg, Gerard; Maksimovic, Vojislav</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Robust Econometric Inference for Stock Return Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kostakis, Alexandros; Magdalinos, Tassos; Stamatogiannis, Michalis P.
This study examines stock return predictability via lagged financial variables with unknown stochastic properties. We propose a novel testing procedure that (1) robustifies inference to regressors' degree of persistence, (2) accommodates testing the joint predictive ability of financial variables in multiple regression, (3) is easy to implement as it is based on a linear estimation procedure, and (4) can be used for long-horizon predictability tests. We provide some evidence in favor of short-horizon predictability during the 1927-2012 period. Nevertheless, this evidence almost entirely disappears in the post-1952 period. Moreover, predictability becomes weaker, not stronger, as the predictive horizon increases.</description><author>Kostakis, Alexandros; Magdalinos, Tassos; Stamatogiannis, Michalis P.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Modeling Covariance Risk in Merton's ICAPM</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Rossi, Alberto G.; Timmermann, Allan
We propose a new method for constructing the hedge component in Merton's ICAPM that uses a daily summary measure of economic activity to track time-varying investment opportunities. We then use nonparametric projections to compute a robust estimate of the conditional covariance between stock market returns and our daily economic activity index. We find that the new conditional covariance risk measure plays an important role in explaining time variation in the equity risk premium. Specification tests as well as out-of-sample forecasts of aggregate stock returns suggest that the new covariance risk measure performs well compared to alternative covariance measures previously proposed in the literature.</description><author>Rossi, Alberto G.; Timmermann, Allan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Informational Role of Stock and Bond Volume</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Back, Kerry; Crotty, Kevin
In a Kyle (1985) model, the sign of the correlation between a firm's debt and equity returns is the same as the sign of the cross-market Kyle's lambda. The sign is positive (negative) if private information concerns the mean (risk) of the firm's assets. We show empirically that information conveyed by order flows is primarily about asset means. The cross-market lambdas are quite large; consequently, the portions of bond and stock returns explained by order flows are highly correlated, even though the order flows themselves are virtually uncorrelated.</description><author>Back, Kerry; Crotty, Kevin</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamics of Innovation and Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Biais, Bruno; Rochet, Jean-Charles; Woolley, Paul
We study the dynamics of an innovative industry in which agents learn about the likelihood of negative shocks. Managers can exert risk prevention effort to mitigate the consequences of shocks. If no shock occurs, confidence improves, attracting managers to the innovative sector. But, when confidence becomes high, inefficient managers exerting low risk-prevention effort also enter. This stimulates growth, while reducing risk prevention. The longer the boom, the larger the losses if a shock occurs. Although these dynamics arise in the first-best, asymmetric information generates excessive entry of inefficient managers, earning informational rents, inflating the innovative sector, and increasing its vulnerability.</description><author>Biais, Bruno; Rochet, Jean-Charles; Woolley, Paul</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Evidence on the Financialization of Commodity Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Henderson, Brian J.; Pearson, Neil D.; Wang, Li
This paper uses a novel dataset of commodity-linked notes (CLNs) to examine the impact of the flows of financial investors on commodity futures prices. Investor flows into and out of CLNs are passed to and withdrawn from the futures markets via issuers' trades to hedge their CLN liabilities. The flows are not based on information about futures price movements but nonetheless cause increases and decreases in commodity futures prices when they are passed through to and withdrawn from the futures markets. These finding are consistent with the hypothesis that non-information-based financial investments have important impacts on commodity prices.</description><author>Henderson, Brian J.; Pearson, Neil D.; Wang, Li</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Distress, Stock Returns, and the 1978 Bankruptcy Reform Act</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hackbarth, Dirk; Haselmann, Rainer; Schoenherr, David
We study distress risk premia around a bankruptcy reform that shifts bargaining power in financial distress from debtholders to shareholders. We find that the reform reduces risk factor loadings and returns of distressed stocks. The reform effect is stronger for firms with lower firm-level shareholder bargaining power. An increase in credit spreads of riskier relative to safer firms, in particular for firms with lower firm-level shareholder bargaining power, confirms a shift in bargaining power from bondholders to shareholders. Out-of-sample tests reveal that a reversal of the reform's effect leads to a reversal of factor loadings and returns.</description><author>Hackbarth, Dirk; Haselmann, Rainer; Schoenherr, David</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When Less Is More: The Benefits of Limits on Executive Pay</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cebon, Peter; Hermalin, Benjamin E.
We derive conditions under which limits on executive compensation can enhance efficiency and benefit shareholders (but not executives). Having its hands tied in the future allows a board of directors to credibly enter into relational contracts with executives that are more efficient than performance-contingent contracts. This has implications for the ideal composition of the board. The analysis also offers insights into the political economy of executive-compensation reform.</description><author>Cebon, Peter; Hermalin, Benjamin E.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capital Account Opening and Wage Inequality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Larrain, Mauricio
Opening the capital account allows financially constrained firms to raise capital from abroad. Since capital and skilled labor are relative complements, this increases the relative demand for skilled labor versus unskilled labor, leading to higher wage inequality. Using aggregate data and exploiting variation in the timing of capital account openings across 20 mainly European countries, I find that opening the capital account increases aggregate wage inequality. In order to identify the mechanism, I use sectoral data and exploit variation in external financial dependence and capital-skill complementarity across industries. I find that capital account opening increases sectoral wage inequality, particularly in industries with both high financial needs and strong complementarity.</description><author>Larrain, Mauricio</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Digesting Anomalies: An Investment Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hou, Kewei; Xue, Chen; Zhang, Lu
An empirical -factor model consisting of the market factor, a size factor, an investment factor, and a profitability factor largely summarizes the cross section of average stock returns. A comprehensive examination of nearly 80 anomalies reveals that about one-half of the anomalies are insignificant in the broad cross section. More importantly, with a few exceptions, the -factor model's performance is at least comparable to, and in many cases better than that of the Fama-French (1993) 3-factor model and the Carhart (1997) 4-factor model in capturing the remaining significant anomalies.</description><author>Hou, Kewei; Xue, Chen; Zhang, Lu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Public Financial News Resolve Asymmetric Information? (vol 23, pg 3520, 2010)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tetlock, Paul C.
nan</description><author>Tetlock, Paul C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Housing Risk Be Diversified? A Cautionary Tale from the Housing Boom and Bust</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cotter, John; Gabriel, Stuart; Roll, Richard
This study evaluates the effectiveness of geographic diversification in reducing housing investment risk. To characterize diversification potential, we estimate spatial correlation and integration among 401 U.S. metropolitan housing markets. The 2000s boom brought a marked uptrend in housing market integration associated with eased residential lending standards and rapid growth in private mortgage securitization. As boom turned to bust, other macroeconomic factors, including employment and income fundamentals, importantly contributed to the trending up in housing return integration. Portfolio simulations reveal substantially lower diversification potential and higher risk in the wake of increased market integration.</description><author>Cotter, John; Gabriel, Stuart; Roll, Richard</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Self-Exciting Jumps, Learning, and Asset Pricing Implications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fulop, Andras; Li, Junye; Yu, Jun
The paper proposes a self-exciting asset pricing model that takes into account co-jumps between prices and volatility and self-exciting jump clustering. We employ a Bayesian learning approach to implement real-time sequential analysis. We find evidence of self-exciting jump clustering since the 1987 market crash, and its importance becomes more obvious at the onset of the 2008 global financial crisis. We also find that learning affects the tail behaviors of the return distributions and has important implications for risk management, volatility forecasting, and option pricing.</description><author>Fulop, Andras; Li, Junye; Yu, Jun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cognitive Limitation and Investment Performance: Evidence from Limit Order Clustering</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kuo, Wei-Yu; Lin, Tse-Chun; Zhao, Jing
We hypothesize that cognitive limitation may be manifested in a disproportionately large volume of limit orders submitted at round-number prices if investors use these numbers as cognitive shortcuts. Using detailed limit order data in the Taiwan Futures Exchange, we find that investors with lower cognitive abilities, defined as higher limit order submission ratios at round numbers, suffer greater losses in their round-numbered and non-round-numbered limit orders, market orders, and round-trip trades. The positive correlation between cognitive ability and investment performance is monotonic and robust across futures and options markets. In addition, past trading experience helps mitigate cognitive limitation.</description><author>Kuo, Wei-Yu; Lin, Tse-Chun; Zhao, Jing</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Information, Long-Run Risk, and the Term Structure of Equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Croce, Mariano M.; Lettau, Martin; Ludvigson, Sydney C.
We study the role of information in asset-pricing models with long-run cash flow risk. When investors can distinguish short- from long-run consumption risks (full information), the model generates a sizable equity risk premium only if the equity term structure slopes up, contrary to the data. In general, the short- and long-run components are unidentified. We propose a sparsity-based bounded rationality model of long-run risk that is both parsimonious and fully identified from historical data. In contrast to full information, the model generates a sizable market risk premium simultaneously with a downward-sloping equity term structure, as in the data.</description><author>Croce, Mariano M.; Lettau, Martin; Ludvigson, Sydney C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Editorial: Cosmetic Surgery in the Academic Review Process</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, David
Has the academic review process become excessive? In a setting where editors cannot distinguish significant flaws from mere blemishes, reviewers recommend the repair of blemishes in order to acquire reputations for high skill. In equilibrium, editors accede to reviewer insistence upon such cosmetic surgery. If blemishes are sometimes unremovable, demands for repair sometimes block good papers from publication. This implies a social value to active editing. Reviewer signal-jamming may especially suppress innovative research and research designed to verify others' findings. This perspective strongly suggests that the growth of the review process is harmful. I therefore offer tentative proposals for reform.</description><author>Hirshleifer, David</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Peer Effects in Risk Aversion and Trust</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ahern, Kenneth R.; Duchin, Ran; Shumway, Tyler
Existing evidence shows that risk aversion and trust are largely determined by environmental factors. We test whether one such factor is peer influence. Using random assignment of MBA students to peer groups and predetermined survey responses of economic attitudes, we find causal evidence of positive peer effects in risk aversion and no effects in trust. After the first year of the MBA program, the difference between an individual and her peers' average risk aversion has shrunk by 41%. Finding no peer effects in trust is consistent with recent research showing that distinct cognitive processes govern risk aversion and trust.</description><author>Ahern, Kenneth R.; Duchin, Ran; Shumway, Tyler</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading for Status</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hong, Harrison; Jiang, Wenxi; Wang, Na; Zhao, Bin
We show that Keeping-Up-with-the-Joneses preferences can explain several puzzling retail investor behaviors, including the excessive trading of small local stocks. Status concerns lead households, especially those living in affluent areas, to demand these stocks to track their neighbors' wealth. This demand varies procyclically with the stock market's value and generates household trading. Using Chinese data on local stock turnover, stock message boards, and brokerage account trading, we test and confirm this hypothesis by exploiting the uneven rise of affluence across Chinese cities between 1998 and 2012.</description><author>Hong, Harrison; Jiang, Wenxi; Wang, Na; Zhao, Bin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Window Dressing in Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agarwal, Vikas; Gay, Gerald D.; Ling, Leng
We provide a rationale for window dressing wherein investors respond to conflicting signals of managerial ability inferred from a fund's performance and disclosed portfolio holdings. We contend that window dressers make a risky bet on their performance during a reporting delay period, which affects investors' interpretation of the conflicting signals and hence their capital allocations. Conditional on good (bad) performance, window dressers benefit (suffer) from higher (lower) investor flows compared with non-window dressers. Window dressers also show poor past performance, possess little skill, and incur high portfolio turnover and trade costs, characteristics which in turn result in worse future performance.</description><author>Agarwal, Vikas; Gay, Gerald D.; Ling, Leng</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fooling Some of the People All of the Time: The Inefficient Performance and Persistence of Commodity Trading Advisors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhardwaj, Geetesh; Gorton, Gary B.; Rouwenhorst, K. Geert
Investors face significant barriers in evaluating the performance of investment advisors. We focus on commodity trading advisors (CTAs) and show that from 1994 to 2012, CTA excess returns to investors (i.e., net of fees) were insignificantly different from zero while gross excess returns (i.e., before fees) were 6.1%, which implies that managers captured the performance in fees. Moreover, we find that CTAs display no alpha relative to simple future strategies in the public domain. Our results have implications for all hedge fund studies in that we find the typical adjustments for biases in the hedge fund databases still leave upward bias in fund performance.</description><author>Bhardwaj, Geetesh; Gorton, Gary B.; Rouwenhorst, K. Geert</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Media Coverage of Stocks Affect Mutual Funds' Trading and Performance?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fang, Lily H.; Peress, Joel; Zheng, Lu
We study the relation between mutual fund trades and mass media coverage of stocks. We find that funds exhibit persistent differences in their propensity to buy media-covered stocks. Moreover, this propensity is negatively related to their future performance. Funds in the highest propensity decile underperform funds in the lowest propensity decile by 1.1% to 2.8% per year. These results do not extend to fund sells, likely because of funds' inability to sell short. Overall, the findings suggest that professional investors are subject to limited attention.</description><author>Fang, Lily H.; Peress, Joel; Zheng, Lu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Opacity in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sato, Yuki
This paper studies the implications of opacity in financial markets for investor behavior, asset prices, and welfare. Transparent funds (e.g., mutual funds) and opaque funds (e.g., hedge funds) trade transparent assets (e.g., plain-vanilla products) and opaque assets (e.g., structured products). Investors observe neither opaque funds' portfolios nor opaque assets' payoffs. Consistent with empirical observations, an "opacity price premium" arises: opaque assets trade at a premium over transparent ones despite identical payoffs. This accompanies endogenous market segmentation: transparent (opaque) funds trade only transparent (opaque) assets. The opacity price premium incentivizes financial engineers to render transparent assets opaque deliberately.</description><author>Sato, Yuki</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Media Makes Momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hillert, Alexander; Jacobs, Heiko; Mueller, Sebastian
Relying on 2.2 million articles from forty-five national and local U.S. newspapers between 1989 and 2010, we find that firms particularly covered by the media exhibit, ceteris paribus, significantly stronger momentum. The effect depends on article tone, reverses in the long run, is more pronounced for stocks with high uncertainty, and is stronger in states with high investor individualism. Our findings suggest that media coverage can exacerbate investor biases, leading return predictability to be strongest for firms in the spotlight of public attention. These results collectively lend credibility to an overreaction-based explanation for the momentum effect.</description><author>Hillert, Alexander; Jacobs, Heiko; Mueller, Sebastian</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Prices and Real Exchange Rates with Deep Habits</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heyerdahl-Larsen, Christian
I introduce an external habit for each consumption good, known as deep habits, into an otherwise standard international equilibrium model with multiple consumption goods and multiple countries. I show that deep habits coupled with consumption home bias account for a wide range of asset pricing and exchange rate moments. Calibrated to a set of ten countries, the model reproduces the cross-sectional evidence on currency risk premiums when sorting on interest rates, interest rate volatility, innovations to global exchange rate volatility, and value. Hence, the model provides an equilibrium interpretation of these empirical regularities.</description><author>Heyerdahl-Larsen, Christian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Aggregate Investment and Investor Sentiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Arif, Salman; Lee, Charles M. C.
Using bottom-up information from corporate financial statements, we examine the relation between aggregate investment, future equity returns, and investor sentiment. Consistent with the business cycle literature, corporate investments peak during periods of positive sentiment, yet these periods are followed by lower equity returns. This pattern exists in most developed countries and survives controls for discount rates, equity flows, valuation multiples, operating accruals, and other investor sentiment measures. Higher aggregate investments also precede greater earnings disappointments, lower short-window earnings announcement returns, and lower macroeconomic growth. We conclude aggregate corporate investment is an alternative, and possibly sharper, measure of market-wide investor sentiment.</description><author>Arif, Salman; Lee, Charles M. C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual Funds and Information Diffusion: The Role of Country-Level Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lin, Chunmei; Massa, Massimo; Zhang, Hong
We hypothesize that poor country-level governance, which makes public information less reliable, induces fund managers to increase their use of semipublic information. Utilizing data from international mutual funds and stocks over the 2000-2009 period, we find that semipublic information-related stock rebalancing can be five times higher in countries with the worst quality of governance than in countries with the best. The use of semipublic information increases price informativeness but also increases information asymmetry and reduces stock liquidity. It also intensified the price impact and liquidity crunch during the recent global financial crisis.</description><author>Lin, Chunmei; Massa, Massimo; Zhang, Hong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debtholder Responses to Shareholder Activism: Evidence from Hedge Fund Interventions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sunder, Jayanthi; Sunder, Shyam V.; Wongsunwai, Wan
We investigate the effect of shareholder activism on debtholders by examining a sample of bank loans for firms targeted by activist hedge funds. We compare loan spreads before and after intervention and show the effects of heterogeneous shareholder actions. Spreads increase when shareholder activism relies on the market for corporate control or financial restructuring. In contrast, spreads decrease when activists address managerial entrenchment. Furthermore, the effects are more pronounced when pre-existing governance mechanisms are weak. Our findings suggest that shareholder activism does not necessarily exacerbate bondholder-shareholder conflicts of interest and highlight the role of activism in aligning investors.</description><author>Sunder, Jayanthi; Sunder, Shyam V.; Wongsunwai, Wan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Referee Recommendations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Welch, Ivo
This paper quantitatively analyzes referee recommendations at eight prominent economics and finance journals, and the SFS (Society for Financial Studies) Cavalcade Conference, where a known algorithm matched referees to submissions. The behavior of referees was similar in all venues. The referee-specific component in the disposition recommendation was about twice as important as the common component. Referees differed both in their scales (some referees were intrinsically more generous than others) and in their opinions of what a good paper was (they often disagreed about the relative ordering of papers). (JEL A14)</description><author>Welch, Ivo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real Estate Prices and Firm Capital Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cvijanovic, Dragana
This paper examines the impact of real estate prices on firm capital structure decisions. For a typical U.S. listed company, a one-standard-deviation increase in predicted value of firm pledgeable collateral translates into a 3 percentage points increase in firm leverage ratio. The identification strategy employs a triple interaction of MSA-level land supply elasticity, real estate prices, and a measure of a firm's real estate holdings as an exogenous source of variation in firm collateral values. Firms significantly change their debt structure in response to collateral value appreciation. The results indicate the importance of collateral values in mitigating potential informational imperfections. (JEL G30, G32)</description><author>Cvijanovic, Dragana</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Repossession and the Democratization of Credit</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Assuncao, Juliano J.; Benmelech, Efraim; Silva, Fernando S. S.
We exploit a 2004 credit reform in Brazil that simplified the sale of repossessed cars used as collateral for auto loans. We show that the reform expanded credit to riskier, self-employed borrowers who purchased newer, more expensive cars. The legal change has led to larger loans with lower spreads and longer maturities. Although the credit reform improved riskier borrowers' access to credit, it also led to increased incidences of delinquency and default. Our results shed light on the consequences of a credit reform and highlight the crucial role that collateral and repossession play in the liberalization and democratization of credit. (JEL G32, G33, K12, K40)</description><author>Assuncao, Juliano J.; Benmelech, Efraim; Silva, Fernando S. S.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Nationalism and Economic Exchange: Evidence from Shocks to Sino-Japanese Relations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fisman, Raymond; Hamao, Yasushi; Wang, Yongxiang
We study the impact of nationalism and interstate frictions on international economic relations by analyzing market reaction to adverse shocks to Sino-Japanese relations in 2005 and 2010. Japanese companies with high China exposure suffer relative declines during each event window; a symmetric effect is observed for Chinese companies with high Japanese exposure. The effect on Japanese companies is more pronounced for those operating in industries dominated by Chinese state-owned enterprises, whereas firms with high Chinese employment experience lower declines. These results emphasize the role of countries' economic and political institutions in mediating the impact of interstate frictions on firm-level outcomes. (JEL F13, F51, G14, G15)</description><author>Fisman, Raymond; Hamao, Yasushi; Wang, Yongxiang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Ownership of Japanese Corporations in the 20th Century</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Franks, Julian; Mayer, Colin; Miyajima, Hideaki
Twentieth century Japan provides a remarkable laboratory for examining how an externally imposed institutional and regulatory intervention affects the ownership of corporations. In the first half of the century, Japan had weak legal protection but strong institutional arrangements. The institutions were dismantled after the war and replaced by a strong form of legal protection. This inversion resulted in a switch from Japan being a country in which equity markets flourished and ownership was dispersed in the first half of the century to one in which banks and companies dominated with interlocking shareholdings in the second half of the century. (JEL G32, K22)</description><author>Franks, Julian; Mayer, Colin; Miyajima, Hideaki</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning from Stock Prices and Economic Growth</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peress, Joel
A competitive stock market is embedded into a neoclassical growth economy to analyze the interplay between the acquisition of information about firms, its partial revelation through stock prices, capital allocation, and income. The stock market allows investors to share their costly private signals in a cost-effective incentive-compatible way. It contributes to economic growth by raising total factor productivity (TFP). A calibration indicates the effect on TFP to be large but that on income to be modest. Several predictions on the evolution of real and financial variables are derived. Finally, the growth impact of two common forms of investor irrationality, overconfidence and inattention, are analyzed.</description><author>Peress, Joel</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Complex Securities and Underwriter Reputation: Do Reputable Underwriters Produce Better Securities?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, John; Lowery, Richard; Saretto, Alessio
Conventional wisdom suggests that high-reputation banks will generally produce good securities to maintain their long-run reputation. We show with a simple model that, when securities are complex a high-reputation bank may produce assets that underperform during market downturns. We examine this possibility using a unique sample of $10.1 trillion of CLO, MBS, ABS, and CDOs. Contrary to the conventional view, securities issued by more reputable banks did not outperform but, rather, had higher proportions of capital in default.</description><author>Griffin, John; Lowery, Richard; Saretto, Alessio</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tail Risk and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kelly, Bryan; Jiang, Hao
We propose a new measure of time-varying tail risk that is directly estimable from the cross-section of returns. We exploit firm-level price crashes every month to identify common fluctuations in tail risk among individual stocks. Our tail measure is significantly correlated with tail risk measures extracted from S&amp;P 500 index options and negatively predicts real economic activity. We show that tail risk has strong predictive power for aggregate market returns. Cross-sectionally, stocks with high loadings on past tail risk earn an annual three-factor alpha 5.4% higher than stocks with low tail risk loadings. We explore potential mechanisms giving rise to these asset pricing facts.</description><author>Kelly, Bryan; Jiang, Hao</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ambiguity Aversion and Asset Prices in Production Economies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jahan-Parvar, Mohammad R.; Liu, Hening
We examine a production-based asset-pricing model with an unobservable mean growth rate following a two-state Markov chain and with an ambiguity-averse representative agent. Our model requires a low coefficient of relative risk aversion to produce: (i) a high equity premium and volatile equity returns, (ii) a low and smooth risk-free rate, (iii) smooth consumption growth and volatile investment growth, (iv) countercyclical equity premium and market price of risk, (v) conditional heteroscedasticity in returns, and (vi) long-horizon predictability of excess returns.</description><author>Jahan-Parvar, Mohammad R.; Liu, Hening</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateral-Motivated Financial Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shen, Ji; Yan, Hongjun; Zhang, Jinfan
Collateral frictions have a profound effect on our economic landscape, ranging from the design of financial securities, laws, and institutions, to various rules and regulations. We analyze a model with disagreement, where securities and collateral requirements are endogenous. It shows that the security that isolates the variable with disagreement is "optimal" in the sense that alternative securities cannot generate any trading. In an economy with N states, investors may introduce more than N securities, and markets are still incomplete. The model has several novel predictions on the behavior of basis-the spread between the prices of an asset and its replicating portfolio.</description><author>Shen, Ji; Yan, Hongjun; Zhang, Jinfan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does the Tail Wag the Dog?: The Effect of Credit Default Swaps on Credit Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Subrahmanyam, Marti G.; Tang, Dragon Yongjun; Wang, Sarah Qian
We use credit default swaps (CDS) trading data to demonstrate that the credit risk of reference firms, reflected in rating downgrades and bankruptcies, increases significantly upon the inception of CDS trading, a finding that is robust after controlling for the endogeneity of CDS trading. Additionally, distressed firms are more likely to file for bankruptcy if they are linked to CDS trading. Furthermore, firms with more "no restructuring" contracts than other types of CDS contracts (i.e., contracts that include restructuring) are more adversely affected by CDS trading, and the number of creditors increases after CDS trading begins, exacerbating creditor coordination failure in the resolution of financial distress.</description><author>Subrahmanyam, Marti G.; Tang, Dragon Yongjun; Wang, Sarah Qian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Incentives and the Role of Advisors in the Continuous-Time Agency Model (vol 26, pg 2620, 2013)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hori, Keiichi; Osano, Hiroshi
nan</description><author>Hori, Keiichi; Osano, Hiroshi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entrepreneurial Finance and Innovation: An Introduction and Agenda for Future Research</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Fulghieri, Paolo
The increasingly large role played by financial intermediaries, such as venture capitalists and angels, in nurturing entrepreneurial firms and in promoting product market innovation has led to great research interest in the area of entrepreneurial finance and innovation. This paper introduces the special issue of the Review of Financial Studies dedicated to entrepreneurial finance and innovation and highlights some of the promising topics for future research in this area. The special issue combines papers presented at the June 2010 "Entrepreneurial Finance and Innovation (EFIC)" conference, which was jointly sponsored by the Kauffman Foundation and the Review of Financial Studies, with other related papers.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Fulghieri, Paolo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Venture Capitalists on Boards of Mature Public Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Celikyurt, Ugur; Sevilir, Merih; Shivdasani, Anil
Venture capitalists (VCs) often serve on the board of mature public firms long after their initial public offering (IPO), even for companies that were not VC-backed at the IPO. Board appointments of VC directors are followed by increases in research and development intensity, innovation output, and greater deal activity with other VC-backed firms. VC director appointments are associated with positive announcement returns and are followed by an improvement in operating performance. Firms experience higher announcement returns from acquisitions of VC-backed targets following the appointment of a VC director to the board. Hence, in addition to providing finance, monitoring and advice for small private firms, VCs play a significant role in mature public firms and have a broader influence in promoting innovation than has been established in the literature.</description><author>Celikyurt, Ugur; Sevilir, Merih; Shivdasani, Anil</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Informational Holdup and Performance Persistence in Venture Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hochberg, Yael V.; Ljungqvist, Alexander; Vissing-Jorgensen, Annette
Why don't VCs eliminate excess demand for follow-on funds by raising fees? We propose a model of learning that leads to informational holdup. Current investors learn about skill whereas outside investors observe only returns. This gives current investors holdup power when the VC raises his next fund: Without their backing, no-one will fund him, as outside investors interpret the lack of backing as a sign of low skill. Holdup power diminishes the VC's ability to increase fees in line with performance, leading to return persistence. Empirical evidence supports the model. We estimate that up to two-thirds of VC firms lack skill.</description><author>Hochberg, Yael V.; Ljungqvist, Alexander; Vissing-Jorgensen, Annette</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Capital Structure Decisions of New Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Robb, Alicia M.; Robinson, David T.
We study capital structure choices that entrepreneurs make in their firms' initial year of operation, using restricted-access data from the Kauffman Firm Survey. Firms in our data rely heavily on external debt sources, such as bank financing, and less extensively on friends-and-family-based funding sources. Many startups receive debt financed through the personal balance sheets of the entrepreneur, effectively resulting in the entrepreneur holding levered equity claims in their startups. This fact is robust to numerous controls, including credit quality. The reliance on external debt underscores the importance of credit markets for the success of nascent business activity.</description><author>Robb, Alicia M.; Robinson, David T.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Real Option Financing Under Asymmetric Information</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bouvard, Matthieu
This study examines the financing of innovation in the presence of adverse selection in the capital market. An entrepreneur with private information needs outside funding for a project requiring costly experimentation. Equilibrium contracts use the duration of the experimentation period, together with pay-for-performance, to signal information to outside investors. As a result, investment is delayed, entrepreneurs with stronger growth options receive vested stock options, and entrepreneurs with a lower probability of success are compensated in case of failure. These predictions are in line with empirical evidence on venture capital contracts, and on the impact of internal financing on risk taking.</description><author>Bouvard, Matthieu</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tolerance for Failure and Corporate Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tian, Xuan; Wang, Tracy Yue
Based on a sample of venture capital (VC)-backed IPO firms, we examine whether tolerance for failure spurs corporate innovation. We develop a novel measure of VC investors' failure tolerance by examining their willingness to continue investing in underperforming ventures. We find that IPO firms backed by more failure-tolerant VC investors are significantly more innovative and VC failure tolerance is particularly important for ventures that are subject to high failure risk. We show that these results are not driven by endogenous matching between failure-tolerant VC firms and start-ups with high ex ante innovative potential. We also examine the determinants of the cross-sectional heterogeneity in a VC firm's failure tolerance. We find that both capital constraints and career concerns can negatively distort a VC firm's failure tolerance. Less experienced VC firms are more exposed to these distortions, making them less failure tolerant than are more established VC firms.</description><author>Tian, Xuan; Wang, Tracy Yue</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Incentives to Innovate and the Decision to Go Public or Private</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferreira, Daniel; Manso, Gustavo; Silva, Andre C.
We model the impact of public and private ownership structures on firms' incentives to invest in innovative projects. We show that it is optimal to go public when exploiting existing ideas and optimal to go private when exploring new ideas. This result derives from the fact that private firms are less transparent to outside investors than are public firms. In private firms, insiders can time the market by choosing an early exit strategy if they receive bad news. This option makes insiders more tolerant of failures and thus more inclined to invest in innovative projects. In contrast, the prices of publicly traded securities react quickly to good news, providing insiders with incentives to choose conventional projects and cash in early.</description><author>Ferreira, Daniel; Manso, Gustavo; Silva, Andre C.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wrongful Discharge Laws and Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Baghai, Ramin P.; Subramanian, Krishnamurthy V.
We show that wrongful discharge laws-laws that protect employees against unjust dismissal-spur innovation and new firm creation. Wrongful discharge laws, particularly those that prohibit employers from acting in bad faith ex post, limit employers' ability to hold up innovating employees after the innovation is successful. By reducing the possibility of holdup, these laws enhance employees'innovative efforts and encourage firms to invest in risky but potentially mould-breaking projects. We develop a model and provide supporting empirical evidence of this effect using the staggered adoption of wrongful discharge laws across U.S. states.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Baghai, Ramin P.; Subramanian, Krishnamurthy V.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Interbank Liquidity Crunch and the Firm Credit Crunch: Evidence from the 2007-2009 Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Iyer, Rajkamal; Peydro, Jose-Luis; da-Rocha-Lopes, Samuel; Schoar, Antoinette
We study the credit supply effects of the unexpected freeze of the European interbank market, using exhaustive Portuguese loan-level data. We find that banks that rely more on interbank borrowing before the crisis decrease their credit supply more during the crisis. The credit supply reduction is stronger for firms that are smaller, with weaker banking relationships. Small firms cannot compensate the credit crunch with other sources of debt. Furthermore, the impact of illiquidity on the credit crunch is stronger for less solvent banks. Finally, we find no overall positive effects of central bank liquidity but instead higher hoarding of liquidity.</description><author>Iyer, Rajkamal; Peydro, Jose-Luis; da-Rocha-Lopes, Samuel; Schoar, Antoinette</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Money Left on the Table: An Analysis of Participation in Employee Stock Purchase Plans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Babenko, Ilona; Sen, Rik
We analyze participation decisions in employee stock purchase plans. These plans allow employees to buy company stock at a discount from the market price and resell it immediately for a sure profit. Although an average employee stands to gain $3,079 annually, only 30% of individuals take advantage of this risk-free opportunity. Participation is more likely among employees who are familiar with stocks, are more educated, are less financially constrained, and make fewer errors in valuing financial securities. Our results suggest that compensation plans requiring active decisions by individuals can result in poor financial outcomes for employees of lower socioeconomic status.</description><author>Babenko, Ilona; Sen, Rik</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash-Flow Sensitivities and the Allocation of Internal Cash Flow</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chang, Xin; Dasgupta, Sudipto; Wong, George; Yao, Jiaquan
We study how firms allocate cash flow by estimating the cash-flow sensitivities of various uses of cash flow. We decompose cash flow into a transitory and a permanent component and focus on the allocation of the transitory component, which by construction contains little information about future growth opportunities. We find that more financially constrained firms allocate more transitory cash flow to cash savings and direct less toward investment than do less constrained firms, consistent with constrained firms accumulating liquidity to buffer against future financial constraints. We also illustrate several methodological advantages of our approach over alternative methods in previous studies.</description><author>Chang, Xin; Dasgupta, Sudipto; Wong, George; Yao, Jiaquan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Happens in Nevada? Self-Selecting into Lax Law</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barzuza, Michal; Smith, David C.
We find that Nevada, the second most popular state for out-of-state incorporations and a state with lax corporate law, attracts firms that are 30-40% more likely to report financial results that later require restatement than firms incorporated in other states, including Delaware. Our results suggest that firms favoring protections for insiders select Nevada as a corporate home, and these firms are prone to financial reporting failures. We provide some evidence that Nevada law also has a causal impact by increasing a Nevada firm's propensity to misreport financials after the firm has incorporated in Nevada.</description><author>Barzuza, Michal; Smith, David C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Complementarity, Fragility, and Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vives, Xavier
Fragility is affected by how the balance sheet composition of financial intermediaries, the precision of information signals, and market stress parameters all influence the extent of strategic complementarity among investors' strategies. A solvency and a liquidity ratio are required to control the likelihood of insolvency and illiquidity. The solvency requirement must be strengthened in the face of increased competition, whereas the liquidity requirement must be strengthened under more conservative fund managers and higher penalties for fire sales. Greater disclosure may aggravate fragility and require an increase in the liquidity ratio, so regulators should establish prudential and disclosure policies in tandem.</description><author>Vives, Xavier</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>No News Is News: Do Markets Underreact to Nothing?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giglio, Stefano; Shue, Kelly
As illustrated in the tale of "the dog that did not bark," the absence of news and the passage of time often contain information. We test whether markets fully incorporate this information using the empirical context of mergers. During the year after merger announcement, the passage of time is informative about the probability that the merger will ultimately complete. We show that the variation in hazard rates of completion after announcement strongly predicts returns. This pattern is consistent with a behavioral model of underreaction to the passage of time and cannot be explained by changes in risk or frictions.</description><author>Giglio, Stefano; Shue, Kelly</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>In Harm'sWay? Payday Loan Access and Military Personnel Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carrell, Scott; Zinman, Jonathan
Does borrowing at 400% APR do more harm than good? The U. S. Department of Defense thinks so and successfully lobbied for a 36% APR cap on loans to servicemen. But existing evidence on how access to high-interest debt affects borrowers is inconclusive. We estimate effects of payday loan access on enlisted personnel using exogenous variation in Air Force rules assigning personnel to bases across the United States, and within-state variation in lending laws over time. Airmen job performance and retention declines with payday loan access, and severely poor readiness increases. These effects are strongest among relatively inexperienced and financially unsophisticated airmen. (JEL G23, G28, D14, D18, J24)</description><author>Carrell, Scott; Zinman, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond Supply and Excess Bond Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenwood, Robin; Vayanos, Dimitri
We examine empirically how the supply and maturity structure of government debt affect bond yields and expected returns. We organize our investigation around a term-structure model in which risk-averse arbitrageurs absorb shocks to the demand and supply for bonds of different maturities. These shocks affect the term structure because they alter the price of duration risk. Consistent with the model, we find that the maturity-weighted-debt-to-GDP ratio is positively related to bond yields and future returns, controlling for the short rate. Moreover, these effects are stronger for longer-maturity bonds and following periods when arbitrageurs have lost money.</description><author>Greenwood, Robin; Vayanos, Dimitri</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Dark Pools Harm Price Discovery?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhu, Haoxiang
Dark pools are equity trading systems that do not publicly display orders. Dark pools offer potential price improvements but do not guarantee execution. Informed traders tend to trade in the same direction, crowd on the heavy side of the market, and face a higher execution risk in the dark pool, relative to uninformed traders. Consequently, exchanges are more attractive to informed traders, and dark pools are more attractive to uninformed traders. Under certain conditions, adding a dark pool alongside an exchange concentrates price-relevant information into the exchange and improves price discovery. Improved price discovery coincides with reduced exchange liquidity.</description><author>Zhu, Haoxiang</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expected Returns and Dividend Growth Rates Implied by Derivative Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Golez, Benjamin
The dividend-price ratio is a noisy proxy for expected returns when expected dividend growth is time-varying. This paper uses a new and forward-looking measure of dividend growth extracted from S&amp;P 500 futures and options to correct the dividend-price ratio for changes in expected dividend growth. Over January 1994 through June 2011, dividend growth implied by derivative markets reliably forecasts future dividend growth, and the corrected dividend-price ratio predicts S&amp;P 500 returns substantially better than the standard dividend-price ratio, in-sample and out-of-sample. Time-varying expected dividend growth is important to explain price movements, especially because it is highly correlated with expected returns.</description><author>Golez, Benjamin</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Portfolio Choice with Predictability in House Prices and Transaction Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Corradin, Stefano; Fillat, Jose L.; Vergara-Alert, Carles
We develop and solve a model of optimal portfolio choice with transaction costs and predictability in house prices. We model house prices using a process with a time-varying expected growth rate. Housing adjustments are infrequent and characterized by both the wealth-to-housing ratio and the expected growth in house prices. We find that the housing portfolio share immediately after moving to a more valuable house is higher during periods of high expected growth in house prices. We also find that the share of wealth invested in risky assets is lower during periods of high expected growth in house prices. Finally, the decrease in risky portfolio holdings for households moving to a more valuable house is greater in high-growth periods. These findings are robust to tests using household-level data from the Panel Study of Income Dynamics (PSID) and Survey of Income and Program Participation (SIPP) surveys. The coefficients obtained using model-simulated data are consistent with those obtained in the empirical tests.</description><author>Corradin, Stefano; Fillat, Jose L.; Vergara-Alert, Carles</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Speculation and Hedging in Segmented Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goldstein, Itay; Li, Yan; Yang, Liyan
We analyze a model in which traders have different trading opportunities and learn information from prices. The difference in trading opportunities implies that different traders may have different trading motives when trading in the same market-some trade for speculation and others for hedging-and thus they may respond to the same information in opposite directions. This implies that adding more informed traders may reduce price informativeness and therefore provides a source for learning complementarities leading to multiple equilibria and price jumps. Our model is relevant to various realistic settings and helps to understand a variety of modern financial markets.</description><author>Goldstein, Itay; Li, Yan; Yang, Liyan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Preventing Zombie Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bruche, Max; Llobet, Gerard
Because of limited liability, insolvent banks have an incentive to continue lending to insolvent borrowers, in order to hide losses and gamble for resurrection, even though this is socially inefficient. We suggest a scheme that regulators could use to solve this problem. The scheme would induce banks to reveal their bad loans, which can then be dealt with. Bank participation in the scheme would be voluntary. Even though banks have private information on the quantity of bad loans on their balance sheets, the scheme avoids creating windfall gains for bank equity holders. In addition, some losses can be imposed on debt holders.</description><author>Bruche, Max; Llobet, Gerard</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expectations of Returns and Expected Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenwood, Robin; Shleifer, Andrei
We analyze time series of investor expectations of future stock market returns from six data sources between 1963 and 2011. The six measures of expectations are highly positively correlated with each other, as well as with past stock returns and with the level of the stock market. However, investor expectations are strongly negatively correlated with model-based expected returns. The evidence is not consistent with rational expectations representative investor models of returns.</description><author>Greenwood, Robin; Shleifer, Andrei</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Did Holdings of Highly Rated Securitization Tranches Differ So Much across Banks?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erel, Isil; Nadauld, Taylor; Stulz, Rene M.
We provide estimates of holdings of highly rated securitization tranches of U.S. bank holding companies before the credit crisis and evaluate hypotheses that have been advanced to explain them. Whereas holdings exceeded Tier 1 capital for some large banks, they were economically trivial for the typical bank. Banks with high holdings were not riskier before the crisis using conventional measures, but they performed poorly during the crisis. We find that holdings of highly rated tranches were correlated with a bank's securitization activity. Theories unrelated to the securitization activity, such as "bad incentives" or "bad risk management," are not supported in the data.</description><author>Erel, Isil; Nadauld, Taylor; Stulz, Rene M.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization and Loan Performance: Ex Ante and Ex Post Relations in the Mortgage Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jiang, Wei; Nelson, Ashlyn Aiko; Vytlacil, Edward
This study examines the relation between securitization and loan performance using a comprehensive dataset from a major national mortgage lender. Loans remaining on the bank's balance sheet ex post incurred higher delinquency rates than sold loans, contrasting the negative relation between screening efforts and ex ante probability of loan sale explored by prior studies. Moreover, the performance gap between sold and retained loans was wider among the subsample of loans that were perceived as easier to resell. The investors'seeming advantage over the originating bank can mostly be explained by information revealed during the time between loan origination and sale.</description><author>Jiang, Wei; Nelson, Ashlyn Aiko; Vytlacil, Edward</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Prices with Heterogeneity in Preferences and Beliefs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhamra, Harjoat S.; Uppal, Raman
In this paper, we study asset prices in a dynamic, continuous-time, and general-equilibrium endowment economy in which agents have "catching up with the Joneses" utility functions and differ with respect to their beliefs (because of differences in priors) and their preference parameters for time discount, risk aversion, and sensitivity to habit. A key contribution of our paper is to demonstrate how one can obtain a closed-form solution to the consumption-sharing rule for agents who have both heterogeneous priors and heterogeneous preferences without restricting the risk aversion of the two agents to special values. We solve in closed form also for the state-price density, the risk-free interest rate and market price of risk, the stock price, equity risk premium, and volatility of stock returns, the term structure of interest rates, and the conditions necessary to obtain a stationary equilibrium in which both agents survive in the long run. The methodology we develop is sufficiently general in that, as long as markets are complete, it can be used to obtain the sharing rule and state prices for models set in discrete or continuous time and for arbitrary endowment and belief updating processes.</description><author>Bhamra, Harjoat S.; Uppal, Raman</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>When There Is No Place to Hide: Correlation Risk and the Cross-Section of Hedge Fund Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buraschi, Andrea; Kosowski, Robert; Trojani, Fabio
Using a novel data set on correlation swaps, we study the relation between correlation risk, hedge fund characteristics, and their risk-return profile. We find that the ability of hedge funds to create market-neutral returns is often associated with a significant exposure to correlation risk, which helps to explain the large abnormal returns found in previous models. We also estimate a significant negative market price of correlation risk, which accounts for the cross-section of hedge fund excess returns. Finally, we detect a pronounced nonlinear relation between correlation risk exposure and the tail risk of hedge fund returns.</description><author>Buraschi, Andrea; Kosowski, Robert; Trojani, Fabio</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Procyclical Leverage and Value-at-Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Adrian, Tobias; Shin, Hyun Song
The availability of credit varies over the business cycle through shifts in the leverage of financial intermediaries. Empirically, we find that intermediary leverage is negatively aligned with the banks' Value-at-Risk (VaR). Motivated by the evidence, we explore a contracting model that captures the observed features. Under general conditions on the outcome distribution given by extreme value theory (EVT), intermediaries maintain a constant probability of default to shifts in the outcome distribution, implying substantial deleveraging during downturns. For some parameter values, we can solve the model explicitly, thereby endogenizing the VaR threshold probability from the contracting problem.</description><author>Adrian, Tobias; Shin, Hyun Song</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Solicited and Unsolicited Credit Ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fulghieri, Paolo; Strobl, Guenter; Xia, Han
This paper develops a dynamic rational expectations model of the credit rating process, incorporating three critical elements of this industry: (1) the rating agencies' ability to misreport the issuer's credit quality, (2) their ability to issue unsolicited ratings, and (3) their reputational concerns. We analyze the incentives of credit rating agencies to issue unsolicited credit ratings and the effects of this practice on the agencies' rating strategies. We find that issuance of unfavorable unsolicited credit ratings enables rating agencies to extract higher fees from issuers by credibly threatening to punish those that refuse to acquire a rating. Also, issuing unfavorable unsolicited ratings increases the rating agencies' reputation by demonstrating to investors that they resist the temptation to issue inflated ratings. In equilibrium, unsolicited credit ratings are lower than solicited ratings, because all favorable ratings are solicited; however, they do not have a downward bias. We show that, under certain conditions, a credit rating system that incorporates unsolicited ratings leads to more stringent rating standards.</description><author>Fulghieri, Paolo; Strobl, Guenter; Xia, Han</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Common Errors: How to (and Not to) Control for Unobserved Heterogeneity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gormley, Todd A.; Matsa, David A.
Controlling for unobserved heterogeneity (or "common errors"), such as industry-specific shocks, is a fundamental challenge in empirical research.This paper discusses the limitations of two approaches widely used in corporate finance and asset pricing research: demeaning the dependent variable with respect to the group (e.g., "industry-adjusting") and adding the mean of the group's dependent variable as a control. We show that these methods produce inconsistent estimates and can distort inference. In contrast, the fixed effects estimator is consistent and should be used instead. We also explain how to estimate the fixed effects model when traditional methods are computationally infeasible.</description><author>Gormley, Todd A.; Matsa, David A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Consequences of Entrepreneurial Finance: Evidence from Angel Financings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kerr, William R.; Lerner, Josh; Schoar, Antoinette
This article documents the fact that ventures funded by two successful angel groups experience superior outcomes to rejected ventures: They have improved survival, exits, employment, patenting, Web traffic, and financing. We use strong discontinuities in angel- funding behavior over small changes in their collective interest levels to implement a regression discontinuity approach. We confirm the positive effects for venture operations, with qualitative support for a higher likelihood of successful exits. On the other hand, there is no difference in access to additional financing around the discontinuity. This might suggest that financing is not a central input of angel groups.</description><author>Kerr, William R.; Lerner, Josh; Schoar, Antoinette</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Microprudential Regulation in a Dynamic Model of Banking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Nicolo, Gianni; Gamba, Andrea; Lucchetta, Marcella
This paper studies the quantitative impact of microprudential bank regulations on bank lending and value metrics of efficiency and welfare in a dynamic model of banks that are financed by debt and equity, undertake maturity transformation, are exposed to credit and liquidity risks, and face financing frictions. We show that (1) there exists an inverted U-shaped relationship between bank lending, welfare, and capital requirements, (2) liquidity requirements unambiguously reduce lending, efficiency, and welfare, and (3) resolution policies contingent on observed capital, such as prompt corrective action, dominate in efficiency and welfare terms (noncontingent) capital and liquidity requirements.</description><author>De Nicolo, Gianni; Gamba, Andrea; Lucchetta, Marcella</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Swaption Cube</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Trolle, Anders B.; Schwartz, Eduardo S.
We infer conditional swap rate moments model independently from swaption cubes. Conditional volatility and skewness exhibit systematic variation across swap maturities and option expiries (conditional kurtosis less so), with conditional skewness sometimes changing sign. Conditional skewness displays some relation to the level and volatility of swap rates but is most consistently related to the conditional correlation between swap rates and swap rate variances. From realized excess returns on synthetic variance and skewness swap contracts, we infer that variance and (to a lesser extent) skewness risk premia are negative and time varying. For the most part, results hold true in both the USD and EUR markets and in both precrisis and crisis subsamples. We design and estimate a dynamic term structure model that captures much of the dynamics of conditional swap rate moments.</description><author>Trolle, Anders B.; Schwartz, Eduardo S.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Lenders Still Monitor When They Can Securitize Loans?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wang, Yihui; Xia, Han
We examine how securitization markets affect the role of banks as monitors in corporate lending. We find that banks active in securitization impose looser covenants on borrowers at origination. After origination, these borrowers take on substantially more risk than do borrowers of non-securitization-active banks. We use borrowers' geographic locations to instrument for borrower-lender matching to distinguish the effect of securitization on the banks' ex post monitoring from its effect on ex ante screening. We further investigate direct evidence of banks' monitoring role by examining their actions following covenant violations and find that securitization-active lenders are more likely to grant waivers without changing loan terms. Our results suggest that banks exert less effort on ex post monitoring when they can securitize loans.</description><author>Wang, Yihui; Xia, Han</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Stock Liquidity Affect Incentives to Monitor? Evidence from Corporate Takeovers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Roosenboom, Peter; Schlingemann, Frederik P.; Vasconcelos, Manuel
We test whether stock liquidity affects acquirer returns through its hypothesized effect on institutional monitoring. We find that firms with lower stock liquidity have higher acquirer gains for takeovers of private targets, but not for takeovers of public targets. The negative relation between liquidity and acquirer gains is stronger when the threat of disciplinary trading (exit) by institutions is weaker and acquirers have higher agency costs. Acquirers of private targets with lower stock liquidity are more likely to withdraw deals and experience higher involuntary CEO turnover following value-destroying acquisitions. Our results support the hypothesis that stock liquidity weakens institutions' incentives to monitor management decisions, except in those cases where the disciplining effect of the threat of exit may be particularly high.</description><author>Roosenboom, Peter; Schlingemann, Frederik P.; Vasconcelos, Manuel</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Advance Disclosure of Insider Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lenkey, Stephen L.
Using a strategic rational expectations equilibrium framework, we show that forcing a well-informed insider to disclose her trades in advance tends to increase welfare for both the insider and less-informed outsiders. Advance disclosure generates price risk for the insider, and to mitigate this risk, the insider trades less aggressively on her private information. Consequently, outsiders face lower adverse selection costs, which improves risk sharing and increases welfare. The drop in trading aggressiveness also causes market efficiency to decline. Furthermore, pretrade disclosure encourages excessive risk taking but may either encourage or discourage managerial effort.</description><author>Lenkey, Stephen L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>High-Frequency Trading and Price Discovery</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brogaard, Jonathan; Hendershott, Terrence; Riordan, Ryan
We examine the role of high-frequency traders (HFTs) in price discovery and price efficiency. Overall HFTs facilitate price efficiency by trading in the direction of permanent price changes and in the opposite direction of transitory pricing errors, both on average and on the highest volatility days. This is done through their liquidity demanding orders. In contrast, HFTs' liquidity supplying orders are adversely selected. The direction of HFTs' trading predicts price changes over short horizons measured in seconds. The direction of HFTs' trading is correlated with public information, such as macro news announcements, market-wide price movements, and limit order book imbalances.</description><author>Brogaard, Jonathan; Hendershott, Terrence; Riordan, Ryan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Venture Capital, Value Creation, and Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Loutskina, Elena; Tian, Xuan
We analyze how corporate venture capital (CVC) differs from independent venture capital (IVC) in nurturing innovation in entrepreneurial firms. We find that CVC-backed firms are more innovative, as measured by their patenting outcome, although they are younger, riskier, and less profitable than IVC-backed firms. Our baseline results continue to hold in a propensity score matching analysis of IPO firms and a difference-in-differences analysis of the universe of VC-backed entrepreneurial firms. We present evidence consistent with two possible underlying mechanisms: CVC's greater industry knowledge due to the technological fit between their parent firms and entrepreneurial firms and CVC's greater tolerance for failure.</description><author>Chemmanur, Thomas J.; Loutskina, Elena; Tian, Xuan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Prior Client Performance and the Choice of Investment Bank Advisors in Corporate Acquisitions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sibilkov, Valeriy; McConnell, John J.
Contrary to earlier studies, we find that prior client performance is a significant determinant of the likelihood that an investment bank will be chosen as the advisor by future acquirers and of the changes through time in banks' shares of the advisory business. Further, the changes in the market values of acquirers at the announcement of acquisition attempts are positively correlated with contemporaneous changes in the market values of their advisors. Two implications arise: (1) acquirers consider advisors' prior client performance when choosing their advisors and (2) market forces work to align advisors' and clients' interests in the acquisition market.</description><author>Sibilkov, Valeriy; McConnell, John J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Going-Private Transactions Affect Plant Efficiency and Investment?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bharath, Sreedhar; Dittmar, Amy; Sivadasan, Jagadeesh
We examine whether constraints on public firms affect firms' efficiency by testing if going private improves plant-level productivity relative to peer control groups. We find that, despite increases in productivity after going private, there is little evidence of efficiency gains relative to peer groups of plants constructed to control for industry, age, size, past productivity, and the endogeneity of the going-private decision. Going-private firms do extensively restructure their portfolio of plants, selling and closing plants more quickly than others. Our findings cast doubt on the view that public markets cause listed firms to operate plants less efficiently due to overinvestment but indicate that going private increases restructuring activity.</description><author>Bharath, Sreedhar; Dittmar, Amy; Sivadasan, Jagadeesh</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Smart Money? The Effect of Education on Financial Outcomes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cole, Shawn; Paulson, Anna; Shastry, Gauri Kartini
Household financial decisions are important for household welfare, economic growth, and financial stability. Yet our understanding of the determinants of financial decision making is limited. Exploiting exogenous variation in state compulsory schooling laws in both standard and two-sample instrumental variable strategies, we show that education increases financial market participation, measured by investment income and equities ownership, while dramatically reducing the probability that an individual declares bankruptcy, experiences a foreclosure, or is delinquent on a loan. Further results and a simple calibration suggest that the result is driven by changes in savings or investment behavior, rather than simply increased labor earnings.</description><author>Cole, Shawn; Paulson, Anna; Shastry, Gauri Kartini</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Choice under High-Water Marks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drechsler, Itamar
I solve in closed form for the optimal dynamic risk choice of a fund manager who is compensated with a high-water mark contract. The optimal risk choice depends on the ratio of the fund's assets under management to its high-water mark. If the manager's outside option value is low, investors' termination policy is strict, or management fees are high, then negative returns induce the manager into "derisking." Otherwise, he engages in "gambling." Having the option to walk away increases risk taking, though in many cases exercise is never optimal. In particular, leaving to restart at a proportionally smaller fund is always suboptimal.</description><author>Drechsler, Itamar</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Misspecification-Robust Inference in Linear Asset-Pricing Models with Irrelevant Risk Factors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gospodinov, Nikolay; Kan, Raymond; Robotti, Cesare
This paper shows that in misspecified models with risk factors that are uncorrelated with the test asset returns, the conventional inference methods tend to erroneously conclude, with high probability, that these factors are priced. Our proposed model selection procedure, which is robust to identification failure and potential model misspecification, restores the standard inference and proves to be effective in eliminating factors that do not improve the model's pricing ability. Applying our methodology to several popular asset-pricing models suggests that only the market and book-to-market factors appear to be priced, while the statistical evidence on the pricing ability of many macroeconomic factors is rather weak.</description><author>Gospodinov, Nikolay; Kan, Raymond; Robotti, Cesare</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Variety of Maturities Offered by Firms and Institutional Investment in Corporate Bonds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dass, Nishant; Massa, Massimo
We study how a firm's decision to offer bonds of various maturities affects the portfolio allocations of institutional investors. We argue that because of lower information-collection costs, institutional investors tilt their portfolios towards firms that offer bonds of various maturities. We show that this translates into lower bond yields, both in the primary and in the secondary bond markets.</description><author>Dass, Nishant; Massa, Massimo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Valuing Private Equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sorensen, Morten; Wang, Neng; Yang, Jinqiang
We investigate whether the performance of private equity (PE) investments is sufficient to compensate investors (LPs) for risk, long-term illiquidity, management, and incentive fees charged by the general partner (GP). We analyze the LPs' portfolio-choice problem and find that management fees, carried interest, and illiquidity are costly, and GPs must generate substantial alpha to compensate LPs for bearing these costs. Debt is cheap and reduces these costs, potentially explaining the high leverage of buyout transactions. Conventional interpretations of PE performance measures appear optimistic. On average, LPs may just break even, net of management fees, carry, risk, and costs of illiquidity.</description><author>Sorensen, Morten; Wang, Neng; Yang, Jinqiang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Frog in the Pan: Continuous Information and Momentum</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Da, Zhi; Gurun, Umit G.; Warachka, Mitch
We test a frog-in-the-pan (FIP) hypothesis that predicts investors are inattentive to information arriving continuously in small amounts. Intuitively, we hypothesize that a series of frequent gradual changes attracts less attention than infrequent dramatic changes. Consistent with the FIP hypothesis, we find that continuous information induces strong persistent return continuation that does not reverse in the long run. Momentum decreases monotonically from 5.94% for stocks with continuous information during their formation period to -2.07% for stocks with discrete information but similar cumulative formation-period returns. Higher media coverage coincides with discrete information and mitigates the stronger momentum following continuous information.</description><author>Da, Zhi; Gurun, Umit G.; Warachka, Mitch</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Guarantees, Leverage, and Taxes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Luciano, Elisa; Nicodano, Giovanna
This paper considers the optimal joint decision on firm organization and capital structure under a tax-bankruptcy trade-off, stressing the role of guarantees against default. Conditional guarantees, which are embedded in parent-subsidiary structures, increase joint value and joint debt relative to unguaranteed stand-alone firms. Such guarantees, that are unilateral rather than mutual for moderate default costs, may dominate the unconditional mutual guarantees built in mergers. We study the optimal characteristics of both guarantors and beneficiaries, as well as their impact on the self-enforcement potential of conditional guarantees. (JEL G32, G34, L22)</description><author>Luciano, Elisa; Nicodano, Giovanna</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Labor Market for Bankers and Regulators</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bond, Philip; Glode, Vincent
We propose a labor market model in which agents with heterogenous ability levels choose to work as bankers or as financial regulators. When workers extract intrinsic benefits from working in regulation (such as public-sector motivation or human capital accumulation), our model jointly predicts that bankers are, on average, more skilled than regulators and their compensation is more sensitive to performance. During financial booms, banks draw the best workers away from the regulatory sector and misbehavior increases. In a dynamic extension of our model, young regulators accumulate human capital and the best ones switch to banking in mid-career. (JEL G28, J24, J45)</description><author>Bond, Philip; Glode, Vincent</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Security Analysts Speak in Two Tongues?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malmendier, Ulrike; Shanthikumar, Devin
Why do security analysts issue overly positive recommendations? We propose a novel approach to distinguish strategic motives (e.g., generating small-investor purchases and pleasing management) from nonstrategic motives (genuine overoptimism). We argue that nonstrategic distorters tend to issue both positive recommendations and optimistic forecasts, while strategic distorters speak in two tongues, issuing overly positive recommendations but less optimistic forecasts. We show that the incidence of strategic distortion is large and systematically related to proxies for incentive misalignment. Our two-tongues metric reveals strategic distortion beyond those indicators and provides a new tool for detecting incentives to distort that are hard to identify otherwise.</description><author>Malmendier, Ulrike; Shanthikumar, Devin</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Illiquidity Contagion and Liquidity Crashes</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cespa, Giovanni; Foucault, Thierry
Liquidity providers often learn information about an asset from prices of other assets. We show that this generates a self-reinforcing positive relationship between price informativeness and liquidity. This relationship causes liquidity spillovers and is a source of fragility: a small drop in the liquidity of one asset can, through a feedback loop, result in a very large drop in market liquidity and price informativeness (a liquidity crash). This feedback loop provides a new explanation for comovements in liquidity and liquidity dry-ups. It also generates multiple equilibria.</description><author>Cespa, Giovanni; Foucault, Thierry</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investors' and Central Bank's Uncertainty Embedded in Index Options</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>David, Alexander; Veronesi, Pietro
Shocks to equity options' implied volatility are followed by persistently lower short-term rates. Shocks to puts' over calls' out-of-the-money implied volatilities (P/C) are followed by persistently higher rates. Stock and Treasury bond implied volatilities, which measure market and policy uncertainty, are countercyclical, while P/C, which measures downside risk, is procyclical. An equilibrium model in which investors and the central bank learn about composite regimes of economic and policy variables explains these dynamics, linking them to a learning-based, forward-looking Taylor rule. Survey data support our model's predictions on the effect of uncertainty on the level and fluctuations of implied volatilities.</description><author>David, Alexander; Veronesi, Pietro</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Co-opted Boards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Coles, Jeffrey L.; Daniel, Naveen D.; Naveen, Lalitha
We develop two measures of board composition to investigate whether directors appointed by the CEO have allegiance to the CEO and decrease their monitoring. Co-option is the fraction of the board comprised of directors appointed after the CEO assumed office. As Co-option increases, board monitoring decreases: turnover-performance sensitivity diminishes, pay increases (without commensurate increase in pay-performance sensitivity), and investment increases. Non-Co-opted Independence-the fraction of directors who are independent and were appointed before the CEO-has more explanatory power for monitoring effectiveness than the conventional measure of board independence. Our results suggest that not all independent directors are effective monitors.</description><author>Coles, Jeffrey L.; Daniel, Naveen D.; Naveen, Lalitha</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Attracting Investor Attention through Advertising</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lou, Dong
This paper provides evidence that managers adjust firm advertising, in part, to attract investor attention and influence short-term stock returns. First, I show that increased advertising spending is associated with a contemporaneous rise in retail buying and abnormal stock returns, and is followed by lower future returns. Second, I document a significant increase in advertising spending prior to insider sales and a significant decrease in the subsequent year. Additional analyses suggest that the inverted V-shaped pattern in advertising spending around insider sales is most consistent with managers' opportunistically adjusting firm advertising to exploit the temporary return effect to their own benefit.</description><author>Lou, Dong</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Networks in the Stock Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ozsoylev, Han N.; Walden, Johan; Yavuz, M. Deniz; Bildik, Recep
We study the trading behavior of investors in an entire stock market. Using an account level dataset of all trades on the Istanbul Stock Exchange in 2005, we identify investors with similar trading behavior as linked in an empirical investor network (EIN). Consistent with the theory of information networks, we find that central investors earn higher returns and trade earlier than peripheral investors with respect to information events. Overall, our results support the view that information diffusion among the investor population influences trading behavior and returns.</description><author>Ozsoylev, Han N.; Walden, Johan; Yavuz, M. Deniz; Bildik, Recep</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Household Debt and Social Interactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Georgarakos, Dimitris; Haliassos, Michael; Pasini, Giacomo
Can concern with relative standing, which has been shown to influence consumption and labor supply, also increase borrowing and the likelihood of financial distress? We find that perceived peer income contributes to debt and the likelihood of financial distress among those who consider themselves poorer than their peers. We use unique responses describing perceived peer characteristics from a Dutch population-wide survey to handle two major challenges of uncovering social interaction effects on borrowing: (1) debts, unlike conspicuous consumption, are often hidden from peers and (1) location is missing in anonymized data. We employ several approaches to uncover exogenous, rather than correlated, effects.</description><author>Georgarakos, Dimitris; Haliassos, Michael; Pasini, Giacomo</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity Shocks and Stock Market Reactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bali, Turan G.; Peng, Lin; Shen, Yannan; Tang, Yi
We find that the stock market underreacts to stock-level liquidity shocks: liquidity shocks are not only positively associated with contemporaneous returns, but they also predict future return continuations for up to six months. Long-short portfolios sorted on liquidity shocks generate significant returns of 0.70% to 1.20% per month that are robust across alternative shock measures and after controlling for risk factors and stock characteristics. Furthermore, we show that investor inattention and illiquidity contribute to the underreaction: while both are significant in explaining short-term return predictability of liquidity shocks, the inattention-based mechanism is more powerful for the longer-term return predictability.</description><author>Bali, Turan G.; Peng, Lin; Shen, Yannan; Tang, Yi</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Communication and Decision-Making in Corporate Boards</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Malenko, Nadya
Time constraints, managerial power, and reputational concerns can impede board communication. This paper develops a model where board decisions depend on directors' effort in communicating their information to others. I show that directors communicate more effectively when pressure for conformity is stronger-that is, when directors are more reluctant to disagree with each other. Hence, open ballot voting can be optimal, even though it induces directors to disregard their information and conform their votes to others. I also show that communication can be more efficient when directors' preferences are more diverse. The analysis has implications for executive sessions, transparency, and committees.</description><author>Malenko, Nadya</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Year-End Trading Activities of Institutional Investors: Evidence from Daily Trades</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hu, Gang; McLean, R. David; Pontiff, Jeffrey; Wang, Qinghai
At year-end, some allege that institutional investors try to mislead investors by placing trades that inflate performance (portfolio pumping) or distort reported holdings (window dressing). We contribute direct tests using daily institutional trades and find that year-end price inflation derives from a lack of institutional selling rather than institutional buying. In fact, institutional buying declines at year-end. Consistent with pumping, institutions tend to buy stocks in which they already have large positions. We find no evidence of window dressing, as institutions are not more likely to buy high-past return stocks or sell low-past return stocks at year- or quarter-end.</description><author>Hu, Gang; McLean, R. David; Pontiff, Jeffrey; Wang, Qinghai</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wisdom of Crowds: The Value of Stock Opinions Transmitted Through Social Media</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hailiang; De, Prabuddha; Hu, Yu; Hwang, Byoung-Hyoun
Social media has become a popular venue for individuals to share the results of their own analysis on financial securities. This paper investigates the extent to which investor opinions transmitted through social media predict future stock returns and earnings surprises. We conduct textual analysis of articles published on one of the most popular social media platforms for investors in the United States. We also consider the readers perspective as inferred via commentaries written in response to these articles. We find that the views expressed in both articles and commentaries predict future stock returns and earnings surprises.</description><author>Chen, Hailiang; De, Prabuddha; Hu, Yu; Hwang, Byoung-Hyoun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Board Expertise: Do Directors from Related Industries Help Bridge the Information Gap?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dass, Nishant; Kini, Omesh; Nanda, Vikram; Onal, Bunyamin; Wang, Jun
We analyze the role of "directors from related industries" (DRIs) on a firm's board. DRIs are officers and/or directors of companies in the upstream/downstream industries of the firm. DRIs are more likely when the information gap vis-a-vis related industries is more severe or the firm has greater market power. DRIs have a significant impact on firm value/performance, especially when information problems are worse. Furthermore, DRIs help firms handle industry shocks and shorten their cash conversion cycles. Overall, our evidence suggests that firms choose DRIs when the adverse effects due to conflicts of interest are dominated by the benefits due to DRIs' information and expertise.</description><author>Dass, Nishant; Kini, Omesh; Nanda, Vikram; Onal, Bunyamin; Wang, Jun</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Repo Runs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Martin, Antoine; Skeie, David; von Thadden, Ernst-Ludwig
The recent financial crisis has shown that short-term collateralized borrowing may be a highly unstable source of funds in times of stress. In this paper, we develop a dynamic equilibrium model and analyze under what conditions such instability can be a consequence of market-wide changes in expectations. We derive a liquidity constraint and a collateral constraint that determine whether such expectations-driven runs are possible and show that they depend crucially on the microstructure of particular funding markets that we examine in detail. This provides insights into the differences between the tri-party repo market and the bilateral repo market, which were both at the heart of the recent financial crisis.</description><author>Martin, Antoine; Skeie, David; von Thadden, Ernst-Ludwig</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Limited and Varying Consumer Attention: Evidence from Shocks to the Salience of Bank Overdraft Fees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Stango, Victor; Zinman, Jonathan
We explore dynamics of limited attention in the $35 billion market for checking overdrafts, using survey content as shocks to the salience of overdraft fees. Conditional on selection into surveys, individuals who face overdraft-related questions are less likely to incur a fee in the survey month. Taking multiple overdraft surveys builds a stock of attention that reduces overdrafts for up to two years. The effects are significant among consumers with lower education and financial literacy. Individuals avoid overdrafts by making fewer low-balance debit transactions and cancelling automatic recurring withdrawals. The results raise new questions about consumer financial protection policy.</description><author>Stango, Victor; Zinman, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Flexibility, Risk Management, and Payout Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bonaime, Alice Adams; Hankins, Kristine Watson; Harford, Jarrad
Both risk management and payout decisions affect a firm's financial flexibility-the ability to avoid costly financial distress as well as underinvestment. We provide evidence of substitution between hedging and payout decisions using samples of both financial and nonfinancial firms. We find that a more flexible distribution, favoring repurchases over dividends, is negatively related to financial hedging within a firm, consistent with financial flexibility in payout decisions and hedging being substitutes. Our findings, which are robust to controlling for the endogeneity of hedging and payout choices, suggest that payout flexibility offers operational hedging benefits.</description><author>Bonaime, Alice Adams; Hankins, Kristine Watson; Harford, Jarrad</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Internal Capital Market and Dividend Policies: Evidence From Business Groups</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Nanda, Vikram; Seru, Amit
We argue that internal capital market imperatives of business groups i.e., reallocation of capital across group firms, influences an affiliated firms dividend policy. Intuition is developed in a model in which business group insiders distribute dividends from cash-rich firms and use their share of payout to invest in other affiliated firms. Employing multi-country panel-data, we find support for this channel: Dividends by a group firm are positively related with equity-financed investments by its affiliated firms. Results are corroborated by exploiting variation in a firms investment opportunity generated by changes in import tariff policy: a shock to investment opportunity of an affiliated firm is propagated to dividend policies of other firms in its group.</description><author>Gopalan, Radhakrishnan; Nanda, Vikram; Seru, Amit</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Resource Allocation within Firms and Financial Market Dislocation: Evidence from Diversified Conglomerates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Matvos, Gregor; Seru, Amit
We argue and demonstrate that resource allocation within firms internal capital markets provides an important force countervailing financial market dislocation. We estimate a structural model of internal capital markets to separately identify and quantify the forces driving the reallocation decision and illustrate how these forces interact with external capital market stress. The weaker (stronger) division obtains too much (little) capital, as though it is 12 (9) more (less) productive than it really is. Out-of-sample simulated data are consistent with the actual data showing that internal capital markets offset financial market stress during the recent financial crisis by 1630.</description><author>Matvos, Gregor; Seru, Amit</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Growth and Limits of Arbitrage: Evidence from Short Interest</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hanson, Samuel G.; Sunderam, Adi
We develop a novel methodology to infer the amount of capital allocated to quantitative equity arbitrage strategies. Using this methodology, which exploits time-variation in the cross-section of short interest, we document that the amount of capital devoted to value and momentum strategies has grown significantly since the late 1980s. We provide evidence that this increase in capital has resulted in lower strategy returns. However, consistent with theories of limited arbitrage, we show that strategy-level capital flows are influenced by past strategy returns and strategy return volatility and that arbitrage capital is most limited during times when strategies perform best. This suggests that the growth of arbitrage capital may not completely eliminate returns to these strategies.</description><author>Hanson, Samuel G.; Sunderam, Adi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Stock Return Serial Dependence and Out-of-Sample Portfolio Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>DeMiguel, Victor; Nogales, Francisco J.; Uppal, Raman
We study whether investors can exploit serial dependence in stock returns to improve out-of-sample portfolio performance. We show that a vector-autoregressive (VAR) model captures stock return serial dependence in a statistically significant manner. Analytically, we demonstrate that, unlike contrarian and momentum portfolios, an arbitrage portfolio based on the VAR model attains positive expected returns regardless of the sign of asset return cross-covariances and autocovariances. Empirically, we show, however, that both the arbitrage and mean-variance portfolios based on the VAR model outperform the traditional unconditional portfolios only for transaction costs below ten basis points.</description><author>DeMiguel, Victor; Nogales, Francisco J.; Uppal, Raman</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Opaque Trading, Disclosure, and Asset Prices: Implications for Hedge Fund Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easley, David; O'Hara, Maureen; Yang, Liyan
We investigate the effect of ambiguity about hedge fund investment strategies on asset prices and aggregate welfare. We model some traders (mutual funds) as facing ambiguity about the equilibrium trading strategies of other traders (hedge funds). This ambiguity limits the ability of mutual funds to infer information from prices and has negative effects on market outcomes. We use this analysis to investigate the implications of regulations that affect disclosure requirements of hedge funds or the cost of operating a hedge fund. Our analysis demonstrates how regulations affect asset prices and welfare through their influence on opaque trading.</description><author>Easley, David; O'Hara, Maureen; Yang, Liyan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Frictions in Shadow Banking: Evidence from the Lending Behavior of Money Market Mutual Funds</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernenko, Sergey; Sunderam, Adi
We document frictions in money market mutual fund lending that lead to the transmission of distress across borrowers. Using novel security-level holdings data, we show that funds exposed to Eurozone banks suffered large outflows in mid-2011. These outflows had significant spillovers: non-European issuers relying on such funds raised less short-term debt financing. Issuer characteristics do not explain the results: holding fixed the issuer, funds with higher Eurozone exposure cut lending more. Due to credit market frictions, funds with low Eurozone exposure provided substitute financing only to issuers they had pre-existing relationships with, even though issuers are large, highly rated firms.</description><author>Chernenko, Sergey; Sunderam, Adi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Heterogeneity and Stability: Bolster the Strong, Not the Weak</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Dong Beom
We first study a stylized model of self-fulfilling panic among agents with differing fragilities to strategic risk and show that depending on the severity of coordination problems, the panic trigger threshold can depend only on one type's fragility. We then present a model of systemic panic among financial institutions with heterogeneous fragilities to financial spillovers. Concerns about potential spillovers generate strategic interaction, triggering a pre-emption game in which one tries to exit the market before others to avoid spillovers. Although financial contagion originates in weaker institutions, systemic risk can critically depend on financial health of stronger in the contagion chain. In this case, bolstering the strong, rather than the weak, more effectively enhances systemic stability.</description><author>Choi, Dong Beom</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Market Dislocations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pasquariello, Paolo
Dislocations occur when financial markets, operating under stressful conditions, experience large, widespread asset mispricings. This study documents systematic dislocations in world capital markets and the importance of their fluctuations for expected asset returns. Our novel, model-free measure of these dislocations is a monthly average of hundreds of individual abnormal absolute violations of three textbook arbitrage parities in stock, foreign exchange, and money markets. We find that investors demand statistically and economically significant risk premiums to hold financial assets performing poorly during market dislocations, that is, when both frictions to the trading activity of speculators and arbitrageurs and their marginal utility of wealth are likely to be high.</description><author>Pasquariello, Paolo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Index Option Returns: Still Puzzling</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chambers, Donald R.; Foy, Matthew; Liebner, Jeffrey; Lu, Qin
Previous research indicates mixed conclusions on the potential mispricing of equity index put options. We examine the returns of put writing and other option strategies by comparing historical option returns with returns generated using option pricing models. We find it is generally possible to reject the hypothesis that put returns are consistent with option pricing models. An implication is that the average cost of buying out-of-the-money put options to provide tail-risk protection to a portfolio may include a significant premium. Our results are based on a sample period of 1987-2012 that includes periods of high volatility in equity returns.</description><author>Chambers, Donald R.; Foy, Matthew; Liebner, Jeffrey; Lu, Qin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Convergence Trade Strategies</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Jun; Timmermann, Allan
Convergence trades exploit temporary mispricing by simultaneously buying relatively underpriced assets and selling short relatively overpriced assets. This paper studies optimal convergence trades under both recurring and nonrecurring arbitrage opportunities represented by continuing and "stopped" cointegrated price processes and considers both fixed and stochastic (Poisson) horizons. Conventional long-short delta neutral strategies are generally suboptimal and it can be optimal to simultaneously go long (or short) in two mispriced assets. Optimal portfolio holdings critically depend on whether the risky asset position is liquidated when prices converge. Our theoretical results are illustrated on pairs of Chinese bank shares traded on both the Hong Kong and China stock exchanges.</description><author>Liu, Jun; Timmermann, Allan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Corporate Governance in the Presence of an Activist Investor</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohn, Jonathan B.; Rajan, Uday
We provide a model of governance in which a board arbitrates between an activist investor and a manager facing reputational concerns. The optimal level of internal board governance depends on both the severity of the agency conflict and the strength of external governance. Internal governance creates a certification effect, so greater intervention by the board can lead to worse managerial behavior. Internal and external governance are substitutes when external governance is weak (the board commits to an interventionist policy to induce participation from the activist) and complements when external governance is strong (the board relies to a greater extent on the activist's information).</description><author>Cohn, Jonathan B.; Rajan, Uday</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Motivates Minority Acquisitions? The Trade-Offs between a Partial Equity Stake and Complete Integration</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ouimet, Paige Parker
Minority acquisitions, involving less than 50% of the target, represent a distinct organizational choice. Minority acquisition can mitigate some of the incentive problems that arise in contractual relationships. Less is known, however, about the trade-off between minority acquisitions and complete integration. We find that minority acquisitions are more common when keeping target managerial incentives intact is important and when the target is financially constrained or can benefit from certification. Minority acquisitions are also more likely when the target's valuation is especially uncertain; integrating internal capital markets will be costly; and consolidating earning will lower earnings per share (EPS).</description><author>Ouimet, Paige Parker</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Delegated Lucas Tree</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kaniel, Ron; Kondor, Peter
We analyze the effects of the observed increased share of delegated capital for trading strategies and equilibrium prices by introducing delegation into a standard Lucas exchange economy. In equilibrium, some investors trade on their own account, but others decide to delegate trading to professional fund managers. Flow-performance incentive functions describe how much capital clients provide to funds at each date as a function of past performance. Convex flow-performance relations imply that the average fund outperforms the market in recessions and underperforms in expansions. When the share of capital that is delegated is low, all funds follow the same strategy. However, when the equilibrium share of delegated capital is high, funds with identical incentives employ heterogeneous trading strategies. A group of managers borrows to take on a levered position on the stock. Thus, fund returns are dispersed in the cross-section and the outstanding amounts of borrowing and lending increase. The relation between the share of delegated capital and the Sharpe ratio typically follows an inverse U-shaped pattern.</description><author>Kaniel, Ron; Kondor, Peter</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Sovereign Debt, Government Myopia, and the Financial Sector</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Rajan, Raghuram G.
What determines the sustainability of sovereign debt? We develop a model where myopic governments seek popularity but can nevertheless commit credibly to service external debt. They do not default when debt is low because they would lose access to debt markets and be forced to reduce spending; they do not default as debt builds up and net new borrowing becomes difficult, because of the adverse consequences from default to the domestic financial sector. More myopic governments default less often, but tax in a more distortionary way and increase the vulnerability of the domestic financial sector to future government debt default.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Rajan, Raghuram G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Shackling Short Sellers: The 2008 Shorting Ban</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Jones, Charles M.; Zhang, Xiaoyan
In September 2008, the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) temporarily banned most short sales in nearly 1,000 financial stocks. We examine the ban's effect on market quality, shorting activity, the aggressiveness of short sellers, and stock prices. The ban's effects are concentrated in larger stocks; there is little effect on firms in the lower half of the size distribution. Although shorting activity drops by about 77% in large-cap stocks, stock prices appear unaffected by the ban. All but the smallest quartile of firms subject to the ban suffer a severe degradation in market quality.</description><author>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Jones, Charles M.; Zhang, Xiaoyan</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive Networks and Firm Policies: Evidence from the Random Assignment of MBA Peers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Shue, Kelly
Using the historical random assignment of MBA students to sections at Harvard Business School (HBS), I explore how executive peer networks can affect managerial decision making. Within an HBS class, firm outcomes are significantly more similar among graduates from the same section than among graduates from different sections, with the strongest effects in executive compensation and acquisitions strategy. I demonstrate the role of ongoing social interactions by showing that peer effects are more than twice as strong in the year following staggered alumni reunions. Supplementary tests suggest that peer influence can operate in ways that do not contribute to firm productivity.</description><author>Shue, Kelly</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>