<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>RFS3</title><link>http://www.example.com/rss</link><description>This is the feed for items from my zotero.</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 22:32:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>The Effect of Liquidity on Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex; Fang, Vivian W.; Zur, Emanuel
This paper demonstrates a positive effect of stock liquidity on blockholder governance. Liquidity increases the likelihood of block formation. Conditional upon acquiring a stake, liquidity reduces the likelihood that the blockholder governs through voice (intervention)-as shown by the lower propensity for active investment (filing Schedule 13D) than passive investment (filing Schedule 13G). The lower frequency of activism does not reflect the abandonment of governance, but governance through the alternative channel of exit (selling one's shares): A 13G filing leads to positive announcement returns and improvements in operating performance, especially in liquid firms. Moreover, taking into account the increase in block formation, liquidity has an unconditional positive effect on voice as well as exit. We use decimalization as an exogenous shock to liquidity to identify causal effects.</description><author>Edmans, Alex; Fang, Vivian W.; Zur, Emanuel</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Issuer Quality and Corporate Bond Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Greenwood, Robin; Hanson, Samuel G.
We show that the credit quality of corporate debt issuers deteriorates during credit booms and that this deterioration forecasts low excess returns to corporate bondholders. The key insight is that changes in the pricing of credit risk disproportionately affect the financing costs faced by low-quality firms, so debt issuance of low-quality firms is particularly useful for forecasting bond returns. We show that a significant decline in issuer quality is a more reliable signal of credit market overheating than rapid aggregate credit growth. We use these findings to investigate the forces driving time variation in expected corporate bond returns.</description><author>Greenwood, Robin; Hanson, Samuel G.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the Puzzling Risk-Return Relationship for Housing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Han, Lu
Standard theory predicts a positive relationship between risk and return, yet recent data show that housing returns vary positively with risk in some markets but negatively in others. This paper rationalizes these cross-market differences in the risk-return relationship for housing, and in so doing, explains the puzzling negative relationship. The paper shows that when the current house provides a hedge against the risk associated with the future housing consumption, households are willing to accept a lower return to compensate for risk, thus weakening the positive risk-return relationship. Further, in markets with less elastic housing supply and a growing population, hedging incentives can be sufficiently strong to make the relationship negative. The empirical analysis confirms these predictions, suggesting that hedging incentives, housing supply, and urban growth are indeed central to understanding the risk-return relationship for housing.</description><author>Han, Lu</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Supply of Corporate Directors and Board Independence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Knyazeva, Anzhela; Knyazeva, Diana; Masulis, Ronald W.
Empirical evidence on the relations between board independence and board decisions and firm performance is generally confounded by serious endogeneity issues. We circumvent these endogeneity problems by demonstrating the strong impact of the local director labor market on board composition. Specifically, we show that proximity to larger pools of local director talent leads to more independent boards for all but the largest quartile of S&amp;P 1500. Using local director pools as an instrument for board independence, we document that board independence has a positive effect on firm value, operating performance, fraction of CEO incentive-based pay, and CEO turnover.</description><author>Knyazeva, Anzhela; Knyazeva, Diana; Masulis, Ronald W.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Book-to-Market Equity, Financial Leverage, and the Cross-Section of Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Obreja, Iulian
I propose a new dynamic model of the firm that links operating leverage to both value premium and book-leverage premium in stock returns. Value firms are low-productivity firms with either high operating leverage or high financial leverage. Firms with high operating leverage maintain low book leverage ratios. When operating leverage is economically significant, both value firms and low book-leverage firms can have high equity risk premiums. In particular, value premium becomes positive while book-leverage premium becomes negative. Without operating leverage, the signs of these premiums are reversed. The model captures quantitatively several important properties of the cross-section of stock returns.</description><author>Obreja, Iulian</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Leverage, Debt Maturity, and Credit Supply: The Role of Credit Default Swaps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Saretto, Alessio; Tookes, Heather E.
Does the ability of suppliers of corporate debt capital to hedge risk through credit default swap (CDS) contracts impact firms' capital structures? We find that firms with traded CDS contracts on their debt are able to maintain higher leverage ratios and longer debt maturities. This is especially true during periods in which credit constraints become binding, as would be expected if the ability to hedge helps alleviate frictions on the supply side of credit markets.</description><author>Saretto, Alessio; Tookes, Heather E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Indirect Costs of Financial Distress in Durable Goods Industries: The Case of Auto Manufacturers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hortacsu, Ali; Matvos, Gregor; Syverson, Chad; Venkataraman, Sriram
Financial distress can disrupt a durable goods producer's provision of complementary goods and services such as warranties, spare parts and maintenance. This reduces consumers' demand for the core product, causing indirect costs of financial distress. We test this hypothesis in the market for used cars sold at wholesale auctions. An increase in a manufacturer's credit default swaps significantly decreases the prices of its cars at auction, especially cars with longer expected service lives. Our estimates imply substantial indirect costs of financial distress for car manufacturers. These costs have occasionally even exceeded the tax savings benefits for General Motors and Ford.</description><author>Hortacsu, Ali; Matvos, Gregor; Syverson, Chad; Venkataraman, Sriram</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Economic Linkages, Relative Scarcity, and Commodity Futures Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Casassus, Jaime; Liu, Peng; Tang, Ke
This paper shows that economic linkages among commodities create a source of long-term correlation between futures returns. We extend the theory of storage to a multi-commodity level and find that the convenience yield of a commodity depends on its relative scarcity with respect to other related commodities. This implies a feedback effect between commodities that is necessary to replicate the upward-sloping correlation term structure of futures returns observed for related commodities. We present a multi-commodity affine model that validates our theoretical predictions and considerably reduces the pricing errors in out-of-sample crack spread options.</description><author>Casassus, Jaime; Liu, Peng; Tang, Ke</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>An Institutional Theory of Momentum and Reversal</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vayanos, Dimitri; Woolley, Paul
We propose a theory of momentum and reversal based on flows between investment funds. Flows are triggered by changes in fund managers' efficiency, which investors either observe directly or infer from past performance. Momentum arises if flows exhibit inertia, and because rational prices underreact to expected future flows. Reversal arises because flows push prices away from fundamental values. Besides momentum and reversal, flows generate comovement, lead-lag effects, and amplification, with these being larger for high idiosyncratic risk assets. A calibration of our model using evidence on mutual fund returns and flows generates sizeable Sharpe ratios for momentum and value strategies.</description><author>Vayanos, Dimitri; Woolley, Paul</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Entangled Financial Systems</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zawadowski, Adam
I model an entangled financial system in which banks hedge their portfolio risks using over-the-counter (OTC) contracts. However, banks choose not to hedge counterparty risk, and thus the idiosyncratic failure of a bank can lead to a systemic run of lenders. An inefficiency arises because banks engage in a version of risk shifting through the network externalities created by OTC contracts. Banks do not take into account that the costly hedging of low-probability counterparty risk also benefits other banks. In the model, it is welfare improving to tax OTC contracts to finance a bailout fund.</description><author>Zawadowski, Adam</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Drives Stock Price Movements?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Long; Da, Zhi; Zhao, Xinlei
A central issue in finance is whether stock prices move because of revisions in expected cash flows or discount rates, and by how much of each. Using direct cash flow forecasts, we show that stock returns have a significant cash flow news component whose importance increases with the investment horizon. For horizons over two years, cash flow news is more important. These conclusions hold at both the firm and aggregate levels, and diversification plays a secondary role in affecting the relative importance of cash flow and discount rate news. Our findings highlight the importance of cash flows in asset pricing.</description><author>Chen, Long; Da, Zhi; Zhao, Xinlei</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Contractual Resolutions of Financial Distress</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gennaioli, Nicola; Rossi, Stefano
In a financial contracting model, we study the optimal debt structure to resolve financial distress. We show that a debt structure where two distinct debt classes coexist-one class fully concentrated and with control rights upon default, the other dispersed and without control rights-removes the controlling creditor's liquidation bias when investor protection is strong. These results rationalize the use and the performance of floating charge financing, which refers to debt financing where the controlling creditor takes the entire business as collateral, in countries with strong investor protection. Our theory predicts that the efficiency of contractual resolutions of financial distress should increase with investor protection.</description><author>Gennaioli, Nicola; Rossi, Stefano</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>R&amp;D and the Incentives from Merger and Acquisition Activity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Phillips, Gordon M.; Zhdanov, Alexei
We provide a model and empirical tests showing how an active acquisition market affects firm incentives to innovate and conduct R&amp;D. Our model shows that small firms optimally may decide to innovate more when they can sell out to larger firms. Large firms may find it disadvantageous to engage in an "R&amp;D race" with small firms, as they can obtain access to innovation through acquisition. Our model and evidence also show that the R&amp;D responsiveness of firms increases with demand, competition, and industry merger and acquisition activity. All of these effects are stronger for smaller firms than for larger firms.</description><author>Phillips, Gordon M.; Zhdanov, Alexei</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Long-Run Risks Explanation of Predictability Puzzles in Bond and Currency Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bansal, Ravi; Shaliastovich, Ivan
We show that bond risk premia rise with uncertainty about expected inflation and fall with uncertainty about expected growth; the magnitude of return predictability using these uncertainty measures is similar to that by multiple yields. Motivated by this evidence, we develop and estimate a long-run risks model with timevarying volatilities of expected growth and inflation. The model simultaneously accounts for bond return predictability and violations of uncovered interest parity in currency markets. We find that preference for early resolution of uncertainty, time-varying volatilities, and non-neutral effects of inflation on growth are important to account for these aspects of asset markets.</description><author>Bansal, Ravi; Shaliastovich, Ivan</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Price of a CEO's Rolodex</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Engelberg, Joseph; Gao, Pengjie; Parsons, Christopher A.
CEOs with large networks earn more than those with small networks. An additional connection to an executive or director outside the firm increases compensation by about $17,000 on average, more so for "important" members, such as CEOs of big firms. Pay-for-connectivity is unrelated to several measures of corporate governance, evidence in favor of an efficient contracting explanation for CEO pay.</description><author>Engelberg, Joseph; Gao, Pengjie; Parsons, Christopher A.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Misvaluing Innovation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cohen, Lauren; Diether, Karl; Malloy, Christopher
We demonstrate that a firm's ability to innovate is predictable, persistent, and relatively simple to compute, and yet the stock market appears to ignore the implications of past successes when valuing future innovation. We show that two firms that invest the same in R&amp;D can have quite divergent, but predictably divergent, future paths based on their past track records. A long-short portfolio strategy that takes advantage of the information in past track records earns abnormal returns of roughly 11% annually. Importantly, these past track records also predict divergent future real outcomes in patents, patent citations, and new product innovations.</description><author>Cohen, Lauren; Diether, Karl; Malloy, Christopher</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>New Orders and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jones, Christopher S.; Tuzel, Selale
We investigate the asset pricing and macroeconomic implications of the ratio of new orders (NO) to shipments (S) of durable goods. NO/S measures investment commitments by firms, and high values of NO/S are associated with a business cycle peak. We find that NO/S proxies for a short-horizon component of risk premia not identified in prior work. Higher levels of NO/S forecast lower excess returns on equities and many types of bonds, at horizons from one month to one year. These effects are generally robust to the inclusion of common return predictors and are significant on an out-of-sample basis as well. We also address the term structure of risk premia by constructing a similar ratio to measure longer-term investment commitments, which predicts returns primarily at longer horizons.</description><author>Jones, Christopher S.; Tuzel, Selale</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Factor-Loading Uncertainty and Expected Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Armstrong, Christopher S.; Banerjee, Snehal; Corona, Carlos
Firm-specific information can affect expected returns if it affects investor uncertainty about risk-factor loadings. We show that a stock's expected return is decreasing in factor-loading uncertainty, controlling for the average level of its factor loading. When loadings are persistent, learning by investors can induce time-series variation in price-dividend ratios, expected returns, and idiosyncratic volatility, even when the aggregate risk-premium is constant and fundamental shocks are homoscedastic. Consistent with our predictions, we estimate that average annual returns of a firm with the median level of factor-loading uncertainty are 400 to 525 basis points lower than a comparable firm without factor-loading uncertainty.</description><author>Armstrong, Christopher S.; Banerjee, Snehal; Corona, Carlos</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Out of the Dark: Hedge Fund Reporting Biases and Commercial Databases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aiken, Adam L.; Clifford, Christopher P.; Ellis, Jesse
We examine the potential for selection bias in voluntarily reported hedge fund performance data. We construct a set of hedge fund returns that have never been reported to a commercial hedge fund database. These returns allow a direct comparison of performance between funds that choose to report to commercial databases and funds that do not. We find that funds that report their performance to commercial databases significantly outperform nonreporting funds. Our results suggest that the voluntarily reported performance in commercial databases suffers from a selection bias that may exaggerate the average skill of the universe of hedge fund managers.</description><author>Aiken, Adam L.; Clifford, Christopher P.; Ellis, Jesse</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Running for the Exit? International Bank Lending During a Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>De Haas, Ralph; Van Horen, Neeltje
We use loan-level data to examine how large international banks reduced their cross-border lending after the collapse of Lehman Brothers. Country, firm, and bank fixed effects allow us to disentangle credit supply and demand and to simultaneously control for the unobserved traits of banks and the countries and firms they lend to. We document substantial heterogeneity in the extent to which different banks retrenched from the same country. Banks reduced credit less to markets that were geographically close; where they were more experienced; where they operated a subsidiary; and where they were integrated into a network of domestic co-lenders.</description><author>De Haas, Ralph; Van Horen, Neeltje</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Using Option Prices to Infer Overpayments and Synergies in M&amp;A Transactions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Barraclough, Kathryn; Robinson, David T.; Smith, Tom; Whaley, Robert E.
In this paper, we use call option prices to identify synergies and news from merger and acquisition (M&amp;A) transaction announcements. We find that M&amp;A announcements result in large and approximately equal gains to the bidder and the target on average, with the combined gains being large enough to justify the premium paid to target shareholders. On average, M&amp;A announcements release good news about targets, but bad news about bidders. This suggests that market prices understate true synergy gains, and helps reconcile the generally negative market-based evidence on value-creation in takeovers with their continued prominence in everyday business strategy.</description><author>Barraclough, Kathryn; Robinson, David T.; Smith, Tom; Whaley, Robert E.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Realization Utility with Reference-Dependent Preferences</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ingersoll, Jonathan E.; Jin, Lawrence J.
We develop a tractable model of realization utility that studies the role of reference-dependent S-shaped preferences in a dynamic investment setting with reinvestment. Our model generates both voluntarily realized gains and losses. It makes specific predictions about the volume of gains and losses, the holding periods, and the sizes of both realized and paper gains and losses that can be calibrated to a variety of statistics, including Odean's measure of the disposition effect. Our model also predicts several anomalies, including, among others, the flattening of the capital market line and a negative price for idiosyncratic risk.</description><author>Ingersoll, Jonathan E.; Jin, Lawrence J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>CDS Auctions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernov, Mikhail; Gorbenko, Alexander S.; Makarov, Igor
We analyze auctions for the settlement of credit default swaps (CDS) theoretically and evaluate them empirically. The requirement to settle in cash with an option to settle physically leads to an unusual two-stage process. In the first stage, participants affect the amount of the bonds to be auctioned off in the second stage. Participants in the second stage may hold positions in derivatives on the assets being auctioned. We show that the final auction price might be either above or below the fair bond price because of strategic bidding on the part of participants holding CDS. Empirically, we observe both types of outcomes, with undervaluation occurring in most cases. We find that auctions undervalue bonds by an average of 6% on the auction day. Undervaluation is related positively to the amount of bonds exchanged in the second stage of the auction, as predicted by the theory. We suggest modifications of the settlement procedure to minimize the underpricing.</description><author>Chernov, Mikhail; Gorbenko, Alexander S.; Makarov, Igor</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Disclosure an Effective Cleansing Mechanism? The Dynamics of Compensation Peer Benchmarking</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faulkender, Michael; Yang, Jun
Firms routinely justify CEO compensation by benchmarking against companies with highly paid CEOs. We examine whether the 2006 regulatory requirement of disclosing compensation peers mitigated firms' opportunistic peer selection activities. We find that strategic peer benchmarking did not disappear after enhanced disclosure. In fact, it intensified at firms with low institutional ownership, low director ownership, low CEO ownership, busy boards, large boards, and non-intensive monitoring boards, and at firms with shareholders complaining about compensation practices. The effect is also stronger at firms with new CEOs. These findings call into question whether disclosure regulation can remedy potential problems in compensation practices.</description><author>Faulkender, Michael; Yang, Jun</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managers with and without Style: Evidence Using Exogenous Variation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fee, C. Edward; Hadlock, Charles J.; Pierce, Joshua R.
In a large panel of Compustat firms, we find that firm policy changes after exogenous CEO departures do not display abnormally high levels of variability, casting doubt on the presence of idiosyncratic-style effects in policy choices. After endogenous CEO departures, we do detect abnormally large policy changes. These changes are larger when the firm is likely to draw from a deeper pool of replacement CEO candidates, suggesting the presence of causal-style effects that are anticipated by the board. Our evidence suggests that managerial styles are not transferred across employers and that standard F-tests are inappropriate for identifying style effects.</description><author>Fee, C. Edward; Hadlock, Charles J.; Pierce, Joshua R.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual Fund's R-2 as Predictor of Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Amihud, Yakov; Goyenko, Ruslan
We propose that fund performance can be predicted by its R-2, obtained from a regression of its returns on a multifactor benchmark model. Lower R-2 indicates greater selectivity, and it significantly predicts better performance. Stock funds sorted into lowest-quintile lagged R-2 and highest-quintile lagged alpha produce significant annual alpha of 3.8%. Across funds, R-2 is positively associated with fund size and negatively associated with its expenses and manager's tenure.</description><author>Amihud, Yakov; Goyenko, Ruslan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are U.S. CEOs Paid More? New International Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fernandes, Nuno; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro; Murphy, Kevin J.
This paper challenges the widely accepted stylized fact that chief executive officers (CEOs) in the United States are paid significantly more than their foreign counterparts. Using CEO pay data across fourteen countries with mandated pay disclosures, we show that the U.S. pay premium is economically modest and primarily reflects the performance-based pay demanded by institutional shareholders and independent boards. Indeed, we find no significant difference in either level of CEO pay or the use of equity-based pay between U.S. and non-U.S. firms exposed to international and U.S. capital, product, and labor markets. We also show that U.S. and non-U.S. CEO pay has largely converged in the 2000s.</description><author>Fernandes, Nuno; Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro; Murphy, Kevin J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Local Overweighting and Underperformance: Evidence from Limited Partner Private Equity Investments</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hochberg, Yael V.; Rauh, Joshua D.
Institutional investors exhibit substantial home-state bias in private equity. This effect is particularly pronounced for public pension funds, where overweighting amounts to 9.8% of aggregate private-equity investments and 16.5% for the average limited partner. Public pension funds' in-state investments achieve performance that is lower by two to four percentage points than both their own similar out-of-state investments and similar investments in their state by out-of-state investors. Overweighting in home-state investments by public pension funds is greater in venture capital and real estate than in buyout funds. States with political climates characterized by more self-dealing invest a larger share of their portfolio in local investments, although a given local investment performs only as poorly in these states as in other states. Relative to the performance of the rest of the private equity universe, overweighting and underperformance in local investments reduce public pension fund resources by $1.2 billion per year.</description><author>Hochberg, Yael V.; Rauh, Joshua D.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fiscal Policy and Asset Prices with Incomplete Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gomes, Francisco; Michaelides, Alexander; Polkovnichenko, Valery
We study the simultaneous impact of fiscal policy decisions on macroeconomic activity, wealth distribution, and asset prices. We consider a general equilibrium, overlapping generations model with incomplete markets and heterogeneous agents, where government debt and capital are imperfect substitutes. Increases in public debt lead to significant increases in the riskless rate and to a reduction in the equity premium, while higher capital income tax rates lead to a higher equity premium. The crowding-out effects (on capital and output) are much higher than in models where government debt and capital are perfect substitutes, which thus ignore households' portfolio reallocation decisions.</description><author>Gomes, Francisco; Michaelides, Alexander; Polkovnichenko, Valery</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Short Selling and the Price Discovery Process</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Wu, Juan
We show that stock prices are more accurate when short sellers are more active. First, in a large panel of NYSE-listed stocks, intraday informational efficiency of prices improves with greater shorting flow. Second, at monthly and annual horizons, more shorting flow accelerates the incorporation of public information into prices. Third, greater shorting flow reduces post-earnings-announcement drift for negative earnings surprises. Fourth, short sellers change their trading around extreme return events in a way that aids price discovery and reduces divergence from fundamental values. These results are robust to various econometric specifications, and their magnitude is economically meaningful. (JEL G14)</description><author>Boehmer, Ekkehart; Wu, Juan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance and Value Creation: Evidence from Private Equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral V.; Gottschalg, Oliver F.; Hahn, Moritz; Kehoe, Conor
Using deal-level data from transactions initiated by large private equity houses, we find that the abnormal performance of deals is positive on average, after controlling for leverage and sector returns. Higher abnormal performance is related to improvement in sales and operating margin during the private phase, relative to that for quoted peers. General partners who are ex-consultants or ex-industry managers are associated with outperforming deals focused on internal value-creation programs, and ex-bankers or ex-accountants with outperforming deals involving significant mergers and acquisitions. The findings suggest the presence, on average, of positive but heterogeneous skills at the deal-partner level in large private equity transactions.</description><author>Acharya, Viral V.; Gottschalg, Oliver F.; Hahn, Moritz; Kehoe, Conor</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Procyclical Effects of Bank Capital Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Repullo, Rafael; Suarez, Javier
We compare various bank capital regulation regimes using a dynamic equilibrium model of relationship lending in which banks are unable to access the equity markets every period and the business cycle determines loans' probabilities of default. Banks hold endogenous capital buffers as a precaution against shocks that impair their future lending capacity. We find that Basel II is more procyclical than Basel I but makes banks safer, and it is generally superior in welfare terms. For high social costs of bank failure, the optimal capital requirements are higher but less cyclically varying, like those currently targeted by Basel III.</description><author>Repullo, Rafael; Suarez, Javier</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Toward a Quantitative General Equilibrium Asset Pricing Model with Intangible Capital</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ai, Hengjie; Croce, Mariano Massimiliano; Li, Kai
We model investment options as intangible capital in a production economy in which younger vintages of assets in place have lower exposure to aggregate productivity risk. In equilibrium, physical capital requires a substantially higher expected return than intangible capital. Quantitatively, our model rationalizes a significant share of the observed difference in the average return of book-to-market-sorted portfolios (value premium). Our economy also produces (1) a high premium of the aggregate stock market over the risk-free interest rate, (2) a low and smooth risk-free interest rate, and (3) key features of the consumption and investment dynamics in the U.S. data.</description><author>Ai, Hengjie; Croce, Mariano Massimiliano; Li, Kai</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investor Heterogeneity, Investor-Management Disagreement and Share Repurchases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Sheng; Thakor, Anjan V.
This paper develops and tests a new theoretical explanation for stock repurchases. Investors may disagree with the manager about the firm's investment projects. Arepurchase causes a change in the investor base as investors who are most likely to disagree with the manager tender their shares. Therefore, a firm is more likely to buy back shares when the level of investor-management agreement is lower, and agreement improves as a consequence. Moreover, dispersion of opinion among investors cannot explain repurchase activity once the stock price and investor-management agreement are controlled for. Overall, the evidence is consistent with firms strategically using repurchases to improve alignment between management and shareholders.</description><author>Huang, Sheng; Thakor, Anjan V.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Untitled</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hirshleifer, David; Schwert, G. William; Singleton, Kenneth J.
nan</description><author>Hirshleifer, David; Schwert, G. William; Singleton, Kenneth J.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Market Shocks and the Macroeconomy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Titman, Sheridan
Feedback from stock prices to cash flows occurs because information revealed by firms' stock prices influences the actions of competitors. We explore the implications of feedback within a noisy rational expectations setting with incumbent publicly traded firms and privately held new entrants. In this setting the equilibrium relation among stock prices and both future dividends and aggregate output depends on the strategic environment in which these firms operate. In general, under reasonable conditions, the relations between prices, dividends, and economic output in our framework are consistent with empirical evidence in the macroliterature. We also generate new, potentially testable, implications.</description><author>Subrahmanyam, Avanidhar; Titman, Sheridan</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Firm Characteristics and Stock Returns: The Role of Investment-Specific Shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kogan, Leonid; Papanikolaou, Dimitris
Average return differences among firms sorted on valuation ratios, past investment, profitability, market beta, or idiosyncratic volatility are largely driven by differences in exposures of firms to the same systematic factor related to embodied technology shocks. Using a calibrated structural model, we show that these firm characteristics are correlated with the ratio of growth opportunities to firm value, which affects firms' exposures to capital-embodied productivity shocks and risk premia. We thus provide a unified explanation for several apparent anomalies in the cross-section of stock returns-namely, predictability of returns by these firm characteristics and return comovement among firms with similar characteristics.</description><author>Kogan, Leonid; Papanikolaou, Dimitris</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the Benefits of Contractual Completeness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Matvos, Gregor
I provide a revealed-preference-based framework that uses covenant prices and choices to quantitatively study how covenants generate firm benefits by completing debt contracts. I use a rational-expectations-based panel estimator of covenant prices, which does not require quasi-experimental variation, to circumvent the problem of endogenous covenant choices. I find that firms' surpluses exceed the spread paid on a loan. Leverage and interest-rate covenants produce the largest benefits, lending quantitative credence to several standard theories of covenants. Once covenants are chosen, the benefits from fine-tuning them are small, thus rationalizing "boilerplate" covenants. I conclude by discussing the extensions and limitations of my method.</description><author>Matvos, Gregor</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Long-Run Risk and the Persistence of Consumption Shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ortu, Fulvio; Tamoni, Andrea; Tebaldi, Claudio
We propose a decomposition for time series in components classified by levels of persistence. Employing this decomposition, we provide empirical evidence that consumption growth contains predictable components highly correlated with well-known proxies of consumption variability. These components generate a term-structure of sizable risk premia. At low frequencies we identify a component correlated with long-run productivity growth and commanding a yearly premium of approximately 2%. At high frequencies we identify a component with yearly half-life, which contributes to the equity premium for another 2%. Accounting for persistence heterogeneity, we obtain an estimate of the IES strictly above one and robust across subsamples.</description><author>Ortu, Fulvio; Tamoni, Andrea; Tebaldi, Claudio</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Pricing with Endogenous Disasters</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Tiu, Cristian; Yoeli, Uzi
We develop a parsimonious model in which frictions in the labor market may turn small, continuous labor productivity declines into large drops in employment, endogenously causing disasters. Assuming one state variable and CRRA agents, we solve for prices in closed form, calibrate the model using labor market data, and show that this simple setting captures the high, countercyclical volatility and equity premium observed in the United States. Moreover, returns in our model are conditionally predicted by dividend yields. Finally, as in the data, in our setting the disasters are larger when the capital's share of income is higher.</description><author>Tiu, Cristian; Yoeli, Uzi</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Specialization, Productivity, and Financing Constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marquez, Robert; Yavuz, M. Deniz
We analyze optimal financial contracts when the specificity of investments is endogenous. Specialization decreases the liquidation value of assets, but improves the asset's long-term productivity. While the former is known to make financing more difficult, we show that the latter can ease financing constraints and increase financing capacity by improving an entrepreneur's incentive to repay. The overall impact of specialization on the terms of financing depends on which effect is more important. Specialization decisions interact with the nature of investments, their timing, the need for outside financing, and an entrepreneur's ability to commit to a level of specialization.</description><author>Marquez, Robert; Yavuz, M. Deniz</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Private Equity Fund Managers Earn Their Fees? Compensation, Ownership, and Cash Flow Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Robinson, David T.; Sensoy, Berk A.
We study the relations between management contract terms and performance in private equity using new data for 837 funds from 1984-2010. We find no evidence that higher fees or lower managerial ownership are associated with lower net-of-fee performance. Nevertheless, compensation rises and shifts to performance-insensitive components during fundraising booms. Further, the behavior of distributions around contractual fee triggers is consistent with an underlying agency conflict between investors and fund managers. Our evidence suggests that managers with higher fees deliver higher gross performance, and highlights that agency costs are an inevitable consequence of the information frictions endemic to agency relationships.</description><author>Robinson, David T.; Sensoy, Berk A.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Drives the Value Premium?: The Role of Asset Risk and Leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Jaewon
This paper shows empirically how asset risk and financial leverage interact to explain the equity risk dynamics of value versus growth stocks. During economic downturns, the asset betas and leverage of value firms increase, contributing to a sharp rise in equity betas. Asset betas of growth firms are much less sensitive to economic conditions, and, consistent with the tradeoff theory of capital structure, growth firms are also less levered, contributing to the relative stability of their equity betas. By incorporating instruments that better capture beta dynamics, I show that the interactions of conditional betas with the market risk premium and volatility explain approximately 40% of the unconditional value premium.</description><author>Choi, Jaewon</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>With a Little Help from My (Random) Friends: Success and Failure in Post-Business School Entrepreneurship</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lerner, Josh; Malmendier, Ulrike
How do individuals decide to become entrepreneurs and learn to make optimal entrepreneurial decisions? The concentration of entrepreneurs in regions such as Silicon Valley has stimulated research and policy interest into the influence of peers, but the causal effect is hard to identify empirically. We exploit the exogenous assignment of students into business-school sections to identify the causal effect of entrepreneurial peers. We show that, in contrast to prior findings, a higher share of entrepreneurial peers decreases, rather than increases, entrepreneurship. The decrease is driven by a reduction in unsuccessful entrepreneurial ventures; the effect on successful ventures is significantly more positive.</description><author>Lerner, Josh; Malmendier, Ulrike</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Structural Model of Dynamic Market Timing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Detemple, Jerome; Rindisbacher, Marcel
This paper derives and analyzes dynamic timing strategies of a fund manager with private information. Endogenous timing strategies generated by various information structures and skills, and associated fund styles, are identified. Endogenous fund returns are characterized in the public information of an uninformed observer. Timing components are identified. The paper provides foundations for regression analyses of fund returns and tests of market timing.</description><author>Detemple, Jerome; Rindisbacher, Marcel</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Family Control Matter? International Evidence from the 2008-2009 Financial Crisis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lins, Karl V.; Volpin, Paolo; Wagner, Hannes F.
We study whether and how family control affects valuation and corporate decisions during the 2008-2009 financial crisis using a sample of more than 8,500 firms from 35 countries. We find that family-controlled firms underperform significantly, they cut investment more relative to other firms, and these investment cuts are associated with greater underperformance. Further, we find that within family groups liquidity shocks are passed on through investment cuts across the group. Our evidence is consistent with families taking actions to increase the likelihood that the firms under their control and their control benefits survive the crisis, at the expense of outside shareholders.</description><author>Lins, Karl V.; Volpin, Paolo; Wagner, Hannes F.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Incentives and the Role of Advisors in the Continuous-Time Agency Model</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hori, Keiichi; Osano, Hiroshi
We explore a continuous-time agency model with double moral hazard. Using a venture capitalist (VC)-entrepreneur relationship where the VC both supplies costly effort and chooses the optimal timing of the initial public offering (IPO), we show that optimal IPO timing is earlier under double moral hazard than under single moral hazard. Our results also indicate that the manager's compensation tends to be paid earlier under double moral hazard. We derive several comparative static results, notably that IPO timing is earlier when the need for monitoring by the VC is smaller and when the volatility of cash flows is larger.</description><author>Hori, Keiichi; Osano, Hiroshi</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of Trader Profits in Commodity Futures Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dewally, Michael; Ederington, Louis H.; Fernando, Chitru S.
Using proprietary energy futures position data, we provide evidence that mean hedger profits are negative whereas speculator (especially hedge fund) profits are positive, that traders (whether speculators or hedgers) who hold net positions opposite in sign to likely hedgers in aggregate have higher profits than traders whose net positions align with likely hedgers, and that profits on long positions vary inversely with inventories and directly with price volatility. These findings are consistent with the risk premium, hedging pressure, and modern theory of storage hypotheses, respectively. Further, our findings suggest that commodity futures momentum may be due largely to hedging pressure.</description><author>Dewally, Michael; Ederington, Louis H.; Fernando, Chitru S.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Attractions and Perils of Flexible Mortgage Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garmaise, Mark J.
A mortgage program that offered borrowers greater flexibility in the timing of repayments increased a bank's volume by over 35%. Loans in the program exhibited superior performance. Despite this, a regression discontinuity analysis shows that the causal impact of offering flexibility was to attract borrowers to the bank who experienced quadruple the average delinquency rate. These contrasting findings are driven by the fact that the bank engaged in ex post sorting of stronger borrowers into the flexible program. This sorting masked the ex ante adverse selection effects that offering flexibility had on the entire borrowing pool.</description><author>Garmaise, Mark J.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Pricing in the Dark: The Cross-Section of OTC Stocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ang, Andrew; Shtauber, Assaf A.; Tetlock, Paul C.
Over-the-counter (OTC) stocks are far less liquid, disclose less information, and exhibit lower institutional holdings than do listed stocks. We exploit these different market conditions to test theories of cross-sectional return premiums. Compared with premiums in listed markets, the OTC illiquidity premium is several times higher, the size, value, and volatility premiums are similar, and the momentum premium is three times lower. The OTC illiquidity, size, value, and volatility premiums are largest among stocks held predominantly by retail investors and those not disclosing financial information. Theories of differences in investors' opinions and limits on short sales help explain these return premiums.</description><author>Ang, Andrew; Shtauber, Assaf A.; Tetlock, Paul C.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Supply Approach to Valuation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Belo, Frederico; Xue, Chen; Zhang, Lu
A new methodology for equity valuation arises from the perspective of managers' supply of capital assets. Under q-theory, managers optimally adjust the supply of assets to changes in their market value. The first-order condition of investment then provides a valuation equation that infers asset prices from managers' costs of supplying the assets. This equation fits well the Tobin's q levels across many testing assets, including portfolios formed on q. With current investment-to-capital as the only input, the supply approach does not require cash flow forecasts or discount rate estimates, both of which are notoriously difficult to obtain in practice.</description><author>Belo, Frederico; Xue, Chen; Zhang, Lu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond Illiquidity and Excess Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bao, Jack; Pan, Jun
We find that the empirical volatilities of corporate bond and CDS returns are higher than implied by equity return volatilities and the Merton model. This excess volatility may arise because structural models inadequately capture either fundamentals or illiquidity. Our evidence supports the latter explanation. We find little relation between excess volatility and measures of firm fundamentals and the volatility of firm fundamentals but some relation with variables proxying for time-varying illiquidity. Consistent with an illiquidity explanation, firm-level bond portfolio returns, which average out bond-specific effects, significantly decrease excess volatility.</description><author>Bao, Jack; Pan, Jun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Equilibrium with Two Stocks, Heterogeneous Investors, and Portfolio Constraints</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chabakauri, Georgy
We study dynamic equilibrium in a Lucas economy with two stocks, two heterogeneous constant relative risk aversion investors, and portfolio constraints. We focus on margin and leverage constraints, which restrict access to credit. We find a positive relationship between the amount of leverage in the economy and magnitudes of stock return correlations and volatilities. Tighter constraints generate rich patterns in correlations and volatilities, make them less countercyclical, increase risk premia proportionally to assets' margins, and increase prices of low-margin assets more than prices of high-margin assets. We derive closed-form solutions for the unconstrained case and the case of leverage constraints.</description><author>Chabakauri, Georgy</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Flip Side of Financial Synergies: Coinsurance Versus Risk Contamination</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Banal-Estanol, Albert; Ottaviani, Marco; Winton, Andrerw
This paper characterizes when joint financing of two projects through debt increases expected default costs, contrary to conventional wisdom. Separate financing dominates joint financing when risk-contamination losses-that are associated with the contagious default of a well-performing project that is dragged down by the other project's poor performance-outweigh standard coinsurance gains. Separate financing becomes more attractive than joint financing when the fraction of returns lost under default increases and when projects have lower mean returns, higher variability, more positive correlation, and more negative skewness. These predictions are broadly consistent with evidence on conglomerate mergers, spinoffs, project finance, and securitization.</description><author>Banal-Estanol, Albert; Ottaviani, Marco; Winton, Andrerw</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Indexing Executive Compensation Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dittmann, Ingolf; Maug, Ernst; Spalt, Oliver G.
We analyze the efficiency of indexing executive pay by calibrating the standard compensation model to a large sample of U.S. CEOs. The benefits from indexing the strike price of options are small, and fully indexing all options would increase compensation costs by 50% for most firms. Indexing has several effects with overall ambiguous outcome; the quantitatively most important effect is to reduce incentives, because indexed options pay off when CEOs' marginal utility is low. The results also hold if CEOs can extract rents and extend to the case of indexing shares. Our findings may justify the common practice of "pay-for-luck.".</description><author>Dittmann, Ingolf; Maug, Ernst; Spalt, Oliver G.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Equity Volatility Explain the Global Loan Pricing Puzzle?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gaul, Lewis; Uysal, Pinar
This paper examines whether unobservable differences in firm volatility are responsible for the global loan pricing puzzle, which is the observation that corporate loan interest rates appear to be lower in Europe than in the United States. We analyze whether equity volatility, an error prone measure of firm volatility, can explain this difference in loan spreads. We show that using equity volatility in OLS regressions will result in biased and inconsistent estimates of the difference in U.S. and European loan spreads. We use instrumental variable methods to identify consistent estimates and find no difference in U.S. and European loan spreads.</description><author>Gaul, Lewis; Uysal, Pinar</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pricing Credit Default Swaps with Observable Covariates</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Doshi, Hitesh; Ericsson, Jan; Jacobs, Kris; Turnbull, Stuart M.
Observable covariates are useful for predicting default, but several studies question their value for explaining credit spreads. We introduce a discrete-time no-arbitrage model with observable covariates, which allows for a closed-form solution for the value of credit default swaps (CDS). The default intensity is a quadratic function of the covariates, specified such that it is always positive. The model yields economically plausible results in terms of fit, the economic impact of the covariates, and the prices of risk. Risk premiums are large and account for a smaller percentage of spreads for firms with lower credit quality. Macroeconomic and firm-specific information can explain most of the variation in CDS spreads over time and across firms, even with a parsimonious specification. These findings resolve the existing disconnect in the literature regarding the value of observable covariates for credit risk pricing and default prediction.</description><author>Doshi, Hitesh; Ericsson, Jan; Jacobs, Kris; Turnbull, Stuart M.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hidden and Displayed Liquidity in Securities Markets with Informed Liquidity Providers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boulatov, Alex; George, Thomas J.
We examine the impact on the quality of a securities market of hiding versus displaying orders that provide liquidity. Display expropriates informational rents from informed agents who trade as liquidity providers. The informed then exit liquidity provision in favor of demanding liquidity where they trade less aggressively. Trading costs to uninformed liquidity demanders are higher, bid-ask spreads are wider, and midquotes are less informationally efficient when orders that provide liquidity are displayed. Our analysis suggests that market innovations, which might seem to favor the informed over the uninformed, can enhance market quality by intensifying competition among the informed.</description><author>Boulatov, Alex; George, Thomas J.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Price of Diversifiable Risk in Venture Capital and Private Equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ewens, Michael; Jones, Charles M.; Rhodes-Kropf, Matthew
This paper demonstrates how the principal-agent problem between venture capitalists and their investors (limited partners) causes limited partner returns to depend on diversifiable risk. Our theory shows why the need for investors to motivate VCs alters the negotiations between VCs and entrepreneurs and changes how new firms are priced. The three-way interaction rationalizes the use of high discount rates by VCs and predicts a correlation between total risk and net of fee investor returns. We take our theory to a unique data set and find empirical support for the effect of the principal-agent problem on equilibrium private equity asset prices.</description><author>Ewens, Michael; Jones, Charles M.; Rhodes-Kropf, Matthew</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Capturing Option Anomalies with a Variance-Dependent Pricing Kernel</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Peter; Heston, Steven; Jacobs, Kris
We develop a GARCH option model with a new pricing kernel allowing for a variance premium. While the pricing kernel is monotonic in the stock return and in variance, its projection onto the stock return is nonmonotonic. A negative variance premium makes it U shaped. We present new semiparametric evidence to confirm this U-shaped relationship between the risk-neutral and physical probability densities. The new pricing kernel substantially improves our ability to reconcile the time-series properties of stock returns with the cross-section of option prices. It provides a unified explanation for the implied volatility puzzle, the overreaction of long-term options to changes in short-term variance, and the fat tails of the risk-neutral return distribution relative to the physical distribution.</description><author>Christoffersen, Peter; Heston, Steven; Jacobs, Kris</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do CEOs Matter? The Effect of Industry Expertise on Acquisition Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Custodio, Claudia; Metzger, Daniel
This paper shows how chief executive officer (CEO) characteristics affect the performance of acquirers in diversifying takeovers. When the acquirer's CEO has previous experience in the target industry, the acquirer's abnormal announcement returns are between 1.2 and 2.0 percentage points larger than those generated by a CEO who is new to the target industry. This outcome is driven by the industryexpert CEO's ability to capture a larger fraction of the merger surplus. Industryexpert CEOs typically negotiate better deals and pay a lower premium for the target. This effect is stronger when information asymmetry is high and in bilateral negotiations compared to auctions. We also find that industryexpert CEOs on average select lower surplus deals. This evidence is consistent with industryexpert CEOs having superior negotiation skills.</description><author>Custodio, Claudia; Metzger, Daniel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investors' Horizons and the Amplification of Market Shocks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cella, Cristina; Ellul, Andrew; Giannetti, Mariassunta
This paper shows that during episodes of market turmoil, 13F institutional investors with short trading horizons sell their stockholdings to a larger extent than 13F institutional investors with longer trading horizons. This creates price pressure for stocks held mostly by short-horizon investors, which, as a consequence, experience larger price drops, and subsequent reversals, than stocks held mostly by long-horizon investors. These findings, obtained after controlling for the withdrawals experienced by the investors, are not driven by other institutional investors' and firms' characteristics. Overall, the evidence indicates that investors with short horizons amplify the effects of market-wide negative shocks by demanding liquidity at times when other potential buyers'capital is scarce.</description><author>Cella, Cristina; Ellul, Andrew; Giannetti, Mariassunta</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Momentum in Corporate Bond Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jostova, Gergana; Nikolova, Stanislava; Philipov, Alexander; Stahel, Christof W.
This paper documents significant momentum in a comprehensive sample of 81,491 U.S. corporate bonds with both transaction and dealer-quote data from 1973 to 2011. Momentum is driven by noninvestment grade (NIG) bonds. Momentum profits have increased over time, along with the growth of this segment. From 1991 to 2011, they average 59 basis points (bps) per month across all bonds and 192 bps in NIG bonds. NIG bonds issued by private firms earn even higher profits (282 bps). Momentum profits do not appear to compensate for risk or persist as a result of trading frictions. Bond momentum is not just a manifestation of equity momentum.</description><author>Jostova, Gergana; Nikolova, Stanislava; Philipov, Alexander; Stahel, Christof W.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identifying the Valuation Effects and Agency Costs of Corporate Diversification: Evidence from the Geographic Diversification of US Banks</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Goetz, Martin R.; Laeven, Luc; Levine, Ross
This paper assesses the impact of the geographic diversification of bank holding company (BHC) assets across the United States on their market valuations. Using two new identification strategies based on the dynamic process of interstate bank deregulation, we find that exogenous increases in geographic diversity reduced BHC valuations. We also find that the geographic diversification of BHC assets increased insider lending and reduced loan quality. Taken together, these findings are consistent with theories predicting that geographic diversity intensifies agency problems.</description><author>Goetz, Martin R.; Laeven, Luc; Levine, Ross</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Implicit Barriers Matter for Globalization?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carrieri, Francesca; Chaieb, Ines; Errunza, Vihang
Market liberalization may not result in full market integration if implicit barriers are important. We test this proposition for investable and non-investable segments of twenty-two emerging markets (EMs). We also measure the degree of integration for six major developed markets (DMs) as a meaningful benchmark. We find that while the DMs are close to fully integrated, both EM segments are not effectively integrated with the global economy. We quantify the importance of implicit barriers and show that better institutions, stronger corporate governance, and more transparent markets in EMs would jointly contribute to a higher degree of integration by about 20% to 30%.</description><author>Carrieri, Francesca; Chaieb, Ines; Errunza, Vihang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ambiguous Volatility and Asset Pricing in Continuous Time</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Epstein, Larry G.; Ji, Shaolin
We formulate a model of utility for a continuous-time framework that captures aversion to ambiguity about both volatility and drift. Corresponding extensions of some basic results in asset pricing theory are presented. First, we derive arbitrage-free pricing rules based on hedging arguments. Because ambiguous volatility implies market incompleteness, hedging arguments determine prices only up to intervals. In order to obtain sharper predictions, we apply the model of utility to a representative agent endowment economy and study equilibrium asset returns. A version of the consumption capital asset pricing model is derived, and the effects of ambiguous volatility are described.</description><author>Epstein, Larry G.; Ji, Shaolin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>'O Sole Mio: An Experimental Analysis of Weather and Risk Attitudes in Financial Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bassi, Anna; Colacito, Riccardo; Fulghieri, Paolo
Although weather has been shown to affect financial markets and financial decision making, a still open question is the channel through which such influence is exerted. By employing a multiple price list method, this paper provides direct experimental evidence that sunshine and good weather promote risk-taking behavior. This effect is present whether relying on objective measures of meteorological conditions or subjective weather assessments. Finally, employing a psychological test, we find evidence that weather may affect individual risk tolerance through its effect on mood.</description><author>Bassi, Anna; Colacito, Riccardo; Fulghieri, Paolo</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond Market Clienteles, the Yield Curve, and the Optimal Maturity Structure of Government Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Guibaud, Stephane; Nosbusch, Yves; Vayanos, Dimitri
We propose a clientele-based model of the yield curve and optimal maturity structure of government debt. Clienteles are generations of agents at different lifecycle stages in an overlapping-generations economy. An optimal maturity structure exists in the absence of distortionary taxes and induces efficient intergenerational risksharing. If agents are more risk-averse than log, then an increase in the long-horizon clientele raises the price and optimal supply of long-term bonds-effects that we also confirm empirically in a panel of OECD countries. Moreover, under the optimal maturity structure, catering to clienteles is limited and long-term bonds earn negative expected excess returns.</description><author>Guibaud, Stephane; Nosbusch, Yves; Vayanos, Dimitri</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Anticipated and Repeated Shocks in Liquid Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lou, Dong; Yan, Hongjun; Zhang, Jinfan
We show that Treasury security prices in the secondary market decrease significantly in the few days before Treasury auctions and recover shortly thereafter, even though the time and amount of each auction are announced in advance. These results are linked to dealers' limited risk-bearing capacity and end-investors' imperfect capital mobility, highlighting the important role of frictions even in very liquid financial markets. Our results imply a hidden issuance cost to the U. S. Department of the Treasury, estimated to be 9 to 18 bps of the auction size, or over half a billion dollars for the issuance size in 2007.</description><author>Lou, Dong; Yan, Hongjun; Zhang, Jinfan</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rating Shopping or Catering? An Examination of the Response to Competitive Pressure for CDO Credit Ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, John M.; Nickerson, Jordan; Tang, Dragon Yongjun
We examine whether "rating shopping" or "rating catering" is a more accurate characterization of rating agency interactions regarding collateralized debt obligations (CDOs). Although investors paid a premium for dual ratings, AAA CDO tranches rated by both Moody's and S&amp;P defaulted more frequently than tranches rated by only one of them, which is inconsistent with pure rating shopping. Rating agencies made upward adjustments beyond their model when their competitor had more lenient assumptions. Finally, consistent with rating catering, S&amp;P's and Moody's adjustments and disagreements at security issuance were reflected in subsequent rating downgrades, suggesting that adjustments were harmful.</description><author>Griffin, John M.; Nickerson, Jordan; Tang, Dragon Yongjun</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Skew Risk Premium in the Equity Index Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kozhan, Roman; Neuberger, Anthony; Schneider, Paul
We develop a new method for measuring moment risk premiums. We find that the skew premium accounts for over 40% of the slope in the implied volatility curve in the S&amp;P 500 market. Skew risk is tightly related to variance risk, in the sense that strategies designed to capture the one and hedge out exposure to the other earn an insignificant risk premium. This provides a new testable restriction for asset pricing models trying to capture, in particular, disaster risk premiums. We base our results on a general trading strategy by replicating contracts that swap implied for realized conditional asset moments.</description><author>Kozhan, Roman; Neuberger, Anthony; Schneider, Paul</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Combining Banking with Private Equity Investing</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fang, Lily; Ivashina, Victoria; Lerner, Josh
Bank-affiliated private equity groups account for 30% of all private equity investments. Their market share is highest during peaks of the private equity market, when the parent banks arrange more debt financing for in-house transactions yet have the lowest exposure to debt. Using financing terms and ex post performance, we show overall that banks do not make superior equity investments to those of stand-alone private equity groups. Instead, they appear to expand their private equity engagement to take advantage of the credit market booms, while capturing private benefits from cross-selling of other banking services.</description><author>Fang, Lily; Ivashina, Victoria; Lerner, Josh</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Libertarian Paternalism, Information Production, and Financial Decision Making</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Carlin, Bruce Ian; Gervais, Simon; Manso, Gustavo
We develop a theoretical model to analyze the effects of libertarian paternalism on information production and financial decision making. Individuals in our model appreciate the information content of the recommendations made by a social planner. This affects their incentive to gather information, and in turn the speed at which information spreads across market participants, via social learning or formal advice channels. We characterize situations in which libertarian paternalism improves welfare and contrast them with scenarios in which this policy is suboptimal because of its negative impact on the production and propagation of information.</description><author>Carlin, Bruce Ian; Gervais, Simon; Manso, Gustavo</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Estimating the Costs of Issuer-Paid Credit Ratings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cornaggia, Jess; Cornaggia, Kimberly J.
We compare the stability and timeliness of credit ratings produced by a traditional issuer-paid rating agency (Moody's Investors Service) and a subscriber-paid rater (Rapid Ratings). Moody's ratings exhibit less volatility but are slower to identify default risk. We control for Moody's aversion to ratings volatility and still find its ratings lag Rapid Ratings'. More importantly, accuracy ratios indicate that Rapid Ratings provides a better ordinal ranking of credit risk. We quantify the loss avoidance associated with Rapid Ratings' signals to estimate costs associated with regulatory and contractual systems based on issuer-paid ratings.</description><author>Cornaggia, Jess; Cornaggia, Kimberly J.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Life Cycle Portfolio Choice with Housing Market Cycles</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fischer, Marcel; Stamos, Michael Z.
In recent decades U.S. households have experienced residential house prices moving persistently, that is, returns being positively serially correlated. We set up a realistically calibrated life cycle model with slow-moving time variation in expected housing returns, showing that not only age, labor income, and pre-existing housing wealth but also the state of the housing market significantly affect household decisions. Consistently with the data, the model predicts that in good states of housing market cycles (1) homeownership rates increase, (2) households buying homes invest a larger share of their net worth in their home, and (3) these households lever up more.</description><author>Fischer, Marcel; Stamos, Michael Z.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Subprime Consumer Credit Demand: Evidence from a Lender's Pricing Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Alan, Sule; Loranth, Gyongyi
Using a unique panel data set from a U.K. credit card company, we analyze the interest rate sensitivity of subprime credit card borrowers. In addition to all individual transactions and loan terms, we have access to details of a randomized interest rate experiment conducted by the lender on existing (inframarginal) loans. For the whole sample, we estimate a statistically significant 3.4 pound reduction in monthly credit demand in response to a five percentage point increase in interest rates. This aggregate response is small, but it masks very interesting heterogeneity in the sample. We find that only low-risk borrowers who fully utilize their credit cards lower their credit demand significantly when faced with an increase in interest rates. We also document that a five percentage point increase in interest rates generates significant additional revenue for the lender without inducing delinquency over a short horizon.</description><author>Alan, Sule; Loranth, Gyongyi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Capacity and Discontinuous Investment: Evidence from Emerging Market Multibusiness Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Natividad, Gabriel
I provide a new characterization of internal capital markets in an emerging economy using daily divisional data on all Peruvian fish-processing firms. A regression discontinuity model exploiting government production bans on regulated divisions ("fishmeal") shows that the increased investment in the nonfishmeal divisions due to the bans is substantial (over 30% of the mean value), after controlling for productivity. The redeployment of financial capacity into nonfishmeal investments is particularly sharper when external financing is more costly and when firms are more closely monitored by creditors. The value-creating nature of this redeployment is supported by its positive effects on nonfishmeal exports.</description><author>Natividad, Gabriel</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Journalists and the Stock Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dougal, Casey; Engelberg, Joseph; Garcia, Diego; Parsons, Christopher A.
We use exogenous scheduling of Wall Street Journal columnists to identify a causal relation between financial reporting and stock market performance. To measure the media's unconditional effect, we add columnist fixed effects to a daily regression of excess Dow Jones Industrial Average returns. Relative to standard control variables, these fixed effects increase the R-2 by about 35%, indicating each columnist's average persistent "bullishness" or "bearishness." To measure the media's conditional effect, we interact columnist fixed effects with lagged returns. This increases explanatory power by yet another one-third, and identifies amplification or attenuation of prevailing sentiment as a tool used by financial journalists.</description><author>Dougal, Casey; Engelberg, Joseph; Garcia, Diego; Parsons, Christopher A.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Snow and Leverage</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Giroud, Xavier; Mueller, Holger M.; Stomper, Alex; Westerkamp, Arne
Based on a sample of highly leveraged Austrian ski hotels undergoing debt restructurings, we show that reducing a debt overhang leads to a significant improvement in operating performance. Changes in leverage in the debt restructurings are instrumented with Unexpected Snow, which captures the extent to which a ski hotel experienced unusually good or bad snow conditions prior to the debt restructuring. Unexpected Snow provides lending banks with the counterfactual of what would have been the ski hotel's operating performance in the absence of strategic default, allowing them to distinguish between ski hotels that are in distress due to negative demand shocks ("liquidity defaulters") and those that are in distress due to debt overhang ("strategic defaulters").</description><author>Giroud, Xavier; Mueller, Holger M.; Stomper, Alex; Westerkamp, Arne</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Liquidity and Asset Returns Under Asymmetric Information and Imperfect Competition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Vayanos, Dimitri; Wang, Jiang
We analyze how asymmetric information and imperfect competition affect liquidity and asset prices. Our model has three periods: Agents are identical in the first, become heterogeneous and trade in the second, and consume asset payoffs in the third. We show that asymmetric information in the second period raises ex ante expected asset returns in the first, comparing both to the case where all private signals are made public and to that where private signals are not observed. Imperfect competition can instead lower expected returns. Each imperfection can move common measures of illiquidity in opposite directions.</description><author>Vayanos, Dimitri; Wang, Jiang</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Reviewing Less-Progressing More</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Spiegel, Matthew
Editorial: Presumably, academic journals exist and publish articles to disseminate new ideas. Somehow that simple goal has been lost. Today, articles appear in print only after a referee is convinced that all other alternative explanations for its results have been ruled out. In reality, no article can exclude every possible alternative, so this is basically an exercise in futility. The criterion for publication should be that once an article crosses some threshold it is good enough to publish. The problem seemingly lies in our inability to say "good enough." But this is a problem we can fix.</description><author>Spiegel, Matthew</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Debt Runs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Zhiguo; Xiong, Wei
This article analyzes the dynamic coordination problem among creditors of a firm with a time-varying fundamental and a staggered debt structure. In deciding whether to roll over his debt, each maturing creditor is concerned about the rollover decisions of other creditors whose debt matures during his next contract period. We derive a unique threshold equilibrium and characterize the roles of fundamental volatility, credit lines, and debt maturity in driving runs. In particular, we show that when fundamental volatility is sufficiently high, commonly used measures such as temporarily keeping the firm alive under runs and increasing debt maturity can exacerbate rather than mitigate runs.</description><author>He, Zhiguo; Xiong, Wei</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Creditor Control Rights, Corporate Governance, and Firm Value</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nini, Greg; Smith, David C.; Sufi, Amir
We provide evidence that creditors play an active role in the governance of corporations well outside of payment default states. By examining the Securities and Exchange Commission's filings of all U.S. nonfinancial firms from 1996 through 2008, we document that, in any given year, between 10% and 20% of firms report being in violation of a financial covenant in a credit agreement. We show that violations are followed immediately by a decline in acquisitions and capital expenditures, a sharp reduction in leverage and shareholder payouts, and an increase in CEO turnover. The changes in the investment and financing behavior of violating firms coincide with amended credit agreements that contain stronger restrictions on firm decision-making; changes in the management of violating firms suggest that creditors also exert informal influence on corporate governance. Finally, we show that firm operating and stock price performance improve post-violation. We conclude that actions taken by creditors increase the value of the average violating firm.</description><author>Nini, Greg; Smith, David C.; Sufi, Amir</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Life Cycle of Family Ownership: International Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Franks, Julian; Mayer, Colin; Volpin, Paolo; Wagner, Hannes F.
We show that in countries with strong investor protection, developed financial markets, and active markets for corporate control, family firms evolve into widely held companies as they age. In countries with weak investor protection, less developed financial markets, and inactive markets for corporate control, family control is very persistent over time. While family control in high investor protection countries is concentrated in industries that have low investment opportunities and low merger and acquisition (M&amp;A) activity, the same is not so in countries that have low investor protection, where the presence of family control in an industry is unrelated to investment opportunities and M&amp;A activity.</description><author>Franks, Julian; Mayer, Colin; Volpin, Paolo; Wagner, Hannes F.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financing Constraints and the Cost of Capital: Evidence from the Funding of Corporate Pension Plans</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Campbell, John L.; Dhaliwal, Dan S.; Schwartz, William C.
We investigate the relation between firms' weighted average cost of capital and internal financial resources, using mandatory pension contributions as a proxy for internal financial resources. Rauh (2006) documents a negative association between mandatory pension contributions and capital expenditures. We find that an increase in mandatory pension contributions increases the cost of capital, but only for firms facing greater external financing constraints. Our results suggest that firms' cost of capital is an intervening variable that can explain Rauh's finding that mandatory pension contributions (i.e., internal financing constraints) result in foregone investment. Overall, we provide evidence consistent with recent studies (Rauh 2006; Almeida and Campello 2007) that conclude that financial market frictions affect real economic activity and, in particular, corporate investment.</description><author>Campbell, John L.; Dhaliwal, Dan S.; Schwartz, William C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Executive Compensation and the Role for Corporate Governance Regulation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dicks, David L.
This article establishes a role for corporate governance regulation. An externality operating through executive compensation motivates regulation. Governance lowers agency costs, allowing firms to grant less incentive pay. When a firm increases governance and lowers incentive pay, other firms can also lower executive compensation. Because firms do not internalize the full benefit of governance, regulation can improve investor welfare. When regulation is enforced, large firms increase in value, small firms decrease in value, and all firms lower incentive pay. Distinct cross-sectional and cross-country predictions for the number of voluntary governance firms are provided.</description><author>Dicks, David L.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Testing Asymmetric-Information Asset Pricing Models</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Kelly, Bryan; Ljungqvist, Alexander
We provide evidence for the importance of information asymmetry in asset pricing by using three natural experiments. Consistent with rational expectations models with multiple assets and multiple signals, we find that prices and uninformed demand fall as asymmetry increases. These falls are larger when more investors are uninformed, turnover is larger and more variable, payoffs are more uncertain, and the lost signal is more precise. Prices fall partly because expected returns become more sensitive to liquidity risk. Our results confirm that information asymmetry is priced and imply that a primary channel that links asymmetry to prices is liquidity.</description><author>Kelly, Bryan; Ljungqvist, Alexander</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lack of Anonymity and the Inference from Order Flow</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Linnainmaa, Juhani T.; Saar, Gideon
This article investigates the information content of signals about the identity of investors and their role in price formation. Whereas we document that investors use multiple brokers, broker identity is nevertheless a powerful signal about the identity of investors who initiate trades. The market also correctly processes this signal: the permanent price impact of orders coming from different brokers fits the information profile of the investors associated with these brokers. Our results suggest that an increase in the degree of anonymity may render order flow less informative, which could explain why the literature has documented liquidity improvements in exchanges that reduce transparency.</description><author>Linnainmaa, Juhani T.; Saar, Gideon</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Flow Toxicity and Liquidity in a High-frequency World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Easley, David; de Prado, Marcos M. Lopez; O'Hara, Maureen
Order flow is toxic when it adversely selects market makers, who may be unaware they are providing liquidity at a loss. We present a new procedure to estimate flow toxicity based on volume imbalance and trade intensity (the VPIN toxicity metric). VPIN is updated in volume time, making it applicable to the high-frequency world, and it does not require the intermediate estimation of non-observable parameters or the application of numerical methods. It does require trades classified as buys or sells, and we develop a new bulk volume classification procedure that we argue is more useful in high-frequency markets than standard classification procedures. We show that the VPIN metric is a useful indicator of short-term, toxicity-induced volatility.</description><author>Easley, David; de Prado, Marcos M. Lopez; O'Hara, Maureen</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Compensation Contracts with Private Savings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>He, Zhiguo
This article studies a dynamic agency problem in which a risk-averse agent can save privately. In the optimal contract, (i) cash compensations exhibit downward rigidity to failures; (ii) permanent pay raises occur when the agent's historical performance is sufficiently good; (iii) and when the agent is dismissed due to poor performance, he walks away with severance pay to support his post-firing consumption at the current compensation level. Thus, the theory can simultaneously explain the popularity of options-like compensation contracts and the increasing incidence of forced turnovers with sizeable severance pay.</description><author>He, Zhiguo</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Why Does Financial Strength Forecast Stock Returns? Evidence from Subsequent Demand by Institutional Investors</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Choi, Nicole Y.; Sias, Richard W.
Using institutional investor demand as a proxy for revisions in sophisticated investors' expectations, we test whether financial strength information is gradually impounded over time. Consistent with the gradual incorporation of information, financial strength predicts both future returns and future institutional investor demand. Further consistent with the gradual incorporation of information, more sophisticated transient (high-turnover) institutions respond to financial strength signals prior to less sophisticated, nontransient institutions. A number of additional tests suggest that financial strength forecasts stock returns, at least in part, because it forecasts institutional demand, and institutional demand drives prices.</description><author>Choi, Nicole Y.; Sias, Richard W.</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Skewness in Stock Returns: Reconciling the Evidence on Firm Versus Aggregate Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Albuquerque, Rui
Aggregate stock market returns display negative skewness. Firm stock returns display positive skewness. The large literature that tries to explain the first stylized fact ignores the second. This article provides a unified theory that reconciles the two facts by explicitly modeling firm-level heterogeneity. I build a stationary asset pricing model of firm announcement events where firm returns display positive skewness. I then show that cross-sectional heterogeneity in firm announcement events can lead to conditional asymmetric stock return correlations and negative skewness in aggregate returns. I provide evidence consistent with the model predictions.</description><author>Albuquerque, Rui</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Inflation Expectations, Real Rates, and Risk Premia: Evidence from Inflation Swaps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Haubrich, Joseph; Pennacchi, George; Ritchken, Peter
We develop a model of nominal and real bond yield curves that has four stochastic drivers but seven factors: three factors primarily determine the cross-section of yields, whereas four volatility factors solely determine risk premia. The model is estimated using nominal Treasury yields, survey inflation forecasts, and inflation swap rates and has attractive empirical properties. Time-varying volatility is particularly apparent in short-term real rates and expected inflation. Also, we detail the different economic forces that drive short- and long-term real and inflation risk premia and provide evidence that Treasury inflation-protected securities were undervalued prior to 2004 and during the recent financial crisis.</description><author>Haubrich, Joseph; Pennacchi, George; Ritchken, Peter</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Financial Leverage, Corporate Investment, and Stock Returns</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ozdagli, Ali K.
This article rationalizes empirical patterns of market leverage, book leverage, book-to-market ratios, and stock returns across different book-to-market portfolios, using a model of firm financing and investment. The model analytically shows that tax deductibility of interest payments increases. effective investment irreversibility and that investment irreversibility weakens the relation between book-to-market values and returns. This provides a clear and novel mechanism showing how financial leverage affects stock returns beyond the standard Modigliani-Miller paradigm. The article argues that market leverage, rather than operating leverage or investment irreversibility, explains a major portion of the value premium. Empirical evidence supports this argument. (JEL G12, G31, G32)</description><author>Ozdagli, Ali K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Hazards of Debt: Rollover Freezes, Incentives, and Bailouts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Cheng, Ing-Haw; Milbradt, Konstantin
We investigate the trade-off between incentive provision and inefficient rollover freezes for a firm financed with short-term debt. First, debt maturity that is too short-term is inefficient, even with incentive provision. The optimal maturity is an interior solution that avoids excessive rollover risk while providing sufficient incentives for the manager to avoid risk-shifting when the firm is in good health. Second, allowing the manager to risk-shift during a freeze actually increases creditor confidence. Debt policy should not prevent the manager from holding what may appear to be otherwise low-mean strategies that have option value during a freeze. Third, a limited but not perfectly reliable form of emergency financing during a freeze-a "bailout"-may improve the terms of the trade-off and increase total ex ante value by instilling confidence in the creditor markets. Our conclusions highlight the endogenous interaction between risk from the asset and liability sides of the balance sheet. (JEL G01, G20, G21, G28, G32)</description><author>Cheng, Ing-Haw; Milbradt, Konstantin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Same Bond at Different Prices: Identifying Search Frictions and Selling Pressures</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Feldhuetter, Peter
I propose a new measure that identifies when the market price of an over-the-counter traded asset is below its fundamental value due to selling pressure. The measure is the difference between prices paid by small traders and those paid by large traders. In a model for over-the-counter trading with search frictions and periods with selling pressures, I show that this measure identifies liquidity crises (i.e., high number of forced sellers). Using a structural estimation, the model is able to identify liquidity crises in the U.S. corporate bond market based on the relative prices paid by small and large traders. New light is shed on two crises, the downgrade of General Motors and Ford in 2005 and the subprime crisis (JEL D4, D83, G01, G12).</description><author>Feldhuetter, Peter</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bond Liquidity Premia</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fontaine, Jean-Sebastien; Garcia, Rene
Theory predicts that funding conditions faced by financial intermediaries are an important limit to arbitrage. We identify and measure the value of funding liquidity from the cross-section of Treasury securities. To validate our interpretation, we establish linkages with funding conditions in the repo market, the shadow banking sector, and the overall economy. Looking at asset pricing implications, we find that increases in funding liquidity predict lower risk premia for all Treasury securities but higher risk premia on LIBOR loans, swap contracts, and corporate bonds. The impact of funding conditions on interest rates is large and pervasive throughout crises and normal times. (JEL E43, H12)</description><author>Fontaine, Jean-Sebastien; Garcia, Rene</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Finding a Good Price in Opaque Over-the-Counter Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Zhu, Haoxiang
This article offers a dynamic model of opaque over-the-counter markets. A seller searches for an attractive price by visiting multiple buyers, one at a time. The buyers do not observe contacts, quotes, or trades elsewhere in the market. A repeat contact with a buyer reveals the seller's reduced outside options and worsens the price offered by the revisited buyer. When the asset value is uncertain and common to all buyers, a visit by the seller suggests that other buyers could have quoted unattractive prices and thus worsens the visited buyer's inference regarding the asset value. (JEL G14, C78, D82, D83)</description><author>Zhu, Haoxiang</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Treating Measurement Error in Tobin's q</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erickson, Timothy; Whited, Toni M.
We compare the ability of three measurement error remedies to deliver unbiased estimates of coefficients in investment regressions. We examine high-order moment estimators, dynamic panel estimators, and simple instrumental variables estimators that use lagged mismeasured regressors as instruments. We show that recent investigations of this question are largely uninformative. We find that all estimators can pet-form well under correct specification, all can be biased under misspecification, and misspecification is easiest to detect in the case of high-order moment estimators. We develop and demonstrate a minimum distance technique that extends the high-order moment estimators to be used on unbalanced panel data. (JEL C15, C26, E22, G31)</description><author>Erickson, Timothy; Whited, Toni M.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is Unbiased Financial Advice to Retail Investors Sufficient? Answers from a Large Field Study</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Hackethal, Andreas; Kaesler, Simon; Loos, Benjamin; Meyer, Steffen
Working with one of the largest brokerages in Germany, we record what happens when unbiased investment advice is offered to a random set of approximately 8,000 active retail customers out of the brokerage's several hundred thousand retail customers. We find that investors who most need the financial advice are least likely to obtain it. The investors who do obtain the advice (about 5%), however, hardly follow the advice and do not improve their portfolio efficiency by much. Overall, our results imply that the mere availability of unbiased financial advice is a necessary but not sufficient condition for benefiting retail investors. (JEL D14, D11, G24, G28)</description><author>Bhattacharya, Utpal; Hackethal, Andreas; Kaesler, Simon; Loos, Benjamin; Meyer, Steffen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Precarious Politics and Return Volatility</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boutchkova, Maria; Doshi, Hitesh; Durnev, Art; Molchanov, Alexander
We examine how local and global political risks affect industry return volatility. Our central premise is that some industries are more sensitive to political events than others. We find that industries that are more dependent on trade, contract enforcement, and labor exhibit greater return volatility when local political risks are higher. Political uncertainty in countries of trading partners of trade-dependent industries similarly results in greater volatility. Volatility decomposition results indicate that while systematic volatility is associated with domestic political uncertainty, global political risks translate into larger idiosyncratic volatility. (JEL G10, G15)</description><author>Boutchkova, Maria; Doshi, Hitesh; Durnev, Art; Molchanov, Alexander</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Liquidity and Capital Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anderson, Ronald W.; Carverhill, Andrew
We solve for a firm's optimal cash holding policy within a continuous time, contingent claims framework using dividends, short-term borrowing, and equity issues as controls assuming mean reversion of earnings. Optimal cash is non-monotone in business conditions and increasing in the level of long-term debt. The model matches closely a wide range of empirical benchmarks and predicts cash and leverage dynamics in line with the empirical literature. Firm value is quite insensitive to changes in the level of long-term debt. The model has interesting implications for asset substitution, hedging, and pecking order. Growth opportunities do not greatly affect cash holding policy.</description><author>Anderson, Ronald W.; Carverhill, Andrew</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Mutual Fund Tournaments: The Sorting Bias and New Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Schwarz, Christopher G.
Previous findings regarding the risk-shifting behavior of mid-year underperforming mutual fund managers are mixed. In this article, I show that this is due to a "sorting bias," which is caused by the sorting of first-half risk levels when establishing relative mid-year performance. Even without risk-shifting behavior, mean reversion of these sorted risk levels results in the detection of tournament behavior. After correcting for this bias, I find evidence supporting the hypothesis that first-half underperforming managers increase portfolio risk during the second half of the year and that this tournament behavior is not dependent on first-half market conditions.</description><author>Schwarz, Christopher G.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tournament Behavior in Hedge Funds: High-water Marks, Fund Liquidation, and Managerial Stake</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aragon, George O.; Nanda, Vikram
We analyze whether risk shifting by a hedge fund manager is related to the manager's incentive contract, personal capital stake, and the risk of fund closure. We find that the propensity to increase risk following poor performance is significantly weaker when incentive pay is tied to the fund's high-water mark and when funds face little immediate risk of liquidation. Risk shifting is also less prevalent when a manager has a significant amount of personal capital invested in the fund. Overall, high-water mark provisions, managerial stake, and low risk of fund closure appear to make a hedge fund manager more conservative with regard to risk shifting.</description><author>Aragon, George O.; Nanda, Vikram</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Governance Objectives of Labor Union Shareholders: Evidence from Proxy Voting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Agrawal, Ashwini K.
Labor union pension funds have become increasingly vocal in governance matters; however, their motives are subject to fierce debate. I examine the proxy votes of AFL-CIO union funds around an exogenous change in the union representation of workers across firms. AFL-CIO-affiliated shareholders become significantly less opposed to directors once the AFL-CIO labor organization no longer represents a firm's workers. Other institutional investors, including mutual funds and public pension funds, do not exhibit similar voting behavior. Union opposition is also associated with negative valuation effects. The data suggest that some investors pursue worker interests, rather than maximize shareholder value alone.</description><author>Agrawal, Ashwini K.</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Debt Financing and Financial Flexibility Evidence from Proactive Leverage Increases</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Denis, David J.; McKeon, Stephen B.
Firms that intentionally increase leverage through substantial debt issuances do so primarily as a response to operating needs rather than a desire to make a large equity payout. Subsequent debt reductions are neither rapid, nor the result of proactive attempts to rebalance the firm's capital structure toward a long-run target. Instead, the evolution of the firm's leverage ratio depends primarily on whether or not the firm produces a financial surplus. In fact, firms that generate subsequent deficits tend to cover these deficits predominantly with more debt even though they exhibit leverage ratios that are well above estimated target levels. Our findings are broadly consistent with a capital structure theory in which financial flexibility, in the form of unused debt capacity, plays an important role in capital structure choices.</description><author>Denis, David J.; McKeon, Stephen B.</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Inventory Growth Spread</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Belo, Frederico; Lin, Xiaoji
Previous studies show that firms with low inventory growth outperform firms with high inventory growth in the cross-section of publicly traded firms. In addition, inventory investment is volatile and procyclical, and inventory-to-sales is persistent and countercyclical. We embed an inventory holding motive into the investment-based asset pricing framework by modeling inventory as a factor of production with convex and nonconvex adjustment costs. The augmented model simultaneously matches the large inventory growth spread in the data, as well as the time-series properties of the firm-level capital investment, inventory investment, and inventory-to-sales. Our conditional single-factor model also implies that traditional unconditional factor models such as the CAPM should fail to explain the inventory growth spread, although not with the same large pricing errors observed in the data.</description><author>Belo, Frederico; Lin, Xiaoji</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Takeovers and Divergence of Investor Opinion</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chatterjee, Sris; John, Kose; Yan, An
We test several hypotheses on how takeover premium is related to investors' divergence of opinion on a target's equity value. We show that the total takeover premium, the pre-announcement target stock price run-up, and the post-announcement stock price markup are all higher when investors have higher divergence of opinion. We obtain identical results with higher market-level investor sentiment. When divergence of opinion is higher, a firm is less likely to be a takeover target, although takeover synergy in successful takeovers is higher. Our results suggest that takeovers may play a role in explaining high contemporaneous stock prices in the presence of high divergence of investor opinion.</description><author>Chatterjee, Sris; John, Kose; Yan, An</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Road Less Traveled: Strategy Distinctiveness and Hedge Fund Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Sun, Zheng; Wang, Ashley; Zheng, Lu
We investigate whether skilled hedge fund managers are more likely to pursue unique investment strategies that result in superior performance. We propose a measure of the distinctiveness of a fund's investment strategy based on historical fund return data. We call the measure the "Strategy Distinctiveness Index" (SDI). We document substantial cross-sectional variations as well as strong persistence in SDI. Our main result indicates that, on average, a higher SDI is associated with better subsequent performance. After adjusting for risk, funds in the highest SDI quintile outperform funds in the lowest quintile by 3.5% in the subsequent year.</description><author>Sun, Zheng; Wang, Ashley; Zheng, Lu</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Level 3 Assets: Booking Profits and Concealing Losses</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Milbradt, Konstantin
Fair value accounting forces institutions to revalue inventory whenever a transaction occurs. An institution that faces a balance sheet constraint may have incentives to suspend trading in Level 3 assets (traded on opaque over-the-counter markets) in order to avoid such marking-to-market. This keeps the book valuation artificially high, relaxing the balance sheet constraint. But, the institution loses direct control of the risk of its position. Solving this "real options" problem, the institution will report profits as they occur but delay reporting losses. A regulator trying to control risk imposes fines for balance sheet manipulation and capital requirements. Both these tools can increase risk-taking and balance sheet manipulation. Audits in comparision generally decrease risk-taking but may be costly to the regulator. The model provides predictions on the distribution of a bank's trading gains in illiquid markets.</description><author>Milbradt, Konstantin</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Hedge Fund Stock Trading in the Financial Crisis of 2007-2009</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben-David, Itzhak; Franzoni, Francesco; Moussawi, Rabih
Hedge funds significantly reduced their equity holdings during the recent financial crisis. In 2008:Q3--Q4, hedge funds sold about 29% of their aggregate portfolio. Redemptions and margin calls were the primary drivers of selloffs. Consistent with forced deleveraging, the selloffs took place in volatile and liquid stocks. In comparison, redemptions and stock sales for mutual funds were not as severe. We show that hedge fund investors withdraw capital three times as intensely as mutual fund investors do in response to poor returns. We relate this stronger sensitivity to losses to share liquidity restrictions and institutional ownership in hedge funds.</description><author>Ben-David, Itzhak; Franzoni, Francesco; Moussawi, Rabih</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Priority Structure, Capital Structure, and Investment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hackbarth, Dirk; Mauer, David C.
We study the interaction between financing and investment decisions in a dynamic model, where the firm has multiple debt issues and equityholders choose the timing of investment. Jointly optimal capital and priority structures can virtually eliminate investment distortions because debt priority serves as a dynamically optimal contract. Examining the relative efficiency of priority rules observed in practice, we develop several predictions about how firms adjust their priority structure in response to changes in leverage, credit conditions, and firm fundamentals. Notably, financially unconstrained firms with few growth opportunities prefer senior debt, while financially constrained firms, with or without growth opportunities, prefer junior debt. Moreover, lower-rated firms are predicted to spread priority across debt classes. Finally, our analysis has a number of important implications for empirical capital structure research, including the relations between market leverage, book leverage, and credit spreads and Tobin's Q, the influence of firm fundamentals on the agency cost of debt, and the conservative debt policy puzzle.</description><author>Hackbarth, Dirk; Mauer, David C.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Performance of Institutional Trading Desks: An Analysis of Persistence in Trading Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Anand, Amber; Irvine, Paul; Puckett, Andy; Venkataraman, Kumar
Using a proprietary dataset of institutional investors' equity transactions, we document that institutional trading desks can sustain relative performance over adjacent periods. We find that trading-desk skill is positively correlated with the performance of the institution's traded portfolio, suggesting that institutions that invest resources in developing execution abilities also invest in generating superior investment ideas. Although some brokers can deliver better executions consistently over time, our analysis suggests that trading-desk skill is not limited to a selection of better brokers. We conclude that the trade implementation process is economically important and can contribute to relative portfolio performance. (JEL G12, G23, G24)</description><author>Anand, Amber; Irvine, Paul; Puckett, Andy; Venkataraman, Kumar</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Optimal Corporate Governance and Compensation in a Dynamic World</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Noe, Thomas H.; Rebello, Michael J.
We model long-run firm performance, management compensation, and corporate governance in a dynamic, nonstationary world. Many features of governance and compensation that have caused consternation among commentators arise naturally in this dynamic setting, even though boards are rational and managers are powerless. Compensation changes depend on changes in the evolution of a latent state variable outside the manager's control. Board passivity is positively correlated with both the value of management compensation and the firm's good fortune. Managerial opportunism tends to follow sudden reversals of good fortune. Moreover, managerial private benefits, by increasing managers' stake in the long-run viability of the firm, may actually ameliorate agency conflicts. (JEL G20, G34)</description><author>Noe, Thomas H.; Rebello, Michael J.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Country-level Investor Protections Affect Security-level Contract Design? Evidence from Foreign Bond Covenants</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Miller, Darius P.; Reisel, Natalia
This article studies the ability of security-level contracts to substitute for poor country-level investor protections. Using a cross-country sample of restrictive covenants, we find that bond contacts are more likely to include covenants when creditor protection laws are weak. Further, the use of restrictive covenants in weak creditor protection countries is associated with a lower cost of debt. We also find that strong country-level shareholder rights are not necessarily harmful to bondholders. Overall, the findings suggest that issuers and investors can create international contracts that overcome some of the deficiencies of country-level investor protections and facilitate access to external finance. (JEL F30, G30, G34)</description><author>Miller, Darius P.; Reisel, Natalia</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Assessing TARP</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bayazitova, Dinara; Shivdasani, Anil
We study the government equity infusions into banks under the Capital Purchase Program (CPP) of the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP). Strong banks opted out of CPP, and equity infusions were provided to banks that posed systemic risk and faced high financial distress costs but had strong asset quality. Concerns over executive compensation led banks to reject CPP infusions and exit the program. CPP infusions did not have meaningful certification effects, but the subsequent stress tests conducted for the major banks had significant certification effects. CPP equity infusions increased investor expectations regarding future regulatory interventions in the banking sector. (JEL G18, G21, G28)</description><author>Bayazitova, Dinara; Shivdasani, Anil</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Corporate Default Probabilities Consistent with the Static Trade-off Theory?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hovakimian, Armen; Kayhan, Ayla; Titman, Sheridan
Default probability plays a central role in the static trade-off theory of capital structure. We directly test this theory by regressing the probability of default on proxies for costs and benefits of debt. Contrary to predictions of the theory, firms with higher bankruptcy costs, i.e., smaller firms and firms with lower asset tangibility, choose capital structures with higher bankruptcy risk. Further analysis suggests that the capital structures of smaller firms with lower asset tangibility-which tend to have less access to capital markets-are more sensitive to negative profitability and equity value shocks, making them more susceptible to bankruptcy risk. (JEL G32)</description><author>Hovakimian, Armen; Kayhan, Ayla; Titman, Sheridan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trade Credit Contracts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Klapper, Leora; Laeven, Luc; Rajan, Raghuram
We employ a novel data set on almost 30,000 trade credit contracts to describe the broad characteristics of the parties that contract together and the key terms of these contracts. Whereas prior work has typically used information on only one side of the buyer-seller transaction, we utilize information on both, allowing for the first analysis of buyer-seller pairs. An equally important distinction is that we have multiple contracts for the same buyer or supplier firms, rather than a firm-average response, allowing for the correction of time-invariant firm characteristics that might determine the choice of credit terms. We find that the largest and most creditworthy buyers receive contracts with the longest maturities from smaller suppliers, and that discounts for early payment tend to be offered to riskier buyers.</description><author>Klapper, Leora; Laeven, Luc; Rajan, Raghuram</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Dividend Policies: Lessons from Private Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Michaely, Roni; Roberts, Michael R.
We compare the dividend policies of publicly and privately held firms in order to help identify the forces shaping corporate dividends, and shed light on the behavior of privately held companies. We show that private firms smooth dividends significantly less than their public counterparts, suggesting that the scrutiny of public capital markets plays a central role in the propensity of firms to smooth dividends over time. Public firms pay relatively higher dividends that tend to be more sensitive to changes in investment opportunities than otherwise similar private firms. Ultimately, ownership structure and incentives play key roles in shaping dividend policies.</description><author>Michaely, Roni; Roberts, Michael R.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Commodity Liquidity Measurement and Transaction Costs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Marshall, Ben R.; Nguyen, Nhut H.; Visaltanachoti, Nuttawat
We examine the performance of liquidity proxies in commodities. The Amihud measure has the largest correlation with liquidity benchmarks. Amivest and Effective Tick measures also perform well. These proxies are useful for studies of commodity liquidity over a long time period and those that lack access to high-frequency data. We use various aspects of transaction costs, such as spread, depth, immediacy, and resiliency, to give insight into the costs of different execution approaches. Transaction costs increase with volatility and exhibit mean reversion. Splitting trades over one hour can reduce trading costs by two-thirds compared to an immediate execution. (JEL G11, G12, G13)</description><author>Marshall, Ben R.; Nguyen, Nhut H.; Visaltanachoti, Nuttawat</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Macroeconomic Conditions and Capital Raising</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Erel, Isil; Julio, Brandon; Kim, Woojin; Weisbach, Michael S.
Do macroeconomic conditions affect firms' abilities to raise capital? If so, how do they affect the manner in which the capital is raised? Using a large sample of publicly traded debt issues, seasoned equity offers, bank loans, and private placements of equity and debt, we find that a borrower's credit quality significantly affects its ability to raise capital during macroeconomic downturns. For noninvestment-grade borrowers, capital raising tends to be procyclical, while for investment-grade borrowers, it is countercyclical. Poor market conditions also affect the structure of securities offered, shifting them toward shorter maturities and more security. Overall, our results suggest that macroeconomic conditions influence the securities that firms issue to raise capital, the way in which these securities are structured, and indeed firms' ability to raise capital at all. (JEL E32, G30, G32)</description><author>Erel, Isil; Julio, Brandon; Kim, Woojin; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Jumps and Information Flow in Financial Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lee, Suzanne S.
This article investigates the predictability of jump arrivals in U.S. stock markets. Using a new test that identifies jump predictors up to the intraday level, I find that jumps are likely to occur shortly after macroeconomic information releases, such as the Federal Reserve announcements, nonfarm payroll reports, and jobless claims, as well as market index jumps. I also find firm-specific jump predictors related to earnings releases, analyst recommendations, past stock jumps, and dividend dates. Evidence suggests that distinguishing systematic jumps from idiosyncratic jumps is possible using the characteristics of jump predictors. Finally, I present a short-term jump size clustering. (JEL G10, C14)</description><author>Lee, Suzanne S.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Takeover Bidding with Signaling Incentives</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Liu, Tingjun
This study examines takeover bidding contests in which privately informed bidders have incentives to signal high values to uninformed investors through their bids. Such incentives could arise in a large number of situations from financing and managerial concerns. The findings show that the dynamic nature of the takeover contests plays a critical role in the signaling process, allowing bidders to signal high values in two ways. Such signaling bears important consequences on the bids, the allocative efficiency, the target's and bidders' profits, as well as the winner's post-takeover stock price performance and volatility. (JEL G34, D44)</description><author>Liu, Tingjun</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fiduciary Duties and Equity-debtholder Conflicts</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Becker, Bo; Stromberg, Per
We use an important legal event to examine the effect of managerial fiduciary duties on equity-debt conflicts. A 1991 legal ruling changed corporate directors' fiduciary duties in Delaware firms, limiting managers' incentives to take actions that favor equity over debt for distressed firms. After this, affected firms responded by increasing equity issues and investment and by reducing risk. The ruling was also followed by an increase in leverage, reduced reliance on covenants, and higher values. Fiduciary duties appear to affect equity-bondholder conflicts in a way that is economically important, has impact on ex ante capital structure choices, and affects welfare.</description><author>Becker, Bo; Stromberg, Per</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Hedging in Incomplete Markets: A Simple Solution</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Basak, Suleyman; Chabakauri, Georgy
We provide fully analytical, optimal dynamic hedges in incomplete markets by employing the traditional minimum-variance criterion. Our hedges are in terms of generalized "Greeks" and naturally extend no-arbitrage-based risk management in complete markets to incomplete markets. Whereas the literature characterizes either minimum-variance static, myopic, or dynamic hedges from which a hedger may deviate unless able to precommit, our hedges are time-consistent. We apply our results to derivatives replication with infrequent trading and determine hedges and replication values, which reduce to generalized Black-Scholes expressions in specific settings. We also investigate dynamic hedging with jumps, stochastic correlation, and portfolio management with benchmarking.</description><author>Basak, Suleyman; Chabakauri, Georgy</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trading Fees and Efficiency in Limit Order Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Colliard, Jean-Edouard; Foucault, Thierry
Competition among trading platforms has considerably reduced trading fees in stock markets. We show that this evolution is not necessarily beneficial to investors. Although they increase gains from trade when a trade happens, lower trading costs can induce investors to post limit orders with a smaller execution probability. In this case, gains from trade are realized less frequently and investors can be worse off. Our model has testable implications for the effects of trading fees and their breakdown between liquidity suppliers and liquidity demanders on limit order fill rates and bid-ask spreads.</description><author>Colliard, Jean-Edouard; Foucault, Thierry</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cross-Listing, Investment Sensitivity to Stock Price, and the Learning Hypothesis</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Foucault, Thierry; Fresard, Laurent
Cross-listed firms in the United States have a higher investment-to-price sensitivity than do firms that never cross-list. This difference is strong, does not exist prior to the cross-listing date, and does not vanish afterward. Moreover, it does not appear to be primarily driven by improvements in governance, disclosure, and access to capital associated with a U.S. cross-listing. Instead, we argue that a cross-listing enhances managers' reliance on stock prices because it makes stock prices more informative to them. Consistent with this explanation, U.S. cross-listings that are more likely to strengthen the informativeness of stock prices for managers feature a higher investment-to-price sensitivity.</description><author>Foucault, Thierry; Fresard, Laurent</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Important is Having Skin in the Game? Originator-Sponsor Affiliation and Losses on Mortgage-backed Securities</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Demiroglu, Cem; James, Christopher
This article examines the relationship between a mortgage originator's affiliation with the sponsor of a securitization or the servicer of the securitized loans and the default rate on the securitized mortgages. We find that default rates are significantly lower for securitizations in which the originator is affiliated with the sponsor or servicer. Consistent with investors expecting performance to vary with affiliation, we find that the initial yields on mortgage-backed securities (MBS) are lower and the percentage of AAA-rated securities issued against the securitized pool of loans is higher when the originator is affiliated with either the sponsor or servicer.</description><author>Demiroglu, Cem; James, Christopher</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asset Pricing and the Credit Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Longstaff, Francis A.; Wang, Jiang
This article studies the central role of the credit market. We show that the credit market facilitates optimal risk sharing by allowing less risk-averse investors to take on levered positions and consume more risk. The equilibrium amount behaves procyclically when aggregate consumption is low but countercyclically when it is high. The varying size of the credit market modifies the amount of risk sharing, which in turn influences asset prices such as expected stock returns, stock return volatility, and the term structure of interest rates. Our article provides a frictionless benchmark for the role and the behavior of the credit market.</description><author>Longstaff, Francis A.; Wang, Jiang</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Investment and Capital Constraints: Repatriations Under the American Jobs Creation Act</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Faulkender, Michael; Petersen, Mitchell
The American Jobs Creation Act (AJCA) significantly lowered U.S. firms' tax cost when accessing their unrepatriated foreign earnings. Using this temporary shock to the cost of internal financing, we examine the role of capital constraints in firms' investment decisions. Controlling for the capacity to repatriate foreign earnings under the AJCA, we find that a majority of the funds repatriated by capital-constrained firms were allocated to approved domestic investment. Although unconstrained firms account for a majority of repatriated funds, no increase in investment resulted. Contrary to other examinations of the AJCA, we find little change in leverage and equity payouts.</description><author>Faulkender, Michael; Petersen, Mitchell</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Is the Potential for International Diversification Disappearing? A Dynamic Copula Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Christoffersen, Peter; Errunza, Vihang; Jacobs, Kris; Langlois, Hugues
International equity markets are characterized by nonlinear dependence and asymmetries. We propose a new dynamic asymmetric copula model to capture long-run and short-run dependence, multivariate nonnormality, and asymmetries in large cross-sections. We find that correlations have increased markedly in both developed markets (DMs) and emerging markets (EMs), but they are much lower in EMs than in DMs. Tail dependence has also increased, but its level is still relatively low in EMs. We propose new measures of dynamic diversification benefits that take into account higher-order moments and nonlinear dependence. The benefits from international diversification have reduced over time, drastically so for DMs. EMs still offer significant diversification benefits, especially during large market downturns.</description><author>Christoffersen, Peter; Errunza, Vihang; Jacobs, Kris; Langlois, Hugues</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Ability or Finances as Constraints on Entrepreneurship? Evidence from Survival Rates in a Natural Experiment</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Andersen, Steffen; Nielsen, Kasper Meisner
We use a natural experiment in Denmark to test the hypothesis that aspiring entrepreneurs face financial constraints because of low entrepreneurial quality. We identify 304 constrained entrepreneurs who start a business after receiving windfall wealth and examine the performance of these marginal entrepreneurs. We find that constrained entrepreneurs have significantly lower survival rates and lower profits when compared with a matched sample of unconstrained entrepreneurs. These results are consistent with the hypothesis that the marginal entrepreneur is of low quality.</description><author>Andersen, Steffen; Nielsen, Kasper Meisner</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Pay for Performance from Future Fund Flows: The Case of Private Equity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chung, Ji-Woong; Sensoy, Berk A.; Stern, Lea; Weisbach, Michael S.
Lifetime incomes of private equity general partners (GPs) are affected by their current funds' performance not only directly, through carried interest profit-sharing provisions, but also indirectly by the effect of the current fund's performance on GPs' abilities to raise capital for future funds. In the context of a rational learning model, which we show better matches the empirical relations between future fund-raising and current performance than behavioral alternatives, we estimate that indirect pay for performance from future fund-raising is of the same order of magnitude as direct pay for performance from carried interest. Consistent with the learning framework, indirect pay for performance is stronger when managerial abilities are more scalable and weaker when current performance is less informative about ability. Specifically, it is stronger for buyout funds than for venture capital funds, and declines in the sequence of a partnership's funds. Total pay for performance in private equity is both considerably larger and much more heterogeneous than implied by the carried interest alone. Our framework can be adapted to estimate indirect pay for performance in other asset management settings.</description><author>Chung, Ji-Woong; Sensoy, Berk A.; Stern, Lea; Weisbach, Michael S.</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Realized Skewness</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Neuberger, Anthony
The third moment of returns is important for asset pricing, but it is hard to measure precisely, particularly at long horizons. This paper proposes a definition of the realized third moment that is computed from high-frequency returns. It provides an unbiased estimate of the true third moment of long-horizon returns, doing for the third moment what realized variance does for the second moment. The methodology is used to demonstrate that the skewness of equity index returns, far from diminishing with horizon, actually increases with horizons up to a year, and its magnitude is economically important.</description><author>Neuberger, Anthony</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Reexamination of Tunneling and Business Groups: New Data and New Methods</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Siegel, Jordan; Choudhury, Prithwiraj
One of the most rigorous methodologies in the corporate governance literature uses firms' reactions to industry shocks to characterize the quality of governance. This methodology can produce the wrong answer unless one considers the ways firms compete. Because macro-level shocks reverberate differently at the firm level depending on whether a firm has a cost structure that requires significant adjustment, the quality of governance can only be elucidated accurately analyzing a firm's business strategy and their corporate governance. These differences can help one determine whether the fruits of a positive macro-level shock have been expropriated by insiders. Using the example of Indian firms, we show that an influential finding is reversed when these differences are considered. We further argue that the conventional wisdom about tunneling and business groups will need to be reformulated in light of the data, methodology, and findings presented here.</description><author>Siegel, Jordan; Choudhury, Prithwiraj</author><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do Investors Buy What They Know? Product Market Choices and Investment Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keloharju, Matti; Knuepfer, Samuli; Linnainmaa, Juhani
This article shows that individuals' product market choices influence their investment decisions. Using microdata from the brokerage and automotive industries, we find a strong positive relation between customer relationship, ownership of a company, and size of the ownership stake. Investors are also more likely to purchase and less likely to sell shares of companies they frequent as customers. These effects are stronger for individuals with longer customer relationships. A merger-based natural experiment supports a causal interpretation of our results. We also find evidence of causality in the other direction: inheritances and gifts have an effect on individuals' patronage decisions. A setup in which customer-investors regard stocks as consumption goods, not just as investments, seems to best explain our results. (JEL G11, G24, D83).</description><author>Keloharju, Matti; Knuepfer, Samuli; Linnainmaa, Juhani</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Systemic Risk in the Financial Sector Predict Future Economic Downturns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Allen, Linda; Bali, Turan G.; Tang, Yi
We derive a measure of aggregate systemic risk, designated CATFIN, that complements bank-specific systemic risk measures by forecasting macroeconomic downturns six months into the future using out-of-sample tests conducted with U.S., European, and Asian bank data. Consistent with bank "specialness," the CATFIN of both large and small banks forecasts macroeconomic declines, whereas a similarly defined measure for both nonfinancial firms and simulated "fake banks" has no marginal predictive ability. High levels of systemic risk in the banking sector impact the macroeconomy through aggregate lending activity. A conditional asset pricing model shows that CATFIN is priced for financial and nonfinancial firms.</description><author>Allen, Linda; Bali, Turan G.; Tang, Yi</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Market-Based Study of the Cost of Default</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Davydenko, Sergei A.; Strebulaev, Ilya A.; Zhao, Xiaofei
This article proposes a novel method of extracting the cost of default from the change in the market value of a firm's assets upon default. Using a large sample of firms with observed prices of debt and equity that defaulted over fourteen years, we estimate the cost of default for an average defaulting firm to be 21.7% of the market value of assets. The costs vary from 14.7% for bond renegotiations to 30.5% for bankruptcies, and are substantially higher for investment-grade firms (28.8%) than for highly levered bond issuers (20.2%), which extant estimates are based on exclusively. (JEL G21, G30, G33).</description><author>Davydenko, Sergei A.; Strebulaev, Ilya A.; Zhao, Xiaofei</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Out-of-Sample Predictions of Bond Excess Returns and Forward Rates: An Asset Allocation Perspective</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Thornton, Daniel L.; Valente, Giorgio
This article investigates the out-of-sample predictability of bond excess returns. We assess the economic value of the forecasting ability of empirical models based on long-term forward interest rates in a dynamic asset allocation strategy. The results show that the information content of forward rates does not generate systematic economic value to investors. Indeed, these models do not outperform the no-predictability benchmark. Furthermore, their relative performance deteriorates over time.</description><author>Thornton, Daniel L.; Valente, Giorgio</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Measuring Equity Risk with Option-implied Correlations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Buss, Adrian; Vilkov, Grigory
We use forward-looking information from option prices to estimate option-implied correlations and to construct an option-implied predictor of factor betas. With our implied market betas, we find a monotonically increasing risk-return relation, not detectable with standard rolling-window betas, with the slope close to the market excess return. Our implied betas confirm a risk-return relation consistent with linear factor models because, when compared to other beta approaches: (i) they are better predictors of realized betas, and (ii) they exhibit smaller and less systematic prediction errors. The predictive power of our betas is not related to known relations between option-implied characteristics and returns.</description><author>Buss, Adrian; Vilkov, Grigory</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Convertibles and Hedge Funds as Distributors of Equity Exposure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Stephen J.; Grundy, Bruce D.; Lewis, Craig M.; Verwijmeren, Patrick
By buying convertibles and shorting the underlying stock, hedge funds distribute equity exposure to well-diversified shareholders. We find that firms with characteristics that make seasoned equity offerings expensive are more likely to issue convertibles to hedge funds. We conclude that hedge funds provide opportunities for firms to issue convertible securities at a lower cost than seasoned equity by serving as relatively low-cost distributors of equity exposure. A higher fraction of a convertible is privately placed with hedge funds when institutional ownership, stock liquidity, issue size, concurrent stock repurchases, and limitations on callability suggest that shorting costs will be lower.</description><author>Brown, Stephen J.; Grundy, Bruce D.; Lewis, Craig M.; Verwijmeren, Patrick</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can Rare Events Explain the Equity Premium Puzzle?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Julliard, Christian; Ghosh, Anisha
Probably not. First, allowing the probabilities of the states of the economy to differ from their sample frequencies, the consumption-CAPM is still rejected in both U.S. and international data. Second, the recorded world disasters are too small to rationalize the puzzle, unless one assumes that disasters occur every 6-10 years. Third, if the data were generated by the rare events distribution needed to rationalize the equity premium puzzle, the puzzle itself would be unlikely to arise. Fourth, the rare events hypothesis, by reducing the cross-sectional dispersion of consumption risk, worsens the ability of the consumption-CAPM to explain the cross-section of returns.</description><author>Julliard, Christian; Ghosh, Anisha</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Overvalued Equity and Financing Decisions</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dong, Ming; Hirshleifer, David; Teoh, Siew Hong
We test whether and how equity overvaluation affects corporate financing decisions using an ex ante misvaluation measure that filters firm scale and growth prospects from market price. We find that equity issuance and total financing increase with equity overvaluation, but only among overvalued stocks, and that equity issuance is more sensitive than debt issuance to misvaluation. Consistent with managers catering to maintain overvaluation and with investment-scale economy effects, the sensitivity of equity issuance and total financing to misvaluation is stronger among firms with potential growth opportunities (low book-to-market, high R&amp;D, or small size) and high share turnover.</description><author>Dong, Ming; Hirshleifer, David; Teoh, Siew Hong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Flow-Based Explanation for Return Predictability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Lou, Dong
I propose and test a capital-flow-based explanation for some well-known empirical regularities concerning return predictability-the persistence of mutual fund performance, the "smart money" effect, and stock price momentum. First, I construct a measure of demand shocks to individual stocks by aggregating flow-induced trading across all mutual funds, and document a significant, temporary price impact of such uninformed trading. Next, given that mutual fund flows are highly predictable, I show that the expected part of flow-induced trading positively forecasts stock and mutual fund returns in the following year, which are then reversed in subsequent years. The main findings of the paper are that the flow-driven return effect can fully account for mutual fund performance persistence and the smart money effect, and can partially explain stock price momentum.</description><author>Lou, Dong</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Forecasting Stock Returns Through an Efficient Aggregation of Mutual Fund Holdings</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Wermers, Russ; Yao, Tong; Zhao, Jane
We develop a stock return-predictive measure based on an efficient aggregation of the portfolio holdings of all actively managed U.S. domestic equity mutual funds, and use this model to study the source of fund managers' stock selection abilities. This "generalized inverse alpha" (GIA) approach reveals differences in the ability of managers to predict firms' future earnings from fundamental research. Notably, the GIA's return-forecasting power is not subsumed by publicly available quantitative predictors, such as momentum, value, and earnings quality, nor is it subsumed by methods shown in past research to forecast stock returns using fund holdings or trades.</description><author>Wermers, Russ; Yao, Tong; Zhao, Jane</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Institutional Investors and Mutual Fund Governance: Evidence from Retail-Institutional Fund Twins</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Evans, Richard B.; Fahlenbrach, Ruediger
Advisors often manage multiple versions of a fund. These "twins" have the same manager and similar performance but are sold to different investors with differing abilities to select and monitor managers. Comparing investor flows in retail and institutional twins, we find that institutional investors are more sensitive to high fees and poor risk-adjusted performance. Consistent with the reduction of agency problems from greater monitoring, retail funds with an institutional twin outperform other retail funds by 1.5% per year. After the institutional twin is created, expenses decrease while measures of managerial effort at the retail fund increase.</description><author>Evans, Richard B.; Fahlenbrach, Ruediger</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Cash Holdings and Credit Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Acharya, Viral; Davydenko, Sergei A.; Strebulaev, Ilya A.
Intuition suggests that firms with higher cash holdings should be "safer" and have lower credit spreads. Yet empirically, the correlation between cash and spreads is robustly positive. This puzzling finding can be explained by the precautionary motive for saving cash, which in our model causes riskier firms to accumulate higher cash reserves. In contrast, spreads are negatively related to the part of cash holdings that is not determined by credit risk factors. Similarly, although firms with higher cash reserves are less likely to default in the short term, endogenously determined liquidity may be related positively to the longer-term probability of default. Our empirical analysis confirms these predictions, suggesting that precautionary savings are central to understanding the effects of cash on credit risk.</description><author>Acharya, Viral; Davydenko, Sergei A.; Strebulaev, Ilya A.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Sensitivity of Corporate Cash Holdings to Corporate Governance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Qi; Chen, Xiao; Schipper, Katherine; Xu, Yongxin; Xue, Jian
The average cash holdings of Chinese-listed firms decreased significantly after the split share structure reform in China, which specified a process that allowed previously nontradable shares held by controlling shareholders to be freely tradable on the exchanges. The reduction in cash holdings is greater for firms with weaker governance and firms facing more financial constraints prior to the reform. The reform also significantly reduced the average corporate savings rate, as measured by cash-to-cash-flow sensitivity. These findings are consistent with the premise that the reform removed a significant market friction, which led to better incentive alignment between controlling shareholders and minority shareholders and relaxed financial constraints. Additional analyses show that the reform affects firms' cash management policies, investment decisions, dividend payout policies, and financing choices differently in private firms than in state-owned enterprises.</description><author>Chen, Qi; Chen, Xiao; Schipper, Katherine; Xu, Yongxin; Xue, Jian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Convertibles and Hedge Funds as Distributors of Equity Exposure (vol 25, pg 3077, 2012)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Brown, Stephen J.; Grundy, Bruce D.; Lewis, Craig M.; Verwijmeren, Patrick
nan</description><author>Brown, Stephen J.; Grundy, Bruce D.; Lewis, Craig M.; Verwijmeren, Patrick</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Real Consequences of Market Segmentation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chernenko, Sergey; Sunderam, Adi
We study the real effects of market segmentation due to credit ratings by using a matched sample of firms just above and just below the investment-grade cutoff. These firms have similar observables, including average investment rates. However, flows into high-yield mutual funds have an economically significant effect on the issuance and investment of the speculative-grade firms relative to their matches, especially for firms likely to be financially constrained. The effect is associated with the discrete change in label from investment- to speculative-grade, not with changes in continuous measures of credit quality. We do not find similar effects at other rating boundaries.</description><author>Chernenko, Sergey; Sunderam, Adi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Evaporating Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Nagel, Stefan
The returns of short-term reversal strategies in equity markets can be interpreted as a proxy for the returns from liquidity provision. Using this approach, this article shows that the return from liquidity provision is highly predictable with the VIX index. Expected returns and conditional Sharpe ratios from liquidity provision spike during periods of financial market turmoil. The results point to withdrawal of liquidity supply and an associated increase in the expected returns from liquidity provision, as a main driver behind the evaporation of liquidity during times of financial market turmoil, consistent with theories of liquidity provision by financially constrained intermediaries.</description><author>Nagel, Stefan</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Agency Problems and Endogenous Investment Fluctuations</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Favara, Giovanni
This article proposes a theory of investment fluctuations in which the source of the oscillating dynamics is an agency problem between financiers and entrepreneurs. In the model, investment decisions depend on entrepreneurs' initiative to select investment projects ex ante, and financiers' incentive to control entrepreneurs ex post. Too much control discourages entrepreneurial incentive to initiate new investment, whereas too little control jeopardizes its productivity. This initiative-control trade-off is capable of generating endogenous reversal of investment booms, induced by an ongoing deterioration of project profitability. Investment fluctuations may arise even though no external shocks hit the economy and agents are perfectly rational.</description><author>Favara, Giovanni</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Strategic Ownership Structure and the Cost of Debt</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Aslan, Hadiye; Kumar, Praveen
We theoretically and empirically address the endogeneity of corporate ownership structure and the cost of debt, with a novel emphasis on the role of control concentration in post-default firm restructuring. Control concentration raises agency costs of debt, and dominant shareholders trade off private benefits of control against higher borrowing costs in choosing their ownership stakes. Based on our theoretical predictions, and using an international sample of syndicated loans and unique dynamic ownership structure data, we present new evidence on the firm- and macro-level determinants of corporate control concentration and the cost of debt.</description><author>Aslan, Hadiye; Kumar, Praveen</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Generalized Transform Analysis of Affine Processes and Applications in Finance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hui; Joslin, Scott
Nonlinearity is an important consideration in many problems of finance and economics, such as pricing securities and solving equilibrium models. This article provides analytical treatment of a general class of nonlinear transforms for processes with tractable conditional characteristic functions. We extend existing results on characteristic function-based transforms to a substantially wider class of nonlinear functions while maintaining low dimensionality by avoiding the need to compute the density function. We illustrate the applications of the generalized transform in pricing defaultable bonds with stochastic recovery. We also use the method to analytically solve a class of general equilibrium models with multiple goods and apply this model to study the effects of time-varying labor income risk on the equity premium.</description><author>Chen, Hui; Joslin, Scott</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Rare Disasters and Risk Sharing with Heterogeneous Beliefs</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Hui; Joslin, Scott; Tran, Ngoc-Khanh
Risks of rare economic disasters can have a large impact on asset prices. At the same time, difficulties in inference regarding both the likelihood and severity of disasters, as well as agency problems, can lead to significant disagreements among investors about disaster risk. We show that such disagreements generate strong risk-sharing motives, such that just a small number of optimists in the economy will significantly reduce the disaster risk premium. Our model highlights the "latent" nature of disaster risk. The disaster risk premium will likely be low and smooth during normal times but increases dramatically when the risk-sharing capacity of the optimists is reduced, e.g., following a disaster. The model also helps reconcile the difference in the amount of disaster risk implied by financial markets and international macroeconomic data, and provides caution to the approach of extracting disaster probabilities from asset prices, which will disproportionately reflect the beliefs of a small group of optimists. Finally, our model predicts an inverse U-shaped relation between the equity premium and the size of the disaster insurance market.</description><author>Chen, Hui; Joslin, Scott; Tran, Ngoc-Khanh</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Examining the Dark Side of Financial Markets: Do Institutions Trade on Information from Investment Bank Connections?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Griffin, John M.; Shu, Tao; Topaloglu, Selim
Institutions often have access to corporate inside information through their connections, but relatively little is known about the extent to which they exploit their informational advantage through short-term trading. We employ broker-level trading data to systematically examine possible cases of connected trading. Despite examining the issue from multiple angles, we are unable to find much evidence to support that investment bank clients take advantage of connections through takeover advising, IPO and SEO underwriting, or lending relationships. In contrast to recent academic literature and popular press, our findings suggest that institutional investors are reluctant to use inside information in traceable manners.</description><author>Griffin, John M.; Shu, Tao; Topaloglu, Selim</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Asymmetric Information, Portfolio Managers, and Home Bias</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dziuda, Wioletta; Mondria, Jordi
We propose a model of delegated asset management that can explain the following empirical regularities in international markets: the presence of home bias, the lower proportion of mutual funds investing domestically, and the higher market value of mutual funds investing domestically. In the model, fund managers choose whether to specialize in domestic or foreign assets. Individual investors are uncertain about managers' abilities, and they are more informed about domestic markets. This makes domestic investments less risky and generates home bias. Home bias is magnified because higher-ability managers specialize in domestic assets, making them even more attractive to the investors.</description><author>Dziuda, Wioletta; Mondria, Jordi</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Lender Screening and the Role of Securitization: Evidence from Prime and Subprime Mortgage Markets</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Keys, Benjamin J.; Seru, Amit; Vig, Vikrant
This article examines the link between mortgage securitization and lender screening during the boom and bust of the U.S. housing market. Using comprehensive data on both prime and subprime securitized and bank-held loans, we provide evidence that securitization affected lenders' screening decisions in the subprime market for low-documentation loans through two channels: the securitization rate and the time it takes to securitize a loan. The change in decision-making by subprime lenders occurs on dimensions that are unreported to investors. Examining the time-series evolution of the securitization market further reinforces these findings. We exploit heterogeneity across subprime and prime markets to illustrate that the potential for moral hazard may be reduced with greater collection of hard information and increased monitoring of lenders. Our results suggest that the policy debate regarding securitization and lenders' underwriting standards should separately evaluate the agency and non-agency markets, with special attention toward the extent of soft information in assets being securitized.</description><author>Keys, Benjamin J.; Seru, Amit; Vig, Vikrant</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Are Investors Really Reluctant to Realize Their Losses? Trading Responses to Past Returns and the Disposition Effect</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ben-David, Itzhak; Hirshleifer, David
We examine how investor preferences and beliefs affect trading in relation to past gains and losses. The probability of selling as a function of profit is V-shaped; at short holding periods, investors are more likely to sell big losers than small ones. There is little evidence of an upward jump in selling at zero profits. These findings provide no clear indication that realization preference explains trading. Furthermore, the disposition effect is not driven by a simple direct preference for selling a stock by virtue of having a gain versus a loss. Trading based on belief revisions can potentially explain these findings.</description><author>Ben-David, Itzhak; Hirshleifer, David</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Fiscal Policies and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Croce, M. Max; Kung, Howard; Nguyen, Thien T.; Schmid, Lukas
The surge in public debt triggered by the financial crisis has raised uncertainty about future tax pressure and economic activity. We examine the asset pricing effects of fiscal policies in a production-based general equilibrium model in which taxation affects corporate decisions by: (1) distorting profits and investment; (2) reducing the cost of debt through a tax shield; and (3) depressing productivity growth. In settings with recursive preferences, these three tax-based channels generate sizable risk premia, making tax uncertainty a first-order concern. We document further that corporate tax smoothing can substantially alter the effects of public expenditure shocks.</description><author>Croce, M. Max; Kung, Howard; Nguyen, Thien T.; Schmid, Lukas</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Trust and Credit: The Role of Appearance in Peer-to-peer Lending</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Duarte, Jefferson; Siegel, Stephan; Young, Lance
Although it is well known that appearance-based impressions affect labor market and election outcomes, little is known about the role appearance plays in financial transactions. We address this question using photographs of potential borrowers from a peer-to-peer lending site. Consistent with the trust-intensive nature of lending, we find that borrowers who appear more trustworthy have higher probabilities of having their loans funded. Moreover, borrowers who appear more trustworthy indeed have better credit scores and default less often. Overall, our findings suggest that impressions of trustworthiness matter in financial transactions as they predict investor, as well as borrower, behavior. A man I do not trust could not get money from me on all the bonds in Christendom. -John Pierpont Morgan, 1913.</description><author>Duarte, Jefferson; Siegel, Stephan; Young, Lance</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Suspicious Patterns in Hedge Fund Returns and the Risk of Fraud</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bollen, Nicolas P. B.; Pool, Veronika K.
Recent cases of hedge fund fraud have caused large losses for investors and have fueled the debate regarding the ability of regulators to oversee the industry. This article proposes a set of performance flags, based on suspicious patterns in returns, as indicators of a heightened risk of fraud. We collect a sample of hedge funds charged with legal or regulatory violations and find that funds charged with misappropriation, overvaluation, misrepresentation, or Ponzi schemes trigger the performance flags at a higher frequency than other funds.</description><author>Bollen, Nicolas P. B.; Pool, Veronika K.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Universal Banks and Corporate Control: Evidence from the Global Syndicated Loan Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro
We investigate the effects of bank control over borrower firms whether by representation on boards of directors or by the holding of shares through bank asset management divisions. Using a large sample of syndicated loans, we find that banks are more likely to act as lead arrangers in loans when they exert some control over the borrower firm. Bank-firm governance links are associated with higher loan spreads during the 2003-2006 credit boom but lower spreads during the 2007-2008 financial crisis. Additionally, these links mitigate credit rationing effects during the crisis. The results are robust to several methods to correct for the endogeneity of the bank-firm governance link. Our evidence, consistent with intertemporal smoothing of loan rates, suggests that there are costs and benefits from banks' involvement in firm governance.</description><author>Ferreira, Miguel A.; Matos, Pedro</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Idiosyncratic Volatility Proxy for Risk Exposure?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Zhanhui; Petkova, Ralitsa
We decompose aggregate market variance into an average correlation component and an average variance component. Only the latter commands a negative price of risk in the cross section of portfolios sorted by idiosyncratic volatility. Portfolios with high (low) idiosyncratic volatility relative to the Fama-French (1993) model have positive (negative) exposures to innovations in average stock variance and therefore lower (higher) expected returns. These two findings explain the idiosyncratic volatility puzzle of Ang et al. (2006, 2009). The factor related to innovations in average variance also reduces the pricing errors of book-to-market and momentum portfolios relative to the Fama-French (1993) model.</description><author>Chen, Zhanhui; Petkova, Ralitsa</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Decomposition of Optimal Portfolio Weight in a Jump-Diffusion Model and Its Applications</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Jin, Xing; Zhang, Allen X.
This article solves the portfolio choice problem in a multi-asset jump-diffusion model. We decompose the optimal portfolio weight into components that correspond to a collection of fictitious economies, one of which is a standard diffusion economy, and the others of which are pure-jump economies. We derive a semi-closed-form solution for the optimal portfolio weight, and investigate its properties with or without ambiguity aversion. We find that an investor may not reduce her investment in risky assets when facing more frequent jumps, as suggested by a single-asset jump-diffusion model. Moreover, an investor who is extremely cautious about her estimates of higher moments of asset returns may still hold risky assets, contrary to the prediction of a pure-diffusion model with ambiguity aversion to the first moment.</description><author>Jin, Xing; Zhang, Allen X.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Does Beta Move with News? Firm-Specific Information Flows and Learning about Profitability</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Patton, Andrew J.; Verardo, Michela
We investigate whether stock betas vary with the release of firm-specific news. Using daily firm-level betas estimated from intraday prices, we find that betas increase on earnings announcement days and revert to their average levels two to five days later. The increase in betas is greater for earnings announcements that have larger positive or negative surprises, convey more information about other firms in the market, and resolve greater ex ante uncertainty. Our results are consistent with a learning model in which investors use information on announcing firms to revise their expectations about the profitability of the aggregate economy.</description><author>Patton, Andrew J.; Verardo, Michela</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Identifying Expectation Errors in Value/Glamour Strategies: A Fundamental Analysis Approach</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Piotroski, Joseph D.; So, Eric C.
It is well established that value stocks outperform glamour stocks, yet considerable debate exists about whether the return differential reflects compensation for risk or mispricing. Under mispricing explanations, prices of glamour (value) firms reflect systematically optimistic (pessimistic) expectations; thus, the value/glamour effect should be concentrated (absent) among firms with (without) ex ante identifiable expectation errors. Classifying firms based upon whether expectations implied by current pricing multiples are congruent with the strength of their fundamentals, we document that value/glamour returns and ex post revisions to market expectations are predictably concentrated (absent) among firms with ex ante biased (unbiased) market expectations.</description><author>Piotroski, Joseph D.; So, Eric C.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Loan Prospecting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Heider, Florian; Inderst, Roman
We analyze corporate lending when loan officers must be incentivized to prospect for loans and to transmit the soft information they obtain in that process. We explore how this multi-task agency problem shapes loan officers' compensation, banks' use of soft information in credit approval, and their lending standards. When competition intensifies, prospecting for loans becomes more important and banks' internal agency problems worsen. In response to more competition, banks lower lending standards, may choose to disregard soft and use only hard information in their credit approval, and in that case reduce loan officers to salespeople with steep, volume-based compensation. Our model generates "excessive lending" as banks' optimal response to an internal agency problem.</description><author>Heider, Florian; Inderst, Roman</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Educational Networks, Mutual Fund Voting Patterns, and CEO Compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Butler, Alexander W.; Gurun, Umit G.
Mutual funds whose managers are in the same educational network as the firm's CEO are more likely to vote against shareholder-initiated proposals to limit executive compensation than out-of-network funds are. This voting propensity is stronger when voting among the funds in a family is not unanimous. Furthermore, CEOs of firms who have relatively high levels of educationally connected mutual fund ownership have higher levels of compensation than their unconnected counterparts. This aspect of executive compensation is related to both the abnormal trading performance of the connected investors in the firm and the perceived quality of firm management by the connected investors.</description><author>Butler, Alexander W.; Gurun, Umit G.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>No Place Like Home: Familiarity in Mutual Fund Manager Portfolio Choice</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pool, Veronika K.; Stoffman, Noah; Yonker, Scott E.
We show that familiarity affects the portfolio decisions of mutual fund managers. Controlling for fund location, funds overweight stocks from their managers' home states by 12% compared with their peers. In team-managed funds, home-state overweighting is 37% larger than the fund location effect. The home-state bias is stronger if the manager is inexperienced, is resource-constrained, or spent more time in his home state. Home-state stocks do not outperform other holdings, confirming that home-state investments are not informed. The overweighting also leads to excessively risky portfolios.</description><author>Pool, Veronika K.; Stoffman, Noah; Yonker, Scott E.</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Do Retirees Value Life Annuities? Evidence from Public Employees</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chalmers, John; Reuter, Jonathan
Because life annuities can increase the level and decrease the volatility of lifetime consumption, economists have long been puzzled by the low demand for life annuities. One potential rational explanation is that adverse selection drives up life annuity prices, which drives down demand. We study the choice between life annuities and lump sums made by 32,000 retiring public employees. These unique data allow us to extend the existing literature by exploiting economically significant cross-sectional and time-series variation in life annuity pricing. We find little evidence that retiree demand for life annuities rises when life annuity prices fall. We find strong evidence that demand responds to salient variation in individual characteristics, such as health, and to measures of investor sentiment, such as recent equity returns.</description><author>Chalmers, John; Reuter, Jonathan</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Bailouts and Moral Hazard: Evidence from Germany</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Dam, Lammertjan; Koetter, Michael
We use a structural econometric model to provide empirical evidence that safety nets in the banking industry lead to additional risk taking. To identify the moral hazard effect of bailout expectations on bank risk, we exploit the fact that regional political factors explain bank bailouts but not bank risk. The sample includes all observed capital preservation measures and distressed exits in the German banking industry during 1995-2006. A change of bailout expectations by two standard deviations increases the probability of official distress from 6.6% to 9.4%, which is economically significant.</description><author>Dam, Lammertjan; Koetter, Michael</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization, Transparency, and Liquidity</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Pagano, Marco; Volpin, Paolo
We present a model in which issuers of asset-backed securities choose to release coarse information to enhance the liquidity of their primary market, at the cost of reducing secondary market liquidity. The degree of transparency is inefficiently low if the social value of secondary market liquidity exceeds its private value. We show that various types of public intervention (mandatory transparency standards, provision of liquidity to distressed banks, or secondary market price support) have quite different welfare implications. Finally, we extend the model by endogenizing the private and social value of liquidity and the proportion of sophisticated investors.</description><author>Pagano, Marco; Volpin, Paolo</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Attributes and Executive Compensation</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Graham, John R.; Li, Si; Qiu, Jiaping
We study the role of firm- and manager-specific heterogeneities in executive compensation. We decompose the variation in executive compensation and find that time-invariant firm and, especially, manager fixed effects explain a majority of the variation in executive pay. We then show that in many settings, it is important to include fixed effects to mitigate potential omitted variable bias. Furthermore, we find that compensation fixed effects are significantly correlated with management styles (i.e., manager fixed effects in corporate policies). Finally, the method used in the article has a number of potential applications in financial economics.</description><author>Graham, John R.; Li, Si; Qiu, Jiaping</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>How Deep Is the Annuity Market Participation Puzzle?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Inkmann, Joachim; Lopes, Paula; Michaelides, Alexander
Using microeconomic data for the United Kingdom, we analyze the empirical determinants of voluntary annuity market demand. We find that annuity market participation increases with financial wealth, life expectancy, and education and decreases with other pension income and a possible bequest motive for surviving spouses. We then show that these empirically motivated determinants of annuity market participation have the same, quantitatively important, effects in a life-cycle model of annuity and life insurance demand, saving, and portfolio choice. Moreover, reasonable preference parameters predict annuity demand levels comparable to the data. For stockholders, a strong bequest motive can simultaneously generate balanced portfolios and low annuity demand.</description><author>Inkmann, Joachim; Lopes, Paula; Michaelides, Alexander</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Collateral Values by Asset Class: Evidence from Primary Securities Dealers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bartolini, Leonardo; Hilton, Spence; Sundaresan, Suresh; Tonetti, Christopher
Using data on repurchase agreements by primary securities dealers, we show that three classes of securities (Treasury securities, securities issued by government-sponsored agencies, and mortgage-backed securities) can be formally ranked in terms of their collateral values in the general collateral (GC) market. We then show that GC repurchase agreement (repo) spreads across asset classes display jumps and significant temporal variation, especially at times of predictable liquidity needs, consistent with the "safe haven" properties of Treasury securities: These jumps are driven almost entirely by the behavior of the GC repo rates of Treasury securities. Estimating the "collateral rents" earned by owners of these securities, we find such rents to be sizable for Treasury securities and nearly zero for agency and mortgage-backed securities. Finally, we link collateral values to asset prices in a simple no-arbitrage framework and show that variations in collateral values explain a significant fraction of changes in short-term yield spreads but not those of longer-term spreads. Our results point to securities' role as collateral as a promising direction of research to improve understanding of the pricing of money market securities and their spreads.</description><author>Bartolini, Leonardo; Hilton, Spence; Sundaresan, Suresh; Tonetti, Christopher</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Expectations, Bond Yields, and Monetary Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chun, Albert Lee
Through explicitly incorporating analysts' forecasts as observable factors in a dynamic arbitrage-free model of the yield curve, this research proposes a framework for studying the impact of shifts in market sentiment on interest rates of all maturities. An empirical examination reveals that survey expectations about inflation, output growth, and the anticipated path of monetary policy actions contain important information for explaining movements in bond yields. Estimates from a forward-looking monetary policy rule suggest that the central bank exhibits a preemptive response to inflationary expectations while accommodating output growth and monetary policy expectations. Forecasted GDP growth plays a significant role in explaining time variation in the market prices of risk. The sensitivity of long yields is linked to the persistence of expected inflation under the risk-neutral measure. Models of this type may provide traders and policymakers with a new set of tools for formally assessing the reaction of bond yields to shifts in market expectations.</description><author>Chun, Albert Lee</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Relative Wealth Concerns and Complementarities in Information Acquisition</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garcia, Diego; Strobl, Gunter
This article studies how relative wealth concerns, in which a person's satisfaction with their own consumption depends on how much others are consuming, affect investors' incentives to acquire information. We find that such externalities can generate complementarities in information acquisition within the standard rational expectations paradigm. When agents are sensitive to the wealth of others, they herd on the same information, trying to mimic each other's trading strategies. We show that there can be multiple herding equilibria in which different communities pursue different information acquisition strategies. This multiplicity of equilibria generates price discontinuities: An infinitesimal shift in fundamentals can lead to a discrete price movement.</description><author>Garcia, Diego; Strobl, Gunter</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Do the Best Hedge Funds Hedge?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Titman, Sheridan; Tiu, Cristian
We provide a simple argument that suggests that better-informed hedge funds choose to have less exposure to factor risk. Consistent with this argument, we find that hedge funds that exhibit lower R-squareds with respect to systematic factors have higher Sharpe ratios, higher information ratios, and higher alphas. They also exhibit higher manipulation-proof performance measures and charge higher fees.</description><author>Titman, Sheridan; Tiu, Cristian</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>News-Good or Bad-and Its Impact on Volatility Predictions over Multiple Horizons</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Chen, Xilong; Ghysels, Eric
We introduce a new class of parametric models applicable to a mixture of high and low frequency returns and revisit the concept of news impact curves introduced by Engle and Ng (1993). Overall, we find that moderately good (intra-daily) news reduces volatility (the next day), while both very good news (unusual high intra-daily positive returns) and bad news (negative returns) increase volatility, with the latter having a more severe impact. The asymmetries disappear over longer horizons. Models featuring asymmetries dominate in terms of out-of-sample forecasting performance, especially during the 2007-2008 financial crisis.</description><author>Chen, Xilong; Ghysels, Eric</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What's Vol Got to Do with It</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Drechsler, Itamar; Yaron, Amir
Uncertainty plays a key role in economics, finance, and decision sciences. Financial markets, in particular derivative markets, provide fertile ground for understanding how perceptions of economic uncertainty and cash-flow risk manifest themselves in asset prices. We demonstrate that the variance premium, defined as the difference between the squared VIX index and expected realized variance, captures attitudes toward uncertainty. We show conditions under which the variance premium displays significant time variation and return predictability. A calibrated, generalized long-run risks model generates a variance premium with time variation and return predictability that is consistent with the data, while simultaneously matching the levels and volatilities of the market return and risk-free rate. Our evidence indicates an important role for transient non-Gaussian shocks to fundamentals that affect agents' views of economic uncertainty and prices.</description><author>Drechsler, Itamar; Yaron, Amir</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Generalized Disappointment Aversion, Long-run Volatility Risk, and Asset Prices</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bonomo, Marco; Garcia, Rene; Meddahi, Nour; Tedongap, Romeo
We propose an asset pricing model with generalized disappointment aversion preferences and long-run volatility risk. With Markov switching fundamentals, we derive closed-form solutions for all returns moments and predictability regressions. The model produces first and second moments of price-dividend ratios and asset returns as well as return predictability patterns in line with the data. Compared to Bansal and Yaron (2004), we generate (i) more predictability of excess returns by price-dividend ratios; (ii) less predictability of consumption growth rates by price-dividend ratios. Our results do not depend on a value of the elasticity of intertemporal substitution greater than one.</description><author>Bonomo, Marco; Garcia, Rene; Meddahi, Nour; Tedongap, Romeo</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>A Theory of Debt Market Illiquidity and Leverage Cyclicality</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hennessy, Christopher A.; Zechner, Josef
We analyze determinants of secondary debt market liquidity, identifying conditions under which a large investor can profitably buy stakes from small bondholders and offer unilateral debt relief to a distressed firm. We show that endogenous trading by small bondholders may result in multiple equilibria. Some equilibria entail vanishing liquidity and sharp increases in yields absent changing fundamentals. In turn, anticipation of illiquid equilibria induces firms to eschew public debt financing, since such equilibria create higher bankruptcy costs and debt illiquidity discounts. The model thus offers a rational micro-foundation for stylized facts commonly attributed to investor sentiment and CFO market timing. Finally, we show that the vulnerability of debt markets to multiple equilibria is highest during downturns, when small bondholders face severe adverse selection.</description><author>Hennessy, Christopher A.; Zechner, Josef</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Economics of Super Managers</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Baranchuk, Nina; MacDonald, Glenn; Yang, Jun
We study a competitive model in which managers differ in ability and choose unobservable effort. Each firm chooses its size, how able a manager is to hire, and managerial compensation. The model can be considered an amalgam of agency and Superstars, where optimizing incentives enhances the firm's ability to provide a talented manager with greater resources. The model delivers many testable implications. Preliminary results show that the model is useful for understanding interesting compensation trends, for example, why CEO pay has recently become more closely associated with firm size. Allowing for firm productivity differences generally strengthens our results.</description><author>Baranchuk, Nina; MacDonald, Glenn; Yang, Jun</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Determinants of Dividend Smoothing: Empirical Evidence</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Leary, Mark T.; Michaely, Roni
We document the cross-sectional properties of corporate dividend-smoothing policies and relate them to extant theories. We find that younger, smaller firms, firms with low dividend yields and more volatile earnings and returns, and firms with fewer and more disperse analyst forecasts smooth less. Firms that are cash cows, with low growth prospects, weaker governance, and greater institutional holdings, smooth more. We also document that dividend smoothing has steadily increased over the past 80 years, even before firms began using share repurchases in the mid-1980s. Taken together, our results suggest that dividend smoothing is most common among firms that are not financially constrained, face low levels of asymmetric information, and are most susceptible to agency conflicts. These findings provide challenges and guidance for the developing theoretical literature.</description><author>Leary, Mark T.; Michaely, Roni</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Former CEO Directors: Lingering CEOs or Valuable Resources?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Fahlenbrach, Ruediger; Minton, Bernadette A.; Pan, Carrie H.
We investigate corporate governance experts' claim that it is detrimental to a firm to reappoint former CEOs as directors after they step down as CEOs. We find that more successful and more powerful former CEOs are more likely to be reappointed to the board multiple times after they step down as CEOs. Firms benefit, on average, from the presence of former CEOs on their boards. Firms with former CEO directors have better accounting performance, have higher relative turnover-performance sensitivity of the successor CEO, and can rehire their former CEO directors as CEOs after extremely poor firm performance under the successor CEOs.</description><author>Fahlenbrach, Ruediger; Minton, Bernadette A.; Pan, Carrie H.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Managerial Autonomy, Allocation of Control Rights, and Optimal Capital Structure</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Boot, Arnoud W. A.; Thakor, Anjan V.
We examine the design of control rights of external financiers, and how these interact with the firm's security issuance and capital structure when the firm's initial owners and managers may disagree with new investors over project choice. The first main result is an ex ante managerial preference for "soft" financial claims that maximize managerial project-choice autonomy, which is in contrast to agency theory. Second, a dynamic "pecking order" of cash, equity, and debt emerges. Additional results explain equity issuance at high prices, the drifting of leverage ratios with stock returns, cash hoarding, and debt usage without taxes, agency, or signaling.</description><author>Boot, Arnoud W. A.; Thakor, Anjan V.</author><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>What Factors Drive Global Stock Returns?</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Hou, Kewei; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Kho, Bong-Chan
Using monthly returns for over 27,000 stocks from 49 countries over a three-decade period, we show that a multifactor model that includes factor-mimicking portfolios based on momentum and cash flow-to-price captures significant time-series variation in global stock returns, and has lower pricing errors and fewer model rejections than the global CAPM or a popular model that uses size and book-to-market factors. We find reliable evidence that the global cash flow-to-price factor is related to a covariance risk model. In contrast, we reject the covariance risk model in favor of a characteristic model for size and book-to-market factors.</description><author>Hou, Kewei; Karolyi, G. Andrew; Kho, Bong-Chan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Securitization and Mortgage Renegotiation: Evidence from the Great Depression (vol 24, pg 1814, 2011)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghent, Andra C.
nan</description><author>Ghent, Andra C.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>The Effect of Risk on the CEO Market</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex; Gabaix, Xavier
This article presents a market equilibrium model of CEO assignment, pay, and incentives under risk aversion and moral hazard. Each of the three outcomes can be summarized by a single closed-form equation. In the presence of moral hazard, assignment is distorted from positive assortative matching on firm size as firms with higher risk or disutility choose less talented CEOs. Such firms also pay higher salaries in the cross-section, but economy-wide increases in risk or the disutility of being a CEO do not affect pay. The strength of incentives depends only on the disutility of effort and is independent of risk and risk aversion. If the CEO can affect firm risk, incentives rise and are increasing in risk and risk aversion. We calibrate the losses from various forms of poor corporate governance, such as failures in monitoring and inefficiencies in CEO assignment.</description><author>Edmans, Alex; Gabaix, Xavier</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Growing Out of Trouble? Corporate Responses to Liability Risk</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Gormley, Todd A.; Matsa, David A.
This article analyzes corporate responses to the liability risk arising from workers' exposure to newly identified carcinogens. We find that firms, especially those with weak balance sheets, tend to respond to such risks by acquiring large, unrelated businesses with relatively high operating cash flows. The diversifying growth appears to be primarily motivated by managers' personal exposure to their firms' risk in that the growth has negative announcement returns and is related to firms' external governance, managerial stockholdings, and institutional ownership. The results suggest that corporate governance is particularly important when firms are exposed to the risk of large, adverse shocks.</description><author>Gormley, Todd A.; Matsa, David A.</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Learning and Asset-price Jumps</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bansal, Ravi; Shaliastovich, Ivan
We develop a general equilibrium model in which income and dividends are smooth but asset prices contain large moves (jumps). These large price jumps are triggered by optimal decisions of investors to learn the unobserved state. We show that learning choice is determined by preference parameters and the conditional volatility of income process. An important model prediction is that income volatility predicts future jump periods, while income growth does not. Consistent with the model, large moves in returns in the data are predicted by consumption volatility but not by consumption growth. The model quantitatively captures these novel features of the data.</description><author>Bansal, Ravi; Shaliastovich, Ivan</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Bank Liquidity, Interbank Markets, and Monetary Policy</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Freixas, Xavier; Martin, Antoine; Skeie, David
A lesson of the recent financial crisis is that the interbank market is crucial for banks facing uncertainty regarding their liquidity needs. This article studies the efficiency of the interbank market in allocating funds. We show that the central bank should lower the interbank rate when confronted with a crisis that causes a disparity in the liquidity held among banks. This suggests that the traditional tenet prescribing the separation between prudential regulation and monetary policy should be abandoned. We also show that failure to cut interest rates during a crisis erodes financial stability by increasing the risk of bank runs.</description><author>Freixas, Xavier; Martin, Antoine; Skeie, David</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Credit Default Swaps and the Empty Creditor Problem</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Bolton, Patrick; Oehmke, Martin
The empty creditor problem arises when a debtholder has obtained insurance against default but otherwise retains control rights in and outside bankruptcy. We analyze this problem from an ex ante and ex post perspective in a formal model of debt with limited commitment, by comparing contracting outcomes with and without insurance through credit default swaps (CDS). We show that CDS, and the empty creditors they give rise to, have important ex ante commitment benefits: By strengthening creditors' bargaining power, they raise the debtor's pledgeable income and help reduce the incidence of strategic default. However, we also show that lenders will over-insure in equilibrium, giving rise to an inefficiently high incidence of costly bankruptcy. We discuss a number of remedies that have been proposed to overcome the inefficiency resulting from excess insurance.</description><author>Bolton, Patrick; Oehmke, Martin</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Risk Shifting and Mutual Fund Performance</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Huang, Jennifer; Sialm, Clemens; Zhang, Hanjiang
Mutual funds change their risk levels significantly over time. Risk shifting might be caused by ill-motivated trades of unskilled or agency-prone fund managers who trade to increase their personal compensation. Alternatively, risk shifting might occur when skilled fund managers trade to take advantage of their stock selection and timing abilities. This article investigates the performance consequences of risk shifting and sheds light on the mechanisms and the economic motivations behind risk-shifting behavior. Using a holdings-based measure of risk shifting, we find that funds that increase risk perform worse than funds that keep stable risk levels over time, suggesting that risk shifting either is an indication of inferior ability or is motivated by agency issues.</description><author>Huang, Jennifer; Sialm, Clemens; Zhang, Hanjiang</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Tractability in Incentive Contracting</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Edmans, Alex; Gabaix, Xavier
This article develops a framework that delivers tractable (i.e., closed-form) optimal contracts, with few restrictions on the utility function, cost of effort, or noise distribution. By modeling the noise before the action in each period, we force the contract to provide correct incentives state-by-state, rather than merely on average. This tightly constrains the set of admissible contracts and allows for a simple solution to the contracting problem. Our results continue to hold in continuous time, where noise and actions are simultaneous. We illustrate the potential usefulness of our setup by a series of examples related to CEO incentives. In particular, the model derives predictions for the optimal measure of incentives and whether the contract should be convex, concave, or linear. (JEL D86, G34)</description><author>Edmans, Alex; Gabaix, Xavier</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Wealth, Information Acquisition and Portfolio Choice (vol 17, pg 879, 2004)</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Peress, Joel
nan</description><author>Peress, Joel</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Recourse and Residential Mortgage Default: Evidence from US States</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ghent, Andra C.; Kudlyak, Marianna
We quantify the effect of recourse on default and find that recourse affects default by lowering the borrower's sensitivity to negative equity. At the mean value of the default option for defaulted loans, borrowers are 30% more likely to default in non-recourse states. Furthermore, for homes appraised at $500,000 to $750,000, borrowers are twice as likely to default in non-recourse states. We also find that defaults are more likely to occur through a lender-friendly procedure, such as a deed in lieu, in states that allow deficiency judgments. We find no evidence that mortgage interest rates are lower in recourse states. (JEL E44, G21, G28, K11, R20)</description><author>Ghent, Andra C.; Kudlyak, Marianna</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Can VCs Time the Market? An Analysis of Exit Choice for Venture-backed Firms</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Ball, Eric; Chiu, Hsin Hui; Smith, Richard
We use a sample of 8,163 venture-backed companies over three decades to test the competing hypotheses that levels and relative shares of IPO (initial public offering) and M&amp;A(mergers and acquisitions) exits are affected by market timing, versus pseudo-market timing that reflects market conditions. We find evidence of pseudo-market timing. Venture-backed issuers react to market or sector runups but do not predict downturns. We find no evidence that firm-specific market timing contributes to IPO or M&amp;A waves. We also find that acquirers turn to acquisition when other opportunities are unattractive, and that the market may be slow to recognize that such opportunities are declining. (JEL G14, G24, G32, G34)</description><author>Ball, Eric; Chiu, Hsin Hui; Smith, Richard</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item><item><title>Information Sales and Strategic Trading</title><link>http://www.example.com/articles/1</link><description>Garcia, Diego; Sangiorgi, Francesco
We study information sales in financial markets with strategic risk-averse traders. The optimal selling mechanism is one of the following two: (i) sell to as many agents as possible very imprecise information; (ii) sell to a small number of agents information as precise as possible. As risk-sharing considerations prevail over the negative effects of competition, the newsletters or rumors associated with (i) dominate the exclusivity contract in (ii). These allocations of information have implications for price informativeness and trading volume, and thus we suggest a direct link between properties of asset prices and financial intermediation. Moreover, as more information is sold when the externality in its valuation is relatively less intense, we find a ranking reversal of the informational content of prices between (a) market structures (market-orders vs. limit-orders); and (b) models of traders' behavior (imperfect vs. perfect competition). (JEL D82, G14)</description><author>Garcia, Diego; Sangiorgi, Francesco</author><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.example.com/articles/1</guid></item></channel></rss>